<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Protests Expose Deeper Fragility as Leaders Struggle to Contain Crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/irans-protests-expose-deeper-fragility-as-leaders-struggle-to-contain-crisis</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/an-iranian-woman-stands-in-an-area-outside-a-holy-shrine-in-northern-tehran-iran-on-december-31-2025-following-the-latest-un.jpg?id=62651190&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C314%2C0%2C314&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIPHER BRIEF EXPERT INTERVIEW&lt;/strong&gt; -- Economic grievances in Iran have sparked demonstrations for a fifth straight day, with protests surfacing in Tehran and multiple provincial cities as inflation, a collapsing currency, and worsening living conditions fuel public anger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports from state-linked media, local officials, and rights groups confirm new clashes and at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/01/world/middleeast/iran-protests-deaths.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one additional death&lt;/a&gt;, though accounts differ over whether the deceased was a member of a pro-government militia or a protester. Several other incidents of violence were reported in western and southern regions, but independent verification remains difficult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Masoud Pezeshkian, traveling in southwestern and eastern Iran, has acknowledged mounting public dissatisfaction and urged officials to address the population’s concerns, calling mismanagement - not foreign adversaries - the primary cause of the crisis. His remarks contrasted with harder-line figures who continue to blame unnamed “enemies” for the unrest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest protests began after the Iranian rial plunged to &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/iran-traders-protest-rial-currency-ddc955739fb412b642251dee10638f03&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;record lows&lt;/a&gt;, prompting the resignation of Central Bank Governor Mohammad Reza Farzin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The broader economic backdrop is bleak: inflation remains above 40 percent, food and household costs have surged, and nearly every major sector outside oil is contracting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The ongoing, still relatively small, economic protests now unfolding in several cities in Iran are the latest indicator of the Islamic Republic's fragility,” Middle East Expert and former National Security Manager for Iran at ODNI, Norm Roule tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roule explains in this exclusive Cipher Brief analysis, why he believes the latest protests are likely a sign of what could be waiting for Tehran in the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;expert-block-container expert-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Norman T. Roule&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.rbl.ms/56514528/origin.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;expert-name&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule&quot;&gt;Norman T. Roule&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;expert-original-about&quot;&gt;
          Norman Roule is a geopolitical and energy consultant who served for 34 years in the Central Intelligence Agency, managing numerous programs relating to Iran and the Middle East. He also served as the National Intelligence Manager for Iran (NIM-I)\n at ODNI, where he was responsible for all aspects of national intelligence policy related to Iran.
    	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ANALYSIS -- “Since 2017, Tehran’s domestic oppression, persistent inflation, declining standards of living, international isolation, and weak domestic policy credibility have produced periods of sharp and widespread unrest. Iran’s security forces have responded brutally. But the protests have shattered the Islamic Republic’s political self-confidence. Tehran’s response to the ongoing demonstrations reflects that mood. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A regime that once boasted that its high national election turnout reflected the support of its people is now unable to hide historic low voter turnout and accepts the threat of destabilizing national unrest as an inevitable consequence of life in modern-day Iran. Economic challenges are not the regime’s only concern. Iran’s historic drought and other environmental problems persist. Winter saw a sharp decline in air quality in large areas of Tehran, Khuzestan, and Isfahan provinces. In early December, Iran’s health minister announced that ongoing air pollution problems had sent more than 170,000 Iranians to emergency wards with heart and respiratory problems. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether the current unrest expands or dissipates - like prior waves of protest - remains uncertain. What is clearer is that the underlying drivers are durable, making future episodes virtually certain. The more consequential question is whether disillusionment will remain confined to civilians or will begin to test the cohesion and confidence of the security forces the Islamic Republic has relied upon for so many years to contain dissent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ongoing collapse of Iran’s currency, the rial, ignited the protests this week. After the currency fell as low as 1.42 million per dollar, Central Bank Governor Mohammad Reza Farzin resigned. The magnitude of the slide is best understood with some history: In 1979, the Iranian rial stood at 72 to the dollar. On July 14, 2015, the day the Iran nuclear deal was signed in Vienna, the Iranian rial was at 29,500 per dollar. When Farzin entered office in December 2022, the rial traded at about 430,000 to the dollar. Whatever the precise benchmarks, the trend is unmistakable: the rial’s weakness has become both a symbol of policy failure and a driver of unrest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The currency’s decline has coincided with bleak economic signals. Except for anemic growth in the oil sector, every key sector of Iran’s economy is entering recession, foreshadowing higher unemployment. Industry and mining declined by 3.4%, construction by 12.9% and agriculture contracted by 2.9%. At the same time, inflation is growing. The Statistical Center of Iran (SCI) reported that Iran’s average annual inflation reached 42.2% in December. A close examination of this number indicates the significant impact of inflation on Iranian consumers. Food, tobacco, and beverages rose 72% year over year. This persistent high inflation erodes the purchasing power of Iranians and drives an increasing number into poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tehran’s options are few. Iran’s problems are deep and structural, and durable improvement would require political and ideological shifts beyond what the Pezeshkian administration is likely able to deliver. Even so, the government will be compelled to act on three fronts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, Farzin’s resignation provides the president with a convenient focal point for public anger, but it does nothing to address the issues that precipitated the crisis: fiscal mismanagement, sanctions pressure, and chronic credibility deficits. President Pezeshkian has reportedly selected 64-year-old former economy minister Abdolnaser Hemmati as Farzin’s successor. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hemmati may at first seem a counterintuitive choice, given that the Iranian Parliament impeached him in March for failing in similar circumstances. However, he has a background that offers potential for stability. First, he is experienced. He led the Central Bank of Iran (CBI) from 2018 until late May 2021, during the Trump administration's earlier sanctions, and his work helped stabilize the foreign exchange market under similar difficult circumstances. He also qualifies as a regime insider with decades of experience with hardliners and more pragmatic conservatives. After beginning his career as an agricultural economist, he moved to Iran’s broadcasting organization, where he rose to become its political deputy and director general of news broadcasting. He then became the Director of Iran’s Central Insurance Corporation. Between 2006 and 2016, Hemmati led Sina Bank and Bank Mellat, banks with close ties to the Revolutionary Guard's Qods Force, to the extent that the U.S. and the European Union designated each. Hemmati attempted to enter the 2024 presidential election on a platform offering economic stabilization, but the Guardian Council rejected his candidacy. He instead became Pezeshkian’s economy minister, a position he held until his impeachment on 2 March 2024, following a spike in inflation and the rial's fall to 950,000 to the dollar. Ironically, that value would be seen as a significant improvement in its status today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hemmati will need to work quickly with Pezeshkian to propose measures to decelerate inflation, with an emphasis on protecting low-income and rural households. In the medium term, Hemmati will need to target Iran’s banking sector to strengthen balance sheets and prevent further failures. The downside of this last step is that it will inevitably involve some recognition of bad loans and credit tightening to prevent additional poor loan issuance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, Pezeshkian will focus on budget reform. Details on his latest budget are limited, but we know that security and military entities remain well-resourced, which will constrain his options on the civilian side. He has proposed a 20% salary increase for public workers, but it will not keep up with inflation, and even here, he will struggle to find the funds. The budget debate will continue until 20 March 2026, and will likely remain contentious, given its emphasis on tax collection and subsidy cuts rather than oil revenues as a source of income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last, foreign policy will remain the most complicated aspect of Pezeshkian’s economic challenges. His government will do whatever it can to mitigate the impact of sanctions through engagement with Russia, China, and Africa, and will continue to seek talks with Washington. Initiating negotiations with the U.S., even without a prospect of an outcome, has in the past strengthened the rial. But if Pezeshkian would welcome talks with the West, the hardline actors within the regime responsible for Iran’s foreign policy remain focused on aggressive goals that remain one of the primary obstacles to peace in the region. The Quds Force shows every sign of seeking to rebuild its shattered proxies and establish new relationships with the Khartoum and other actors in Africa. The Trump administration’s approach to Tehran has been consistent. It will not waste time on talks that offer sanctions relief without seismic changes in the regime’s approach to nuclear, missiles, and regional issues. Gulf Arabs are willing to maintain a strategy of détente but will not consider rapprochement without an end to Qods Force activity in the region. Absent political rapprochement and a belief that capital invested in Iran will not be subject to terrorism or human rights sanctions, foreign investment for Iran will remain impossible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last, Iran’s leaders will inevitably recognize that this unrest is unfolding amid several hallmarks of a pre-revolutionary situation: institutional failure, fragmentation among the ruling elites, generational alienation, persistent fiscal crisis, widespread economic suffering, class antagonism, escalating and chronic protests, and the absence of a unifying state narrative. President Pezeshkian recently stated that his country was “in a full-fledged war with America, Israel, and Europe.” Such rhetoric will play to domestic hardline audiences while reinforcing Iran’s aggressive reputation abroad. During this sensitive period, Iran is unlikely to take actions that would further exacerbate its domestic fragility and instead seeks to gradually test Western red lines while navigating the Islamic Republic through what remains the regime's most sensitive and challenging economic and political period since the 1980s.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the White House Will Shape 2026</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/01/trump-shape-2026-immigration-diplomacy-midterms/</link>
      <description>FP Live looks at the year ahead in U.S. politics—and how that will impact the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin Again Bungles Strategy: Why His War of Attrition will Sink Russia</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putin-ukraine-war-sink-russia</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;On February 14, 2022, with Russia poised to invade Ukraine, I questioned whether Vladimir Putin’s reign to that point had revealed him to be a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/is-the-russian-president-a-strategic-master-or-a-strategic-failure&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;strategic master or a strategic failure&lt;/a&gt;. Nearly four years later, the verdict is even more apparent. Putin, confident in his strategic calculus that the West would provide only token assistance to Ukraine, which would quickly fold under the weight and violence of Russian military might, fatefully launched his attack days later with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putin-strategic-failure-ukraine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;disastrous consequences for Russia&lt;/a&gt;. The country he leads is now even poorer, more isolated, brittle, and dependent (on China) than before. Putin grossly underestimated Ukrainian will, overestimated the competence of his own military and intelligence apparatus, and misjudged Western cohesion. By the Fall of 2022, it was obvious even to Putin that his expected quick victory was unattainable. This was surely a bitter pill to swallow, but he quickly pivoted to a “wait and win” war strategy of grinding attrition, calculating that through sheer mass and perseverance--and Western impatience--time would be on his side. Most pundits, even those in the West, have tended to agree with him, much as they did in 2022 about the likelihood that Russia would quickly roll over Ukraine. This mindset, however--that time is on Russia’s side--risks a strategic misreading no less profound than his original blunder, because there is a strong argument to be made that Putin’s attrition strategy is eroding key foundations of Russian power faster and more deeply than it is eroding the Ukrainian front lines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus far Russia has managed to sustain a high level of war spending, but there are growing signs of strain. Russia’s numerical troop advantage over Ukraine is maintained almost entirely through extraordinarily high financial incentives, but these are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euronews.com/2025/12/02/russia-cuts-troop-bonuses-and-delays-death-benefits-amid-budget-shortfalls&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;starting to drop steeply&lt;/a&gt; due to growing budget shortfalls, particularly in regional budgets on which such spending disproportionately falls. New contracts for soldiers in April-June 2025 were less than half the level of the same period in 2024, signaling a significant weakening in the effectiveness of financial inducements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it’s not just the money. The death toll for Russian soldiers is accelerating. U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/releases/office-of-the-spokesperson/2025/07/secretary-of-state-marco-rubios-remarks-to-the-press-at-the-kuala-lumpur-convention-center&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stated in July of this year&lt;/a&gt; that the number of Russian dead for the first half of 2025 alone exceeded 100,000. This has likely contributed to a sharp increase in desertions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://frontelligence.substack.com/p/silent-exodus-rising-desertions-in&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;estimated to have doubled in 2025&lt;/a&gt; with approximately 70,000 desertions, or approximately 10% of the force in Ukraine. Russia is increasingly reliant on coerced recruits, harsh punishments for desertion, including torture and extrajudicial executions, all signs of a military struggling to maintain sustainable, motivated troop levels. While tactical adaptations have allowed Russian forces to regain some initiative on the battlefield, they rest on a manpower model that burns through human capital, i.e., human beings, at a pace no country with Russia’s demographic profile can long sustain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who’s Reading this? More than 500K of the most influential national security experts in the world. Need &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;full access&lt;/a&gt; to what the Experts are reading?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the war drags on, Russia is also becoming even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-russia-relationship&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more dependent on China&lt;/a&gt;. Post-2022 trade patterns show a Russia increasingly locked into an asymmetric partnership in which Russia humiliatingly relies on China for critical imports of technology, while Beijing gains leverage through discounted energy purchases and control over supply chains, making Moscow increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/china-is-russias-crutch&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vulnerable to Beijing’s whims&lt;/a&gt; over time. For a leader obsessed with sovereignty, the long-term trajectory Putin has embarked on contains a glaring paradox: the longer he fights to keep Ukraine out of the Western orbit, the more he locks Russia into a subordinate position in China’s. Talk about strategic irony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These financial strains and deepening dependence on China are compounded by the continued tightening of international sanctions on the Russian energy sector, a general decrease in the price of oil and gas on which Russia is so heavily dependent as the global economy cools, and the heavy depletion of Russia’s “rainy day” sovereign wealth fund, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/content-series/russia-tomorrow/the-russian-economy-in-2025-between-stagnation-and-militarization/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;which has dropped by almost 60%&lt;/a&gt; and now mostly consists of Chinese Renminbi and gold, having exhausted its hard currency holdings. Maintaining current defense spending will thus increasingly require either higher borrowing from domestic banks or visible cuts in social spending and civilian projects, further eroding living standards and stoking popular war fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Putin’s war-of-choice with Ukraine has only intensified Russia’s pre-war weaknesses. Russia’s economy, already underperforming relative to its resource base and human potential, must now deal with permanent war spending and sanctions-induced inefficiencies. Its demographics, already fragile, are being further hollowed out by horrific war casualties and the emigration of skilled workers. Russia’s civic life, already stunted, is being further smothered by wartime repression. Finally, Putin’s invasion not only failed to restore a pliant Ukrainian “little brother”, it locked Russia into a costly struggle against the second largest country in Europe, after itself, and one that is moreover more anti-Russian, better armed, and more deeply integrated with the West than before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And now, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/trump-zelenskiy-talks-yield-no-progress-ukraine-russia-territorial-issues-2025-12-29/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;slow-rolling negotiations&lt;/a&gt; to end the conflict, Putin misreads the trajectory of this war in the same way he misread its opening act. He underestimates the cumulative effect of casualties and consequences of economic distortions and social fatigue inside Russia; he overestimates the degree that support of the Western democracies for Ukraine will collapse under the weight of their debates and divisions; and he also, again, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/perhaps-ukraines-most-dangerous-time&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;overestimates&lt;/a&gt; his ability to break Ukraine by military force. In analyzing the arc of Putin’s rule, the war in Ukraine is not an aberration from Putinism, but its logical culmination. In strategic terms, it represents a transition from a condition of chronic underperformance to one of active and acute self-harm. Nearly four years after his decision to invade Ukraine, which more than anything else will define his reign, Putin is not outplaying history on a grand chessboard by doubling down on the war, he is sacrificing Russia’s future for the sake of victories and imperial fantasies that cannot be won, much less sustained. This is the definition of strategic failure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a self-proclaimed student of Russian history, Putin would be wise to remember the setting of Russia’s original regime-toppling “color revolution,” the February Revolution of 1917. This was the spontaneous Russian popular uprising that led to the abdication of the Tsar and formation of a Provisional Government, not the subsequent Bolshevik coup d’etat later that year. While popular discontent with the monarchy had long been rising, it was the accumulated privations of war that brought events to a boiling point. As with that war, time in this one is not on Putin’s side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the US Economy Headed in 2026?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/where-is-the-us-economy-headed-in-2026</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a tumultuous 12 months for the US economy, the coming year may well be marked by even greater upheaval. From the likelihood that President Donald Trump’s tariff chickens will come home to roost to the risk of a stock-market crash, there is good reason to fear that the global economy’s most powerful engine may stall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/where-is-the-us-economy-headed-in-2026-doc-2026-01</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Year’s Resolutions for Global VIPs</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/01/new-years-resolutions-trump-putin-netanyahu-tech-europe/</link>
      <description>Some tailored advice for international elites in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Intrigue</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/new-year-new-intrigue</link>
      <description>The secret services of Israel, Turkey, China, the U.S. and UAE vie for influence in Somaliland</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Middle East Looks Toward a Grim 2026</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/01/trump-israel-hamas-hezbollah-iran-peace-gaza-2026/</link>
      <description>Simmering conflicts require more attention than can be expected from a mercurial U.S. president.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elections to Watch in 2026</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/01/top-world-elections-2026-brazil-israel-hungary-bangladesh-colombia-ethiopia/</link>
      <description>These are the year’s biggest races, from Bangladesh to Brazil.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 in review: defense systems</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/01/2025-review/410396/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba on the Brink</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/cuba/cuba-brink</link>
      <description>Where will the island’s crisis end?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
