<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>China Is Building a Better, More Modern Military</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/china-military-xi-jinping-purges/</link>
      <description>Xi’s purges are part of a generational reshuffling of generals.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace negotiations give freezing Kyiv a hint of hope</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/30/peace-negotiations-give-freezing-kyiv-a-hint-of-hope</link>
      <description>Talks with Russia in Abu Dhabi could point towards a compromise</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moscow Agrees to Halt Kyiv Attacks Until Feb. 1 at Trump’s Request</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/russia-halts-attacks-kyiv-ukraine-energy-infrastructure-trump-trilateral-talks/</link>
      <description>But Russian forces continue to target Ukraine’s energy infrastructure amid sub-zero temperatures.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/news-quiz-china-xi-anti-corruption-trump-minneapolis-ice-israel-gaza/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Jan. 24: China’s anti-corruption crusade continues, Trump pushes boundaries in Minneapolis, and India and the EU reach a trade deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the ‘Mad Max’ World Order</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/mad-max-uranium-convoy-sahel/</link>
      <description>How a runaway uranium convoy encapsulates the collapse of global rules.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Downfall of General Zhang Youxia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-downfall-of-general-zhang-youxia/</link>
      <description>What does the recent upheaval in the top ranks of China's military tell us about politics, security and Xi Jinping's China?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day Russia’s War Collided With History</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/russia-ukraine-putin-propaganda-world-war-narrative-military/</link>
      <description>By lasting longer than World War II, the invasion of Ukraine has shattered the Kremlin’s most sacred myth.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the U.S. Forgot It Was an Arctic Nation</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/reluctant-conquest-review-us-arctic-history-trump/</link>
      <description>The story of how Washington neglected the Arctic—until Trump 2.0.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Succession Without a Successor: Kim Ju Ae as a Legitimacy Asset</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/succession-without-a-successor-kim-ju-ae-as-a-legitimacy-asset/</link>
      <description>North Korea may be preparing less for a next ruler than for the risks of transition.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside China’s Rerouted Supply Chains</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/inside-chinas-rerouted-supply-chains/</link>
      <description>New data shows that Chinese exporters are increasingly transiting goods through lower-tariff trade partners. But is the practice legal?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Tech Regulation Paradox Amid Great Power Competition</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-tech-regulation-paradox-amid-great-power-competition/</link>
      <description>Beijing’s efforts to tighten control over technology outflows are increasingly in tension with the need to sustain domestic innovation and global competitiveness.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story newsletter: The ICE test</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/30/cover-story-newsletter-the-ice-test</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s Intelligence Satellites are Proliferating: Their Protection is Not, With Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/americas-intelligence-satellites-are-proliferating-their-protection-is-not-with-exceptions</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;The pace of U.S. national-security launches over the past several months has been staggering. But buried beneath the impressive cadence is an uncomfortable truth: many of the most sensitive intelligence assets now orbiting Earth remain dangerously exposed to enemy action by hostile actors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These assets are launched primarily by the National Reconnaissance Office and the U.S. Space Force Space Systems Command, operating under the National Security Space Launch program (NSSL). The government’s private-sector partners - SpaceX and United Launch Alliance (a joint-venture by Lockheed Martin and Boeing) provide the lift capacity using Falcon 9, the soon to enter operations Falcon Heavy (SpaceX), and the newly introduced Vulcan Centaur rocket (ULA).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congress has long recognized the importance of assured access to space. As the Congressional Research Service &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.jumpto.es/l/178c4d348dbce6e83dbaf7399ea03e15eec2b93c?notrack=1&amp;amp;u=179354&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;, U.S. law mandates maintaining at least two launch vehicles capable of delivering any national-security payload to orbit. That policy has worked. The problem is what happens after launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past four years, most NRO launches fall into three categories. First are signals-intelligence satellites (SIGINT). Second are large, electro-optical imaging satellites (IMINT) - capable of extraordinary resolution, as the public briefly glimpsed when Donald Trump released an undegraded intelligence &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.jumpto.es/l/ae2956f5297b55ecee975f224fd7fd89cf3a0d0f?notrack=1&amp;amp;u=179354&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt; in a startling lapse of operational security. Third are the Starshield (the name of the program) satellites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proliferated Architecture represents a strategic shift; its &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.jumpto.es/l/49522628c681abff983fa37fef6a40ecbe6f84bb?notrack=1&amp;amp;u=179354&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;goal&lt;/a&gt; is to establish &lt;em&gt;“the largest government constellation in history” &lt;/em&gt;consisting of hundreds of satellites with launches planned through 2029. There are roughly half a dozen missions planned for 2026. This project replaces the model of few exquisite, irreplaceable satellites, in favor of resilience through numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That logic is sound - but it applies unevenly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proliferation ensures continuity if adversaries degrade or destroy some satellites. Yet the most sensitive NRO platforms - large SIGINT collectors and high-resolution imaging satellites - remain singular, expensive, and irreplaceable. They are also increasingly vulnerable. Both China and Russia are fielding counterspace capabilities that include electronic warfare, cyber intrusion, co-orbital inspection satellites, and direct-ascent anti-satellite weapons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, America is hardening its communications backbone while leaving its crown jewels exposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deterrence in space no longer comes from secrecy alone. It requires active protection: improved space-domain awareness, on-orbit maneuverability, electronic countermeasures, rapid reconstitution plans, and – ultimately - the willingness to impose costs on adversaries who threaten U.S. space assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States has demonstrated it can launch fast, often, and at scale. The next challenge is more difficult and more urgent: ensuring that the satellites underpinning American military power and intelligence dominance can survive in a contested orbital environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starshield redundancy is a start. Protection of existing assets must be the next step. if a rival has the ability to blind, deceive, or degrade satellites, then a lack of clarity may emerge exactly when clarity is most needed. A lack of clarity in a crisis is a catalyst. In fact, space is crowded, competitive, and, more to the point, contested. The dangers?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, kinetic anti-satellite weapons (ASAT) and debris. Anti-satellite weapons, such as one that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.jumpto.es/l/8eb465dc05d8e7c1dfd0a0c3bb758949b800c830?notrack=1&amp;amp;u=179354&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tested by China in 2007&lt;/a&gt; are some of the most threatening because they have the capability to destroy a satellite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, non-kinetic attacks, like dazzling, jamming, cyber-tampering, and spoofing. The greatest threats on a daily basis are also likely to be non-kinetic, meaning they are temporary or reversible, although still potentially operationally decisive. A threat &lt;a href=&quot;https://l.jumpto.es/l/8a6a1c6ba93ad27649db1954f3182e71cb2bcf4e?notrack=1&amp;amp;u=179354&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;assessment&lt;/a&gt; has found categories of threats such as electronic warfare, cyber, and directed-energy effects that are being developed and employed by hostile nations as part of their counter-space capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Third, co-orbital proximity operations and grey-zone activity. Proximity operations are activities that are legitimate in themselves. However, the same activities can be used for coercion, interference, and &lt;em&gt;“accidents on purpose.”&lt;/em&gt; The issue in this regard is one of attribution. This leads to a gray zone in which norms are important in addition to deterrence. In this regard, the U.S. Space Force has described space domain awareness (SDA) as &lt;em&gt;“the ability to perceive and understand the nature of space-based phenomena to inform &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://l.jumpto.es/l/299979f1c6cdba01aa3882a1e888fd6564cf5b1d?notrack=1&amp;amp;u=179354&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;decisions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The policy should be to combine these elite systems with more distributed architectures: more nodes, more paths, and more means of recovery. Resilience is about the need to ensure that the loss of one satellite’s signal does not cause the end of the entire mission. The Proliferated Architecture (Starshield) program is a step towards that direction. But it’s only one NRO project in place and has redundancies set in place. What can be done to protect other multi-billion satellites already in orbit and not part of a constellation of satellites?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, apply maneuver, unpredictability and mobility in space, which comes down to strong cyber protection for mission systems and ground networks, encryption and authentication to protect command and telemetry, anti-jamming techniques and alternative communication routes and rigorous integrity checks, such that analysts can rely on the data generated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, engage in rapid reconstitution and continuity of operations including: pre-planned fallback modes, alternate tasking workflows, ground processing surge capacity, and alternatives for reconstituting capability with allied or commercial sources if needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the problem is narrowed down to its core, ensuring the protection of single-operated NRO satellites can be achieved via better access to sensor data and faster decision cycles and a resilient architecture (combination of high-end assets and proliferated assets).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Equally important are end-to-end cybersecurity and integrity controls, debris-conscious operations &amp; sustainability in coordination with civilian agencies such as NASA where necessary and proactive deterrence through resilience and consequence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NRO satellites are strategic tools, as they reduce uncertainties, detect deception, and enable decision advantage. The threats to these satellites, which are both kinetic and non-kinetic, are rapidly increasing in their sophistication and frequency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The protection of such satellites has nothing to do with making space a battlefield for its own sake. It has to do with being able to see clearly enough to avoid mistakes that could escalate quickly in space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best way to ensure such protection is not through a single technology but through a comprehensive approach that involves situational awareness, resilience, secure data communication, sustainable operations, deterrence and dispersion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Mission Maduro—when special ops succeed</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/30/the-war-room-newsletter-mission-maduro-when-special-ops-succeed</link>
      <description>Richard Cockett, a senior editor, discusses history’s best special operations with an SAS officer</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s War Against the States</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-happens-if-trump-follows-through-on-threat-to-invoke-insurrection-act-by-steven-simon-and-jonathan-stevenson-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The killing of two US citizens by federal immigration officers marks a grim turning point in President Donald Trump’s efforts to militarize domestic law enforcement. The events in Minneapolis underscore the dangers of unchecked executive power, as weakened courts and a compliant Congress leave states exposed to federal coercion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will Kevin Warsh’s Federal Reserve look like?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/30/what-will-kevin-warshs-federal-reserve-look-like</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s nominee was an inflation hawk—until he wasn’t</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s American Titanic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trumps-america-a-sinking-ship-rest-of-world-seeking-dry-land-by-harold-james-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump’s bullying of allies and fallacious arguments have put the US on a collision course with disaster, winning only rare plaudits, notably from the likes of Vladimir Putin. The rest of the world is reorienting itself away from the United States, making an orderly dash for the life rafts that will carry them to dry land together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of a Middle-Power Alliance</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-middle-powers-can-realize-mark-carney-alliance-vision-by-moreno-bertoldi-and-marco-buti-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his landmark Davos speech, Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney urged the world’s middle powers to band together, or else risk being dominated by the United States and China. To succeed, they must strengthen trade ties, develop autonomous supply chains, and implement meaningful institutional reforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a matcha latte better for you than a builder’s brew?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/30/is-a-matcha-latte-better-for-you-than-a-builders-brew</link>
      <description>We spill the tea</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Affluence a Barrier to Living Well?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democratic-capitalism-not-obstacle-to-human-flourishing-by-michael-r-strain-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a new book, Brink Lindsey argues that wealthy liberal democracies have essentially solved the problem of material provision and are now experiencing a nervous breakdown. But humans have always struggled with the challenge of living well and wisely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Should Consider Joining Trump’s ‘Board of Peace’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-china-should-consider-joining-trumps-board-of-peace/</link>
      <description>Non-participation carries costs, both for China’s influence in the Middle East and for its broader role in shaping an emerging mechanism of global governance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Normalize the Nordic Nuke</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/nuclear-weapons-nordic-scandinavia-sweden-finland-norway-denmark-russia-greenland/</link>
      <description>As Nordic countries rethink their security, seeking nuclear weapons would bring more problems than solutions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Shutdown watch; Lingering defense-strategy qs; JAGs’ unusual new jobs; Secret drone’s recent mission; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-30-2026/411084/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Quiet Partnership With Rwanda and the Limits of Non-Conditional Aid</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/japans-quiet-partnership-with-rwanda-and-the-limits-of-non-conditional-aid/</link>
      <description>As Western donors increasingly tie development aid to political conditions, Japan’s quiet partnership with Rwanda raises a question: Can Tokyo translate quiet development cooperation into real diplomatic influence?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Bipartisanship Is Taiwan’s Best Defense in Paraguay (and Beyond)</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-bipartisanship-is-taiwans-best-defense-in-paraguay-and-beyond/</link>
      <description>Taipei's strategy built a relationship almost exclusively with Paraguay’s Colorado Party, while neglecting opposition actors. That's not a recipe for long-term success.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Coupang Probe Is a South Korea-US Diplomatic Row in the Making</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-coupang-probe-is-a-south-korea-us-diplomatic-row-in-the-making/</link>
      <description>Despite the South Korean government’s efforts to downplay speculation linking the tariff hike to the Coupang probe, concerns continue to grow as Washington signals its displeasure through multiple channels.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People-Centered Rhetoric, Indigenous Exclusion: Indonesia’s Climate Contradiction</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/people-centered-rhetoric-indigenous-exclusion-indonesias-climate-contradiction/</link>
      <description>Indonesia's government persistently refuses to recognize Indigenous Peoples as rights-holders with authority over their lands, territories, and futures.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Taps Kevin Warsh to Head Federal Reserve</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/kevin-warsh-federal-reserve-chair-trump-powell/</link>
      <description>Trump’s pick did not rattle markets, but the Fed’s future and independence remains uncertain.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Japan Prepared to Evacuate Its Nationals in a Taiwan War?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/is-japan-prepared-to-evacuate-its-nationals-in-a-taiwan-war/</link>
      <description>Part one of a two-part series exploring Japan’s civil protection planning for its southwestern islands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Taliban’s New Criminal Procedure Code Does and Does Not Say</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/what-the-talibans-new-criminal-procedure-code-does-and-does-not-say/</link>
      <description>Accurate scrutiny should begin with precision about what the law actually says, how it functions legally, and where interpretation begins to exceed text.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Emerging Two Front Problem</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-emerging-two-front-problem/</link>
      <description>Growing Japan-Philippines defense ties are linking the East China Sea and South China Sea.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Would a Bardella Presidency Mean For France?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/french-presidential-frontrunner-jordan-bardella-more-opportunist-than-arsonist-by-brigitte-granville-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;National Rally’s Jordan Bardella has emerged as the frontrunner in France’s presidential race, confronting the European Union with the prospect of a far-right Euroskeptic in the Elysée. Yet Bardella appears less intent on dismantling the EU than on exploiting its existing arrangements, which already work to France’s advantage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Calculation and Canada’s Capitulation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-calculation-and-canadas-capitulation/</link>
      <description>Carney is trying to find an answer to his American problem by increasing Canada's engagement with China. He should remember he himself called China Canada’s “biggest geopolitical risk.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Copper Boom</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/copper-prices-latin-america-trump-tariffs-critical-minerals/</link>
      <description>Surging demand—and prices—for the mineral stand to benefit exporters in Latin America.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye New START: How China’s Rise Ended Nuclear Arms Control</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/goodbye-new-start-how-chinas-rise-ended-nuclear-arms-control/</link>
      <description>As China continues to expand its nuclear capabilities, and Russia and the U.S. walk away from arms control, the future is terrifying: a new nuclear arms race, with more players, and less predictability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Waterloo?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/trump-venezuela-gambit-may-fracture-maga-coalition-accelerate-his-political-decline-by-harold-hongju-koh-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s second term has been defined by unilateralism, militarism, and lawlessness, pushing constitutional checks and balances to their limits. His intervention in Venezuela could be the point at which his governing style collides with reality, alienating his base and accelerating his political decline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India-EU FTA: Some Challenges Ahead, but Strategic Signal Is Clear</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/india-eu-fta-some-challenges-ahead-but-strategic-signal-is-clear/</link>
      <description>Described as the &quot;mother of all deals,&quot; this is the largest trade agreement that the EU and India have ever concluded.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Realistic Is Carney’s Call to Action?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/30/carney-davos-speech-realistic/</link>
      <description>U.S. allies are uniquely vulnerable to coercion by the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Pakistan’s Increasing Interest in the Mineral Sector</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/inside-pakistans-increasing-interest-in-the-mineral-sector/</link>
      <description>Its participation in the Future Mineral Forum meeting in Saudi Arabia reflects its plans to market its mineral reserves. But people in mining areas remain unenthused.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Can’t Go It Alone</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/japan/japan-cant-go-it-alone</link>
      <description>Tokyo has stepped up on China—now it’s Washington’s turn .</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unsettling Implications of Xi’s Military Purge</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/unsettling-implications-xis-military-purge</link>
      <description>Why his impatience with Chinese commanders should worry U.S. policymakers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Changed, and What Hasn’t, in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/whats-changed-and-what-hasnt-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>The BNP has a new leader. Students speak more openly about their affiliations with right-wing politics, and there is more freedom to criticize the powerful intelligence agencies.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASEAN Will Not Recognize Myanmar Military’s Election, Lazaro Says</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/asean-will-not-recognize-myanmar-militarys-election-lazaro-says/</link>
      <description>The Philippine foreign secretary nonetheless expressed optimism that &quot;something positive&quot; might emerge from the recent one-sided polls.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASEAN’s Quiet Competition for Digital Nomads</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/aseans-quiet-competition-for-digital-nomads/</link>
      <description>How Thailand, Indonesia, Malaysia, Vietnam, and the Philippines are vying for the world's mobile workforce, and what it means for the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam, European Union Announce Major Diplomatic Upgrade Amid Trade Uncertainties</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/vietnam-european-union-announce-major-diplomatic-upgrade-amid-trade-uncertainties/</link>
      <description>António Costa, the president of the European Council, said that the upgrade “underlines the importance we attach to the region and to Vietnam’s growing role within it.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Changing Role of ‘Alternate’ Members on the Central Committee of Vietnam’s Communist Party</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-changing-role-of-alternate-members-on-the-central-committee-of-vietnams-communist-party/</link>
      <description>From 2021-2026, despite massive vacancies leaving 35 empty seats in the Central Committee (due to disciplinary dismissals or deaths), none were filled by alternates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Reform at a Glance: Centralisation and a ‘British FBI’?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/police-reform-glance-centralisation-and-british-fbi</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UK Home Secretary Mahmood presented a long-awaited police reform plan. Still at the starting line, here is what the plans entail – and what they do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RUSI Reflects: The Future of European Energy Security</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/news-and-comment/rusi-reflects/rusi-reflects-future-european-energy-security</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The 2026 International North Sea Summit set ambitious targets for joint offshore wind projects which, if implemented successfully, could significantly improve European energy security.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands Stranded in Cambodia After Fleeing Online Scamming Compounds</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/thousands-stranded-in-cambodia-after-fleeing-online-scamming-compounds/</link>
      <description>The rights group Amnesty International says that the government is doing nothing to deal with the mounting &quot;humanitarian crisis.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 23:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Growing Cost of China’s GDP Target</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-growing-cost-of-chinas-gdp-target/</link>
      <description>The country's growth has become increasingly expensive to maintain, and its dividends are reaching ordinary households with diminishing force.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe risks a rare-earths crunch between China and America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/29/europe-risks-a-rare-earths-crunch-between-china-and-america</link>
      <description>The old continent must play to its strengths as a large market with stable rules</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Magyar could defeat Viktor Orban, Hungary’s leader</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/29/peter-magyar-could-defeat-viktor-orban-hungarys-leader</link>
      <description>The authoritarian prime minister, a friend of Donald Trump, trails in the polls. But the rules favour him</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
