<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Russian Strikes on Ukraine’s Energy Threaten Trilateral Peace Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/russia-ukraine-energy-strikes-trilateral-peace-talks-putin-zelensky/</link>
      <description>Kyiv accuses Moscow of using a temporary halt in strikes to stockpile weapons.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the U.S. and India Finally Reached a Deal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/us-india-trade-deal-tariffs-ambassador-gor/</link>
      <description>The new U.S. ambassador in New Delhi may have played an instrumental role in this week’s trade agreement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk is betting the future of his business empire on AI</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/04/elon-musk-is-betting-the-future-of-his-business-empire-on-ai</link>
      <description>The fates of xAI, SpaceX and Tesla are increasingly intertwined</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Will the U.S. Critical Minerals Summit Mean for Africa?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/us-critical-minerals-summit-africa-mining-china/</link>
      <description>How African nations fit into the Trump administration’s plans to combat China.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 21:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How an art restorer sneaked Giorgia Meloni into a church fresco</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/04/how-an-art-restorer-sneaked-giorgia-meloni-into-a-church-fresco</link>
      <description>Romans noticed a winged figure’s odd resemblance to their prime minister</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US-Backed Ukraine Peace Talks Ignore Russia's Unfettered Air Assaults</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/us-backed-ukraine-peace-talks-ignore</link>
      <description>Kyiv needs long range Tomahawks to raise costs for a weakened Russia, says strategist Ken Robinson</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The American Teen Caught in Israel’s Prison System</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/mohammed-ibrahim-detention-israel-palestine-west-bank-us/</link>
      <description>Mohammed Ibrahim is one of hundreds of Palestinian children who report physical abuse in Israeli detention.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can emerging markets’ stellar run continue?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/04/can-emerging-markets-stellar-run-continue</link>
      <description>There is a lot more going for them than “sell America”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Despair Is U.S. Policy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/iran-sanctions-trump-despair-protest-revolution-reform-khamenei/</link>
      <description>Western sanctions helped kill Iranians’ earlier hopes of their country’s transformation from within.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Pakistan and China Revive Their ‘All-Weather Friendship’?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/can-pakistan-and-china-revive-their-all-weather-friendship/</link>
      <description>There is little doubt that China-U.S. dynamics will continue to have a major influence over Islamabad's relations with Washington and Beijing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In America science-sceptics are now in charge</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/04/in-america-science-sceptics-are-now-in-charge</link>
      <description>The Trump administration seems to want less clean energy and more preventable diseases</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than a third of cancers arise from preventable risks</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/04/more-than-a-third-of-cancers-arise-from-preventable-risks</link>
      <description>Smoking, infections and alcohol are the top causes</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump administration is eroding vital climate data</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/04/the-trump-administration-is-eroding-vital-climate-data</link>
      <description>American citizens are left vulnerable</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 18:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Israeli visit to the site of the Bondi attack tests Australia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/04/an-israeli-visit-to-the-site-of-the-bondi-attack-tests-australia</link>
      <description>The prime minister, Anthony Albanese, is under most pressure</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump wants to end America’s half-century conflict with Iran</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/04/donald-trump-wants-to-end-americas-half-century-conflict-with-iran</link>
      <description>His showdown with Iran’s supreme leader will shape the region for a generation</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines Brokers South China Sea Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/philippines-south-china-sea-code-conduct/</link>
      <description>Why the ASEAN chair is pushing for a code of conduct with China.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO’s Leader Is Totally Lost</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/nato-rutte-trump-lost/</link>
      <description>What does Mark Rutte think he’s doing?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: US downs Iranian UAV; Army to host drone competition; Guardsmen in civvies at ICE jail; Hegseth threatens Scouts; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-04-2026/411185/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kremlin Files: Russian Double Agents and Operational Games</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-kremlin-files-russian-double-agents-and-operational-games</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/the-kgb-id-card-of-british-double-agent-kim-philby-is-displayed-at-the-exhibition-90-years-of-russia-s-foreign-intelligence-serv.jpg?id=63831073&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=95%2C0%2C95%2C0&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE KREMLIN FILES / COLUMN &lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;There are similarities among intelligence agencies worldwide. All professional services rely on tradecraft to recruit and manage assets. They all operate within bureaucratic systems and ultimately answer to political leaders. At a basic level, espionage tradecraft is a common professional language. However, Russian intelligence services (RIS) differ significantly from their Western counterparts in several key aspects. First, their primary mission is not to serve the interests of the Russian people, nor to protect the country's constitution; instead, their loyalty is to the regime and Putin’s personal political survival. And secondly, in terms of tradecraft, they differ from the CIA and other Western services in their approach and tactics. One of the most important—and often misunderstood—aspects of Russian intelligence is their use of double agents, known in Russian intelligence doctrine as operational games (&lt;em&gt;operativnye igry&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Russian intelligence, operational games are not just niche skills or occasional counterintelligence tactics. They are fundamental. Double agent operations are central to how Russian agencies define success, justify their importance, and maintain their institutional identity. Whether other collection methods succeed or fail, the RIS reliably and continually default back to operational games. Therefore, understanding how and why the RIS use double agents is essential to understanding Russian intelligence itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before examining how these operations work, it is important to get the terminology right, and something that even experienced national security reporters, espionage writers, and analysts in the West frequently get wrong. The term &lt;em&gt;double agent&lt;/em&gt; is often misapplied to describe penetrations of one intelligence service by another. In reality, these are two very different phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A penetration is an agent who betrays their own service to spy for a foreign power. Aldrich Ames, who recently passed away three decades after he was arrested, was a traitor and a penetration of the CIA by Russian intelligence. He was not a double agent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A double agent, by contrast, is an intelligence asset who is knowingly and deliberately directed by one service to engage another in espionage. The controlling service uses that agent to feed information (called feed material) —true, false, or mixed—to the adversary. They do so to simultaneously study the adversary’s tradecraft, collection priorities, and decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Russian system, double agents also serve a bureaucratic function: they generate statistics, “success stories,” and operational narratives that demonstrate effectiveness to political overseers and ultimately to Putin himself. Putin knows this; after all, he was a Lieutenant Colonel in the KGB Second Chief Directorate (responsible for Counterintelligence for the USSR), and he later headed the FSB himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscribe to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Double agents are used in the West and by the U.S. services, but we don’t lie to our government about the origins of the cases or pretend they are real counterintelligence successes when they reach their conclusion. The distinction is not academic. It lies at the heart of how Russian intelligence thinks about espionage. Every year, the FSB publishes an annual report and claims statistics on hundreds of alleged spies it has caught. The vast majority of them are invented, manufactured, or the FSB’s own double agents. In other words, they are not &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian services employ multiple varieties of double agents and operational games. They have many names, including the &lt;em&gt;initsiativnik&lt;/em&gt;, which is a false volunteer who often “walks in” to an embassy. Also used is the &lt;em&gt;podstava&lt;/em&gt;, or dangle, in which Russian services will use the routine of an intelligence officer, diplomat, or journalist and insert the “dangle” right in front of the target at a gym, reception, or other function to appeal to the target. There are still more different varieties and names for other types of double agents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These operations are not limited to targeting foreign intelligence services. They are also used against businesspeople, journalists, diplomats, nongovernmental organizations, and even Russian citizens themselves. The objective is often not solely intelligence collection, but also control, as the Russians say, to have the target “&lt;em&gt;pod kontrolem&lt;/em&gt;,” or under 100% operational control and influence. That is why the Russians prefer, though not exclusively, to carry out double agent operations on Russian soil. Abroad, they are less confident that the SVR or GRU can fully control their double agent during meetings with the adversary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The end goal is to ensnare, compromise, manipulate, arrest, or extort targets for recruitment and long-term exploitation. A few examples from history help illustrate Russian intelligence’s fixation on double agents, dating back to its earliest institutional roots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cheka and later the NKVD/OGPU perfected operational games in the 1920s through landmark deceptions such as Operation TRUST. With the TRUST operation, the OGPU (Soviet counterintelligence at the time, another forerunner of the KGB) created a fictitious anti-Bolshevik underground to lure in Western intelligence services and Russian émigrés. TRUST sent intelligence officers to the West, or cooptees, who they intimidated to pose as members of this fake organization that claimed to stand against the Bolsheviks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The operation ran for years, successfully feeding disinformation to multiple foreign services while identifying, neutralizing, or recruiting their agents. They often lured Russians home to “help in operations” only to have them arrested, interrogated, and usually shot in the back of the head in a Chekist-style &lt;em&gt;vyshama mera&lt;/em&gt; (highest measure) execution. The TRUST culminated in the capture of the famous British intelligence officer Sidney Reilly, one of the most celebrated spies of the era, who was executed in a similar fashion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That double-agent tradition continued throughout the Cold War, when Soviet intelligence used double agents not merely to mislead adversaries but also to validate its own competence. Kim Philby, while often remembered in the West as a Soviet penetration of British intelligence, was also used as part of broader operational games to shape Western threat perceptions and protect other Soviet assets. Scores of Western intelligence officers or special operations team members were wrapped up in the Soviet Union or Eastern Europe immediately after World War II, the victims of KGB and OGPU/GRU operational games Philby had detailed to the USSR. Most were eventually executed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In later decades, the KGB ran controlled double agents against Western services to exaggerate Soviet capabilities, mask vulnerabilities, and manipulate counterintelligence priorities. The Soviet KGB ran a wave of double-agents at the CIA in the late 1980s with false feed material to explain the 1985 U.S. intelligence losses. Rick Ames volunteered and compromised a dozen agents working for the CIA and FBI (Ames was not arrested till 1994). The KGB and later SVR used these operational games and false volunteers to protect him, trying to give CIA and the broader U.S. IC reasons why the compromise may have happened (&lt;em&gt;Circle of Treason &lt;/em&gt;is a classic read on this period and all the various games the KGB was playing to protect Ames with false feeds to CIA and the FBI).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;These operations reinforced an internal belief that intelligence success could be measured by how convincingly one could influence the enemy’s perception of reality. In Russian intelligence culture, the double agent is not an exception — it is the ideal. In today’s FSB, however, as well as their foreign counterparts, the SVR, the double agent too often is used to justify their very own existence, instead of paying dividends in terms of tradecraft learned or secrets protected. Operations like TRUST are mostly a relic of the past. Today, the FSB is too busy entrapping innocent foreigners like basketball players, teachers, and NGO workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. IC and our Western allies have learned over the decades that the FSB/SVR and GRU have presented double-agent cases to their political leadership as if they were genuine agents caught and arrested, all the while the case was simply that they were double agents. They feed statistics from the FSB each year about exaggerated intelligence operations—more than all the services in the world could carry out against Russia—and also claim to have thwarted all of them. These reports reach Putin and the Presidential Administration to justify larger budgets, which in turn breed more corruption and line the pockets of senior and middle managers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not unique to Russia; it is often the case across the former Soviet countries of Central Asia, where many of the services remain close and subservient to the Russian FSB and SVR. These services, often serving despotic regimes, swear by double agent operations because, in many cases and over many years, the only “spies” they can really uncover are those they falsely created under a double agent operation. They use them against a range of unwitting foreign citizens, including in legitimate business practices, to extort them and their companies for money when brought up on false charges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The practice has been expanded in recent years by the Russian FSB, particularly its counterintelligence division, DKRO (the Department of Counterintelligence Operations), which uses double agents against journalists, businesspeople, and others to trap them and hold them hostage for exchanges with the West. DKRO was responsible for the false arrest and imprisonment of Wall Street Journal reporter Evan Gershkovich before his 2024 swap with the West.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In sum, operational games and the double agents associated with them allow Russian intelligence to shape narratives, manufacture threats, and create the appearance of omnipresence. They are dirty tricks elevated to doctrine. And they remain one of Moscow’s most effective tools for compensating for broader institutional weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Not All Wrong About Mexico</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-military-intervention-in-mexico-will-not-weaken-cartels-by-guillermo-ortiz-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since intervening in Venezuela, US President Donald Trump has escalated his threats to use direct military action against Mexico’s drug cartels. But this would be ineffective, because curbing the cartels' power requires exposing their connections to the ruling Morena party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oyu Tolgoi: Mongolia’s High-Stakes Clash With Rio Tinto</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/oyu-tolgoi-mongolias-high-stakes-clash-with-rio-tinto/</link>
      <description>15 years of tensions over the massive copper mine boiled over in December 2025. Can Mongolia and the mining giant reach a resolution?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Sphere for Me but Not for Thee</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/trump-spheres-of-influence-russia-china-venezuela/</link>
      <description>Trump does not want spheres of influence. He wants it all.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Jam at Kazakh-Kyrgyz Border Result of Increased Inspections</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/traffic-jam-at-kazakh-kyrgyz-border-result-of-increased-inspections/</link>
      <description>Kazakh authorities, and the Eurasian Economic Commission, say the slowdown is resulting from increased measure to combat the “illegal trafficking of goods.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO Is Thinking About Defense Spending Wrong</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/nato-defense-spending-italy-gdp/</link>
      <description>Prioritizing GDP-based targets doesn’t necessarily strengthen military capabilities, as Italy shows.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Mistake Warsh Could Make</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/kevin-warsh-well-suited-to-handle-ai-revolution-but-could-contribute-to-a-bond-market-crisis-by-desmond-lachman-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump's nominee for US Federal Reserve chair, Kevin Warsh, appears to be well qualified to respond effectively to the AI revolution. But his stated commitment to shrinking the Fed's bloated balance sheet could increase the risk of a bond market-induced financial crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Dancing in Shackles’: China’s Vibrant – But Constrained – Internet Culture</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/dancing-in-shackles-chinas-vibrant-but-constrained-internet-culture/</link>
      <description>Insights from Yi-Ling Liu.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is New Zealand’s Defense and Intelligence Policy Aligning With AUKUS in All But Name?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-new-zealands-defense-and-intelligence-policy-aligning-with-aukus-in-all-but-name/</link>
      <description>Officially, New Zealand is “assessing” membership. But key government documents suggest many of the practical steps Pillar II of AUKUS would involve are already underway.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of U.S. Military Aid to Israel?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/trump-netanyahu-israel-military-aid/</link>
      <description>Once sacrosanct, the enormous aid package is now in doubt.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karachaganak Arbitration Win Gives Kazakhstan New Leverage Over Big Oil</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/karachaganak-arbitration-win-gives-kazakhstan-new-leverage-over-big-oil/</link>
      <description>The Karachaganak precedent is likely to shape Kazakhstan’s approach to energy governance, production-sharing agreement renegotiations, and investor relations in the years ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New START’s Expiration Is a Win for China</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/new-starts-expiration-is-a-win-for-china/</link>
      <description>The treaty’s looming end sends a damaging signal about how the United States now views nuclear competition – and China is watching.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is No Game Theorist</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/game-theory-shows-why-trump-tariffs-on-china-will-produce-worse-outcomes-for-all-by-koichi-hamada-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump seems to think that he can impose high tariffs on other economies, such as China, without facing retaliation, thereby securing huge gains for the US. But as game theory – in particular, the prisoner's dilemma – shows, the more likely outcome is that both sides will end up worse off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pandemic Roots of the Sino-Russian ‘No-Limits’ Friendship</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-pandemic-roots-of-the-sino-russian-no-limits-friendship/</link>
      <description>Fixation on the “no-limits” formula obscures a more consequential development that occurred at the same time.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan’s New Draft Constitution: A State-Building Blueprint With External Consequences</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/kazakhstans-new-draft-constitution-a-state-building-blueprint-with-external-consequences/</link>
      <description>The draft Constitution is an elegant blueprint. But what does it promise? And what will audiences, internal and external, read in it?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Middle-Power Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-will-struggle-to-join-middle-powers-alliance-due-to-foreign-policy-mindset-by-ajay-shah-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many hope that India will participate in a coalition of middle powers to uphold a rule-based international order. But it will take time for the country’s foreign-policy establishment to move away from “strategic autonomy” as a guiding principle, and recent US behavior has confirmed skeptics’ arguments that the West is unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Defense Policy Accelerates as Public Debate Lags Behind</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/japans-defense-policy-accelerates-as-public-debate-lags-behind/</link>
      <description>Takaichi looks set to win a major victory – but voters are laser-focused on economic issues, not her desired security reforms.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why so many Colombians fight in foreign wars</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/04/why-so-many-colombians-fight-in-foreign-wars</link>
      <description>The ways a booming mercenary market pulls veteran soldiers abroad</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 5% wealth tax would drive billionaires out of California</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/04/a-5-wealth-tax-would-drive-billionaires-out-of-california</link>
      <description>The Golden State’s Democrats are divided over a golden-goose grab</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New World Order or Bust</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-old-order-already-broken-build-new-one-starting-with-ai-by-margrethe-vestager-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Trump gleefully destroying what remains of the old postwar international order, the world is a mess. But the answer is not to defend institutions that have lost their effectiveness and legitimacy; it is to create something better, starting with AI, where we can build from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Showering Trump With Flattery Is a Risky Political Strategy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/trump-far-right-machado-milei-bukele-bolsonaro-honduras/</link>
      <description>Latin American conservatives love to lavish praise upon the U.S. president. But doing so could undermine the region’s long-term interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Finally Treating Its PTSD</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/europe-military-history-militarization-defense-spending-ptsd/</link>
      <description>After decades of trauma and denial, the continent is confronting the reality of war.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia Has Turned Sports Into a Weapon</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/04/russia-ovechkin-putin-olympics-hocke/</link>
      <description>The Olympic ban is a necessary counter to Moscow’s abuse.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balendra Shah: Frontrunner for PM’s Post in Nepal’s Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/balendra-shah-frontrunner-for-pms-post-in-nepals-election/</link>
      <description>The former rapper campaigns in silence. For now, he is winning without speaking. But Nepali elections have a way of demanding answers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made in the USA: How American-Built Weapons Have Wrought Destruction in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/02/04/made-in-the-usa-how-american-built-weapons-have-wrought-destruction-in-gaza/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on our latest investigations, join Bellingcat’s WhatsApp channel&amp;#160;here On the night of Jan. 7 this year, three 250-pound bombs smashed into an apartment block in the Al Tuffah neighbourhood of northern Gaza. Footage of the aftermath shows walls collapsed, rubble piled up and blackened household items scattered across the scene. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/02/04/made-in-the-usa-how-american-built-weapons-have-wrought-destruction-in-gaza/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Made in the USA: How American-Built Weapons Have Wrought Destruction in Gaza&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Prime Minister Modi Dodge Responsibility During a Crucial Clash With China?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/did-prime-minister-modi-dodge-responsibility-during-a-crucial-clash-with-china/</link>
      <description>In his unpublished memoir, then-Indian Army Chief Gen. Naravane claims that a key decision on whether or not to fire upon advancing Chinese tanks and troops was left to him to make.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There Is Only One Sphere of Influence</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/there-only-one-sphere-influence</link>
      <description>America can project power with little constraint—and its rivals cannot.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trouble Is Brewing in Syria</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/syria/trouble-brewing-syria</link>
      <description>Consolidating Shara’s power could undermine the country’s progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Free World Needs Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/taiwan/free-world-needs-taiwan</link>
      <description>Solidarity will protect prosperity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Trump Jump the Gun With the US-India Trade Deal Announcement?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/did-trump-jump-the-gun-with-the-us-india-trade-deal-announcement/</link>
      <description>India and the U.S. seem to have agreed only on a framework to address the reciprocal tariff agreement. More work lies ahead for a full trade agreement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Need to Talk About Ecosystem Collapse</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/we-need-talk-about-ecosystem-collapse</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Climate and nature can no longer be pigeonholed as an environmental problem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pheu Thai is Banking on Corruption to Remedy Thailand’s Informal Economy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/pheu-thai-is-banking-on-corruption-to-remedy-thailands-informal-economy/</link>
      <description>After the collapse of the party's &quot;digital wallet&quot; stimulus plan, voters should not be fooled by its recently announced 1 million-baht election sweepstakes.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new nuclear arms race threatens</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/03/a-new-nuclear-arms-race-threatens</link>
      <description>America wants more nukes to deter Russia and China</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new nuclear arms race is in the offing</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/03/a-new-nuclear-arms-race-is-in-the-offing</link>
      <description>America wants more nukes to deter Russia and China</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disney’s new boss must not forget its creative magic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/03/disneys-new-boss-must-not-forget-its-creative-magic</link>
      <description>Josh D’Amaro faces a tricky balancing act</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disney’s new boss must rekindle its creative magic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/03/disneys-new-boss-must-rekindle-its-creative-magic</link>
      <description>Josh D’Amaro faces a tricky balancing act</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Takes Aim at Tehran: IRGC Terror Listing Opens New Front in Europe’s Iran Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/eu-takes-aim-at-tehran-irgc-terror-listing-opens-new-front-in-europes-iran-policy</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;On January 29, Europe found its voice against Iran’s apparatus of terror. The European Union (EU) announced that it is adding Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC) to its list of designated terrorist entities. The EU spent years mulling this step and taking half measures. Now, the EU and its member states must use this new much-needed tool broadly and effectively. The EU’s designation should mark the start of Europe’s campaign against the IRGC, not its end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Formally listing the IRGC will give Europe important new authorities to limit Iranian attacks and plotting on their soil. The EU’s move also has major symbolic value, particularly at a time when the Iranian regime is under pressure at home and abroad. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU previously sanctioned some of the IRGC’s branches, leaders, and operatives. But EU member states resisted taking action against the IRGC in its entirety for several reasons, including European fears of Tehran’s reaction. Iran has long been vocal in its opposition to an IRGC designation, warning in recent days that an EU label would have “destructive consequences.” The U.S. unwillingness to lift its own Foreign Terrorist Organization listing of the IRGC was reportedly a key reason why U.S.-Iran negotiations fell apart during the Biden administration. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU designation comes on the heels of the Iranian regime’s bloody crackdown against its own outraged people. The EU’s decision—reached by consensus among its 27 member states—lends Europe’s united voice to the Iranian protestors’ indignation against their oppressors. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU action also sends a powerful message to Tehran that it should refrain from conducting attacks on European soil against its perceived enemies, particularly Iranian dissidents and Israeli and Jewish targets. European security officials express great concern about that risk now. Both the IRGC’s deadly Quds Force and Iran’s notorious Ministry of Intelligence and Security (MOIS) have conducted numerous terrorist plots in recent years in Europe, including in Sweden, Germany, Cyprus, and Belgium. Individual European governments have disrupted and prosecuted these networks and issued statements condemning Iranian behavior, but this is the most unified and strongest European stance to date. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the EU designation, any IRGC assets in Europe are now subject to an asset freeze. It is now illegal to provide the group with funds or resources. The designation also requires EU member states to increase police and judicial cooperation on IRGC-related criminal matters. And the EU will impose a travel ban on IRGC members hoping to visit Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Europeans should now aim to use these tools vigorously. The IRGC has historically had near global reach, not only with its terrorist cells but with its procurement and financial networks. Uncovering and disrupting the IRGC’s networks and freezing their assets would weaken the corps’ capabilities to rearm, profit, and funnel materiel and finances to its proxies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe can and should do much more to maximize the impact of the designation and impose real costs on the IRGC and its overlords. The EU’s 2013 designation of Hezbollah’s so-called “military wing” offers a good model for how an EU designation can empower both the EU and its member states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, the EU should ensure that Europol – the EU’s umbrella police agency – gets a key role in coordinating and supporting IRGC-related investigations across Europe, as Europol has done with Hezbollah. Before the EU’s designation, Europol’s ability to police the IRGC’s operatives in Europe was greatly limited. The IRGC’s many European plots often have a consistent modus operandi, including using criminal actors not associated with Iran to carry out attacks and thus offer Tehran a figleaf of deniability. Europol is uniquely positioned to see the whole picture and share relevant information with all EU member states. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For one model, look to Europol’s involvement in the complex multi-jurisdictional investigation of the Hezbollah financier Mohamad Nourredine, which involved multiple European governments as well as several U.S. law enforcement agencies. In 2018, he was convicted in a French court on multiple charges and sentenced to seven years in prison as part of a multi-country investigation codenamed “Operation Cedar.” Europol could use provide similar support in international investigations against IRGC operatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, Europol has also played an integral role, along with the United States, in the Law Enforcement Coordination Group, the sole international body dedicated to countering Hezbollah’s terrorist and illicit activity. The EU should empower Europol to do likewise for the U.S.-led Countering Transnational Terrorism Forum, which focuses on Iran-linked terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, European governments must follow up on the EU’s actions and impose their own national bans and designations. Many European countries did just this against Hezbollah, including Germany, Slovenia, Austria, the United Kingdom, and the Baltics. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take Germany, which shows how national-level actions can strengthen law enforcement and build on Brussels’s actions. In May 2020, Germany formally banned Hezbollah and conducted near simultaneous raids on several Hezbollah-linked organizations in the country. Germany is now prosecuting a Lebanese national allegedly tied to Hezbollah for procuring drone components for the terrorist group – a scheme that also took place in the U.K. and Spain. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU’s IRGC designation won’t tip the balance of power within Iran in favor of the protestors, but it can still help reduce Iran’s ability to stage vicious attacks abroad. The EU and its member states must robustly implement these new authorities for them to have the desperately needed effect. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michael Jacobson, a senior fellow in The Washington Institute’s Reinhard Program on Counterterrorism and Intelligence, formerly served as director of strategy, plans, and initiatives in the State Department’s Counterterrorism Bureau. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 20:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia’s Tigers Benefit When Scientists Collaborate Beyond Borders</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/asias-tigers-benefit-when-scientists-collaborate-beyond-borders/</link>
      <description>Asia’s most iconic species makes an ‘improbable return’ in the forests of Russia and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
