<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Responding to Russian Sabotage Financing</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/insights-papers/responding-russian-sabotage-financing</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Financing is an important yet overlooked element of Russian sabotage in Europe: it can act as both a facilitator and a tool of response.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 114: How Will German Rearmament Shape European Security?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/global-security-briefing/episode-114-how-will-german-rearmament-shape-european-security</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Claudia Major joins Neil Melvin to discuss Germany’s rearmament drive and its implications for European and transatlantic security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three ‘meta trends’ are reshaping warfare, INDOPACOM commander says</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/three-meta-trends-are-reshaping-warfare-indopacom-commander-says/410666/</link>
      <description>Adm. Paparo says they’re key to keeping the U.S. military ready to face off against China.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 23:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Fantastical Geopolitics</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/trump-china-venezuela-geopolitics/</link>
      <description>The White House’s aggressive posture is already pushing other countries to seek strength in numbers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, China Isn’t Going to Take Over Greenland</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/greenland-trump-china-russia-threat-territory-invasion/</link>
      <description>Trump’s absurd justification for potential U.S. action is blatantly false.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Courts South Korea Amid Rift With China</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/japan-takaichi-south-korea-lee-china-xi-taiwan/</link>
      <description>But Seoul’s unwillingness to take a side may deny Takaichi the win she wants.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghosts Are Haunting France’s Remilitarization</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/france-military-macron-remilitarization-history/</link>
      <description>History is shaping, and constraining, the bid to revive French military culture.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump used to be risk-averse. Is that changing?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/13/donald-trump-used-to-be-risk-averse-is-that-changing</link>
      <description>America’s president suddenly seems like a man in a hurry</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump is a man in a hurry</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/13/donald-trump-is-a-man-in-a-hurry</link>
      <description>America’s president used to be risk-averse. Is that changing?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Claims of Vehicular Terrorism in Minnesota Don’t Hold Up</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/vehicular-terrorism-minnesota-trump-ice-protest/</link>
      <description>The U.S. government is adopting dangerous language to justify unlawful killing.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk’s chatbot, Grok, comes under fire for nude deepfakes</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/13/elon-musks-chatbot-grok-comes-under-fire-for-nude-deepfakes</link>
      <description>The real power to discipline it, though, lies outside governments</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Congress to Provide Billions More in Foreign Aid Than Sought by Trump</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/congress-foreign-aid-spending-appropriations-bill-trump-elon-musk-doge-cuts/</link>
      <description>The spending bill is a mix of rebuttal and acceptance of Trump’s efforts to overhaul the foreign affairs bureaucracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 20:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok is in, ethics are out in Pentagon’s new AI-acceleration strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/grok-ethics-are-out-pentagons-new-ai-acceleration-strategy/410649/</link>
      <description>Seven projects are to lead the charge to embed artificial intelligence ever more deeply in military affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s slow advance now threatens Zaporizhia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/13/russias-slow-advance-now-threatens-zaporizhia</link>
      <description>Ukraine’s gradual retreat is not only in Donbas</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon to invest $1B in L3Harris rocket-motor spinoff</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/l3harris-spin-its-rocket-motor-business-pentagon-anchor-investor/410651/</link>
      <description>The apparently unprecedented deal raises questions of fairness, effectiveness, and conflicts of interest.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Internet Blackout by the Numbers</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/iran-internet-shutdown-blackout-ayatollah-protests/</link>
      <description>How the Islamic Republic’s repressive tactics stack up against regimes around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tariffs Have Hurt, Not Helped, the U.S. Economy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/tariffs-hurt-not-helped-the-u-s-economy-trump-trade-ieepa/</link>
      <description>And they will likely play an even bigger role in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Arab states are silent about Iran’s unrest</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/13/why-arab-states-are-silent-about-irans-unrest</link>
      <description>They might welcome the Islamic Republic’s collapse but dread what would follow</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelans believe Donald Trump has offered them a better future</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/13/venezuelans-believe-donald-trump-has-offered-them-a-better-future</link>
      <description>An exclusive poll for The Economist also reveals an overwhelming desire for democracy</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Trump’s Venezuela Plan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/kroenig-case-for-trump-venezuela-plan/</link>
      <description>Former Trump official Matthew Kroenig explains why he thinks the White House made the right call in capturing Nicolás Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middle East Dispatch newsletter: Iran’s bloody crackdown</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/13/middle-east-dispatch-newsletter-irans-bloody-crackdown</link>
      <description>Nicolas Pelham writes about the terror unfolding across the country</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Crumbling Revolutionary Facade: How Today’s Protests Could Reshape the Region in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/iran-crumbling-revolutionary-facade-protests</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;I am&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;closely watching the growing size and momentum of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/irans-protests-expose-deeper-fragility-as-leaders-struggle-to-contain-crisis&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;protesters&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; across Iran’s cities, rural areas, and pious communities who are bravely and vocally rejecting the Supreme Leader’s broken policies. They have shined a light on Khamenei’s gross mismanagement of the economy and the severe multi-year drought; his constant agitation and hostile relations with neighbors; Iran’s loss of prestige and influence with coreligionist communities in Lebanon, Iraq, and Syria; his failures against foreign attacks; and his misguided alliance with Russia against Ukraine. Even regime loyalists have begun murmuring such complaints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regime instability indicators and warnings are blinking. I believe Iran’s revolutionary facade is crumbling, but into an uncertain future. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As more protesters demand a better future, I am watching for evidence of leniency from their fathers, brothers, uncles, and schoolmates who work in the IRGC, the police, and even in the Basij. If such cracks appear, new non-revolutionary leaders could emerge as quickly as al-Sharaa rose to power in Syria. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protesters, however, most likely lack experience running cities, provinces, and the federal government. New non-revolutionary leaders therefore probably would look to the U.S. for assurance and support – and right away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the protests produce a new Supreme Leader under a revolutionary Velāyat-e Faqih theocracy model, however, the future looks quite dark. Crackdowns would probably be quite harsh and swift, the nuclear program would most likely march on, and Tehran undoubtedly would keep funneling money and arms to trusted proxies that threaten the U.S. and Israel. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on Iranian issues since 1979 as an academic, diplomat, intelligence officer, and now as a professor of practice. Nothing, in my view, would stabilize the region between the Black Sea, Eastern Mediterranean, and the Persian Gulf faster than a peaceful, non-nuclear and wealthy Iran that recognizes the state of Israel and distances itself from Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most pendulums eventually swing, and I am watching for this one to swing in support of the Iranian people finally having a chance to rejoin a community of free nations that value peace, prosperity, and democracy. If non-revolutionary leaders were to emerge, the West could&lt;strong&gt; finally and quickly &lt;/strong&gt;work towards restoring a genuinely peaceful future that ends Tehran's nuclear weapons program; breaks its deadly alliance with Russia; terminates its costly support to Hizballah, Hamas, and the Houthis; and welcomes Iran into the community of nations as a responsible, wealth-producing global energy partner. May the pendulum swing decisively in these directions in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new generation of Chinese companies is expanding around the world</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/13/a-new-generation-of-chinese-companies-is-expanding-around-the-world</link>
      <description>They are following a different playbook from that of their elders</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Myanmar, Civilians Bear Consequences of Starlink Cuts</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/myanmar-starlink-scam-centers-elon-musk-civilians-military-elections/</link>
      <description>Further restrictions would almost certainly help the military as it consolidates power.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central Asia’s Studied Silence on Iran’s Turmoil</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/central-asias-studied-silence-on-irans-turmoil/</link>
      <description>Central Asian governments’ silence is a strategic calculation driven by economic interests, authoritarian solidarity, and uncertainty about Washington's next move.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: ‘Perfidy’ in boat strike?; Pentagon’s new AI plan; Venezuela’s broken air defenses; Quantum space cameras; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-13-2026/410643/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan-South Korea Summit: Why Middle Power Cooperation Matters More Than Ever in an Imperializing World</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/japan-south-korea-summit-why-middle-power-cooperation-matters-more-than-ever-in-an-imperializing-world/</link>
      <description>As the international order becomes more volatile and less rule-bound, Tokyo and Seoul must band together.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Serbia Heading Toward a Serbo-Maidan?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/13/serbia-protests-vucic-novi-sad-euromaidan/</link>
      <description>Mass demonstrations against Aleksandar Vucic’s government could turn brutal in the year ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Footage of Minneapolis ICE Shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/13/analysing-footage-of-minneapolis-ice-shooting/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on our latest investigations, join Bellingcat’s WhatsApp channel here On Jan. 7 Renee Good, a 37-year-old mother of three, was shot and killed by a federal agent on Portland Avenue in Minneapolis, Minnesota. The incident was captured on several separate videos and spread rapidly on social media. The videos were soon [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/13/analysing-footage-of-minneapolis-ice-shooting/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Analysing Footage of Minneapolis ICE Shooting&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLA Sorties Around Taiwan: Fewer Aircraft, Higher Threat</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/pla-sorties-around-taiwan-fewer-aircraft-higher-threat/</link>
      <description>Don’t let the quantitative changes mask the qualitative transformation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela Uncovers the Limits of China’s Security Promise in Latin America</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/venezuela-uncovers-the-limits-of-chinas-security-promise-in-latin-america/</link>
      <description>Following the decapitation strike on one of its closest partners, can Beijing still position itself as a credible security actor in the region?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Stronger Than Its Leaders Think</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/european-leaders-must-not-mistake-success-for-failure-by-alberto-alemanno-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past three decades, the European Union has built a political and regulatory system strong enough to shape global competition and bind much of the continent together. Yet instead of doubling down, its leaders are weakening the social and economic model that made that achievement possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korean President Meets Japanese Prime Minister</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/south-korean-president-meets-japanese-prime-minister/</link>
      <description>Three months after the South Korea-Japan summit meeting, the leaders met again in Nara Prefecture, Japan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Without democracy, Donald Trump’s Venezuelan oil quest will fail</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/13/without-democracy-donald-trumps-venezuelan-oil-quest-will-fail</link>
      <description>Sidelining the democratic opposition and its leader, María Corina Machado, would be a mistake</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Days of Fed Independence?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/economic-costs-of-trump-efforts-to-politicize-monetary-policy-by-anne-o-krueger-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump is again ratcheting up pressure on the Federal Reserve, this time with a criminal investigation of Fed Chair Jerome Powell, whose term ends in May. If Trump appoints a pliant successor, monetary policy will likely be looser than warranted, stoking inflation and undermining global economic stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Iran’s Democracy Movement Can Win: Reflections From a Tiananmen Survivor</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-irans-democracy-movement-can-win-reflections-from-a-tiananmen-survivor/</link>
      <description>“Drawing on lived experience from Tiananmen, I have come to believe that 4 concrete conditions determine whether an autocracy like China or Iran has a genuine chance of meaningful democratic change.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Power Doctrine: A $1.5 Trillion Military, Greenland Ambitions, and a World Ruled by Force</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/trump-power-doctrine-military-greenland</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;“After long and difficult negotiations with Senators, Congressmen, Secretaries, and other Political Representatives, I have determined that, for the Good of our Country, especially in these very troubled and dangerous times, our Military Budget for the year 2027 should not be $1 Trillion Dollars, but rather &lt;a href=&quot;https://defensescoop.com/2026/01/07/trump-calls-for-1-5-trillion-defense-budget-2027/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;$1.5 Trillion Dollars&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This will allow us to build the ‘Dream Military’ that we have long been entitled to and, more importantly, that will keep us SAFE and SECURE, regardless of foe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115855894695940909&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Truth Social&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; message from President Trump posted last Wednesday afternoon and illustrates the emphasis on increasing U.S. military power by him and top administration officials since the successful U.S. January 3, raid in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuelas-key-takeaways&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Venezuela&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that captured its former-President Nicolas Maduro and his wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it should, public attention has been focused on Trump’s apparent desire to project force as he publicly savors the plaudits arising from not only the Venezuela operation, but also the June 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts-assess-strikes-response-and-what-comes-next&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Operation Midnight Hammer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; bombing of three Iranian nuclear facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most focus this past week has been paid to remarks Trump made to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/11/us/politics/trump-interview-transcript.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reporters during their more than two hour interview last Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At that time, when asked if there are any limits on his global powers, Trump said, &quot;Yeah, there is one thing. My own morality. My own mind. It’s the only thing that can stop me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump added, “I don’t need international law. I’m not looking to hurt people.” Asked about whether his administration needed to abide by international law, Trump said, “I do,” but added, “it depends what your definition of international law is.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attention is also correctly being paid to remarks Trump’s Deputy Chief of Staff Stephen Miller made last Tuesday during an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2026/01/05/politics/video/senior-white-house-aide-stephen-miller-says-us-military-threat-to-maintain-control-of-venezuela-digvid&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;CNN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We live in a world in which you can talk all you want about international niceties and everything else,” Miller told CNN’s Jake Tapper, “But we live in a world, in the real world … that is governed by strength, that is governed by force, that is governed by power. These are the iron laws of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is against that Trump open-stress-on-power background that I will discuss below a few other incidents last week that could indicate future events. But first I want to explore Trump’s obsession with taking over Greenland, which was also illustrated during the &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; interview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1945, at the end of World War II fighting in Europe, the United States had 17 bases and military installations in Greenland with thousands of soldiers. Today, there is only one American base – U.S. Pituffik Space Base in northwest Greenland, formerly known as Thule Air Base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From this base today some 200 U.S. Air Force and Space Force personnel, plus many more contractors, carry out ballistic missile early warnings, missile defense, and space surveillance missions supported by what the Space Force described as an “Upgraded Early Warning Radar weapon system.” That system includes “a phased-array radar that detects and reports attack assessments of sea-launched and intercontinental ballistic missile threats in support of [a worldwide U.S.] strategic missile warning and missile defense [system],” according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.petersonschriever.spaceforce.mil/pituffik-sb-greenland/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Space Force press release&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same radar also supports what Space Force said is “Space Domain Awareness by tracking and characterizing objects in orbit around the earth.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the 1951 U.S.-Denmark defense agreement, the U.S., with Denmark’s assent, can create new “defense areas” in Greenland “necessary for the development of the defense of Greenland and the rest of the North Atlantic Treaty area, and which the Government of the Kingdom of Denmark is unable to establish and operate singlehanded.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agreement says further: “the Government of the United States of America, without compensation to the Government of the Kingdom of Denmark, shall be entitled within such defense area and the air spaces and waters adjacent thereto to improve and generally to fit the area for military use.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That apparently is not enough freedom for President Trump, still a real estate man. As he explained last week to the &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;reporters, “Ownership is very important, because that’s what I feel is psychologically needed for success. I think that ownership gives you a thing that you can’t do with, you’re talking about a lease or a treaty. Ownership gives you things and elements that you can’t get from just signing a document.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This long-held Trump view that he must have Greenland was explored back in 2021. After his first term as President, Trump was interviewed by Susan Glasser and Peter Baker for the book they were writing, and they asked Trump at that time why he wanted Greenland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/weta/washingtonweek/video/2026/01/trumps-greenland-threats-and-imperialist-ambitions&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;explained&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “You take a look at a map. So I’m in real estate. I look at a [street] corner, I say, ‘I gotta get that store for the building that I’m building,’ et cetera. You know, it’s not that different. I love maps. And I always said, ‘Look at the size of this [Greenland], it’s massive, and that should be part of the United States.’ It’s not different from a real-estate deal. It’s just a little bit larger, to put it mildly.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For all Trump’s repeated threats to seize Greenland militarily, it’s doubtful that will happen. Secretary of State Marco Rubio is scheduled to meet with Danish and Greenland counterparts this week, and afterwards the situation should become clearer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Context is another test for analyzing Trump statements, and that seems to be the case when looking at his call for a $1.5 trillion fiscal 2027 defense budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Wednesday, hours before Trump made his &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Truth Social&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; FY 2027 budget statement, the White House released an Executive Order (EO) entitled, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2026/01/prioritizing-the-warfighter-in-defense-contracting/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prioritizing The Warfighter In Defense Contracting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; The EO called for holding defense contractors accountable and targeted those who engaged in stock buybacks or issued dividends while “underperforming” on government contracts. According to one Washington firm, the Trump EO represented “one of the most aggressive federal interventions into corporate financial decisions in recent memory.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EO caused shares of defense stocks to fall. Lockheed Martin fell 4.8%, Northrop Grumman 5.5%, and General Dynamics 3.6% during that afternoon’s stock exchange trading in New York. After the stock market closed, Trump released his Truth Social message calling for the $1.5 trillion FY 2027 defense budget and the next day, January 8, defense stocks experienced a sharp rebound. Lockheed Martin rebounded with gains of around 7%; Northrop Grumman rose over 8%; and General Dynamics gained around 4%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump has not spoken publicly about the $1.5 trillion for FY 2027, but in his first message, he said the added funds would come from tariffs. He wrote, “Because of tariffs and the tremendous income that they bring, amounts being generated, that would have been unthinkable in the past, we are able to easily hit the $1.5 trillion dollar number.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If that were not enough, Trump added that the new funding would produce “an unparalleled military force, and having the ability to, at the same time, pay down debt, and likewise, pay a substantial dividend to moderate income patriots within our country!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What can be believed?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nonpartisan &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crfb.org/blogs/15-trillion-military-budget-would-add-58-trillion-debt-over-decade&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Committee for a Responsible Federal Budget&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (CRFB) said the $500 billion annual increase in defense spending would be nearly twice as much as the expected yearly tariff revenue, and the spending increase would push the national debt $5.8 trillion higher over the next decade. CRFB added, “Given the $175 billion appropriated to the defense budget under the [2025] One Big Beautiful Bill Act (OBBBA), there is little case for a near-term increase in military spending.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should point out that the FY 2026 $901 billion defense appropriations bill has yet to pass the Congress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One more event from last week needing attention involves Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday January 6, 2026, as Delcy Rodriguez, former Vice President, was sworn in as Venezuela's interim president, General Javier Marcano Tabata. the military officer closest to Maduro as his head of the presidential honor guard and director of the DGCIM, the Venezuelan military counterintelligence agency, was arrested and jailed, according to &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;El Pais Caracas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marcano Tabata was labeled a traitor and accused of facilitating the kidnapping of Maduro by providing the U.S. with exactly where Maduro and First Lady Cilia Flores were sleeping, and identifying blind spots in the Cuban-Venezuelan security ring protecting them, according to &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;El Pais Caracas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s the U.S. responsibility toward Marcano Tabata if the&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; El Pais Caracas &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;facts are correct ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to end this column with another Trump statement last week that stuck in my mind because of its implications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It came up last Friday after Trump, in the White House East Room, started welcoming more than 20 oil and gas executives invited to discuss the situation in Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have many others that were not able to get in…If we had a ballroom, we'd have over a thousand people. Everybody wanted. I never knew your industry was that big. I never knew you had that many people in your industry. But, here we are.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump then paused, got up and turned to look through the glass door behind him that showed the excavation for the new ballroom saying, “I got to look at this myself. Wow. What a view…Take a look, you can see a very big foundation that's moving. We're ahead of schedule in the ballroom and under budget. It's going to be I don't think there'll be anything like it in the world, actually. I think it will be the best.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He then said the remark I want to highlight, “The ballroom will seat many and it'll also take care of the inauguration with bulletproof glass-drone proof ceilings and everything else unfortunately that today you need.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who, other than Trump, would think that the next President of the United States would need to hold his inauguration indoors, inside the White House ballroom, with bullet-proof windows and a roof that protects from a drone attack?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU-Mercosur Deal Puts Principles into Practice</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-mercosur-agreement-why-it-matters-by-carlos-cuerpo-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By pushing through a long-awaited trade agreement with Mercosur (Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay, Uruguay), Europeans have demonstrated that they can manage their political differences and overcome resistance within and outside their borders. The values that the EU was built on are still alive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok Is Testing Whether AI Governance Means Anything</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/grok-sexualized-images-test-of-ai-governance-and-regulation-by-j-b-branch-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By generating increasingly disturbing outputs, Grok has exposed a deep structural problem that should concern regulators everywhere. Advanced AI systems are being deployed and made available to the public without safeguards proportionate to their risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Putin Still Prefers War</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/russia/why-putin-still-prefers-war</link>
      <description>Russia's growing resolve to fight on in Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iranian Regime Could Fall</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/iran/iranian-regime-could-fall</link>
      <description>But a U.S. strike would prop it up.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A World Without Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/world-without-rules</link>
      <description>The consequences of Trump’s assault on international law.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Wolf in Orange Clothing: How the People’s Party Betrayed Thailand’s Democratic Cause</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/a-wolf-in-orange-clothing-how-the-peoples-party-betrayed-thailands-democratic-cause/</link>
      <description>The party's appointment of Pisan Manawapat, a career diplomat who defended the military regime installed after the 2014 coup, is a stain on its reformist image.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Southeast Asia’s Military Modernization Set to Accelerate in 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/southeast-asias-military-modernization-set-to-accelerate-in-2026/</link>
      <description>At a time of growing geopolitical uncertainty, the scale and pace of major military procurements in the region is increasing.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum cameras could remake space-based intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/01/quantum-cameras-could-remake-space-based-intelligence/410636/</link>
      <description>A Boston startup is getting ready to test a new imagery method aboard an orbital satellite.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s People’s Party Leading Polls Ahead of February 8 Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/thailands-peoples-party-leading-polls-ahead-of-february-8-election/</link>
      <description>The opposition party is in a good position ahead of the polls, but it remains to be seen whether it can recreate the success of its predecessor, the Move Forward Party.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS adds office to fly, counter drones</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/dhs-adds-office-fly-counter-drones/410633/</link>
      <description>The new office intends to spend $115 million to ward off drones from the World Cup and U.S. 250th-birthday events.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 9: The Iron Chancellor: Otto von Bismark’s Unification of Germany</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/talking-strategy/episode-9-iron-chancellor-otto-von-bismarks-unification-germany</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Professor Michael Epkenhans describes how Otto von Bismark’s adroit use of war, realpolitik and the harnessing all levers of state power unified the German nation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Should Carefully Consider Bringing Down the Iranian Regime</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/trump-should-carefully-consider-bringing-down-iranian-regime</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Circumstances in Iran do not map easily onto the conditions in Venezuela that abetted Maduro’s kidnapping.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar Attempted to ‘Erase’ Rohingya Minority, Gambian Justice Minister Claims</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/myanmar-attempted-to-erase-rohingya-minority-gambian-justice-minister-claims/</link>
      <description>Yesterday, the International Court of Justice (ICJ) opened its first hearing in the genocide case brought by West African nation in 2019.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Is China’s Overseas Lending Changing in a Post-Default Era?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-is-chinas-overseas-lending-changing-in-a-post-default-era/</link>
      <description>The fractured alignment between SOEs and policy banks that once underpinned China’s overseas lending model is now breaking down after a wave of sovereign defaults.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Aircraft Carrier Is Not a Floating Aid Ship: Rethinking Indonesia’s Maritime Priorities</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/an-aircraft-carrier-is-not-a-floating-aid-ship-rethinking-indonesias-maritime-priorities/</link>
      <description>If disaster response is the Indonesian Navy's true priority, expanding and modernizing its existing fleet would deliver far greater returns.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Raid on Venezuela: The View from Hanoi</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-u-s-raid-on-venezuela-the-view-from-hanoi/</link>
      <description>What Vietnam thinks about the Trump administration's use of force in the Western Hemisphere.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
