<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Is Winning the Trade War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/china-winning-trade-war-trump-xi-beijing/</link>
      <description>Rare earths and other assets have given Beijing an edge in trade talks with Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi Takes the Spotlight at APEC Summit in Trump’s Absence</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/xi-jinping-apec-trump-trade-takaichi-carney-south-korea/</link>
      <description>China aims to portray itself as a champion of free trade amid high U.S. tariffs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Regime Change Temptation in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/venezuela/regime-change-temptation-maduro-trump-venezuela</link>
      <description>If past is prologue, a U.S. attempt to overthrow Maduro would not end well.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/news-quiz-hurricane-melissa-asia-summits-argentina-cameroon-tanzania-us-troops/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Oct. 25: Hurricane Melissa batters the Caribbean, Argentina holds midterm elections, and Trump travels through Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add This to the Canon of Great Diplomacy Books</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/a-wess-mitchell-great-power-diplomacy-book-review/</link>
      <description>A. Wess Mitchell’s tour through two millennia of diplomacy is catnip for foreign-policy wonks.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moscow’s Shadow Looms Over Bratislava</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/slovakia-russia-ukraine-nato-putin-fico/</link>
      <description>Russia’s historic role remains central to the debate over Slovak foreign policy today.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Is Stamping Out Dissident Art</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/china-art-gao-zhen-dissidents/</link>
      <description>Curators, painters, and performers are facing jail or exile.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Politics Are a Family Business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-prevalence-of-political-dynasties-lead-to-worse-governance-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The belief that members of political dynasties are uniquely suited to lead is woven deeply into the fabric of Indian governance, from village councils to the highest echelons of parliament. But when elected office is treated like a family heirloom, the quality of governance inevitably suffers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: The most successful amphibious invasion</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/10/31/the-war-room-newsletter-the-most-successful-amphibious-invasion</link>
      <description>In a bonus edition of our defence newsletter, Richard Cockett takes us back to 1066—and the Battle of Hastings</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Lie Behind Trump’s Boat Strikes</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-big-lies-drug-boat-strikes-venezuela-by-timothy-snyder-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration is training the press and the American people to associate the military strikes on small boats in international waters with stopping the flow of fentanyl and other drugs. This mendacity is a prime example of the falsehoods that imperialists tell before launching doomed wars of aggression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curtis Sliwa’s tough-guy mien evokes an older New York</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/10/31/curtis-sliwas-tough-guy-mien-evokes-an-older-new-york</link>
      <description>He won’t win the mayoral election, but his life story is more colourful than those of his rivals</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Coming US-China Thaw</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-thaw-rare-earths-ban-shows-american-aggression-no-longer-works-by-james-k-galbraith-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After years of increasingly hostile rhetoric from US officials about China, highly authoritative voices in the United States have suddenly become less hawkish, and the Trump administration has begun to pursue new trade negotiations in earnest. Is the American establishment finally waking up to economic reality?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Blind Spot: China’s Transnational Repression</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/europes-blind-spot-chinas-transnational-repression/</link>
      <description>China and other authoritarian regimes often target dissidents and minorities living abroad. The EU must do more to protect vulnerable communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United Council of Rohang: Bangladesh’s Script for Rohingya Leadership</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/united-council-of-rohang-bangladeshs-script-for-rohingya-leadership/</link>
      <description>The refugee camp elections did not provide not self-representation but state-supervised choreography.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development Finance Must Shift Away from Aid</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-must-reduce-foreign-aid-dependence-by-justin-yifu-lin-and-yan-wang-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As traditional donors slash foreign-aid budgets, developing countries must mobilize a broader range of financing sources. National development banks, sovereign wealth funds, debt swaps, and public-private partnerships can foster sustainable investment and help reduce energy poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Trump’s Critical Minerals Blitz Pay Off?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/trump-china-rare-earth-critical-mineral-asia-equity-stake/</link>
      <description>The U.S. president has been on a mission to secure new supply chains—and counter China’s grip.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is This Central Asia’s Green Energy Reckoning?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/is-this-central-asias-green-energy-reckoning/</link>
      <description>When it comes to energy security, Central Asian governments have shown an ability to adapt to shifting global and domestic trends.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Afghanistan Fits in Iran’s Changing Regional Playbook</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/where-afghanistan-fits-in-irans-changing-regional-playbook/</link>
      <description>Afghanistan occupies a central position in Tehran’s changing playbook, as the country is both a risk and a buffer for Iran.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Trump Should Have Raised China’s Transnational Repression With Xi Jinping</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/why-trump-should-have-raised-chinas-transnational-repression-with-xi-jinping/</link>
      <description>Even amid de-escalation efforts, there is strategic value to rebuffing Beijing’s overreach.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Vulnerable Is China?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/how-vulnerable-is-china</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The meeting between US President Donald Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping may have delivered a kind of détente, after months of escalating tariff threats by the United States and retaliatory restrictions on rare-earth exports by China. While China had good reason to de-escalate the conflict with the US, however, it remains beset by political and economic weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-vulnerable-is-china-doc-2025-10</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Pivot from Asia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-pivot-from-asia-to-western-hemisphere-by-richard-haass-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After US President Donald Trump's trip to the region, one could be forgiven for concluding that the &quot;pivot to Asia&quot; begun when Barack Obama was in the White House has been replaced by a pivot to the Western Hemisphere. Needless to say, this is not the pivot America’s friends and allies in Asia were and are counting on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Is Sending Soldiers to Lithuania to Train Ukrainian Troops</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/japan-is-sending-soldiers-to-lithuania-to-train-ukrainian-troops/</link>
      <description>The deployment, small as it is, marks a first for Japan in several ways.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can a dopamine detox reset your brain?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/10/31/can-a-dopamine-detox-reset-your-brain</link>
      <description>Taken literally, the idea makes no sense. But it might still be good for you</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can China Catch Up with the US Economically?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-will-avoid-the-middle-income-trap-but-fail-to-outgrow-the-us-economy-by-keun-lee-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With its GNI per capita having increased steadily in recent years, China has probably evaded the middle-income trap. But the country may yet find itself ensnared in a kind of economic Thucydides trap: attempting to surpass an incumbent hegemon bent on keeping it down – and never quite succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Hardware: The Message Behind Singapore’s New Defense Acquisitions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/beyond-hardware-the-message-behind-singapores-new-defense-acquisitions/</link>
      <description>For Singapore, whose security rests as much on perception as on capability, defense modernization is not a discretionary choice. It is strategic signaling.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taliban Minister Muttaqi’s Visit to Deoband Seminary in India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/taliban-minister-muttaqis-visit-to-deoband-seminary-in-india/</link>
      <description>He was mobbed at the seminary. The rockstar welcome he received should worry Delhi.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheng Li-wun’s Election Raises Questions for the KMT</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/cheng-li-wuns-election-raises-questions-for-the-kmt/</link>
      <description>Cheng's position on cross-strait issues and reformist agenda pits her against more traditional members of the KMT.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C5+1 Summit: What’s at Stake for the US and Central Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/c51-summit-whats-at-stake-for-the-us-and-central-asia/</link>
      <description>Kazakhstan and its neighbors continue to balance their ties with Washington alongside their deep economic and security links with Russia and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Standing by South Korea’s Hanwha Is a US Imperative</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/why-standing-by-south-koreas-hanwha-is-a-us-imperative/</link>
      <description>When China sanctioned units of Hanwha Ocean for its shipbuilding activities in the U.S., Washington's response was a welcome change.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and Xi Revive the Ghost of the G2</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/trump-and-xi-revive-the-ghost-of-the-g2/</link>
      <description>A seemingly offhand remark from Trump signals the return – at least rhetorically – of an idea once proposed and dismissed by both Washington and Beijing.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan’s Water Crisis Spells Debts for Farmers</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/uzbekistans-water-crisis-spells-debts-for-farmers/</link>
      <description>At a time when saving water has become a matter of vital importance, it is no less crucial to monitor how the allocated funds are used.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer: Trump Approves South Korea’s Nuclear Submarine Ambition</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/game-changer-trump-approves-south-koreas-nuclear-submarine-ambition/</link>
      <description>The decision will have major implications for the South Korea-U.S. alliance and beyond.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal Counts the Economic Cost of the Gen Z Uprising</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/nepal-counts-the-economic-cost-of-the-gen-z-uprising/</link>
      <description>The new government has tried to woo businesses, but it will take more than tax cuts and easy loans to convince them to make long-term bets.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Plays Offense in China’s Backyard</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/trump-cambodia-asean-china-geopolitics-rivalry-competition/</link>
      <description>His Cambodia charm offensive is the new normal in U.S. foreign policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will AI Kill the Firm?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ai-rewriting-rules-of-modern-capitalism-by-sami-mahroum-2025-10</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For centuries, the firm has organized economic life, translating human labor into value through hierarchy and routine. But as agentic AI begins to perform the managerial work of coordinating and decision-making, the institutions that once defined modern capitalism are starting to give way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life in Lint: The Cost of India’s Textile Recycling</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/life-in-lint-the-cost-of-indias-textile-recycling/</link>
      <description>Workers trade off their health and welfare for a precarious living.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economics Is Europe’s Tool for Everything</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/31/economics-europe-eu-ukraine-diplomacy/</link>
      <description>Why the bloc always seeks economic solutions to its political problems.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former President Duterte to Appeal ICC Ruling Affirming Its Jurisdiction</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/former-president-duterte-to-appeal-icc-ruling-affirming-its-jurisdiction/</link>
      <description>Duterte's lawyers content that the court did not initiate a full-fledged investigation until after the Philippines withdrew from the court in 2019.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fantasy of a New Middle East</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/middle-east/fantasy-new-middle-east</link>
      <description>Israel cannot destroy its way to peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Put IR Theory Into Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/how-put-ir-theory-practice</link>
      <description>American strategists should think more like social scientists.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timor-Leste Shouldn’t Have to Buy Its ASEAN Seat With Silence</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/10/timor-leste-shouldnt-have-to-buy-its-asean-seat-with-silence/</link>
      <description>Myanmar's military junta has used the bloc's procedures to silence calls for accountability made by the organization's newest member state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
