<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Bad Neighbor Policy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/trump-maduro-venezuela-oil/</link>
      <description>Treating regional countries as vassal states will push them into China’s arms.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Attack on Venezuela Prompts an Identity Crisis at the U.N.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/trump-venezuela-attack-maduro-united-nations-security-council-international-law/</link>
      <description>The international community appears powerless to address the attack.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Political Incoherence of Trump’s Venezuela Gambit</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/trump-venezuela-operation-maduro-international-law/</link>
      <description>The greatest beneficiaries of his actions may be America’s biggest rivals.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Venezuela, Who’s Next?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/trump-venezuela-maduro-donroe-doctrine-colombia-cuba-iran-mexico-greenland/</link>
      <description>U.S. President Donald Trump’s “no new wars” mantra is officially over.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Know About Venezuela’s Interim Leader</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/delcy-rodriguez-venezuela-maduro-regime-oil/</link>
      <description>Delcy Rodríguez is an ambitious and skilled political operator.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 21:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela: Trump, Geopolitics, and the View from Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/venezuela-trump-geopolitics-and-the-view-from-asia/</link>
      <description>How is the U.S. operation to detain the Venezuelan president being perceived in Asia by allies and adversaries?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Inside the mission that snatched Maduro</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/05/the-war-room-newsletter-inside-the-mission-that-snatched-maduro</link>
      <description>Shashank Joshi, our defence editor, digs into the details</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Venezuela, Donald Trump points a finger at Greenland</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/05/after-venezuela-donald-trump-points-a-finger-at-greenland</link>
      <description>Leaders in Greenland and Denmark are in shock. Is the president serious?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Venezuela Raid Is Great TV—but Won’t Win America’s Next War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/venezuela-maduro-trump-military-war-china/</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s obsession with quick strikes and flashy successes is bad news for military readiness.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intervening in Venezuela for the Oil Makes Little Sense</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/trump-maduro-venezuela-oil-intervention-energy/</link>
      <description>Trump is keen to seize the oil, but U.S. firms so far are circumspect.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Agency in a Technology-Mediated World</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/human-agency-in-a-technology-mediated-world</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Occasionally, a speech does more than mark a leadership transition or outline institutional priorities. It captures, with unusual clarity, the nature of the moment we are living through and the choices it demands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blaise Metreweli’s recent inaugural address as Chief (or more colloquially, C) of the UK’s Secret Intelligence Service was one of those moments. Rather than offering a conventional tour of threats or capabilities, she chose a more demanding path. She spoke about human agency in a world increasingly shaped by machines. About trust, judgment, and integrity at a time when technology is accelerating every dimension of competition and conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of working with Metreweli while serving as Deputy Director of the CIA for Digital Innovation. I watched her navigate the intersection of operations and technology with a rare combination of rigor and imagination. Her speech reflects that same sensibility. It is operationally grounded, intellectually disciplined, and quietly ambitious in what it asks of an intelligence service. Just as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What struck me most, reading her remarks, was not simply their alignment with themes I have been working on for years, both inside government and since my departure in 2024. It was the way she wove those themes together into a coherent vision of intelligence suited to the world as it is, not the world we might wish it to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the center of Metreweli’s speech is a proposition that may sound self-evident, yet is increasingly contested in practice: even in a technology-mediated world, human beings must still decide outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence can surface patterns, illuminate possibilities, even accelerate analysis. It cannot decide what matters. It cannot weigh moral tradeoffs. It cannot assume responsibility for consequences. Intelligence, in her framing, remains a human endeavor, even as it becomes ever more technologically enabled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a conclusion I reached years ago while leading digital transformation efforts inside the CIA. As our tools became more powerful, the temptation to treat output as authority grew stronger. We resisted that instinct deliberately. The most effective systems we built were those designed explicitly to support human judgment, not replace it. They forced users to ask better questions or to challenge assumptions, and to understand context before acting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have described this in multiple speeches and articles as human–machine partnering, and Metreweli’s speech reflects the same conviction. The future of intelligence is not technological supremacy alone. Nor is it the return to a romanticized vision of the intelligence mission before the digital revolution. It is the disciplined integration of technology into human decision-making, with clarity about where judgment must reside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metreweli is equally clear about the character of modern conflict. We are no longer operating in a world neatly divided between war and peace. Instead, we inhabit a persistent space between the two, where states seek advantage through pressure that is continuous, deniable, and often difficult to attribute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyber operations, sabotage, influence campaigns, and coercive economic measures all live comfortably in this grey zone. They are designed to intimidate and to erode confidence without triggering a conventional response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One aspect of this competition that deserves particular attention is the emergence of what I have called digital chokepoints. These are points of leverage embedded in digital infrastructure, data ecosystems, platforms, standards, and supply chains. They do not announce themselves boldly as instruments of power, yet they have increasingly come under attack in recent years as a tool of geopolitical competition. In 2024-2025 alone, there were numerous anomalous “incidents” that damaged or cut 13 undersea cables around Taiwan and the Baltic Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grey-zone conflict, viewed through this lens, is not episodic. It is cumulative. And we will see more of it. Intelligence services must therefore understand not just individual operations, but the architecture of pressure that builds quietly and persistently across domains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The convergence of artificial intelligence, biotechnology, and quantum computing, and the way these advances are reshaping both opportunity and risk was featured prominently in Metreweli’s speech. She avoids the dual traps of easy optimism and easy alarmism alike.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have often framed technology as both shield and sword. It accelerates intent, but it does not generally determine outcomes. Technology itself is neutral. What matters is how it is governed, deployed, and constrained by human choice, as well as which values are encoded into its digital foundations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This distinction is not academic. The same AI system that accelerates medical discovery can enable surveillance at scale. The same digital infrastructure that connects societies can be (and is) used to monitor and control them. Metreweli’s speech is careful to emphasize mastery of technology alongside responsibility for its effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That balance is essential. Technological determinism strips leaders of agency and excuses poor judgment. Metreweli’s approach does neither.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most sobering elements of Metreweli’s address is her discussion of trust. Information, once a unifying force, is now routinely weaponized. Falsehood spreads faster than fact. Algorithms reward outrage and reinforce bias. Shared reality seems increasingly elusive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have spent significant time in recent years examining the implications of synthetic media, deepfakes, and AI-enabled influence operations. Today, identity itself has become contested space. Voice, image, and presence can be fabricated convincingly and at scale. Seeing is no longer believing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This presents intelligence services with challenges that extend well beyond traditional counterintelligence or cyber defense. When trust collapses, when one can no longer discern truth from fiction, societies risk losing much more than confidence in institutions. They risk losing the ability to reason collectively about the world they inhabit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metreweli’s insistence that defending the space where truth can still stand as a core intelligence mission reflects a deep understanding of what is at stake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another strength of Metreweli’s speech is her refusal to treat today’s challenges as isolated problems. She describes an interlocking threat landscape that spans physical and digital domains, from seabed cables to space systems, from code to cognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This holistic view is critical. Too often, Western governments have approached cross-domain issues in separate policy lanes. Next-generation communications, artificial intelligence, digital infrastructure, cyber intrusions, disinformation campaigns. All treated as distinct, individual issues. Our principal strategic competitor, the People’s Republic of China, has not made that mistake. These domains are understood as mutually reinforcing components of a comprehensive national digital strategy tied directly to a grand geopolitical ambition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have argued for years that we must respond in kind, not by mirroring authoritarian models, but by approaching this competition in a more holistic fashion and by offering global partners a credible alternative. Countries around the world want to harness new technologies to accelerate development and improve lives. Many also want to protect sovereignty and human freedom. Meeting that demand requires seeing the digital contest as a whole, not as a collection of technical projects about which individual and disconnected policy decisions are made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though not stated in such terms, Metreweli’s framing reflects this reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an operational commander who became a technical leader, Metreweli brings unusual authority to her discussion of technology within intelligence tradecraft. She envisions a service where officers are as comfortable using digital tools as they are recruiting and running human sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not about turning intelligence officers into engineers. It is about understanding technology as both a tool and a terrain. Digital literacy becomes foundational, not because everyone must code, but because everyone must grasp how technology shapes the operational environment and adversary behavior. In modern intelligence, ignorance of technology becomes a vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metreweli also speaks directly to the question of legitimacy. Intelligence services in democracies operate with extraordinary authorities. Their effectiveness ultimately depends on trust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her commitment to openness, where it can responsibly exist, is not about transparency for its own sake. It is about sustaining a relationship with the public rooted in shared values. Accountability, in her formulation, is a strength, not a constraint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a principle I championed consistently inside the Agency and since my departure. In democratic societies, trust can never be taken for granted. It must be earned and maintained, especially as intelligence services operate in the shadows, out of view of the citizens they serve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A particularly powerful portion of Metreweli’s speech focuses on audacity and “hustle,” reflecting a clear understanding of the environment intelligence services face today. In a world defined by exponential change, moving slowly does not preserve relevance. It accelerates decline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have spoken often about urgency, about the reality that institutions unwilling to adapt will become obsolete. That does not mean abandoning discipline or ethics. It means recognizing that delay carries its own significant risks. In today’s dynamic, high-threat landscape, inaction is perhaps the biggest risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metreweli closes her speech where she began, with values. Courage. Creativity. Respect. Integrity. She recounts a conversation with a long-term foreign agent who worked with the UK precisely because of these values. This is not a sentimental anecdote. It is a strategic insight into how intelligence services in western democracies must navigate today’s complexity. Leveraging our core strength. Values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are living through the rise of digital authoritarianism, where technology is used to monitor, manipulate, and control populations at unprecedented scale. The most profound threat this poses is not technical. It is moral. It erodes human agency incrementally, often invisibly, until freedom becomes difficult to reclaim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have warned repeatedly that societies rarely lose freedom in dramatic moments. They lose it through systems that optimize for efficiency or security while stripping away consent, accountability, and choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metreweli’s insistence that none of us have a future without values is therefore a statement of strategic reality, and it gets to the very heart of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blaise Metreweli’s speech deserves close reading, not because it is eloquent (though it is), but because it is consequential. It articulates a vision of intelligence that is technologically fluent without being technologically captive, operationally aggressive without abandoning principle, and deeply human in a world that increasingly tempts us to forget what that means.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For intelligence professionals, policymakers, and citizens alike, it is a reminder that even as our tools evolve, the most important choices remain ours to make.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full speech &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/speech-by-blaise-metreweli-chief-of-sis-15-december-2025&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela Might Be Where Trump’s Luck Runs Out</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/venezuela-trump-us-military-intervention-regime-change-south-america/</link>
      <description>The president keeps threading the needle between the extremely hawkish and dovish factions of his base.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Unfair Trade: Sri Lanka’s Tamil Tea Workers</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/an-unfair-trade-sri-lankas-tamil-tea-workers/</link>
      <description>For more than two centuries, Tamil tea plantation workers in Sri Lanka have been trapped in poverty, enduring structural discrimination and hazardous conditions despite repeated promises of reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military force can topple a dictator, but it cannot create political authority or legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2026/01/can-us-run-venezuela-military-force-can-topple-dictator-it-cannot-create-political-authority-or-legitimacy/410451/</link>
      <description>Trump is the latest to reach for a military solution of the kind that rarely produces durable peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Japan souring on foreign workers and tourists?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/05/why-is-japan-souring-on-foreign-workers-and-tourists</link>
      <description>It is a dangerous attitude for an ageing country that needs more immigrants</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Venezuela, What Is Next in 2026?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-maduro-2026</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/new-york-ny-january-5-nicolas-maduro-and-his-wife-cilia-flores-are-seen-in-handcuffs-after-landing-at-a-manhattan-helipad.jpg?id=62661711&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C92%2C0%2C92&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIPHER BRIEF EXPERT Q&amp;amp;A — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;President Donald Trump said the U.S. is &quot;in charge&quot; in Venezuela after U.S. forces detained President &lt;strong&gt;Nicolas Maduro &lt;/strong&gt;on charges related to drug trafficking. President Trump is also demanding &quot;total access&quot; to Venezuela's oil infrastructure. Venezuela's de-facto leader &lt;strong&gt;Delcy Rodriguez &lt;/strong&gt;said Caracas is seeking &quot;balanced and respectful international relations&quot; with Washington.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intelligence professionals are reacting to this major development as it will have far-reaching consequences far beyond Venezuela, for the Western Hemisphere and elsewhere amid heightened tensions with adversaries such as Russia and China. Cipher Brief Executive Editor Brad Christian spoke with former CIA Senior Executive Paul Kolbe about what Maduro's capture signals for the national security landscape in 2026. The conversation has been lightly edited for length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How are thinking about what just happened in Venezuela? What's top of mind for you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kolbe: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Venezuela has been a problem both for the United States and for the Venezuelan people for over 20 years. For the Chavez years and then the Maduro years, they've driven a country that was once one of the wealthiest in the world, and certainly wealthiest in South America, with unbelievable natural resources, particularly oil, and driven it into the ground through corruption, poor leadership, poor decisions, and oppression of the people. There's a reason eight million Venezuelans have fled the country. So, it's been a series of corrupt, horrible rulers. Not sorry to see Maduro go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela has also been a foothold for Cuba. Very important for Cuba in terms of the oil that they get there, but also as a place to plant the flag and spread Cuban revolution throughout South America. It's been a base and source of money and money laundering for Hezbollah and Iran. Russia has had a long-standing relationship with Chavez and with Maduro, supporting them with weapons, with intelligence, with the Wagner Group. So, Venezuela has been both a thorn in the side of the U.S., and has been involved in so many different things that are against our interests — not sorry to see Maduro go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Christian: Last year, President Trump had authorized covert activity in Venezuela. There had been talk even recently, just days ago, of the CIA being involved in a strike against a target in Venezuela. We don't often see a military operation of this complexity that goes this smoothly. What does that tell you about the intelligence that was at play here and the level of cooperation with the military?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kolbe: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Clearly it was highly professional and extraordinarily well-executed operation, both by the intelligence community and by the U.S. special operations forces that went in. Very pleased that there were no casualties, that we didn't suffer any losses. But the split that I would make is to ask if this is a very well-executed tactical operation that is without a larger strategy?  And if there's a larger strategy, what is it? In particular, what's the follow-on? There's been a number of times where we've gone in and broken things and not done such a great job of fixing them or just leaving. You can look at Libya, at Iraq, and other places where that's not happened. Some folks will point to Panama and Grenada and try to use those as analogies for Venezuela, and they're very different cases. Venezuela's not Panama — much bigger, much different set of dynamics there — and it's certainly not Grenada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the follow-on of who's going to rule, what the transition is, how do you maintain stability? The narco-traffickers are still there, the narco-syndicates, the military is still there, the street gangs are still there. The paramilitaries, which have been supported by the military and have acted as the chief arm of oppression and brutality against the people, they're still there. There's a lot of generals that have an awful lot to lose. So, unless there's been a negotiated handover of power, I don't quite understand, yet, how we're going to run the country without boots on the ground or without a clear negotiated handover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: Russia's been described as a special type of enabler for Venezuela over the years.  Russian officials have called the U.S. operation in Venezuela &quot;unlawful'' and a violation of norms. There have been other Russia developments related to Venezuela recently. The ship, Bella 1, that the United States has been pursuing for the last couple of weeks was reported to have painted a Russian flag on it's hull on Dec 31, and Russia reportedly has asked the United States to stop pursuing it.  What's your reaction to how Russia has publicly responded to these incidents?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kolbe: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I'll start with the irony of Russia's protestations against what they see as the invasion of sovereignty of another country and how awful that is put out there with no sense of irony. Russia is condemning something that is not analogous to what they've done in Ukraine, but also completely ignoring what they've done in Ukraine and the ongoing war that they continue to pursue against the Ukrainian people, against their infrastructure, against everything that stands there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, while Venezuela is going to capture a lot of attention over the next few days, I suspect that's also, perhaps, part of the purpose of it. It distracts from what I think is a far more strategic, far more important issue, i.e., What's going to happen in Ukraine in 2026? Will the U.S. abandon Ukraine? Will we stab them in the back, or will we be able to provide support that lets them fight Russia, preserve their sovereignty?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story with the ship is a pretty interesting one. It feels like watching a sea-born version of OJ Simpson's escape in his Ford Bronco as this Coast Guard cutter trails this gigantic oil freighter, which is running away at the speed of 11 knots and is now in the North Atlantic and is claiming to have Russian protection.  Russia has reportedly put out a diplomatic note dissuading the U.S. from taking any action on that. So it will be interesting to see what actually happens if the ship managed to make good on the escape or if we turn around and say, &quot;Oh, nevermind.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you Subscribed to&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: At the most recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tcbconference.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Threat Conference&lt;/a&gt; back in October, there was a lot of talk of global conflict. And some people use the phrase, &quot;World War III.&quot; Are we in it? Has it begun? There's been a lot of talk about gray zone, the level of gray zone activity, and the risk of major conflicts breaking out such as Taiwan or the situation in Europe growing beyond the borders of Ukraine. How are you thinking about the world as we start 2026 amid what is truly a dynamic national security backdrop?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kolbe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm thinking about it as we're in a state of conflict without recognizing it. Just a couple of days ago over New Year’s, you saw China mount a blockade exercise, clearly practicing for a coming blockade of Taiwan. The signaling coming out of there is ever sharper and, it’s always been clear, but suggests a narrowing timeline for action on Taiwan. I don't believe anything's imminent, but clearly they're building the capability and then the intent, the decision, once they have the capability, can happen at any time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of days ago, we saw another communications cable cut between Estonia and Finland by a Russian ship that had left a Russian port that continues what is essentially low grade warfare on the European continent by Russia: sabotage, assassinations, misinformation, disinformation, and just a series of things which are clearly preparation of the battlefield, designed both to deter Europe and get Europe to self-deter, but also for the U.S., but also to put into place the capabilities that would be useful or used in conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think what is clear to me is that we, the US — as stated in the National Security Strategy that came out in December — are basically carving out Latin America as a U.S. area of influence and seeming to leave Europe and Central Asia to Russia and East Asia to China. And for me, that's very disturbing that America First looks to be coming to include South America First.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan immigrants in America are trapped in policy purgatory</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/05/venezuelan-immigrants-in-america-are-trapped-in-policy-purgatory</link>
      <description>In Florida Nicolás Maduro’s arrest brings cheers and chills</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Trump threatens more countries after Maduro abduction; SCOTUS rejects Guard deployment; Nigerian-strike fallout; 2025 scorecard; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-05-2026/410450/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Unanswered Questions About Trump’s Venezuela Plan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/trump-venezuela-operation-unanswered-questions-maduro-international-law/</link>
      <description>Maduro’s exit doesn’t mean the end of his regime.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s raid on Venezuela reveals the limits of China’s reach</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/05/americas-raid-on-venezuela-reveals-the-limits-of-chinas-reach</link>
      <description>It is not a template for Taiwan but a reality check on China’s global power</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why ‘Taking’ Venezuela’s Oil Hurts U.S. Energy Security</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/maduro-trump-venezuela-oil-energy-security/</link>
      <description>Washington’s long-term interests require a smooth political transition in Caracas, not short-sighted mercantilism.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Precedents to Trump’s Venezuela Operation</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-extraction-of-maduro-from-venezuela-more-about-regime-change-us-by-timothy-snyder-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In ousting and arresting Nicolás Maduro, US President Donald Trump wants the political gains of fighting a war without actually having to fight one. Whereas fascists and imperialists know that war requires real combat, Trump seems unwilling or unable to go that far, not least because he is weak at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An AI revolution in drugmaking is under way</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/05/an-ai-revolution-in-drugmaking-is-under-way</link>
      <description>It will transform how medicines are made—and the industry itself</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan Takes Up Chairmanship of EAEU for 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/kazakhstan-takes-up-chairmanship-of-eaeu-for-2026/</link>
      <description>Tokayev proposed that the EAEU focus on artificial intelligence, logistics, digitalization, free trade, and global dialogue.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Terror Laws Are Creating New Mandelas</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indias-terror-laws-are-creating-new-mandelas/</link>
      <description>Umar Khalid and Zohran Mamdani embody a shared global moment: exposing state excess on one side, and dissent and solidarity on the other.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Real Is China’s $1 Trillion-Plus Trade Surplus?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-real-is-chinas-1-trillion-plus-trade-surplus/</link>
      <description>It’s been celebrated at home and criticized abroad. But there's an important caveat to the record-breaking data.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Special Military Operation in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/trump-venezuela-invasion-defeats-us-constitution-by-stephen-holmes-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The framers of the US Constitution designed a system to compel the executive to explain its actions, wagering that requiring justifications would discipline power and prevent its arbitrary exercise. President Donald Trump has called that bet – and won.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela was a Surprise. What Could be Next?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-was-a-surprise-what-could-be-next</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIPHER BRIEF EXPERT Q&amp;amp;A -- &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deposed Venezuelan President &lt;strong&gt;Nicolás Maduro&lt;/strong&gt; is scheduled to appear in a U.S. courtroom on Monday for the first time since being brought to New York to face &lt;strong&gt;narco-terrorism charges&lt;/strong&gt;. The brief hearing will formally begin what is expected to be a lengthy legal battle over whether he can be prosecuted in the United States.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This, as intelligence professionals are considering what the seemingly flawless U.S. military operation to detain Maduro could mean for what’s next in the region. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cipher Brief Executive Editor Brad Christian spoke with former CIA Senior Executive Glenn Corn about the impact of the Venezuelan operation and what we still don’t know. Their conversation has been lightly edited for length.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: Talk us through how you're reacting to the news of the last 72 hours.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; If I had a hat, I'd take it off to our former partner colleagues in the intelligence community and the special operations community. I mean, great operation. Well planned and executed. I'm sure that the intelligence had to be very good. Honestly, I'm proud because it's good to have a reminder that the U.S. can do this kind of thing. I don't want to go into the international law piece. I'm not a lawyer. But really a great operation and thanks to the people that put it together. You probably remember that we talked recently about the importance of the Western Hemisphere and reasserting some of our influence there and reminding people that, this is our backyard. This administration has made the Western Hemisphere a priority and I think it's a good thing. And here's an example of something that the president is willing to do. I give the president credit - this is a pretty bold move. And the timing was interesting. The other thing I'll say is no leaks, right? Which is also very, very good news because we have a problem in Washington with leaks, and the administration was able to keep this one under wraps. I was completely surprised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who’s Reading this? More than 500K of the most influential national security experts in the world. Need &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;full access&lt;/a&gt; to what the Experts are reading?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: What do you think are going to be some of the things that you're going to be watching most closely? President Trump has said that the United States is going to be involved in administering Venezuela in the near term. There's been a lot of talk about reviving Venezuela's oil industry. Obviously, that's not surprising. There's been some reaction from American adversaries, but everyone's still in a watch and wait mode yet for how China and Russia is going to respond to this. What are you paying attention to in terms of signals for this week?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The president's comments about some type of U.S. administration, at least in some kind of transitory period were interesting. I immediately am reminded of Iraq where the military operation was well done and we removed Saddam Hussein pretty quickly in 2003, but then what came after was not great. So, I hope we've learned that lesson and we're not going to repeat the mistakes we made there. Hopefully there is a plan in place. The president indicated that some people in the administration are going to be giving roles also to help administer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it’s interesting that President Maduro and his wife were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/us-venezuela-strike-nicolas-maduro-captured-how-timeline-trump-rcna252041&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;detained&lt;/a&gt;, but it looks like everybody else is still in their roles which may be an indication that they learned the lesson from Iraq and our experience there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you're the Iranian supreme leader, you probably have to be very nervous right now. I went to bed thinking about Iran and what's happening there. And the president's comments that the U.S. will support those people that are coming out to peacefully protest and if they're... I forget his &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/iran-protests-trump-4e2232877bd1fff11cd80a33db47353d&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exact words&lt;/a&gt;, but basically, &quot;We will punish those who use force against them or who killed protestors.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: The way I interpreted that was that the U.S. was prepared to intervene militarily to protect the protestors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; And we may still be. Last week, I was very focused on Iran, then all of a sudden over the weekend, this operation went down. Now, whether that's the intent or not, I don't know, but it’s really interesting timing. What comes next will be very important. I've been saying for a while that this administration has had some very good foreign policy successes in the last year, since coming to office. Generally, I think they're doing well on the foreign policy front. They've done some bold things. Syria, Azerbaijan, Armenia. Now what comes next is important, and then consistency is important. Do we have the ability to see it through? We’ll have to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: Russia is considered an ally to Venezuela. How might this impact Moscow’s foreign policy in the Western hemisphere, to include their planning and their ongoing operations as it relates to Venezuela or perhaps other parts of the Western hemisphere?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I think Putin has backed himself into a corner when it comes to a lot of these countries that he's aligned with. We saw that with Syria where he was overspent, and he really didn't have anything to help former President Bashar al-Assad when Assad was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/22/world/middleeast/assad-syria-exile-luxury.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in crisis&lt;/a&gt;. And one of his main allies in the Middle East is no longer there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Venezuela, the Russians have come out with some statements in support of Caracas, of Maduro, but they really haven't done much. There was some reporting last year, that Moscow was shipping more air defense systems and weapons to Maduro and the regime as we were ratcheting up our military activity in the Caribbean. But none of that seems to have made a real difference. Putin has to understand right now that he's been unable to come to Assad's assistance and with Maduro, his ally has just been removed and detained. So, he's got to be watching Iran very nervously because that's his other main ally in the Middle East and they've invested a lot in that relationship, and it seems like the Supreme Leader is in trouble right now. The regime is in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the President of the United States making bold comments about what the U.S. will do if the regime goes after protestors in Iran, it’s clear that Putin's influence is waning all over the world and he's eventually going to be unable to stand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief applies expert-level context to national and global security stories. Grant yourself full-access to Cipher Brief expert insights, analysis and private briefings in the new year by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;becoming a Subscriber+Member&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Russians used to like to brag that they stand by their allies when the U.S. abandons them. Actually, it's looking now like the Russians are abandoning their allies. And I assess that's partly because of this quagmire that Putin got himself into in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe some of the Venezuelans who are celebrating the removal of their dictator should think about Ukraine and what the Ukrainians have done for them by stopping the Russian military the way they've done so effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also seems at first blush, that the intelligence services of Russia failed because it looks like this operation went down without any real warning to Maduro. And one would assess that if Putin is an ally of Maduro, he'd have tipped him off about the operation, which the Russians have tried to do in other circumstances in the past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the way, the Cuban bodyguards, what happened to them? Someone was telling me last week, that Maduro's main security force was made up of Cubans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think Putin has painted himself into a corner because I think he's afraid to really upset Trump because he knows that if Trump comes down hard on him on the Ukraine issue, he's in big trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He's already in trouble. And many of us have assessed for a while that if President Trump decides that it's time to really ratchet up the heat on Moscow and the Kremlin, that will probably be a serious, serious blow to Putin and his power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: Do you believe that President Putin thinks he's backed into a corner in the way that you describe? And is it likely that there are people around him who may be telling him that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I don't even want to try to put myself in his head space. I've said for a long time, going back 10 years, that he's put himself in an information vacuum or echo chamber. So, who knows what he's thinking. But my guess is that he feels like he's backed into a corner. If you saw when the U.S. announced sanctions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy2777&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gazprom&lt;/a&gt; and Lukoil, the first thing Putin did was send a delegate to the United States in a rush. That showed me panic and fear. And I'm sure that people around Putin are upset and worried.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, let's watch Iran. I think Iran's a big piece on the chess board, and we should see what happens there. I don't think that the Russians are going to be able to help much if the Iranian regime starts to collapse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: The critics of the operation in Venezuela are saying things like, &quot;This is a bad precedent to set. Other leaders around the world may decide, 'Okay, well, if the U.S. can do something like this...'&quot; And obviously the criticism of this operation is it violates Venezuela's sovereignty. Do you worry about the knock-on effect and the second and third order effects of an operation like this being conducted by the United States, regardless of who's president, and being used in ways that may cause further instability in the world or being used by autocratic leaders or America's adversaries?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; No, I think that ship sailed a long time ago. This is not the first time the United States has done something like this. This is not the first time other countries have done something like this. Countries have made land grabs, have assassinated leaders or tried to remove leaders, overthrow governments. So, there's nothing new here. There's no new precedent here that I see. We've already started down this very ugly road. And to me, now, what's important is to make sure that our national security structure and our intelligence community and armed forces are fully armed and capable of dealing with any threat to U.S. interests and to our allies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christian: At our most recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tcbconference.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cipher Brief Threat Conference&lt;/a&gt; in October, there was a lot of talk about global conflict. Some people use the phrase World War III. Do you believe it’s started and how are you thinking about 2026 from a national security standpoint?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corn:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Deterrence is critical right now. The U.S. has been deterred too much in the past, and we've been unable to deter our adversaries. It's very important that the U.S. maintains and demonstrates an ability to deter adversaries when they threaten our interests. The president is talking about U.S. oil companies going into Venezuela, rebuilding the infrastructure, reviving the Venezuelan oil industry, energy industry. I think this goes along with the administration's approach with commercial diplomacy, getting the U.S. business community actively involved around the world to help promote U.S. interests, which I support but you have to make sure that happens because you don't want vacuums to be created. A year ago in Syria, everybody was very excited about the opportunities, but those opportunities have been very hard to develop because of the realities on the ground. So, you need sustainment. You need the ability to really sustain and be patient and invest in taking advantage of opportunities and bringing some kind of economic development to regions that have suffered for a long time and are in very bad shape that are producing either jihadists or narco traffickers - probably because a lot of those people have no other choice to survive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You and I have both served in countries where that is the case, where the majority of people are not bad people, but they have no choice. There's really no option. We want to give them something better, right? But we have to do it. And that's going to be the big challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, kudos to the administration. This is part of a bigger game. I go back to the Reagan administration and the kind of rollback approach to the Soviet Union when Russia was challenging us around the world and Reagan finally responded to that by challenging them and calling out the Soviets where they were trying to poke on our interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would say that the Trump administration seems to be doing that, which is good, but we've got to be very, very cognizant of the fact that it's going to take a lot of investment and a lot of persistent attention to do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the Iranian regime collapses tomorrow, that could create a great opportunity or a vacuum. There’s a great opportunity in Venezuela right now. Let's take advantage of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Stock Market Could Sink Trump in 2026</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-stock-market-ahead-of-midterms-by-desmond-lachman-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By emphasizing how well the US stock market is doing, US President Donald Trump could be setting himself up for electoral disappointment this November. With equities priced for perfection, any number of risks could deflate today's exuberance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the US Operation in Venezuela Raises the Risk of War on the Korean Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-the-us-operation-in-venezuela-raises-the-risk-of-war-on-the-korean-peninsula/</link>
      <description>The extraction of a sovereign leader by U.S. special forces confirms Kim Jong Un’s deepest fear. That increases the risk of a miscalculation that could trigger nuclear war.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s President Lee Meets China’s Xi</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/south-koreas-president-lee-meets-chinas-xi/</link>
      <description>For the first time since 2017, the South Korean president made a state visit to Beijing to hold a meeting with the Chinese leader.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Fear and Loathing of Europe</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-focus-on-europe-civilizational-decline-puts-eu-liberals-into-corner-by-ian-buruma-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as some early-20th-century German nationalists viewed Russia as a useful ally against more liberal European countries and the &quot;racially chaotic&quot; United States, the US under Donald Trump regards Russia and Hungary as friends united against a common enemy: Europe. There are several reasons for this reversal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If China Invades Taiwan, What Would Japan Do?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/if-china-invades-taiwan-what-would-japan-do/</link>
      <description>Given all that’s at stake, how would Japan respond in a scenario that could lead to the world’s first great power war since 1945?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLA Drills, US Strike on Venezuela Spark Debate in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/pla-drills-us-strike-on-venezuela-spark-debate-in-taiwan/</link>
      <description>The PLA exercise raised the specter of a blockage, while American actions against Venezuela sparked different fears in Taiwan.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba’s regime is now in Donald Trump’s sights</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/05/cubas-regime-is-now-in-donald-trumps-sights</link>
      <description>Excited Cuban exiles are comparing the capture of Nicolás Maduro to the fall of the Berlin Wall</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Winter 2026 Print Issue</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/print-issue-winter-2026-ravi-agrawal-united-states/</link>
      <description>The world-minus-one moment.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World-Minus-One Moment</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/world-minus-one-united-states-isolationism-multilateralism-global-power/</link>
      <description>Managing the global order with an antagonistic Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can China Replace an Absent America in the Climate Fight?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/climate-change-united-states-china-paris-agreement-global-environmental-leadership/</link>
      <description>Beijing never bought the argument that reducing emissions would cause economic harm.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pillars of the Global Nuclear Order Are Cracking</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/nuclear-proliferation-united-states-korea-poland-pakistan-deterrence/</link>
      <description>U.S. allies and partners are taking steps toward a post-American nuclear order.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyberdefense Enters a Dangerous New Phase</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/cybersecurity-ransomware-united-states-cyberattack-china-hacking/</link>
      <description>Allies fear that Washington is retreating from leadership at the worst possible time.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Dangerous Precedent’: Southeast Asia’s Response to US Venezuela Intervention</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/dangerous-precedent-southeast-asias-response-to-us-venezuela-intervention/</link>
      <description>To varying degrees, the region's governments have expressed concerns about the U.S. military's abduction of President Nicolas Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s New About This Wave of Protests in Iran</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/iran-protests-islamic-republic-regime-change/</link>
      <description>The center of gravity has moved toward regime change rather than reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Bombing of Hiroshima Was Covered Up</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/05/hiroshima-bombshell-cover-up-pbs-documentary/</link>
      <description>A new documentary details the complicity of the fourth estate with the U.S. government.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion of Isolationism</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/illusion-isolationism</link>
      <description>No one should have expected Trump to retreat.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Puzzling Death of Indian Singer Zubeen Garg in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-puzzling-death-of-indian-singer-zubeen-garg-in-singapore/</link>
      <description>Singapore authorities say there's no sign of foul play. But Indian investigators have framed murder charges against four people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 02:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Commits to Venezuela’s Transition. Can it Succeed?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/us-commits-venezuelas-transition-can-it-succeed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Capturing Nicolás Maduro is not a shortcut to rebuilding a broken country. Washington must now prevent a lengthy interregnum by Maduristas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
