<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Parliament Dissolves to Head Off No-Confidence Vote</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/thailand-dissolves-parliament-anutin-cambodia-clashes-snap-elections/</link>
      <description>Triggering snap elections raises the specter of more political turmoil amid deadly clashes with Cambodia.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Make of China’s Trade Surplus</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/china-trade-surplus-economics-trump-policy/</link>
      <description>The imbalance raises questions about the global economy and Trump administration policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will California try to block Hollywood’s next megadeal?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/12/will-california-try-to-block-hollywoods-next-megadeal</link>
      <description>States are beefing up their antitrust enforcement</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/news-quiz-west-africa-coup-thailand-cambodia-conflict-lithuania-emergency-trump-semiconductors/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Dec. 6: A West African coup fails, violence flares on the Thailand-Cambodia border, and Lithuania declares a state of emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens to China’s Surplus Men?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/china-gender-dating-demographic-population-documentary/</link>
      <description>The one-child policy’s gender imbalance has spawned desperate bachelors, dubious gurus, and a rising manosphere.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nvidia Chip Deal Is a National Security Disaster Waiting to Happen</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/nvidia-chips-national-security-trump-united-states-china-ai/</link>
      <description>Trump’s latest proposal would cede the United States’ AI advantage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soccer Still Has Some Explaining to Do</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/franklin-foer-how-soccer-explains-the-world-globalization-capitalism-fifa-world-cup/</link>
      <description>Re-read today, Franklin Foer’s 2004 classic inadvertently suggests where globalization went wrong.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh’s Pivotal Election and Referendum Has a Date. Will Unrest Follow?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/bangladeshs-pivotal-election-and-referendum-has-a-date-will-unrest-follow/</link>
      <description>The stakes are high for Bangladesh's first election since the 2024 student-led uprising.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Asylum-Seekers</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/souleymanes-story-film-review-france-migration-politics/</link>
      <description>“Souleymane’s Story” interrogates the fictions we tell ourselves about what makes an acceptable migrant.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Make of North Korea’s End-of-Year Party Plenum</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/what-to-make-of-north-koreas-end-of-year-party-plenum/</link>
      <description>The plenum served as a primer for the bigger party congress that is yet to come.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Framework for Financing Global Security</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/defense-spending-crowding-out-development-aid-other-priorities-by-nilima-gulrajani-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than improving global security, surging military expenditure threatens to deepen geopolitical instability, destroy ecosystems, fuel arms races, raise conflict risks, and crowd out public investment in other priorities, not least development aid. It doesn't have to be this way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s Pharmaceutical Dependence on China Is a National Security Crisis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/americas-pharmaceutical-dependence-on-china-is-a-national-security-crisis/</link>
      <description>China controls a staggering portion of the United States’ pharmaceutical supply chain – and that means U.S. access to medicine can be weaponized.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Immigration Crackdown Isn't Working</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-immigration-crackdown-is-no-model-to-emulate-by-jorge-g-castaneda-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some right-wing political leaders view Donald Trump’s immigration crackdown as a model to emulate. But a closer look at the numbers confirms that, while denouncing foreigners can be politically fruitful, attempting to get rid of them is both economically costly and demonstrably futile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia Sees the Former Soviet Union as a ‘Fiefdom,’ Moldova’s Foreign Minister Says</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/russia-putin-ukraine-moldova-foreign-minister-popsoi-interview/</link>
      <description>The foreign minister also said if anyone can bring peace to the region, it’s U.S. President Donald Trump.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s ‘Low-Human-Rights’ Advantage</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinas-low-human-rights-advantage/</link>
      <description>People in the West say they must avoid a new Cold War without realizing that they are already in one – and China is winning.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story: newsletter Can anyone stop Europe’s populist right?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/12/cover-story-newsletter-can-anyone-stop-europes-populist-right</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are some types of sugar healthier than others?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/12/are-some-types-of-sugar-healthier-than-others</link>
      <description>We weigh up the options</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Diplomats Take Trump to Court Over Mass Firings</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/us-diplomats-state-department-firings-rif-trump-court-injunction-union/</link>
      <description>The U.S. Foreign Service officers union seeks an injunction to prevent nearly 250 terminations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany Loves to Hate Friedrich Merz</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/friedrich-merz-germany-chancellor-economy-ukraine-trump-america/</link>
      <description>Germany’s chancellor is doing far better than everyone seems to think.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benin’s Failed Coup and the Future of African Democracy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/benin-coup-plot-future-of-democracy-in-africa-by-kingsley-moghalu-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent explosion of coups and coup plots in West Africa, most recently in Benin, suggests that the region's performative approach to Western-style democracy is running out of steam. While democracy itself is not dead, the continent most likely is heading toward more varied forms of political organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should China Be Reassured by Trump’s National Security Strategy?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/should-china-be-reassured-by-trumps-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <description>The NSS is likely to offer China short-term relief – but cause for long-term concern.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the EU’s Blacklisting of Russia Make a Difference?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-blacklisting-russia-money-laundering-financing-terrorism-is-effective-but-painful-by-miles-kellerman-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The European Commission has finally added Russia to its list of “high-risk” third countries with strategic deficiencies in their anti-money laundering and counter-terrorist financing controls. This blunt measure will close certain loopholes while also imposing collateral damage on innocent Russians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Electric Buses Are Thriving in Europe – Despite Security and Forced Labor Concerns</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinese-electric-buses-are-thriving-in-europe-despite-security-and-forced-labor-concerns/</link>
      <description>Chinese electric bus manufacturers are using their membership in the U.N. Global Compact to deflect scrutiny from European regulators.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s 27th Amendment Upends Its Nuclear Command</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/pakistan-constitution-amendment-nuclear-weapons-military-policy/</link>
      <description>A constitutional reform throws restraint, deterrence, and regional stability into question.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Chinese Analysts Interpret Trump’s 2025 National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-chinese-analysts-interpret-trumps-2025-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <description>Far from celebrating an American retreat, Beijing’s strategists are reading the NSS as a blueprint for leaner – and potentially more dangerous – U.S. primacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Nepal’s September Uprising Transform the Ballot?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/will-nepals-september-uprising-transform-the-ballot/</link>
      <description>The elections set for March 2026 will test whether the political energy unleashed by the youth uprising can truly break free from transactional politics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump Is Unaffordable</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/affordability-crisis-frustrating-us-voters-ahead-of-2026-elections-by-desmond-lachman-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is every reason to think that US President Donald Trump will not have solved his affordability problem by the time voters head to the polls for next year's midterm elections. After all, his entire economic agenda seems designed to make things worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France and Mauritius: Strengthening Ties in the Indian Ocean</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/france-and-mauritius-strengthening-ties-in-the-indian-ocean/</link>
      <description>With major powers like China and India asserting their ambitions in the Indian Ocean, France relies on partnerships with like-minded countries, including Mauritius, to maintain its influence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omar García Harfuch, Mexico’s “Batman” with big political ambitions</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/12/omar-garcia-harfuch-mexicos-batman-with-big-political-ambitions</link>
      <description>The country’s best security minister in years must contend with drug cartels, Donald Trump and assassins’ bullets</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUKUS After AUSMIN: Why Canberra Must Read Washington Clearly</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/aukus-after-ausmin-why-canberra-must-read-washington-clearly/</link>
      <description>Washington’s political message remains supportive, but its strategic priorities no longer clearly align with the long-term demands of the partnership.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Japan’s First Woman Prime Minister Finally Tackle Violence Against Women?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/will-japans-first-woman-prime-minister-finally-tackle-violence-against-women/</link>
      <description>How Takaichi's government addresses the implementation gap for existing laws will define whether her historic appointment translates into substantive progress for women's safety.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Welfare State Saved Capitalism. Now It Can Save European Democracy.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/europe-democracy-welfare-state-spending-authoritarianism-populism/</link>
      <description>A growing skepticism of social spending risks undermining a post-war pillar of Europe’s stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starmer Acknowledges Britain’s China Problem But Overestimates the UK’s Ability to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/starmer-acknowledges-britains-china-problem-but-overestimates-the-uks-ability-to-fix-it/</link>
      <description>The real problem is not Britain’s lack of engagement with Beijing, but its shrinking leverage in a China-U.S. power dynamic that London has no power to shape.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Land Degradation and Tajikistan’s Food Security Crisis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/land-degradation-and-tajikistans-food-security-crisis/</link>
      <description>The country's small, fragmented farms and climate pressures threaten food security and economic stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USMCA Deal Comes up for Review</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/usmca-review-trump-trade-canada-mexico-tariffs/</link>
      <description>Trump has kept Canada and Mexico guessing about whether he will renew the trade agreement.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Really Changed in ‘New Uzbekistan’?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/whats-really-changed-in-new-uzbekistan/</link>
      <description>Since the 2016 death of the country’s first president, Islam Karimov, his successor, Shavkat Mirziyoyev, has strived to present himself as a reformer forging a “New Uzbekistan.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Far Right’s Gender Playbook</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/gender-politics-authoritarians-secret-weapon-by-cynthia-miller-idriss-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around the world, authoritarian leaders are weaponizing gender-based grievances to rally supporters and roll back women’s and LGBTQ+ rights. By casting feminism as a threat to “family stability” and the “moral order,” they seek to shift public sentiment toward a patriarchal, illiberal future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten Years After the Paris Agreement, Let’s Redouble Efforts</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/france-embraced-climate-leadership-since-paris-climate-agreement-by-emmanuel-macron-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is exactly a decade since 195 countries made a historic commitment to work together to keep the long-term rise in global temperatures well below 2°C above pre-industrial levels. Since then, France has fully embraced a leadership role, placing ecology at the heart of its energy, agricultural, and industrial policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An American oil blockade would devastate the Venezuelan regime</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/12/an-american-oil-blockade-would-devastate-the-venezuelan-regime</link>
      <description>The gangsters who prop up Nicolás Maduro rely heavily on money from oil exports</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan’s Uncertain Gamble for Economic Survival</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/afghanistans-uncertain-gamble-for-economic-survival/</link>
      <description>A struggling regime is caught between countervailing forces.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accountability for Nepal’s China-built Pokhara Airport Has Begun</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/accountability-for-nepals-china-built-pokhara-airport-has-begun/</link>
      <description>Nepal's anti-corruption watchdog has filed a corruption case against 55 individuals and a Chinese company in relation to the construction of the $216 million airport.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Europe Lost</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/how-europe-lost-matthijs-tocci</link>
      <description>Can the continent escape its Trump trap?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Multipolar Mirage</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/multipolar-mirage</link>
      <description>Why America and China are the world's only great powers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Prime Minister Gains Royal Approval For Dissolution of Parliament</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thai-prime-minister-gains-royal-approval-for-dissolution-of-parliament/</link>
      <description>The move, which Anutin Charnvirakul said would &quot;return power to the people,&quot; will pave the way for a snap election in late January or early February.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why North Korea is modernising its conventional arsenal</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/why-north-korea-modernising-its-conventional-arsenal</link>
      <description>Russia's war economy is fuelling Pyongyang's most ambitious military upgrade in decades.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
