<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s Greenland tariffs are no great blow to Europe</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/19/donald-trumps-greenland-tariffs-are-no-great-blow-to-europe</link>
      <description>An escalating trade war would be another matter, however</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of “America First” is in flux</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/19/the-meaning-of-america-first-is-in-flux</link>
      <description>MAGA will have to confront divisions in its approach to foreign policy</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Reports Reveal Years of Unaddressed Osprey Safety Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/reports-reveal-unaddressed-osprey-risks</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/san-diego-california-october-21-a-u-s-marine-corps-bell-boeing-v-22-osprey-tilt-rotor-aircraft-flies-at-sunset-while-traini.jpg?id=62833386&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C53%2C0%2C54&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;It is one of the most lauded defense developments in recent decades, providing preeminent capability to U.S. military personnel worldwide, but that prowess evidently comes with a steep cost that military leadership allowed to grow for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Critics have long asserted that the military failed to adequately address a mounting series of safety issues with the V-22 Osprey aircraft, even as service members died in preventable crashes. The Naval Air Systems Command&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.usni.org/2025/12/12/navy-and-gao-reports-v-22-osprey-program&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;review&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Government Accountability Office&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/12/new-gao-navy-reports-warn-serious-v-22-osprey-safety-risks-some-fixes-stretching-2030s/410150/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;report&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; paint a scathing portrait of systemic failures by the Joint Program Office overseeing V-22 variants for the Air Force, Marine Corps, and Navy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Marine Corps&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.usni.org/2025/09/16/report-to-congress-on-v-22-osprey-aircraft&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;operates&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; approximately 348 MV-22s, the Air Force 52 CV-22s, and the Navy 29 CMV-22s, with the program of record at around 464 total across services. Japan operates 17 MV-22s, with deliveries complete or near-complete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Deadly Track Record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some 30 U.S. Marines lost their lives in three&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/12/new-gao-navy-reports-warn-serious-v-22-osprey-safety-risks-some-fixes-stretching-2030s/410150/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;separate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; crashes during the testing and development phase throughout the 1990s, giving the Osprey the nickname “The Widow Maker.” Since its introduction in 2007, at least 35&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/R48703&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;servicemembers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have died in 10 fatal crashes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Initially, the V-22 suffered from Vortex Ring State, which produced crashes during development. The problem was diagnosed and remediated, and the loss rate went down dramatically,” John Pike, a leading defense, space and intelligence policy expert and Director of GlobalSecurity.org, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “Subsequent losses have been ‘normal accidents’ due to the usual mechanical and human failings.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GAO&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakingdefense.com/2025/12/gao-finds-v-22-serious-accident-rate-shot-up-in-2023-2024/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;found&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that serious Osprey mishaps in 2023 and 2024 exceeded the previous eight years and generally surpassed accident rates of other Navy and Air Force aircraft. In August 2023, three Marines died in Australia. In 2022, four U.S. soldiers were killed in a NATO training mission, and five Marines were killed in California.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unresolved Problems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NAVAIR report&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2025-12-12/navy-investigation-finds-osprey-safety-issues-were-allowed-to-grow-for-years&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;revealed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that “the cumulative risk posture of the V-22 platform has been growing since initial fielding,” and the program office “has not promptly implemented fixes.” Of 12 Class A mishaps in the past four years, seven involved parts failures already identified as major problems but not addressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Issues with hard-clutch engagement (HCE) caused the July 2022 California crash that killed five. The problem occurs when the clutch connecting the engine to the propeller gearbox slips and reengages abruptly, causing a power spike that can throw the aircraft into an uncontrolled roll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were eight Air Force servicemembers killed in the November 2023 crash off Yakushima Island when a catastrophic propeller gearbox failed due to cracks in the metal pinion gear, and the pilot continued flying despite multiple warnings, contributing to the crash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This manufacturing issue&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2025-12-12/navy-investigation-finds-osprey-safety-issues-were-allowed-to-grow-for-years&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;dates&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to 2006, but the Joint Program Office didn’t formally assess the risk until March 2024 – nearly two decades later. A NAVAIR logbook review&lt;a href=&quot;https://theaviationist.com/2025/12/14/navy-gao-v22-report/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;found&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that over 40 safety-critical components were operating beyond their airworthiness limits, and that 81 percent of ground accidents were due to human error.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Broken System: Poor Communication Between Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GAO also found that the three services don’t&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defensenews.com/air/2025/12/12/gao-services-arent-sharing-information-on-longtime-osprey-problems/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;routinely&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; share critical safety information. Aircrews haven’t met regularly to review aircraft knowledge and emergency procedures. The services&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.usni.org/2025/12/12/new-v-22-mishap-reviews-find-material-issues-with-osprey-poor-communication-between-services&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;operate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with significantly different maintenance standards, with three parallel review processes and no common source of material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GAO&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defensenews.com/air/2025/12/12/gao-services-arent-sharing-information-on-longtime-osprey-problems/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;identified&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 34 unresolved safety risks, including eight potentially catastrophic risks that have remained open for a median of 10 years. The V-22 has the oldest&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/12/new-gao-navy-reports-warn-serious-v-22-osprey-safety-risks-some-fixes-stretching-2030s/410150/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;average&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; age of unresolved catastrophic safety risks across the Navy’s aircraft inventory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixes May Take a Decade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Navy report&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2025-12-12/navy-investigation-finds-osprey-safety-issues-were-allowed-to-grow-for-years&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;indicated&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; fixes won’t be complete until 2033-2034. Officials now say the fleet won’t return to unrestricted operations&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/04/ospreys-wont-return-full-flight-operations-until-2026/404966/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;until&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2026 – a year later than planned. The V-22 program plans to upgrade gearboxes with triple-melted steel, reducing inclusions by 90 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under current restrictions, overwater flights are prohibited unless within 30 minutes of a safe landing spot, severely limiting their use by the Navy and Marine Corps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osprey's Unmatched Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Osprey still offers a game-changing advantage for U.S. troops, despite its troubled past, according to its supporters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it currently stands, the entire fleet operates under restrictions that prevent overwater flights unless within 30 minutes of a safe landing spot, significantly limiting its utility for Navy and Marine Corps missions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1979 to 1980, American hostages were taken in Iran during Operation Eagle Claw, which gave rise to the Osprey. As five of the eight Navy helicopters that arrived at Desert One were inoperable, it was clear that rapid troop movement in harsh environmental conditions was urgently needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After development began in 1985, the Osprey entered service in 2007, replacing the Vietnam-era CH-46 Sea Knight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to fixed-wing transports, the Osprey can land troops just where they are needed. Airdrops with parachutes tend to scatter paratroops all over the place; see ‘Saving Private Ryan,’” Pike explained. “And compared with other rotary wing aircraft, the Osprey is much faster and has a much longer range.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Osprey shifts from helicopter to airplane mode in under 12 seconds, reaches speeds of 315 mph, has an operational range of 580 miles, and carries 10,000 pounds – or 24 troops. It’s used for missions ranging from combat operations to the occasional transport of White House staff. During a dust storm in Afghanistan in 2010, two CV-22 helicopters rescued 32 soldiers in under four hours from a distance of 800 miles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic Readiness Problems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet these performance advantages have been undercut by persistent readiness shortfalls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NAVAIR report&lt;a href=&quot;https://theaircurrent.com/aviation-safety/v-22-ospreys-safety-risks-navair-review-confirms/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;noted&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that mission-capable rates between 2020 and 2024 averaged just 50 percent for the Navy and Air Force, and 60 percent for Marines. The Osprey&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.militarytimes.com/news/your-military/2025/12/12/v-22-osprey-at-risk-of-more-catastrophic-mishaps-navy-review-finds/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;requires&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 100 percent more unscheduled maintenance than the Navy averages and 22 maintenance man-hours per flight hour versus 12 for other aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Boeing settled a whistleblower lawsuit in 2023 for $8.1 million after employees accused the company of falsifying records for composite part testing. Boeing, in its defense,&lt;a href=&quot;https://halifax.citynews.ca/2023/12/07/ospreys-had-safety-issues-long-before-they-were-grounded-a-look-at-the-aircrafts-history/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;claimed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the parts were “non-critical” and did not impact flight safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conflicting Views on Safety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Osprey does not have a troubled safety record. Per a recent press release, the V-22 mishap rate per 100,000 flight hours is 3.28, which is in line with helicopters with similar missions.” a government source who works closely with the Osprey fleet but is not authorized to speak on the record contended to &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “Like anything measured statistically, there are periods above and below the mean. Just because humans tend to conclude because of apparent clusters doesn’t necessarily mean there is a pattern or connection – think of how some people say that ‘celebrities die in threes.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The source vowed that “the design issues, such as certain electrical wiring rubbing against hydraulic and oil lines, were fixed before fleet introduction.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The problems with the test plan were a product of pressure applied to accelerate a delayed and overbudget program and were not repeated when the aircraft was reintroduced,” the insider pointed out. “Those mishaps, combined with the distinctive nature of the V-22, mean that any subsequent incident, major or minor, is always viewed as part of the ‘dangerous V-22’ narrative. A U.S. Army Blackhawk crash in November killed five but barely made the news. A Japanese Blackhawk crash killed ten soldiers in April, but the Japanese didn’t ground their Blackhawks.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That perception, however, has done little to quiet families who argue that known risks went unaddressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amber Sax’s husband, Marine Corps Capt. John J. Sax died in the 2022 California crash caused by hard clutch engagement, a problem the Marine Corps had known about for over a decade. “Their findings confirm what we already know: More needs to be done, and more needs to be done,” Sax&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/12/new-gao-navy-reports-warn-serious-v-22-osprey-safety-risks-some-fixes-stretching-2030s/410150/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s clear in the report that these risks were not properly assessed, and that failure cost my husband his life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An Uncertain Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the military confronts those findings, the future of the Osprey fleet is not completely clear. In 2018, the Marine Corps Aviation proposal&lt;a href=&quot;https://nationalinterest.org/blog/buzz/marine-corps-fly-osprey-2060-prep-aircraft-future-wars-31517&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;outlined&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a sustainability plan for the Osprey to at least 2060.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The quality of maintenance training curricula, maturation, and standardization has not kept pace with readiness requirements,” the report&lt;a href=&quot;https://nationalinterest.org/blog/buzz/marine-corps-fly-osprey-2060-prep-aircraft-future-wars-31517&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;stated&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “Current maintenance manning levels are unable to support demands for labor. The current V-22 sustainment system cannot realize improved and sustained aircraft readiness and availability without significant change. Depot-level maintenance cannot keep up with demand.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite extensive recommendations – NAVAIR&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakingdefense.com/2025/12/gao-finds-v-22-serious-accident-rate-shot-up-in-2023-2024/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;underscored&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 32 actions to improve safety – Vice Adm. John Dougherty reaffirmed commitment to the aircraft. Pike believes it’s a matter of when, not if, the Osprey returns to full operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Once the issues are fixed, everyone will resume their regular programming,” he asserted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials and insiders alike expect that process to translate into tangible fixes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I would expect that to lead to some type of corrective action, whether it’s a new procedure or replacing a defective part,” the insider added. “After that, I would expect a long career for the aircraft in the Marine Corps, Navy, and Air Force, as it’s an irreplaceable part of all three services now and gives a unique capability to the American military.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether that optimism proves warranted depends on whether military leadership finally addresses the systemic failures the latest reports have laid bare – failures that cost 20 service members their lives in just the past five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Iran’s massacres, tensions grow inside the regime</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/19/after-irans-massacres-tensions-grow-inside-the-regime</link>
      <description>The country and some of its rulers are unsettled by mounting evidence of an immensely bloody crackdown</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History Marches Past Davos</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/world-economic-forum-touts-dialogue-denies-reality-by-mariana-mazzucato-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Economic Forum meeting in Davos will feature the usual pledges about stakeholder capitalism, purpose-driven business, and sustainable development. But without binding conditionalities, accountability frameworks, and risk-sharing that distinguish genuine value creators from rent extractors, it remains theater.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is There Life After the Dollar?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/limits-of-dollar-exorbitant-privilege-in-a-fracturing-world-by-paola-subacchi-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Global financial stability has long depended on the dollar’s role as the main reserve currency, with the expectation that the United States would both set the rules and uphold them. As American leadership grows more erratic, that dependence has become a vulnerability, underscoring the need for a multicurrency system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi Jinping is carrying Deng Xiaoping’s authoritarian torch in China</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/19/xi-jinping-is-carrying-deng-xiaopings-authoritarian-torch-in-china</link>
      <description>Many see China’s leader as a counter-reformer. But he is really an heir</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi Jinping is carrying Deng Xiaoping’s authoritarian torch</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/19/xi-jinping-is-carrying-deng-xiaopings-authoritarian-torch</link>
      <description>Many see China’s leader as a counter-reformer. But he is really an heir</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superintelligence Is Not the Answer to Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-superintelligence-will-not-solve-climate-crisis-once-tipping-points-crossed-by-alex-friedman-1-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tech evangelists view climate change as an information problem that the arrival of AI superintelligence will solve, rather than a willpower problem that requires concrete measures, like modernizing the electrical grid and implementing a carbon tax. But there can be no miracle fix once critical planetary tipping points are crossed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Serving US Imperialism Raw</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-american-imperialism-unmasked-by-adekeye-adebajo-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While previous instances of American gunboat diplomacy often paid lip service to human rights or democracy, Donald Trump has dispensed with idealistic justifications for military intervention abroad. Everyone, not least Europe, now confronts behavior that was already familiar to many across the Global South.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China hits its GDP target—in a weird way</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/19/china-hits-its-gdp-target-in-a-weird-way</link>
      <description>Strong exports make up for weak investment</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of a teenager with an ultra-rare condition is a medical milestone</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/19/treatment-of-a-teenager-with-an-ultra-rare-condition-is-a-medical-milestone</link>
      <description>It will change regulators’ rule books</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s popular new prime minister gambles on a snap election</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/19/japans-popular-new-prime-minister-gambles-on-a-snap-election</link>
      <description>Will her high approval ratings benefit her tarnished party?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain Must Lead the Pushback Against Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/uk-keir-starmer-must-use-good-ties-with-trump-to-defend-nato-greenland-by-william-r-rhodes-and-stuart-p-m-mackintosh-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To ensure that Greenland remains a territory of Denmark, British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and other European leaders must put pressure on NATO’s most powerful member. Given the US president’s love of royalty, one way to do that would be to organize a public meeting between British King Charles III and Danish King Frederik X.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Trump’s recklessness imperils Europe—and the West</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/19/the-war-room-newsletter-trumps-recklessness-imperils-europe-and-the-west</link>
      <description>The American president’s pursuit of Greenland is “fraught with danger”, Shashank Joshi writes</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Popular music is getting sadder and angstier</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/19/popular-music-is-getting-sadder-and-angstier</link>
      <description>Analyses of top-charting songs find a rise in blue moods</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines Are in for a Turbulent 2026</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/19/philippines-asean-southeast-asia-china-us-trump-tariffs-security-south-china-sea-myanmar/</link>
      <description>Manila takes over the ASEAN chair in what could be a make-or-break year for the bloc.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Failed Chinese Invasion of Taiwan Would Be Disastrous for Xi Jinping</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/19/china-taiwan-invasion-failed-xi-disaster/</link>
      <description>Beijing’s saber-rattling conceals the real possibility of a loss.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s Drift Toward Constitutional Authoritarianism</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/19/americas-drift-toward-constitutional-authoritarianism/</link>
      <description>Trump has shown how democracy can be neutralized without being destroyed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ‘Donroe Doctrine’ Is a Roosevelt Redux</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/19/us-venezuela-maduro-raid-history-trump-roosevelt-monroe/</link>
      <description>Then as now, big stick diplomacy will lead to costly cycles of intervention and retrenchment.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Spheres of Influence Are—and Aren’t</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/19/sphere-influence-trump-venezuela-donroe-doctrine/</link>
      <description>One of the most misunderstood concepts of international politics is back with a force.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awami League Supporters Could Boost BNP’s Chances in Bangladesh’s General Elections</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/awami-league-supporters-could-boost-bnps-chances-in-bangladeshs-general-elections/</link>
      <description>Sheikh Hasina’s party is not contesting the elections. Will its supporters back the BNP to push it across the finish line?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/world/after-paris</link>
      <description>Environmental policy in an interdependent world.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How America Can Stop Getting Played by China</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/how-america-can-stop-getting-played-china</link>
      <description>Breaking Beijing’s hold on the global economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's Crypto Gamble</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/trumps-crypto-gamble</link>
      <description>A stablecoin could preserve dollar dominance—or shatter it.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippine President Announces Discovery of Major Natural Gas Field</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/philippine-president-announces-discovery-of-major-natural-gas-field/</link>
      <description>The discovery, the first in more than a decade, will support the government's attempts to wean itself off coal-powered electricity generation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jammu College Closure Reflects Continued Shrinking of Academic Freedom in India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/jammu-college-closure-reflects-continued-shrinking-of-academic-freedom-in-india/</link>
      <description>Muslims dominated the admission list of the inaugural cohort of the medical college. That irked Hindutva groups, who forced the college’s shutdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Expectations Facing Vietnam’s New Leadership</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-expectations-facing-vietnams-new-leadership/</link>
      <description>Whatever the outcome of this week's 14th National Congress, the Communist Party will face the challenge of turning its resolutions into material progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Does it End? The Iranian Regime</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/how-does-it-end-iranian-regime</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Iranian regime has no answers to the country’s problems and there will eventually be change. But this may not happen quickly or neatly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Iran at a Tipping Point? Protest, Military Escalation and Regime Survival</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/iran-tipping-point-protest-military-escalation-and-regime-survival</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Protests in Iran add to an uncertainty over the fate of the Iranian regime, that is felt within the country and the region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Growth of China’s Navy: Past, Present, and Future</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-growth-of-chinas-navy-past-present-and-future/</link>
      <description>A review of major developments in the PLAN over the past 5 years – and where the fleet is likely to go from here.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
