<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>For the first time, climate models show the 1.5°C goal is dead</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/11/04/for-the-first-time-climate-models-show-the-15c-goal-is-dead</link>
      <description>Governments have failed to limit global warming. What comes next?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Are China’s Nuclear Ambitions?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/china-trump-nuclear-weapons-testing-arsenal/</link>
      <description>Trump’s testing plans revive scrutiny of Beijing’s growing arsenal.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 22:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fall of El Fasher Marks Another Dark Turn in Sudan’s Civil War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/sudan-el-fasher-rsf-famine-killings-sexual-violence-guterres/</link>
      <description>Under Rapid Support Forces control, civilians face summary execution, sexual violence, and famine, experts say.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 21:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The art of Australia’s straight-talking diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/art-australia-s-straight-talking-diplomacy</link>
      <description>A foreign service known for being informal and egalitarian has worked a treat for Canberra’s envoys. But does it reward boldness?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 21:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI’s Rapacious Appetite for Electricity Can Accelerate Clean Energy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/ai-tech-clean-energy-decarbonization-nuclear-power-fusion-solar-climate/</link>
      <description>Why Big Tech’s energy problem might prove crucial to fighting climate change.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 21:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China places a Hong Kong-sized bet on Western decline</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/11/04/china-places-a-hong-kong-sized-bet-on-western-decline</link>
      <description>The territory aims to prove that a non-free society can be a global financial hub</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First, grinning Labubu dolls. Now, a TV show and theme parks</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/11/04/first-grinning-labubu-dolls-now-a-tv-show-and-theme-parks</link>
      <description>Pop Mart, maker of the wildly popular toys, wants to be China’s Disney</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the sheriff of St Louis ended up in jail</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/11/04/how-the-sheriff-of-st-louis-ended-up-in-jail</link>
      <description>And what it says about Democratic cities in Republican states</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30’s Dangerous Omission</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/cop30-climate-united-nations-conference-brazil-hunger-conflict/</link>
      <description>Brazil’s people-centered climate vision risks abandoning the most vulnerable.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Does Trump Think Nuclear Testing Is?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/trump-nuclear-testing-treaties-china-russia/</link>
      <description>A vague statement opens a range of expensive possibilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Beijing Views Trump</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/how-beijing-views-trump/</link>
      <description>A top China scholar and former Biden administration advisor on the Trump-Xi meeting and the future of the U.S.-China relationship.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Africa newsletter: Donald Trump is focusing on the wrong atrocities</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/11/04/analysing-africa-newsletter-donald-trump-is-focusing-on-the-wrong-atrocities</link>
      <description>If only the president would turn his gaze to Sudan, says John McDermott, our chief Africa correspondent</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could the Financial Action Task Force Save U.N. Sanctions?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/financial-action-task-force-un-sanctions-russia-iran-north-korea/</link>
      <description>As a more technical body, the task force might be able to fill the gap left by Security Council paralysis.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Hurricane Melissa’s Wake, Trump’s Foreign Aid Cuts Face Critical Moment</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/hurricane-melissa-jamaica-trump-aid-cuts-humanitarian-response/</link>
      <description>The storm’s devastation is a key test of the United States’ reduced humanitarian response abilities.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ireland’s Next President Will Assume the Progressive Mantle</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/ireland-president-catherine-connolly-progressive-anti-war/</link>
      <description>Anti-war candidate Catherine Connolly’s victory is the country’s latest rebuke to the global right-wing populist wave.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s New U.S. Ambassador Previews Her Pragmatic Approach to Washington</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/ukraine-new-us-ambassador-olha-stefanishyna-russia-war-trump/</link>
      <description>“I am Ukrainian, right? I’m not a Democrat or Republican.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan to Introduce Visa-Free Entry for US Citizens From January 1</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/uzbekistan-to-introduce-visa-free-entry-for-us-citizens-from-january-1/</link>
      <description>Meanwhile, Uzbek citizens face one of the highest visa-refusal rates in the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Many More Cloud Scares Does Europe Need?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/aws-azure-outages-highlight-threat-us-cloud-dominance-poses-to-europe-by-robin-berjon-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three US companies – Amazon, Google, and Microsoft – now control over 60% of the global cloud market, implying major economic and security risks for Europe. Dismantling these monopolies in the European market, and building sovereign digital infrastructure, is not just possible, but essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Donald Trump can dodge a Supreme Court tariff block</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/11/04/how-donald-trump-can-dodge-a-supreme-court-tariff-block</link>
      <description>No matter the ruling, the president has back-up powers</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fraught Politics of Corporate Disclosures</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/anti-esg-politics-misses-the-point-material-information-by-raghuram-g-rajan-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US Securities and Exchange Commission must recognize that a wide variety of interests look at corporate financial disclosures, and that the effects of such information can be material in a variety of ways. To reject environmental, social, and governance concerns as political is itself an example of politicization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An EU-Mercosur trade deal looks close to ratification</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/11/04/an-eu-mercosur-trade-deal-looks-close-to-ratification</link>
      <description>In a hostile world, Europe and Latin America draw closer</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s New Government Boasts High Approval Ratings</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/japans-new-government-boasts-high-approval-ratings/</link>
      <description>New Prime Minister Takaichi enjoys far more support than her immediate predecessors in the early stages of their terms.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India, US Seek to Stabilize Relations By Renewing Defense Pact</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/india-us-seek-to-stabilize-relations-by-renewing-defense-pact/</link>
      <description>New Delhi’s strategy for now seems to be to manage the relationship with the U.S., which till recently was deemed as vital to counter China.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Tryst With Strategic Experimentation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/indias-tryst-with-strategic-experimentation/</link>
      <description>For India, progress has often begun as a gamble. Appetite for experimentation could be its key strategic asset.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Fiber-Optic Cables: Securing Seabed Before the Next Crisis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/beyond-fiber-optic-cables-securing-seabed-before-the-next-crisis/</link>
      <description>Communications cables are only part of the story. A far broader array of systems now covers the ocean floor – and must be protected.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Chinese Leaders Really Think of Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinese-view-of-trump-world-disorder-by-mark-leonard-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to Chinese academics, economists, and retired military officers, the country's leaders are not losing any sleep over Donald Trump's America First agenda. In fact, as they see it, the US president is ushering in a world that Chinese strategists have long been preparing for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia Must Stop Enabling Iran’s Sanctions Evasion</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/malaysia-must-stop-enabling-irans-sanctions-evasion/</link>
      <description>The waters off Malaysia have been the site of more than 500 illicit ship-to-ship transfers involving Iranian oil since the start of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Tech Firms Are Bound by China’s Rising Techno-Nationalism</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/us-tech-firms-are-bound-by-chinas-rising-techno-nationalism/</link>
      <description>As Beijing feeds growing suspicion of U.S. technology products, an expanded move away from American tech could be incoming.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US &amp; Central Asia: What Is the C5+1?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/us-central-asia-what-is-the-c51/</link>
      <description>On November 6, 2025, the Central Asian presidents will gather in Washington DC. The summit will be the crowning achievement for a decade-old format.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dick Cheney’s Legacy: One of the Worst Strategic Failures in U.S. History</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/dick-cheney-obituary-legacy-iraq-war-bush-torture-9-11/</link>
      <description>The former U.S. vice president set out to strengthen the power of the presidency and the country but ultimately undermined both.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolia’s Defector Dilemma: Navigating the Korea Divide</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/mongolias-defector-dilemma-navigating-the-korea-divide/</link>
      <description>Mongolia's bid to remain a neutral bridge between North and South Korea must find a way to balance idealism and pragmatism.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith and the Moral Economy We Have Lost</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/adam-smith-proper-economics-presupposes-moral-commitments-by-antara-haldar-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adam Smith favored neither state socialism nor unbridled markets, but something subtler: a moral economy grounded in sympathy and the pursuit of human flourishing. In a world where markets look increasingly unmoored from ethics, we could do worse than to revisit what the &quot;founding father&quot; of economics actually wrote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the Opposition End the 20 Years of BJP-JD(U) Rule in India’s Bihar?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/can-the-opposition-end-the-20-years-of-bjp-jdu-rule-in-indias-bihar/</link>
      <description>Bihar has traditionally seen bipolar election contests. With the entry of the Jan Suraaj party, the contest is triangular this time.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Can Europe Offer a Fragmenting World?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-update-value-proposition-to-bolster-global-standing-by-ngaire-woods-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the rivalry between the United States and China intensifies, many countries are seeking partners they can trust. The European Union could fill that role by offering economic opportunity, a secure investment environment, and legal systems that are predictable and fair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the Developing World Weather the Next Financial Crisis?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/developing-countries-could-be-hit-hardest-by-future-financial-crisis-by-jayati-ghosh-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As asset prices soar and speculative money floods into risky markets, the global financial system is slipping back into perilous territory. When the inevitable correction arrives, the fallout will spread far beyond the United States and Europe, hitting developing economies already weighed down by debt and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza ceasefire moves forward</title>
      <link>https://www.eiu.com/n/blogs/middle-east-2026-outlook/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The peace plan of the US president, Donald Trump, designed&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiu.com/n/blogs/middle-east-2026-outlook/&quot;&gt;Gaza ceasefire moves forward&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiu.com/n&quot;&gt;Economist Intelligence Unit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 09:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s Generals Are Marching Toward Another Disaster</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/pakistans-generals-are-marching-toward-another-disaster/</link>
      <description>The military’s approach reflects a familiar pattern: engaging in external aggression to mask internal decay and disarray.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 09:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Through the Tempest: The Philippines’ Defense Posture in Troubled Waters</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/through-the-tempest-the-philippines-defense-posture-in-troubled-waters/</link>
      <description>Domestic challenges threaten to derail the military's efforts to upgrade its capabilities and reorient itself toward new strategic priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Belt and Road Railway to Nowhere</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/04/indonesia-high-speed-rail-china-belt-road/</link>
      <description>For a while, it looked as if China had learned its lesson on scaling back investments.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Multipolarity Work</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/making-multipolarity-work</link>
      <description>How America should navigate a new global order.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Can Keep the Indo-Pacific Open and Free</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/japan/japan-can-keep-indo-pacific-open-and-free</link>
      <description>With America stepping back, Tokyo should step up.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Sanae Takaichi, “Japan is back” is back</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/sanae-takaichi-japan-back-back</link>
      <description>Coalition politics, tax resistance and ambitious defence spending goals will require the new PM to strike a fine balance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippine, UAE Have Applied for CPTPP Membership, Report Claims</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/philippine-uae-have-applied-for-cptpp-membership-report-claims/</link>
      <description>The 12-nation trade pact is attracting prospective members eager to preserve the current global multilateral trading regime.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond AUKUS: The maritime strategy Australia needs</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/beyond-aukus-maritime-strategy-australia-needs</link>
      <description>Consolidating maritime departments, and coordination across defence, civil and industry is where the wins will be made.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 01:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Strategic Costs of U.S. Exchange Program Cuts in Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/the-strategic-costs-of-u-s-exchange-program-cuts-in-southeast-asia/</link>
      <description>Such programs are a cost-effective and proven form of partnership-building. Their loss will undermine U.S. influence in a crucial region of the Indo-Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippines, Canada Sign Visiting Forces Agreement Amid South China Sea Tensions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/philippines-canada-sign-visiting-forces-agreement-amid-south-china-sea-tensions/</link>
      <description>The agreement is the fifth that Manila has signed, after similar deals with the United States, Australia, Japan, and New Zealand.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timor-Leste: to join the ASEAN neighbourhood, start with the house next door</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/timor-leste-join-asean-neighbourhood-start-house-next-door</link>
      <description>Indonesia could make ASEAN membership meaningful for Timor-Leste by opening up ferries and flights from Kupang.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 23:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
