<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Widespread Repression, Intimidation Mar Uganda’s Presidential Election</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/uganda-presidential-election-yoweri-museveni-bobi-wine-internet-blackouts/</link>
      <description>Rights groups denounce internet blackouts, violent clashes, and arbitrary arrests by security forces.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Crown Prince Has Become Indispensable</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/iran-crown-prince-reza-pahlavi-protests/</link>
      <description>How Reza Pahlavi went from teenaged exile to symbol of his country’s future.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 21:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Troubled Is the Iranian Economy?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/iran-protests-economy/</link>
      <description>A plunge in exchange rates triggered the huge protests.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Long History of Betrayal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/trump-iran-protests-intervention-kurds-nixon-kissinger-hungary/</link>
      <description>Why Washington keeps encouraging foreign uprisings—and then walking away.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/foreign-policy-news-quiz-federal-reserve-trump-ukraine-russia-uganda/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Jan. 10: Trump threatens the U.S. Fed’s independence, Russia strikes Ukraine, and Uganda cuts internet access.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 20:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela on Screen</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/venezuela-movies-nicolas-maduro-donald-trump-documentary-biopic-review-simon-bolivar-films/</link>
      <description>From a contemplative documentary to a swashbuckling biopic, these films lend a sense of humanity to the present crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Country’s First ‘Cognitive Advantage’ Chief: Influence Is the New Battlefield</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-countrys-first-cognitive-advantage-chief-influence-is-the-new-battlefield</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/washington-dc-united-states-december-1-an-exterior-view-of-the-white-house-in-washington-dc-united-states-on-december-1-2.jpg?id=62826168&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C68%2C0%2C69&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEEKEND INTERVIEW — &lt;/strong&gt;In an era when foreign adversaries can shape public sentiment with a well-timed meme and a handful of AI-driven accounts, the U.S. government is racing to redefine what national power looks like in the information age.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the center of that effort is Shawn Chenoweth, the country’s first Director of Cognitive Advantage - a role designed to help the United States compete in the domain where modern influence, persuasion, and political outcomes are increasingly decided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What, exactly, does a Director of Cognitive Advantage do? It’s not a title most Americans encounter, and it sits far outside the familiar contours of diplomacy, military force, or economic leverage. But as Chenoweth explains, the contest for influence no longer stays neatly within those lanes either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His focus is often on the gray space - where information, perception, culture, and behavior collide, and where adversaries like China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea are operating with staggering resources and strategic focus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this &lt;em&gt;Cipher Brief &lt;/em&gt;conversation, Chenoweth breaks down how cognitive operations actually work, why the U.S. has struggled to keep pace, and what it means to give the President an “information option” that’s not simply kinetic or economic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He offers rare, candid insight into how technology, AI, and social platforms—from TikTok to algorithmically driven personas—are reshaping the battlespace faster than policymakers can write doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our conversation is a deep dive into one of the least understood - but perhaps most consequential - fronts of modern national security. &lt;em&gt;Our conversation has been lightly edited for length and clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shawn Chenoweth&lt;/strong&gt;, Director of Cognitive Advantage, National Security Council&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE INTERVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: How do you explain the role of the director of Cognitive Advantage?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;When you look at traditional elements of military power, you probably think of the DIME construct&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It's not a perfect construct, but it's pretty good. DIME, is broken down into Diplomatic, Information, Military and Economic, and it's very clear who owns the Diplomatic, Military, and Economic components. But there hasn't been, at least in several decades, a good example of where people have really come to the president and the administration with an &quot;I&quot; option, for Information. And it's a shame because when you actually look at the DIME construct, you don't want to break it into stove pipes. We should think of it as a cell. Each of those elements acts as part of a functioning cell, and removing any of those elements means you have an imperfect or failing cell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I was asked to help put the &quot;I&quot; back in DIME so that we can provide additional options and advantages across the other elements of DIME to national power and provide the president with opportunities to accomplish the Administration’s objectives that aren't just warheads on foreheads or threatening economics or expending political leverage. We can enhance those things, but we can also gain advantages by using cognitive effects through the information environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: Let’s set the stage a bit further. If you were to explain to the average American what is happening in terms of cognitive warfare in the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-can-the-u-s-better-manage-the-gray-zone&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;gray zone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; – the area where conflict occurs below the level of warfare - how would you describe it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I think if you look through your military histories, philosophers, politicians, political science, it's all pretty clear. You can pick out the elements. They all have one underlying thread, which is that political victory is the one that matters at its core. That's really what we're talking about. Nothing's changed. How human beings are connected, how technology is affected has certainly changed. But what we really care about is what people do in the real world and the geophysical world, the world we live in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the point of a cognitive advantage is to leverage that so that human beings are taking behaviors favorable to outcomes, to national objectives, which most of the time are also - in the case of the United States - favorable in their own right. So it's core. And that is what we're driving to get: those advantages in what people do in the real world through their sensing, to make decisions that come back to the real world and have the effects that you want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: Can you give an example of what that would look like?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Let's say you're negotiating for a piece of land or a base that you need for overflight intel collection. You're going to conduct a trade-off in negotiations. Maybe it's going to look like, - if you pay more, you'll get more - based off what the value proposition is. But very rarely is it that blatant and simple. So, what you want to be able to do is understand, what advantage would we need in the negotiation? What's actually driving this other party other than maybe just cost or just danger? What’s the risk calculus?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are cultural nuances that affect things: their understanding of influence, political implications. So, the point would be to understand why they would be interested in this in the first place? What advantage does it give them? What are the cultural nuances? Why wouldn't they do this in the first place? Why aren't they taking this action and what can we do to make sure that the outcome is what we want?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are other areas where that applies across the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's say we're conducting counter-terrorism operations, and we know an objective tends to use a particular cafe. Well, what if they were using a different one that day? What can we do to influence them to go to a place that's more favorable for options to decrease our own risk calculus, either because we want to conduct a kinetic strike or make an arrest? Maybe we can't find them. So, what if we use that for our intel collection and our methods to basically make them come up on comms and change their behavior so it's easier to find them, collect on them, and build the data so that we can conduct physical actions to stop or disrupt them? And you can kind of see how that applies across the board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you know more than the person you're dealing with, chances are that you're going to be better at accomplishing your outcome. It’s very similar with the werewolf theory. It's a game where two people are chosen to be the werewolf of the village and everyone else in the group doesn't know who the werewolf is. Most of the time the people who are the werewolves win the game because they have an information advantage over everyone else playing the game. So, it's a human norm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And again, I point out that nothing's new under the sun. It's just that we haven't really thought through the implications of what it means in the information age that we live in - where everyone is connected through software defined radios. We're a long way away from direct sensing where it's communication and things happening in the real world. Now we have sort of indirect sensing where you're fed data feeds and everything else. We can affect cognitive behavior in ways we never imagined, and we really haven't thought through just as we can reach people and sell items. And if I want to find a person whose favorite color is red, who's a military age male who's really into Magnum PI, I can find that person thanks to their radio, and I can craft messages specifically for someone who fits that demographic and move them in a particular direction. That's the first time in history that that's been the case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: You have a background that combines both government and private sector experience. Given that technology is being rapidly developed in the private sector, how do you think that background gives you an advantage in this role?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of people who've served in the military and have been contractors but just by happenstance, I happen to have been in a lot of critical locations at critical times. I think one of the advantages that has brought me is that I saw the frustration within the military when the contracting apparatus didn't work. I was also empowered by industry to go and fix a lot of those structures and enable the government to do it, and now I'm getting afforded the opportunity to work on policy to make the system really hum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the advantage with that is that when it comes to the information space, there's no control. And I try to emphasize this to any policy maker or power broker or decision maker that I can find. You can put an armored brigade in an intersection - fully equipped, fully supported – and a U.S. Armored Brigade could own that intersection. There are things you can control. But when it comes to the information space, there is no control. It is constantly shifting, constantly changing. You have a binary decision. You are either going to participate, preferably at a level that matters, or not, and whatever's going to happen is going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, you could find yourself in an advantageous information space in the morning, lose it by the late morning, get a stalemate in the afternoon, and win it back in the afternoon – just to lose it again at the end of the day. And when you wake up the next morning, you're going to have to do it all over again. There is no, &quot;We have information dominance and we're done and we can crack our beers and go on with other things.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's not how this works because every day new information is being injected into the system. People are changing and developing new opinions. Things are occurring and people are going to react to those things, change their opinions, adapt, age out, age in, so those cultural references may change. It's a constant flux. One of the things that from the U.S. government side we're getting our head around is that we need an information carrier group constantly operating afloat in the information environment, effectively. One that’s engaged 24/7 to affect these changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is partnering with the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Information Professionals Association and the National Center for Narrative Intelligence to bring you Pinnacle 2026: Gray Zone Convergence: Cognitive Security at the Intersection of Influence, Innovation, and Shared Interests. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://information-professionals.us6.list-manage.com/track/click?u=2044c7e92c443c50b2129bd22&amp;amp;id=61b2b7f847&amp;amp;e=f8392d200d&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;https://information-professionals.us6.list-manage.com/track/click?u=2044c7e92c443c50b2129bd22&amp;amp;id=61b2b7f847&amp;amp;e=f8392d200d&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Register for the February 9-10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; conference now to secure your spot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: It's not just the United States that has gotten pretty good at understanding the impact of cognitive advantage. We see these tactics from China and Russia being used with stunning success. In this role, how focused are you on their activities when it comes to doing the exact same thing that you're tasked with doing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;They absolutely practice these activities. I call them the ‘CRINKETT’. Every challenge we're generally dealing with falls in the CRINKETTS. It's China, Russia, Iran, North Korea, Terrorists and Trans[national] criminals. And particularly for the nation states, this is exactly how they want to compete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From their perspective, there are two ways to deal with the United States: asymmetrically and stupidly, largely because of our economic and military power. They get that. They're not interested in a kinetic fight; that is an awful prospect. So the way they want to do this is in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/gray-zone-warfare&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;gray zone activities&lt;/a&gt;, in the information space, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/21st-century-cognitive-advantage&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;cognitive domain&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And they outspend us. I'm not going to say necessarily outperform, but I'll say if you want to compete at a level that matters, they outspend us, period. Iran probably spends around $1.8 billion plus-minus a year, maybe more with their proxies and everything else they do in this particular space. Russia - post Ukraine invasion, spends about $2.6 billion, something like that. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-gray-zone-war&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; - 48 plus billion dollars a year. The U.S., if I take all of the activities from the DoD, the State Department and everything else, and you put those together, you might approach $1.2 billion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It doesn't mean we're executing those funds either. It just means that that's what we've allocated. When you think about how we outspend to have an advantage on the other parts of DIME, we're hideously underperforming here. And again, all props to the administration. They're acutely aware of this and the support I've had at the National Security Council and across the elements of government - the departments and agencies - has been stellar. And we're going to continue to work on this and get it right because we have three and a half more years of President Trump's administration to get this right, do the reps and sets, and make this a durable policy so that the American people can start enjoying those benefits that come when we're really focused on this space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: What does success look like for you in this role and how do you measure it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Measurement has always been a funny thing. People will constantly tell me how hard it is to measure these activities. And what I’ve found time and time again is that we're actually pretty good at these activities. The issues with the measurements are, again, participating at a scale that matters. We need to measure behavior change, and in order to do that, we need to have clear objectives. What are we after?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The big part of that is who is the target audience that has the agency to do the thing we want? We spend a lot of time making plans and CONOPS [Concept of Operations] on sub-target audiences that don't actually have the agency – in hopes that they affect agency - and that's perfectly fine. But why are we doing assessments against this? We spend a lot of time and money generating assessments to target audiences that don't have the agency you want. So, let's focus on the target audience that has the agency and let's do this at scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example; I'm in the DC area and I can go down to the Potomac River, drop a bucket of water in the river, and I have objectively molecularly increased the amount of water in the Potomac. There isn't a sensor on this planet that is going to detect that molecular change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact is that you might be having an effect, but you don't have a sensor that is going to pick that up. So, you need to increase your scale or customize your sensing system to the effect you're having. That tends to be where the assessments fall apart. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard all the time for decades now that assessments are so hard. I don't find that to be true. What I find is that you've sacrificed assessments for effect, which is fine. It's risk calculus. If I had a low amount of resources and I decided to put as much into the effect I've wanted, that's fine. But at the end of the day, you're looking for the real behavior change in the targeted audience that matters. What are the sensors you have on that and what are you doing to collect that data: public opinion, research surveys, building the networks. We're going to see this exacerbate further as the AI revolution continues at pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: How is technology impacting what you're trying to do, your mission, and then how are you also working with the private sector because the private sector is controlling so much of the technology and the innovation that the government needs to work with. So how are you doing that?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;One of the challenges I see emerging from AI is that there's sort of an assumption that AI will fix all your woes. I've seen the best tools out there do one thing: they model the data they have, and that's the core issue. We don't have the data. So again, I'm back to there's not a whole lot of new things under the sun. And the AI models are really good, and it can allow you to find new insights from the data that you have, but new data needs to be created. So, sacrificing collection methodologies and new approaches to gather the data at the foot of a model is terrible. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AI snake oil salesman I would deal with in industry all the time would come in and say, ‘&lt;em&gt;Oh, you're interested in that? I could absolutely model you the thing&lt;/em&gt;.’ Cool. How does that work? &lt;em&gt;‘Well, all you have to do is provide me the data and we'll put all this together and give you the insights.&lt;/em&gt;’ I'm like, &lt;em&gt;whoa&lt;/em&gt;. We don't have the data either. No one has the data. That's kind of the problem. So, let's be honest about what we're doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI is going to be a great boon for industry and for the government and everyone else under the sun. It's going to obviously have impact, but I think as that moves forward, we need to start looking at how we actually employ it. Building an agent or a token for every worker so that they're augmented by an AI that does the thing that they themselves may not be good at or saving them time is going to be amazing, but it needs to be undergirded by being able to detect what's actually happening out in the real world. And those two things are not necessarily - not interrelated. As I said, most things are kind of a whole cell that operate in one unit, and we can't necessarily bifurcate these things and then expect good outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Former Senior CIA Executive Dave Pitts wrote a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-can-the-u-s-better-manage-the-gray-zone&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;three-part series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; exclusively for The Cipher Brief on what the U.S. can do to become more competitive in the Gray Zone. Subscriber+Members can read it here. Need access? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We can help with that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: So you have a mission that is difficult to measure, is hugely impactful, adversaries are using it as well against American citizens effectively, and in some cases, those adversaires are dedicating a lot more resources to this. If you could explaine to the average U.S. citizen how they might be targeted by cognitive operations that are conducted by U.S. adversaries, what would you tell them to look for?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;You need to be mindful of sources obviously. When I look at the construct of how we approach cognitive warfare, I think one of the biggest problems I've had for at least the last 10 years has been the construct of dis- and misinformation. My issue isn't the dis- and misinformation construct. It's the overuse of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disinformation and misinformation are things. They have meaning. But they mean something that is true and people use it for things that are not true. For example, disinformation are lies. The person projecting the information knows it's a lie. They're doing it to accomplish an objective. The bigger problem of disinformation is misinformation. Those are people who are sharing those lies, not knowing they are lies, or taking things out of context like satire, et cetera, and propagating as if it were truth. Those are what those are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But not everything we have to deal with falls into that construct. There are two other portions to this that we have to be mindful of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One is missing information, which used to mean that the target audience wasn't informed enough to make a correct decision, favorable to them or anyone else. ‘&lt;em&gt;It's a tragedy that your family member died and you should mourn their loss, but stop touching the body. That's how you're spreading Ebola&lt;/em&gt;’, right? Pretty straightforward, pretty simple. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we're dealing with nation states with deep pockets, that's been flipped up on its head and they're practicing active missing information, where they will provide wire services into a country saying, &lt;em&gt;‘Congratulations, you can use our wire service for free and we'll provide you all the stuff, and that's your biggest cost except for labor. Isn't that wonderful? The catch is that you just have to use our wire service’&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think [contextual] stories are going to get into the press through those channels, good luck. This isn't happening in the third world. These are happening in major countries and places that would shock you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine something like,&lt;em&gt; ‘If you run this story, all our connected businesses that are connected through us or other means are going to pull their advertising budget from you.’&lt;/em&gt; So again, good luck talking about the story in your environment. No one's going to touch it. No influencer wants a piece of it because they're going to lose their incentive structure and their revenue stream. It's things like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the coin, and the bigger problem, is the rhetoric information. These are the things that aren't necessarily true or false. They are framed by your value system, how you view things, what you think truth actually is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are people out there who will say, I think a communist socialist form of government that is highly authoritarian is more stable and therefore better than a liberal democracy. There are people who believe that, and just by saying, well, history would prove you otherwise, it's not a good enough argument. You need to engage with those people at a scale that matters and be prepared to win the argument. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've seen this time again on the counter-terrorism front where we would shut down the comms of a nobody, and suddenly that person would come back with the reputation that was so valuable, and now they're a terrorist thought leader because the Western world thought that they were so dangerous they needed to be shut down instead of just accepting the fact, that maybe we should just engage with this guy because no one's ever heard of him and maybe we should just point out that he's a moron.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are ways to deal with this, and just because we don't like something doesn't mean it's a lie to the person that's spreading it. They might believe it. Before we just title something disinformation and say, well, it's a lie and we can ignore it — that is not adequate in the modern era where everyone is connected because, again, this person has connective tissue to the internet. They have web platforms. They can be just as connected as a government if they should choose to be and if they have the popularity, because at its core, regardless of whether or not you're a government or a celebrity or anything else, you are fighting for attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: It’s sometimes difficult for busy Americans to navigate the information space today and know what to believe without inviting some serious time into the source. Do you look at part of your mission in this role as helping people understand more of the context they need in order to make good decisions?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I've been more on the side dealing with foreign audiences. But even in that regard, I think that it really matters to ask what are the things that we know to be what we feel are objective truths and things that matter? Things that we want target audiences to know because we know it would be better for them and better for our objectives?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then what are the things where we just want to make sure that if a debate needs to be had, we facilitate the debate so that the target audience, particularly with an American target audience - which again, it's not my forte, we don't do that in government or shouldn't — that needs to be facilitated by Americans pointing out to each other that we do need to have these debates and come to kind of consensus, understanding that there will be disagreements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: Do you think your job is going to be even more important in the future or maybe less?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I've never thought the job wasn't important. I think the thing I'm enjoying right now is that everyone's kind of getting their head around what this means. The overused expression that ‘&lt;em&gt;We need to do some things on Facebook&lt;/em&gt;,’ when you would have policymakers say, ‘&lt;em&gt;Well, I'm concerned that that would destroy Amazon and internet commerce’&lt;/em&gt; and your head would explode as you're trying to explain, ‘&lt;em&gt;That's just not how the internet works, man&lt;/em&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can be comfortable operating on these platforms and doing things that we need to do without destroying internet commerce or the internet. And now I think a lot of policy makers and industry are all connected. They're a lot more comfortable doing these things. Now is the time when we need to get to where the resources and the permissions really match the ability to get us where we need to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've generally not found too many authority problems. I generally find permissions problems. I find that when it comes to authorities, you almost always find that every organization actually has a framework that allows them to do things. It's just that someone somewhere in the chain can say no and is all too comfortable saying no, because, particularly in the past administration, they were very comfortable at avoiding risk and not as comfortable at managing risk. And that is a dynamic that we have to change. The world is a risky place, and we need to be out there participating in it, throwing our elbows around and managing the risk, not avoiding it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: How hard of a job is it to give the U.S. the cognitive advantage in today’s world?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;It's hard, tremendously hard because you're talking about changing culture. I don't think the activity itself and the policy and the things that can be done are hard. I think the hard part will be changing the culture and changing people's mindsets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We've talked about the fact that there used to be three domains: physical domain, information domain and cognitive domain. We have to explore the information domain and actually call it what it is. There is the physical domain, the geophysical domain. But I like the ‘kill web’ approach. A good kill web will constitute a kill chain that is disrupted, and we have to get out of just a kill chain. We need to get into a kill web mentality when it comes to cognitive effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: Explain what you mean by a “kill web”?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You have your geophysical world where things exist in the real world, the place where we all live. When it comes to the information domain, though, it used to consolidate a bunch of things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reality is that when we break that down into a kill web, you're looking from your physical domain up to your logic layer. The internet is not some amorphous cloud that wanders around. It's composed of a system of systems that live in the real world. It's data centers, servers, modems, et cetera. Where does that infrastructure actually exist? Sometimes the files are in the computer. So, we need to be mindful of where does that work? How does the internet, how do these structures work, the mobile networks, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From there, it then creates the digital layer, where all the trons are that exist. You can have effects, that's where your real cyberspace comes into play. That's how the mobile devices work, but that is just data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then it goes up to the persona entity level. These are the real human beings, sometimes fake human beings, they're personas, organizations but entities that potentially could be targeted or addressed or engaged, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then there's the cognitive space. The trick in the cognitive space is what happens in the mind. And that mind is influenced by the sensing that goes up through that chain when they process it. You're able to interdict on its way up or influence, and you're able to influence on the way down when a decision is made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, when something happens in the real world, it's communicated to a decision maker, but it's going to go through the logic layer transmitted through sensors, computers, emails, phones, et cetera, to people and entities who are going to process it themselves, communicate it to a decision maker who's going to make a decision based off that information, or an individual or a bunch of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They're all going to make decisions on how to react to that or not react to that. And that's going to go back down to the physical world when they say, ‘&lt;em&gt;I don't really like what is happening&lt;/em&gt;’, or maybe ‘&lt;em&gt;I do like what's happening. Let's do the thing’&lt;/em&gt;. They're going to communicate that down to ‘&lt;em&gt;Yes, launch the missiles’&lt;/em&gt;, or ‘&lt;em&gt;Let's have a protest’&lt;/em&gt;. So, you can affect the chain up. You can affect the chain down, but that's how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We as the United States have a pipe that exists inside that kill web structure - so does everyone else. And it doesn't matter if you're a nation state or a family or an individual. You have your sensing sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, the direct conversations between people in the real world - even now, you and I are communicating completely over that entire structure - and that structure could be affected on the way up as we're communicating to when this is finally produced and goes back out to the real world where suddenly I have AI effects on me and I'm saying things I never meant to say, but the rest of the world's now interpreting that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn't say that, that wasn't my cognitive decision, but you intercepted on the way down and now you would inadvertently affect everyone else's cognitive approach to what I'm communicating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kelly: What does the future from a technology and AI standpoint really look like?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chenoweth: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;It's having fundamental changes. It's going to be interesting to see what happens in the entertainment industry as AI takes over and suddenly people can have more access. We've seen how the music industry went through huge change just on streaming music. We're about to witness what this is going to look like from our more traditional platforms. We've seen how things move from streaming. I think there is a level of adaptation that's going to go with that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the things that needs to be addressed is how exactly we're going to engage. There is a point where we need to be comfortable with giving sort of guidance to the AIs - human in the loop - but if you think that you're going to be able to review every single message that needs to go out in an AI-driven world, you're out of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, you need to be able to be comfortable generating for your target audience profiles and give sort of thematic guidance and let the AI do some level of engagements against foreign audiences to steer conversations in a particular direction, or at least identify where a conversation might be going so you can intervene when it looks like decisions are being made in a bad way, and then find out if that is an open and honest cultural nuance thing where it is about engagement or if it's being steered by your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that we are not far, and we're probably already in a game, where there are AIs versus AIs as we speak in the information environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What One Film’s Success Reveals About Today’s Russia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/master-margarita-film-review-bulgakov-modern-russia/</link>
      <description>An adaptation of “The Master and Margarita” has become a smash hit—despite Moscow’s attempts to sink it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Thought Experiment That Started a Revolution</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/the-thought-experiment-that-started-a-revolution/</link>
      <description>How a hypothetical scenario started a global movement—and exposed the limits of moral theory.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s ‘battleship’ could be most expensive US warship in history</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2026/01/trumps-battleship-could-be-most-expensive-us-warship-history/410761/</link>
      <description>Congressional researchers wonder whether BBG(X)’s cost and risks were properly analyzed before its rollout.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNO drops hints about forthcoming ‘Fighting Instructions’ strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/cno-hints-forthcoming-fighting-instructions-strategy/410760/</link>
      <description>The new vision will arrive amid Navy efforts to expand its fleet and keep existing ships ready to deploy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pillaging of the American Arctic</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/trump-critical-minerals-arctic-alaska-mining-uranium/</link>
      <description>How Alaskans are navigating the Trump administration’s critical mineral drive.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Next After Iran’s Massacre?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/iran-massacre-protesters-trump/</link>
      <description>After killing thousands of protesters, Tehran has no reason to back down.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The most useful indicator of your overall health</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/16/the-most-useful-indicator-of-your-overall-health</link>
      <description>“Heart-rate variability” has been decades in the making</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Navigate the New World Jungle Law</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/ian-bremmer-jungle-law-donald-trump-foreign-policy/</link>
      <description>Geopolitical analyst Ian Bremmer on Trump’s foreign policy ideology—and how the world is adapting to it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What U.S. – China Cooperation Means for the World</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/what-u-s-china-cooperation-means-for-the-world</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION --&lt;/strong&gt; China was very critical of the capture of Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro last week. The spokesperson for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said the U.S. action was “blatant interference” in Venezuela and a violation of international law. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Maduro was accused of working with Columbian guerrilla groups to traffic cocaine into the U.S. as part of a “narco-terrorism” conspiracy. Of all countries, China should appreciate the need to stop Mr. Maduro from smuggling these illicit drugs into the U.S., killing tens of thousands of Americans. China experienced this in the Opium War of 1839-1842, when Great Britain forced opium on China, despite government protestations, resulting in the humiliating Treaty of Nanjing, ceding Hong Kong to Great Britain. Mr. Maduro was violating U.S. laws, in a conspiracy to aid enemies and kill innocent Americans. Fortunately, the U.S. had the political will, and military might, to quickly and effectively put an end to this assault. China should understand this and withhold criticism, despite their close relationship with Mr. Maduro and Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scheduled April meeting of presidents Donald Trump and Xi Jinping will hopefully ease tension related to the South China Sea and Taiwan. The meeting will also offer an opportunity of the two presidents to elaborate on those transnational issues that the U.S. and China can work together on, for the common good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Security Strategy of 2025 states that deterring a conflict over Taiwan is a priority and does not support any unilateral change to the status quo in the Taiwan Strait. It also states that one-third of global shipping passes annually through the South China Sea and its implications for the U.S. economy are obvious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The April meeting will permit Messrs. Trump and Xi to candidly discuss the South China Sea and Taiwan and ensure that there are guardrails to prevent conflict. Quiet and effective diplomacy is needed to address these issues, and the Trump – Xi meeting could establish the working groups and processes necessary to ensure the U.S. and China do not stumble into conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also important are the transnational issues that require the attention of the U.S. and China. This shouldn’t be too difficult, given the history of cooperation between the U.S. and China, primarily in the 1980s and 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it was China’s Chairman Deng Xiaoping who approved cooperation with the U.S. on the collection and sharing of intelligence on the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; China opposed the December 1979 Soviet Union invasion of Afghanistan and worked with the U.S. to provide weapons and supplies to the resistance forces in Afghanistan – who eventually prevailed, with the Soviet Union admitting defeat and pulling out of Afghanistan in 1989. The war in Afghanistan cost the Soviet Union immense resources, lives and prestige, weakening the Soviet Union and contributing to its later dissolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the 1979 normalization of relations, the U.S. and China cooperated on a few transnational issues: nuclear nonproliferation; counternarcotics, focusing on Southeast Asia’s Golden Triangle and the heroin from Burma going into China and the U.S.; counterterrorism and the sharing of intelligence on extremist networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2002, Secretary of State Colin Powell asked China to assist with the denuclearization of North Korea. The following year, China hosted the Six-Party Talks on North Korea’s nuclear program and actively assisted convincing North Korea, in the Joint Statement of September 19, 2005, to commit to complete and verifiable dismantlement of all nuclear weapons and nuclear weapons programs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; China also cooperated with the U.S. on public health issues, like SARS and the avian flu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cooperation on these transnational issues was issue-specific, pragmatic, and often insulated from political tensions. Indeed, even during periods of rivalry, functional cooperation persisted when interests overlapped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opportunities to Further Enhance Bilateral Cooperation for the Common Good&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although U.S. – China cooperation on counternarcotics is ongoing, specifically regarding the fentanyl crisis, trafficking in cocaine, heroin and methamphetamines also requires close attention. More can be done to enhance bilateral efforts on nuclear nonproliferation, starting with China agreeing to have a dialogue with the U.S. on China’s ambitious nuclear program. Extremist militant groups like ISIS continue to be active, thus requiring better cooperation on counterterrorism. Covid-19 was a wakeup call: there needs to be meaningful cooperation on pandemics. And ensuring that the space domain is used only for peaceful purposes must be a priority, while also ensuring that there are acceptable guidelines for the lawful and moral use of Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. – China cooperation today is more about preventing a catastrophe. The Belgrade Embassy bombing in 1999, when the U.S. accidentally bombed China’s embassy in Belgrade, killing three Chinese officials and the EP-3 incident of 2001, when a Chinese jet crashed into a U.S. reconnaissance plane, killing the Chinese pilot, and China detaining the U.S. crew in Hainan Island are two examples of incidents that could have spiraled out of control. Chinas initially refused to take the telephone calls from Presidents Bill Clinton and George W. Bush, both hoping to deescalate these tense developments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus, crisis management and military de-confliction should be high on the list of subjects to be discussed, with a robust discussion of nuclear risk reduction. Stability in Northeast Asia and a nuclear North Korea, aligned with Russia and viewing the U.S. and South Korea as the enemies, should also be discussed, as well as nuclear nonproliferation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The April summit between Messrs. Trump and Xi will be an opportunity to candidly discuss Taiwan and the South China Sea, to ensure we do not stumble into conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The summit is also an opportunity to message to the world that the U.S. and China are working on a myriad of transnational issues for the common good of all countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The author is the former associate director of national intelligence. All statements of fact, opinion or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the U.S. government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying U.S. government authentication or information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;he Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Western Companies Helped Create Their Chinese Competitors – Like Labubu</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-western-companies-helped-create-their-chinese-competitors-like-labubu/</link>
      <description>Labubu’s success draws on capabilities derived from Western branding and advertising practices over the past two decades – combined with China’s extremely low-cost labor model.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Shots in Five Minutes: Analysing One Federal Agent’s Use of Less-Lethal Launcher in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/16/border-patrol-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This investigation is part of a collaboration between Bellingcat and Evident Media. The fatal shooting of Renee Nicole Good by Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agent Jonathan Ross in Minneapolis on Jan. 7 sparked nationwide protests, with often violent clashes breaking out between protesters and federal agents. Some of the most intense protests took place [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/16/border-patrol-minneapolis/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Five Shots in Five Minutes: Analysing One Federal Agent’s Use of Less-Lethal Launcher in Minneapolis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Lessons from Iraq; Trump’s Insurrection Act-threat; DIU seeks swarm controllers; Russia’s Starlink drones; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-16-2026/410753/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why South Korea’s Welfare State Fails Its Elderly</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-south-koreas-welfare-state-fails-its-elderly/</link>
      <description>Low pension adequacy, restrictive safety nets, and life-course inequality explain why old age so often means poverty in Korea.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela Is Regime Change Under Another Name</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/venezuela-iraq-afghanistan-trump-maduro/</link>
      <description>Maduro’s removal is a familiar story, and one that doesn’t end well.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Cannot Push China out of Latin America</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-us-cannot-push-china-out-of-latin-america/</link>
      <description>China’s role in Latin America is built on trade flows, long-term investment, financial links, and large-scale infrastructure projects that benefit both sides.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story newsletter: The return of gunboat capitalism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/16/cover-story-newsletter-the-return-of-gunboat-capitalism</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Questions About Venezuelan Oil</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-motivations-for-seizing-controlling-venezuelan-oil-by-anas-alhajji-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some analysts have suggested that Donald Trump seized control of Venezuela’s oil reserves to boost profits for US refineries or to lower energy prices for American consumers by flooding the global market with crude. But this resource grab is most likely motivated by greed, as well as the desire to curb China’s access to energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coast Guard, Sovereignty, and Homeland Defense</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/coast-guard-sovereignty-and-homeland-defense</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION —&lt;/strong&gt; U.S. defense planning rests on the assumption that wars are fought abroad, by expeditionary forces, against defined adversaries. For decades, those assumptions held. But today, many of the most consequential security challenges facing the United States violate all three. They occur closer to home, below the threshold of armed conflict, and in domains where sovereignty is enforced incrementally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shift has exposed a chronic mismatch between how the United States defines its defense priorities and how it allocates resources and respect. While defense discourse continues to stubbornly emphasize power projection and high-end conflict, many of today’s challenges revolve around the more modest and rote enforcement of U.S. territorial integrity and national sovereignty—functions that are vital to U.S. strategic objectives yet lack the optical prestige of winning wars abroad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sitting at the center of this gap between prestige and need is the U.S. Coast Guard, whose mission profile aligns directly with America’s most important strategic objectives—the enforcement of sovereignty and homeland defense—yet remains strategically undervalued because its work rarely resembles the celebrated and well-funded styles of conventional warfighting. In an era of increased &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/gray-zone-warfare&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;gray-zone&lt;/a&gt; competition and persistent coercion, the failure to properly appreciate the Coast Guard threatens real strategic fallout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the third decade of the 21st century, U.S. defense planning remains heavily oriented toward expeditionary warfighting and high-end kinetic conflict. Budget conversations still revolve around Ford-class supercarriers, F-35 fighters, and A2/AD penetration. This orientation shapes not only force design and budget &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.usni.org/2026/01/15/billions-in-funding-helps-coast-guard-rapidly-implement-force-design-2028-modernization-efforts&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;allocations&lt;/a&gt;, but also institutional prestige and political capital. The services associated with visible combat power, with the Ford-class and the F-35, continue to dominate strategic discourse—even as many of the most persistent security challenges confronting the United States unfold close to home, in the gray-zone, without the need for fifth-generation air power or heavy armor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the most basic level, any nation’s military exists primarily to defend territorial integrity, enforce sovereignty, and protect the homeland. Power projection, forward presence, and deterrence abroad are important—but they are secondary functions derived from the primary purpose of homeland defense. Yet U.S. defense discourse often treats homeland defense as a background condition when it should be revered as the first priority. The result is a blind spot in how security resources are evaluated and allocated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Coast Guard operates at a unique point where law enforcement, military authority, and sovereign enforcement all converge. On any given day, the Coast Guard may board foreign-flagged vessels suspected of sanctions violations, police maritime borders against illicit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-u-s-coast-guards-quiet-drug-war-wins-amid-trumps-caribbean-strikes&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;trafficking&lt;/a&gt;, secure ports that underpin global supply chains, and maintain a persistent presence in contested spaces, like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pacificarea.uscg.mil/Our-Organization/Arctic-District/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Arctic&lt;/a&gt;, without inviting escalation. The Coast Guard is equipped to intercept illegal fishing fleets, escort commercial shipping through sensitive waterways, and assert jurisdiction in legally ambiguous areas. These activities rarely resemble traditional warfighting, they rarely result in a Hollywood blockbuster, and they can be accomplished without nuclear-powered submarines or intercontinental ballistic missiles. But these are not peripheral activities—they are arguably amongst the most important daily functions the U.S. military undertakes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distinct among the military branches, the Coast Guard operates under a legal framework that is uniquely suited to today’s security environment. Under Title 14 status, the Coast Guard falls within the Department of Homeland Security, conducting law enforcement and regulatory missions on a daily basis. Yet, when needed, the service can transition to Title 10 status, under the Department of Defense, and operate as an armed service when required. This agility allows the Coast Guard to remain continuously engaged across the spectrum of competition, whether enforcing U.S. law in peacetime, managing escalation in gray-zone encounters, or integrating seamlessly into military operations. Few other elements of U.S. power can move so fluidly between legal regimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, despite such strategic relevance, the Coast Guard suffers from a persistent optical problem. U.S. defense culture has long privileged services and missions associated with visible, kinetic combat—those that lend themselves to clear narratives of victory, sacrifice, and heroism. The Coast Guard’s work rarely fits that cinematic mold. Its success is measured not in territory seized or targets destroyed, but in disruptions prevented, borders enforced, and crises that never materialize. Inherently quiet work with outcomes that reflect a force operating exactly as designed, although without generating institutional prestige or political support. In a system that rewards the loudest and the brightest, the Coast Guard’s quiet enforcement of sovereignty is easy to overlook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing to overlook the value of the Coast Guard carries strategic consequences. Specifically, persistent underinvestment in the Coast Guard weakens maritime domain awareness, reduces sustained presence in key waterways, and narrows the set of tools available to manage gray-zone competition. As adversaries increasingly rely on legal ambiguity, deniable actors, and incremental pressure to test U.S. resolve, gaps in enforcement become opportunities. In this environment, the absence of credible, continuous sovereignty enforcement invites probing behavior that becomes harder to deter over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advocacy for the Coast Guard does not require reassigning prestige, or elevating one service at the expense of others. It is merely an argument for strategic alignment. If territorial integrity, sovereignty enforcement, and homeland defense are truly core national-security priorities, then the institutions most directly responsible for those missions should be treated accordingly. As competition increasingly unfolds in the gray-zone between peace and war, the United States will need forces designed not only to win conflicts—but to prevent them from starting in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Multilayered Approach to Rare Earths Under US-Led Decoupling</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-multilayered-approach-to-rare-earths-under-us-led-decoupling/</link>
      <description>Amid intense focus on export restrictions and decoupling, far less attention has been paid to how China is responding to U.S.-led diversification efforts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Won’t Save Iran’s Regime – But Chinese Surveillance Technology Might</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/china-wont-save-irans-regime-but-chinese-surveillance-technology-might/</link>
      <description>Yes, China’s response to the violence in Iran has been muted. But don’t overlook the support that China has already provided in the form of surveillance and drone technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Age of Maritime Multilateralism in the Indian Ocean</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-new-age-of-maritime-multilateralism-in-the-indian-ocean/</link>
      <description>The South Asian littorals are shaping a polycentric security order.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Challenges Trump Faces in His Second Year</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/trump-second-year-challenges-russia-ukraine-midterms-middle-east-tariffs-world-cup/</link>
      <description>From Russia-Ukraine to the U.S. midterms, Trump faces a bumpier year at home and abroad.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privilege Over Rights: Appropriating Indigenous Peoples’ Entitlements in Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/privilege-over-rights-appropriating-indigenous-peoples-entitlements-in-malaysia/</link>
      <description>The belated move to update a 71-year-old law exposes Malaysia’s long-standing failure to safeguard the rights of the Orang Asli.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Putting Venezuelan Democracy on Hold</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/machado-must-assert-herself-before-venezuela-democratic-hopes-slip-away-by-piotr-h-kosicki-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicolás Maduro’s removal initially raised hopes that Venezuelans would finally regain control over their political future. Instead, US President Donald Trump has chosen to preserve the Chavista power structure, sidelining pro-democracy advocates and leaving opposition leader María Corina Machado with little influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Muted Response to Venezuela: Sober Alarm, Not Nationalist Bombast</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-muted-response-to-venezuela-sober-alarm-not-nationalist-bombast/</link>
      <description>The official Chinese narrative foregrounds international condemnation and positions Beijing as defender of the international order. But Chinese commentary strikes a different tone.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baltic Cable-Cutting Is Back</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/baltic-cable-cutting-russia-trump-greenland/</link>
      <description>Renewed attacks pose a continuing challenge for Europe at a difficult moment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Even With High Approval Ratings, Is Takaichi’s Snap Election a Political Gamble?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/even-with-high-approval-ratings-is-takaichis-snap-election-a-political-gamble/</link>
      <description>Takaichi could seek to capitalize on her popularity by dissolving the lower house and calling an early election. However, support for the LDP has stayed persistently low.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakh Soldiers Dying in Peacetime</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/kazakh-soldiers-dying-in-peacetime/</link>
      <description>The number of reported deaths within the ranks of the Kazakh military has surged in recent years, while the circumstances surrounding many of these cases remain murky.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Climate Diplomacy Stalls, the Economics Are Racing Ahead</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/climate-economics-markets-driving-transition-even-as-politicians-fail-by-julie-mccarthy-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite political gridlock within countries and at global summits, climate change and ecological degradation are creating undeniable economic momentum. As renewables scale up, fossil fuels will become even less competitive; and as ecosystems degrade, markets will price in the risks and reward those who adapt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Cuba Calculus</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/16/us-cuba-trump-rubio-maduro-venezuela-oil/</link>
      <description>The U.S. president has his sights on the island. But it’s a very different case from Venezuela.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Lam: The Spectacular Rise of Vietnam’s New Strongman</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/to-lam-the-spectacular-rise-of-vietnams-new-strongman/</link>
      <description>How did To Lam survive a brush with scandal to become Vietnam's most powerful leader in decades?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fight Over the Fed</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-fight-over-the-fed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US Federal Reserve’s independence is widely understood to be vital to the economy’s well-being, by insulating monetary policy from political imperatives. But, following the launch of a criminal investigation of Fed Chair Jerome Powell by President Donald Trump’s minions at the Department of Justice, it is hanging on by a thread.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-fight-over-the-fed-doc-2026-01</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Petrostate Dilemma in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-removal-of-maduro-will-further-destabilize-venezuela-by-terry-lynn-karl-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By capturing his Venezuelan counterpart Nicolás Maduro, US President Donald Trump sought to project power abroad but instead exposed his own political vulnerability. Despite his promises to restore Venezuela’s oil industry, his overt resource grab is far more likely to fuel regional turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Perception of Russian Power Is Outdated</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indian-perception-of-russian-power-is-outdated/</link>
      <description>In the contemporary world, Russia neither has the will nor the ability to unfailingly support India.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Iran-related Sanctions Are Complicating India’s Multi-alignment Policy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/trumps-iran-related-sanctions-are-complicating-indias-multi-alignment-policy/</link>
      <description>A looming test for Delhi's diplomacy will be its handling of the possible impact of U.S. tariffs on the Chabahar Port project.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan Eyes Multi-Billion Dollar JF-17 Export Boom Amid Global Interest</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/pakistan-eyes-multi-billion-dollar-jf-17-export-boom-amid-global-interest/</link>
      <description>If Islamabad is able to seal a few of these major deals, it would be a big win for the current government and Pakistan’s defense industry.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Takeover of All Media Is Coming</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/ai-takeover-of-media-will-be-sweeping-and-profound-by-charles-ferguson-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not only is AI already upending the filmmaking industry, but Hollywood is just one example of how the technology will cause enormous social and economic pain unless managed humanely and carefully. Fiction writing, commercial photography, radio, music, and – most ominously – journalism and legacy news outlets face a similar reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Feed Ten Billion People</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/knowledge-and-technologies-to-end-hunger-already-exist-by-yurdi-yasmi-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the world’s population expected to reach ten billion by mid-century, agriculture must produce more with less – every season, everywhere. The knowledge and tools to end and prevent food insecurity are already in hand, but they have yet to be used wisely and at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s 2026 BRICS Presidency: Multilateralism, Multipolarity, and the Venezuelan Test</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indias-2026-brics-presidency-multilateralism-multipolarity-and-the-venezuelan-test/</link>
      <description>New Delhi’s presidency offers significant opportunities – yet also unavoidable challenges – at a moment when the very idea of multilateralism is under strain.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Venezuela Becomes a Quagmire</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/venezuela/how-venezuela-becomes-quagmire</link>
      <description>Washington is repeating mistakes it made in Iraq.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Must Salvage Its Relationship With India</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/america-must-salvage-its-relationship-india</link>
      <description>Or risk losing a global swing state.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Less Foreign Aid, More Climate Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/less-foreign-aid-more-climate-risk</link>
      <description>The massive costs of gutting USAID.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysian Regulator Receives Australian Journalist’s Apology in Thailand</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/malaysian-regulator-receives-australian-journalists-apology-in-thailand/</link>
      <description>Murray Hunter says that the alternative – a possible two-year prison sentence – left him with little choice.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singaporean PM Removes Workers’ Party Chief as Official Opposition Leader</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/singaporean-pm-removes-workers-party-chief-as-official-opposition-leader/</link>
      <description>The High Court last month upheld Pritam Singh's conviction for lying to a parliamentary committee in connection with a case involving a former lawmaker from his party.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Year-round Social Change Necessary For Southeast Asia?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/is-year-round-social-change-necessary-for-southeast-asia/</link>
      <description>Instead of instituting a progressive monoculture, the region's governments could benefit from a temporal &quot;crop rotation&quot; of public rights and benefits.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan, Philippines Sign New Defense Pact to Facilitate Flow of Military Supplies</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/japan-philippines-sign-new-defense-pact-to-facilitate-flow-of-military-supplies/</link>
      <description>The new deal will support the implementation of the two nations' Reciprocal Access Agreement, which came into force in September.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RUSI Reflects: Could Iran Protests Spell Change for the Country?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/news-and-comment/rusi-reflects/rusi-reflects-could-iran-protests-spell-change-country</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Iran is facing an unprecedented level of uncertainty following protests of great intensity and depth since late 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimmed Stars: South Korea’s Draft Weakens its Soft Power</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/dimmed-stars-south-koreas-draft-weakens-its-soft-power</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Despite decades of public debate, South Korea cannot conscript its athletes and performers fairly while still maximising their soft power contribution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A European ‘Drone Wall’: A Tall Order?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/rusi-newsbrief/european-drone-wall-tall-order</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The paradigm shifting influence of drones in warfare has led to new initiatives in defence, and stirred proposals for a European 'drone wall', a concept that appeals to the success of successful multi-layered air defence systems elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass Criticality: Rethinking Critical Infrastructure in the UK</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/mass-criticality-rethinking-critical-infrastructure-uk</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As digital systems become more interdependent and concentrated, a growing number of ‘ordinary’ components quietly turn into de facto critical infrastructure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could Trump Sleepwalk Into a War Over Taiwan?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/could-trump-sleepwalk-into-a-war-over-taiwan/</link>
      <description>The administration's new National Security Strategy has pushed the U.S. policy toward the island in a decidedly dangerous direction.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
