<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Pennsylvania Democrat Takes on Pam Bondi’s Secret ‘Domestic Terrorist’ List</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/pennsylvania-democrat-takes-on-pam</link>
      <description>Rep. Mary Gay Scanlon says the A.G.'s leftwing 'enemies list' is worse than previous 'Red Scares' because nobody knows who's on it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 23:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Tariff Fight Isn’t Over Yet</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/trump-tariffs-supreme-court-ruling-ieepa-section-122-trade-agreements/</link>
      <description>The U.S. president plans to issue 10 percent global duties under a different authority after the Supreme Court ruled that his IEEPA tariffs were unlawful.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 22:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Economy, One Year Later</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/trump-economy-one-year-later/</link>
      <description>How tariffs, immigration crackdowns, and corruption have shaped the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 21:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Europe Ever Thrive Again?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/can-europe-survive-marsh-review-trump/</link>
      <description>The continent’s survival isn’t a question. The brightness of its future very much is.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embraer joins Northrop to devise autonomous boom system for KC-890 tanker</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/embraer-joins-northrop-devise-autonomous-boom-system-kc-890-tanker/411576/</link>
      <description>The deal aims to court international buyers and the Air Force as it sketches out its future refueling program.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Afghan Gold Rush Is Turning Deadly</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/taliban-china-afghanistan-gold-mining-attacks/</link>
      <description>The Taliban government can’t protect Chinese miners from local hostility.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Blockbuster Captures Japan’s Identity Crisis</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/kokuho-review-japan-movie-film-oscars-nomination-makeup/</link>
      <description>“Kokuho” offers an artful meditation on a country in flux.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a Gripping BBC Drama Gets Wrong About Tehran Prison Life</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/bbc-drama-iran-prison-life-hostage/</link>
      <description>A former hostage of the Iranian regime reviews a series based on the story of Nazanin Zaghari-Ratcliffe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Who Will Innovate With India?’ New Horizons for the France-India Partnership</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/who-will-innovate-with-india-new-horizons-for-the-france-india-partnership/</link>
      <description>“The question is no longer whether India innovates – it is ‘who will innovate with India?’” declared French President Emmanuel Macron.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Supreme Court strikes down Donald Trump’s tariffs</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/20/the-supreme-court-strikes-down-donald-trumps-tariffs</link>
      <description>His “emergency” levies are down, but not out</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump answers a Supreme Court rebuke with new tariff threats</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/20/donald-trump-answers-a-supreme-court-rebuke-with-new-tariff-threats</link>
      <description>The immediate economic impact will be more uncertainty</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should you be fibremaxxing?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/20/should-you-be-fibremaxxing</link>
      <description>What to make of the new dietary fad</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killing the Goose that Lays the Gold Medal</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-anti-immigration-less-competitive-in-sports-science-other-fields-by-nancy-qian-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Winning the race for global preeminence – whether on the Olympic ice rink or in the laboratory – cannot be achieved by closing off from the world. If America turns talent away, talent will not vanish; it will relocate, and other countries will claim the medals and the breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Tariffs Are Unlawful, Supreme Court Rules</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/supreme-court-tariffs-trump-ruling-ieepa/</link>
      <description>But it’s unclear what happens to the tens of billions of dollars already taken from U.S. businesses.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Years of War in Europe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/ukraine-russia-war-anniversary-trump-europe-nato-geopolitics-global-order/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on the lasting impact of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Trump’s China Policy?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/kurt-campbell-trump-xi-china-policy/</link>
      <description>Kurt Campbell: “The president clearly wants short-term deals.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington’s Venezuelan Gamble: The Old Guard’s Continued Grip on Power</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/washingtons-venezuelan-gamble-the-old-guards-continued-grip-on-power</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/a-pro-government-student-holds-a-painting-depicting-ousted-venezuela-s-president-nicolas-madura-during-a-march-on-international.jpg?id=64967487&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;height=800&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C1&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;More than six&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/31/venezuelas-acting-president-delcy-rodriguez-announces-prisoner-amnesty&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;weeks&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after United States special&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/us-court-maduro-venezuela-future-9.7033428&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;forces&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; extracted Nicolás Maduro from Caracas, Venezuela remains under the control of the same intelligence apparatus that ran the regime’s&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/31/venezuelas-acting-president-delcy-rodriguez-announces-prisoner-amnesty&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;torture&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; networks. Acting President Delcy Rodríguez, who&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/who-is-delcy-rodriguez-venezuelas-interim-president-after-maduros-ouster&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;oversaw&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the feared Bolivarian intelligence service under Maduro, now negotiates sanctions relief with Washington while security hardliners who detained political prisoners coordinate their release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For much of the U.S. intelligence community, however, it is not about whether Venezuela’s system can be repaired, but rather whether the Trump administration has enough leverage to prevent the old guard from rebranding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than triggering immediate elections as Venezuelan law&lt;a href=&quot;https://constitutionnet.org/news/voices/venezuela-is-a-democratic-transition-possible&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;requires&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Supreme Court declared Maduro’s capture a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/us-court-maduro-venezuela-future-9.7033428&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;temporary&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; absence, allowing Rodríguez to govern indefinitely without a popular mandate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The regime used a legal mechanism to maintain institutional control while avoiding an immediate electoral process,” Mauricio Vaquero, country coordinator for María Corina Machado’s Vente Venezuela party in Colombia, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “The Supreme Court decided she would assume as interim president, but a Chavista Supreme Court, not the democratic legal one.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, the same loyalist judges who helped Maduro stay in power are now using constitutional loopholes to keep his inner circle in charge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Intelligence Network Remains Intact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The security apparatus that sustained Maduro’s authoritarian rule continues operating largely unchanged. Interior Minister Diosdado Cabello, still wanted by American authorities on a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/dispatches/next-steps-to-secure-venezuelas-democratic-future/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;$25&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; million bounty for narco-terrorism charges, controls Venezuela’s coercive forces and armed collectives. His role in coordinating political prisoner releases illustrates the paradox of the current transition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foro Penal, Venezuela’s leading human rights organization that has provided pro bono legal assistance to victims of arbitrary detention since 2002, estimates that approximately&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2026_political_prisoner_release_in_Venezuela&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;711&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; political prisoners are detained as of mid-February. Releases often come with severe restrictions. When opposition politician Juan Pablo Guanipa was&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2026/02/08/americas/venezuela-political-prisoners-opposition-released-latam-intl&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;freed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on February 8 after eight&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2026/02/08/americas/venezuela-political-prisoners-opposition-released-latam-intl&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;months&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of detention, armed men abducted him hours later. He is now under house arrest with an ankle monitor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They were released, they reunited with their families, until the enlightened stupidity of some politicians led them to believe they could do whatever they wanted and stir up trouble in the country,” Cabello&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breitbart.com/latin-america/2026/02/10/venezuelan-thug-chief-diosdado-cabello-defends-abduction-freed-political-prisoner/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;stated&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after Guanipa’s re-arrest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luis Bustos, the Bogotá-based spokesperson for the Venezuelan opposition party Primero Justicia, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that his party alone has 61 members imprisoned as political prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There is still a high risk of getting arrested if authorities are aware that you are happy about the situation,” Bustos continues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Caracas and popular zones, armed collectives demonstrate the regime’s ability to maintain social control outside of formal state structures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“After Maduro’s arrest, a circular went out saying that opposition supporters would be captured and obviously alluding to actions of justice by these groups,” Vaquero insists. “So repression itself has not diminished, not in a constant way, not in a sustainable way.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elections: A Constitutional Impossibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuelan opposition figures and Washington officials increasingly acknowledge that legitimate elections cannot take place in the near term. The electoral system’s corruption under Chavismo extends beyond fraudulent vote counting to fundamental issues of voter registry manipulation and military involvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This government put deceased people to vote,” Vaquero claims. “This government gave identity cards indiscriminately to Cubans, to Russians, to Chinese, to people from FARC, to people from ELN.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;María Corina Machado, the Nobel Peace Prize&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2026/02/08/americas/venezuela-political-prisoners-opposition-released-latam-intl&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;laureate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; leading Venezuela’s unified opposition, estimated in early February that transparent elections using manual voting could take place within 9 to 10&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wlrn.org/2026-02-13/nbc-news-venezuelan-president-delcy-rodriguez-pledges-free-and-fair-elections-but-no-future-date&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;months&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. However, National Assembly President Jorge Rodríguez, Delcy’s brother and key regime interlocutor with Washington,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upi.com/Top_News/World-News/2026/02/10/latam-venezuela-elelctions-later/1371770749886/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;ruled&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; out elections in the near future, citing the need for stabilization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;White House Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt has&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/7/trump-administration-claims-it-will-dictate-policy-to-venezuela&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;echoed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the administration’s reluctance to commit to an electoral timeline. When pressed on when elections might be held, Leavitt stated: “It’s too premature and too early to dictate a timetable for elections in Venezuela right now.” She emphasized that the administration has “maximum leverage over the interim authorities in Venezuela,” and that “their decisions are going to continue to be dictated by the United States of America.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The constitutional framework technically allows Acting President Rodríguez to serve 90 days, with a possible ninety-day extension if approved by the Chavista-controlled National&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/dispatches/next-steps-to-secure-venezuelas-democratic-future/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Assembly&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Temporary absence provisions, however, are interpreted creatively by the Supreme Court, which effectively eliminates any firm deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A U.S. intelligence official focused on Latin America issues, speaking on background to &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, estimates that credible elections extend well beyond constitutional requirements. The source highlights that comprehensive electoral reform requires dismantling power structures that are still firmly entrenched.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bustos also underscores that elections might realistically occur as early as next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We need first of all to get a country more stable,” he says. “We need to put our institutions on stronger foundations.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without functioning democratic institutions, independent electoral authorities, or international oversight mechanisms in place, any rushed election would ratify the status quo. Under current conditions, elections would not be free or fair because the regime controls voters’ registries and ballots. As long as the same power structure is still in place, cosmetic reforms cannot address this fundamental barrier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage and Limitations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite these obstacles, the Trump administration can drive genuine change by maintaining pressure through its military presence and negotiations over sanctions relief. It appears, however, that the regime is trying to outlast Washington’s attention by complying tactically with American demands while maintaining fundamental power structures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paola Salazar, director for Medellín and Antioquia state at Colombia’s government migration agency, Migración Colombia, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that pendular migratory flows between Colombia and Venezuela have&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/5/delcy-rodriguez-sworn-in-as-venezuelas-president-after-maduro-abduction&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;remained&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stable since January 3, suggesting Venezuelans are not yet convinced conditions have fundamentally changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Alejandro Méndez Hernández, a Venezuelan community organizer in Bogotá, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that trust is still absent, hence migrants are not returning despite Maduro’s removal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have a huge amount of Venezuelans being arrested as political prisoners, who haven’t been released until today, so it’s not building trust,” he continues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acting President Rodríguez&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wlrn.org/2026-02-13/nbc-news-venezuelan-president-delcy-rodriguez-pledges-free-and-fair-elections-but-no-future-date&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;told&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; NBC News earlier this month that she would hold free and fair elections but declined to commit to a timeline, stating that the schedule would be determined through political dialogue. When pressed about Machado, Rodríguez said she would face legal scrutiny upon any return for calling for military intervention and sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Secretary of State Marco Rubio has publicly outlined a three-phase approach for Venezuela’s future — stability, recovery, and transition to democracy — though he has declined to provide a specific timeline. During his January 28 Senate Foreign Relations Committee testimony, Rubio emphasized that “the end state here is we want a friendly, stable, prosperous Venezuela, and democratic, in which all elements of society are represented in free and fair elections.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Rubio acknowledged the complexity of the timeline, stating, “We’re not going to get there in three weeks. It’s going to take some time.” In subsequent remarks to reporters, he added that the transition “can’t take forever” and acknowledged there must be progress within several months. However, he cautioned that “this is not a campaign to leave in place the systems currently in place.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Diosdado Factor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interior Minister Cabello represents the most significant obstacle to a genuine transition. With control over security forces, intelligence services, and armed collectives, he possesses the coercive apparatus necessary to maintain regime control independent of formal governmental structures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Diosdado Cabello has a price imposed by the United States,” Vaquero explains. “He controls the coercive apparatus and all the internal loyalties. We’ve seen him lately. Every time he appears in Venezuelan media, he looks scared.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. intelligence source identifies Cabello as the key figure whose removal or neutralization would be necessary for an authentic democratic opening. As long as Cabello maintains control of security forces, any political transition will be cosmetic rather than substantive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His control extends beyond formal military and police to encompass armed civilian collectives that intimidate opposition supporters and maintain social control, operating with impunity while allowing the regime to claim official restraint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreign Influence and Regional Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regime’s historical relationships with Iran, Hezbollah, Russia, and China complicate transition planning. Despite keeping a low profile after Maduro’s removal, these actors continue to threaten American national security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bustos stresses that the presence of Hezbollah and Iranian-linked entities necessitates an extended transition period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The United States certainly knows about it,” he says. “I think that it’s not possible to get them out of the country really quickly.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The re-extradition of Colombian-Venezuelan businessman Alex Saab in early&lt;a href=&quot;https://colombiaone.com/2026/02/04/fbi-arrests-alex-saab-maduro-venezuela/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;February&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, designated by the United States as a key financial operator for Maduro, demonstrates some cooperation from regime elements with American law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saab’s arrest represents a significant test of cooperation with Washington. U.S. authorities accused Saab of moving approximately&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alex_Saab&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;$350&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; million out of Venezuela through corrupt contracts, making him central to understanding how the regime financed itself under sanctions. His potential extradition signals Rodríguez is willing to sacrifice even Maduro’s closest financial operatives to maintain Washington’s support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly 9&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/longform/2026/2/4/these-exiled-venezuelans-dream-of-returning-home-whats-stopping-them&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;million&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Venezuelans in the diaspora are reassessing their return prospects, yet few are making immediate plans to return. The combination of continued repression, economic uncertainty, and the presence of the same officials who forced their exile creates a wait-and-see dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuelan passports cost approximately&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/longform/2026/2/4/these-exiled-venezuelans-dream-of-returning-home-whats-stopping-them&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;$700&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the black market when available, complicating both legal status abroad and potential return. Embassies and consulates are largely non-functional, creating a documentation crisis that traps Venezuelans in limbo regardless of whether they wish to return home or establish permanent residence elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic Implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a fundamental question for Washington intelligence planners: Does the current arrangement represent a genuine transition, or is it simply the regime’s survival under American pressure? Continuing imprisonment of opposition figures and constitutional maneuvers to avoid elections suggest the former.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The official from the U.S. intelligence community notes the regime is maintaining strategic control while ensuring tactical compliance. In the absence of sustained military and economic pressure and clear benchmarks, the current government will likely continue to drag its feet on reforms for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prisoner release pattern is illustrative. While&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2026_political_prisoner_release_in_Venezuela&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;hundreds&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have been freed, the process is opaque, reversible, and controlled entirely by Cabello’s interior ministry. As well as gag orders, those released are subject to re-arrest for hypothetical “political activity.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Defense Minister Vladimir Padrino’s presentation of a golden baton to Rodríguez at a military&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wunc.org/2026-02-05/venezuelas-interim-leader-works-to-balance-u-s-demands-and-chavista-expectations&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;parade&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in February symbolized the armed forces’ continued allegiance to Chavista structures rather than any new democratic order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela’s situation tests the Trump administration’s approach to authoritarian transitions. Government policy toward Venezuela currently reflects a calculated preference for energy security over democratic reform. Washington views maintaining regional stability and securing oil access as more pressing strategic priorities than the unpredictable outcomes of rapid political reforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration’s stated objectives for Venezuela emphasize democratic transition. Rubio&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/releases/office-of-the-spokesperson/2026/01/secretary-of-state-marco-rubio-before-the-senate-committee-on-foreign-relations-on-u-s-policy-towards-venezuela&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;told the Senate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Washington seeks “free and fair elections” where “all elements of society are represented,” noting pointedly that “you can have elections all day,” but without media access for opposition and the ability for opposition candidates to run freely, “those aren’t free and fair elections.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet the administration’s actions reveal a calculated preference for energy security over rapid political reform. In the same testimony, Rubio prioritized Venezuela becoming “a friendly, stable, prosperous” partner and ending threats from “Hezbollah and Iran in our own hemisphere.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washington views maintaining regional stability and securing oil access as more pressing strategic priorities than the unpredictable outcomes of immediate democratic reforms. This pragmatism risks legitimizing a rebranded authoritarianism, retaining the repressive mechanisms of Maduro’s regime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, observers caution that this pragmatism may come at a cost in the long run. By prioritizing energy and migration management, the U.S. risks legitimizing a rebranded authoritarianism that retains the repressive mechanisms of Maduro’s regime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former U.S. Ambassador to Venezuela James Story&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wunc.org/2026-02-05/venezuelas-interim-leader-works-to-balance-u-s-demands-and-chavista-expectations&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;assessed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Rodríguez will play for time, doing “just enough to make it look as if they are complying” while waiting for U.S. focus to shift.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela’s post-Maduro transition ultimately reveals limitations of decapitation strategies against entrenched authoritarian systems. While removing Maduro eliminated the regime’s symbolic figurehead, the intelligence and security apparatus is intact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elections cannot occur in the short term, at least not elections meeting minimal standards of freedom and fairness. There is corruption in the electoral infrastructure, arrests of opposition figures for political activities, and the ability and leadership of those who would suppress genuine democratic opening is intact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the current arrangement provides tactical benefits, it also leaves strategic vulnerabilities regarding oil access and preventing a migration surge. The same figures wanted on U.S. criminal charges coordinate government functions. The same security services that tortured political prisoners manage their conditional release. The same armed collectives that intimidated voters patrol neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Where Diosdado Cabello has been, obviously repression has not disappeared,” Vaquero adds. “It materializes with collectives, with social pressure, with selective judicialization. And obviously, while Diosdado remains in power, there won’t be profound change but rather tactical changes.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USFK Aerial Encounter With China Underlines the Hidden Danger of OPCON Transfer</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/usfk-aerial-encounter-with-china-underlines-the-hidden-danger-of-opcon-transfer/</link>
      <description>Structural separation inadvertently reduces alliance accountability at precisely the moment when regional great power rivalry is intensifying.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Ramayana Trail: Why Indian Tourists Matter More Than Ever to Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/beyond-the-ramayana-trail-why-indian-tourists-matter-more-than-ever-to-sri-lanka/</link>
      <description>Sri Lanka is no longer simply attracting Indian tourists. It is increasingly being shaped around them.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Iran buildup’s unclear aims; Army’s drone contest; Board of Peace, convened; More UFO info?; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-20-2026/411558/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Supreme Court Strikes Down Trump’s Tariffs</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/us-supreme-court-ruling-trump-tariffs-trade-war-read-full-text-ieepa/</link>
      <description>The court ruled that the president does not have the authority to impose tariffs during peacetime under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Erasure of Ethnic Minority Languages</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/chinas-erasure-of-ethnic-minority-languages/</link>
      <description>China’s linguistic assimilation campaign continues to advance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of a Lie</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/mark-carney-abandoning-the-pretense-of-the-rules-based-international-order-by-antara-haldar-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his now-famous speech to this year's gathering of global elites in Davos, Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney rightly drew on a key insight from the late Václav Havel. Institutions fall first in the realm of belief, when people begin abandoning their assigned roles in legitimizing rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Europe Assist India in Fulfilling Its Defense Aviation Dreams?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/can-europe-assist-india-in-fulfilling-its-defense-aviation-dreams/</link>
      <description>Currently, GE, Safran, and Rolls-Royce are all in contention for engine development for India’s fifth-generation Advanced Medium Combat Aircraft and Twin-Engine Deck-Based Fighter.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s New Special Security Unit Underscores China’s Hold on the Country</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/pakistans-new-special-security-unit-underscores-chinas-hold-on-the-country/</link>
      <description>This is the closest Islamabad has come so far to yielding to Beijing’s demands for Chinese security forces to be stationed in Pakistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epstein Links Threaten Norway’s Global Image</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/norway-epstein-oslo-nobel-peace-prize-jagland-mette-marit/</link>
      <description>The country parlayed a reputation for probity into diplomatic currency. Now that’s in tatters.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How North Korea Is Ranking Southeast Asian Countries</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-north-korea-is-ranking-southeast-asian-countries/</link>
      <description>Pyongyang is pruning its diplomatic network to concentrate on the partners where sanctions enforcement is weakest and digital evasion infrastructure is already in place.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marco Rubio’s Munich Speech Is More Dangerous Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/marco-rubio-munich-speech-trans-atlantic-relations-europe-us-democracy/</link>
      <description>What the U.S. secretary of state laid bare about the Trump worldview.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia and Timor-Leste: A New Partnership for a New Era</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/australia-and-timor-leste-a-new-partnership-for-a-new-era/</link>
      <description>With the Parseria Foun ba Era Foun declaration, Australia and Timir-Leste hope to build a partnership grounded in equality, shared regional interests, and respectful cooperation between neighbors.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inequality Will Make the Next Pandemic Worse</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/inequality-pandemics-breaking-the-vicious-cycle-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-et-al-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crowded living conditions, frontline occupations, and poverty all fuel the spread of pandemics, as do poor nutrition and baseline health characteristics. Unless these issues –&amp;nbsp;which came to define the COVID-19 pandemic –&amp;nbsp;are addressed head-on, the most vulnerable will surely suffer the most in the next crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Scenarios for a Postwar Iran</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/four-scenarios-war-iran-trump/</link>
      <description>Trump wants regime change but not the messy aftermath.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Do India and Pakistan Stand in Kazakhstan’s Southward Connectivity Push?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/where-do-india-and-pakistan-stand-in-kazakhstans-southward-connectivity-push/</link>
      <description>Political friction and logistical barriers limit India’s integration into the evolving connectivity landscape, even as the broader promise of Eurasian integration remains contingent on its inclusion.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Primer on North Korea’s Party Congresses</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/a-primer-on-north-koreas-party-congresses/</link>
      <description>To understand what may emerge from the Ninth Party Congress, it is worth examining what these meetings are and how their functions have evolved.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Security Needs Turkey</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-security-framework-must-include-turkey-by-abdullah-gul-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the turn that future US administrations take, Europe can no longer rely on American supremacy and goodwill, especially when it comes to its own defense and security. The quest for strategic autonomy has begun, and it should include re-engagement with one of NATO's leading military powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan Under Taliban Rule Makes the World Less Safe</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/afghanistan-under-taliban-rule-makes-the-world-less-safe/</link>
      <description>The world has shifted focus away from Afghanistan, much as it did in the lead-up to September 2001, giving dangerous networks room to rebuild.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for Bangladesh’s Youth-Led National Citizen Party?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/whats-next-for-bangladeshs-youth-led-national-citizen-party/</link>
      <description>The NCP was born of revolution, then aligned with Jamaat-e-Islami. Will that partnership outlast the election?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yoon Denounces Insurrection Verdict as PPP Clings to Ousted Leader</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/yoon-denounces-insurrection-verdict-as-ppp-clings-to-ousted-leader/</link>
      <description>The former president challenged judicial neutrality, and conservative leaders continue to back him, with an eye toward appeasing the increasingly hardline base.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drought May Test Central Asia’s New Cooperative Approach</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/drought-may-test-central-asias-new-cooperative-approach/</link>
      <description>Are the new ties that bind Central Asian countries strong enough to weather drought?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In India, Lula Puts Middle-Power Diplomacy on Display</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/20/brazil-india-lula-modi-visit-ai-rare-earths-cooperation/</link>
      <description>Brazil’s president hopes to cooperate on AI, critical minerals, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Thailand’s Messy Politics Fueled Its Border War With Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-thailands-messy-politics-fueled-its-border-war-with-cambodia/</link>
      <description>The war helped secure an election victory for Anutin and Thai conservatives. And that was almost certainly by design.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why MAGA Fears Europe</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/why-maga-fears-europe</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump and his acolytes have long promoted the narrative that the European Union is weak and misguided, and there was no let-up at the World Economic Forum’s annual gathering Davos in January or at this month’s Munich Security Conference. But the truth is that Europe’s social-market model and commitment to openness continue to pay dividends. Far from doubting itself, the EU should double down on its strengths and, as the US-China geopolitical rivalry heats up, tout them as an example for the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-s-fear-and-loathing-of-europe-doc-2026-02</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viral Child Soldiers on TikTok: The ‘Disney Stars’ of Sudan’s Civil War</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/02/20/viral-child-soldiers-on-tiktok-the-disney-stars-of-sudans-civil-war/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on our latest investigations, join Bellingcat’s WhatsApp channel here. Child soldiers linked to Sudan’s warring factions have gained viral fame on TikTok, with their videos attracting millions of views. A Bellingcat investigation has found that the young boys – widely referred to as “lion cubs” – have become celebrated figures [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/02/20/viral-child-soldiers-on-tiktok-the-disney-stars-of-sudans-civil-war/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Viral Child Soldiers on TikTok: The ‘Disney Stars’ of Sudan’s Civil War&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan Democracy Needs Action, Not Cheap Talk</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-plan-wrongly-puts-oil-before-democracy-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s Venezuela strategy prioritizes oil reconstruction over elections, treating democracy as an afterthought. But without credible institutions and political legitimacy, Venezuela cannot attract the private capital needed to rebuild its oil sector or provide the legal certainty long-term projects demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Iranian Revolution?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/will-iran-protests-and-trump-pressure-bring-down-islamic-republic-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amid deepening economic crisis, rising popular discontent, and mounting US pressure, the odds appear to be stacked against the Islamic Republic. Unless Iran's ruling regime embraces a more moderate approach, it may soon face collapse, with destabilizing effects on the entire region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Cambodia’s Forgotten Prophet</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/finding-cambodias-forgotten-prophet/</link>
      <description>Five decades after his prescient wartime exposé of the Khmer Rouge, Ith Sarin resurfaces to shed new light on his life ahead of the publication of a new translation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Doesn’t Want the US and Iran to Make Peace</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-china-doesnt-want-the-us-and-iran-to-make-peace/</link>
      <description>While Beijing publicly advocates restraint, sustained tensions between the U.S. and Iran serve its strategic interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Lines and the Reshaping of Asia’s Maritime Order</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/red-lines-and-the-reshaping-of-asias-maritime-order/</link>
      <description>While restraint remains the order of the day, recent developments suggest that rival nations' maritime &quot;red lines&quot; are hardening.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Private Sector Pivot</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/chinas-private-sector-pivot</link>
      <description>How Beijing is encouraging entrepreneurs without giving up control.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP’s Victory in Bangladesh Opens Door Wider for Islamabad</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/bnps-victory-in-bangladesh-opens-door-wider-for-islamabad/</link>
      <description>Pakistan’s goal should not be to replace India in Bangladesh, but to foster a relationship based on sovereign equality.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 03:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia Signs Reciprocal Trade Agreement With US, Tariff Set at 19%</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesia-signs-reciprocal-trade-agreement-with-us-tariff-set-at-19/</link>
      <description>Jakarta will cut trade barriers on more than 99 percent of American imports, in exchange for tariff exemptions for certain key goods.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 03:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Indonesia’s Web3 Pivot is Helping to Build the Country’s Digital Sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-indonesias-web3-pivot-is-helping-to-build-the-countrys-digital-sovereignty/</link>
      <description>A host of new initiatives are helping to inoculate Southeast Asia's largest nation against China’s fintech dominance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Crypto Economy Feeding Russia’s War Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/shadow-crypto-economy-feeding-russias-war-machine</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Crypto is embedded in Russia’s procurement model, allowing it an access to Common High Priority Items that international sanctions were intended to deny. Huge disruption is necessary to apply pressure to Russia's supply chains for critical military components.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Potential of Reserve Combat Aviation for the Counter Drone Mission</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/rusi-defence-systems/potential-reserve-combat-aviation-counter-drone-mission</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While training civilian pilots as military reserve pilots for fast jets is not a realistic prospect for the UK and most other European nations, it is worth considering reservist pilots for secondary air defence duties in turboprop aircraft against one-way attack drones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constellation Class Failure and its Consequences</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/rusi-newsbrief/constellation-class-failure-and-its-consequences</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The failure of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Constellation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; Class underlines problems in US Navy procurement that will have detrimental operational and strategic consequences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of New START: What's Next?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/members-event-recordings/end-new-start-whats-next</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A conversation with The Hon Rose Gottemoeller, chief US negotiator for the New Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty (New START), on the treaty's expiration and the implications for nuclear arms control.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Impeachment Complaint Filed Against Philippine Vice-President</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/fourth-impeachment-complaint-filed-against-philippine-vice-president/</link>
      <description>The move came a day after Sara Duterte officially announced her intention to run for the presidency in 2028.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 23:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China Views Bangladesh’s Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-china-views-bangladeshs-election/</link>
      <description>Chinese official statements and comments from academics reflect a clear assessment that the polls have not altered the fundamental structure of bilateral relations.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 20:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump is reshaping American health care</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/19/donald-trump-is-reshaping-american-health-care</link>
      <description>And the consequences will ripple through both health and politics</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
