<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Checks and Balance: A chilling week in Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/09/checks-and-balance-a-chilling-week-in-minnesota</link>
      <description>The shooting of an American citizen by an ICE agent raises grave questions, argues Charlotte Howard, our New York bureau chief</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU-Mercosur Trade Deal May Not Be the Big Win Some in Europe Think</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/european-union-eu-mercosur-trade-deal-farmers-environment-protests-tariffs/</link>
      <description>The accord is expected to add only 0.05 percent to the EU’s economy and has ignited political upheaval across Europe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Oil Doesn’t Explain Trump’s Venezuela Gambit</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/oil-trump-venezuela-maduro/</link>
      <description>The “Donroe Doctrine” is about the spectacle of violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What We Know and Don’t Know About the Legal Case Against Maduro</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/legal-case-maduro-venezuela-trump-new-york/</link>
      <description>The case is poised to be long and complicated.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/news-quiz-trump-maduro-venezuela-iran-protests-greenland-annexation/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Jan. 3: Trump abducts Venezuela’s Maduro, protests continue in Iran, and the U.S. threatens Greenland.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Rigged Election Is No Reason to Reengage Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/myanmar-junta-beijing-china-elections/</link>
      <description>Washington’s outreach to Myanmar’s junta is shortsighted.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland’s Filmmakers Are Ready to Tell Their Own Stories</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/greenlandic-filmmakers-are-ready-to-tell-their-own-stories/</link>
      <description>A burgeoning movie industry seeks to give the island an international voice.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Army’s noncommittal procurement strategy is creating quandaries for vendors</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/army-procurement-vendor-uncertainty/410593/</link>
      <description>It's creating tension that the government is likely going to have to solve, one expert says.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World-Historical Murder Mysteries</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/international-fiction-releases-postcolonial-murder-nina-mcconigley-age-calamities-senaa-ahmad/</link>
      <description>Plus, more international fiction releases in January.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are We Really Living in a Global Monoculture?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/w-david-marx-blank-space-review-global-monoculture/</link>
      <description>A new book argues—unconvincingly—that there is a “blank space” where culture used to be.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why This Time Is Different for Iran</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-this-time-is-different-deadly-combination-internal-and-external-threats-by-vali-nasr-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Iran's rulers, today's mass protests pose a vexing dilemma. Cracking down too hard could undo the entente that the regime forged with the population after last year's 12-day war with Israel and the United States, but letting them grow could itself invite foreign intervention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do RFK junior’s new dietary guidelines make sense?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/09/do-rfk-juniors-new-dietary-guidelines-make-sense</link>
      <description>We break them down for you</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As protests surge, the Iranian regime’s options are narrowing</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/09/as-protests-surge-the-iranian-regimes-options-are-narrowing</link>
      <description>Iran’s fate depends on who has more staying power: its ruler or its people</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TSMC’s Trade Theft Cases Aren’t a ‘Bad Look’ for Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/tsmcs-trade-theft-cases-arent-a-bad-look-for-taiwan/</link>
      <description>TSMC’s legal cases should not be taken for more than they are: the company’s pursuit of protecting its IP and Taiwan’s trade theft protection system working as it should.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI and the “Human-in-the-Loop” Luxury in Modern Defense</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/agentic-ai-human-in-loop</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Welcome to the inaugural edition of “The Iron Triangle”, my new &lt;em&gt;Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt; column that serves the three pillars of modern defense: Procurement Officers tasked with buying the future, Investors who fund the technology, and Policy Wonks who analyze the impact of technology on the global order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first column explores the shift from &quot;Chatbots&quot; to &quot;Agents.&quot; In Washington, they call it Agentic AI. In the Valley, they call it Action-Oriented LLMs. In the field, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/artificial-intelligence-modeling-earth-geoint&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;the difference&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; between a system that tells you a storm is coming and one that autonomously moves your fleet to a safe harbor before the first raindrop falls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Technology: From &quot;Prediction&quot; to &quot;Agency&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, AI in defense has been about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/leveraging-ai-in-no-fail-mission-for-u-s-intelligence&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, tasks such as labeling tanks in a photo. While Computer Vision has saved countless hours of labor, it doesn't address the challenges associated with overloading analysts with data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agentic AI (Agentic) is a generational leap. For clarity, Agentic refers to systems capable of:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Analyzing the commander’s intent.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Identifying and evaluating subordinate tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Executing a sequence of actions across multiple platforms without human prompting.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agentic processes vast amounts of data into knowledge, exponentially increasing each user’s effectiveness. With Agentic, teams of analysts will no longer pour through volumes of irrelevant information searching for a few key indicators. Agentic will distill torrents of data, a side effect of exponential increases in the number of sensors (drones), down to just the essential elements. In some cases, Agentic may even make decisions without user input.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several questions come to mind. First, &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;what will my analysts do with this windfall of time?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; That's a discussion for another article. Instead, let’s make this relevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief applies expert-level context to national and global security stories. Grant yourself full-access to Cipher Brief expert insights, analysis and private briefings in the new year by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a Subscriber+Member&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Procurement Officer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Procurement officers should be wary of &quot;Black Box&quot; Contracts. If a vendor claims their agent uses &quot;proprietary reasoning&quot; that’s difficult to audit, walk away. Consider commanders whose primary concern is managing risk. In the inevitable post-accident investigation, &quot;the algorithm made a choice&quot; will not serve as strong legal defense. The Pentagon must demand Chain of Preference Transparency. The software must log why it chose one course of action over another, and the decision tree must be continually refined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pentagon should also move away from Firm-Fixed-Price contracts. Agentic requires Continuous Authority to Operate, not only to remain functional, but in a competitive context (war with a global power). If The Pentagon buys a &quot;static&quot; version, the system will be obsolete by the time the invoice is cleared, especially considering the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/defense-acquisition-pentagon-steve-blank&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Pentagon bureaucracy&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Procurement Officers should buy the pipeline, not the package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Investment Thesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The challenge for investors is distinguishing between a &quot;thin wrapper&quot; on AI and a foundational defense operating system. Investment firms often hire retired officers to evaluate defense technology. These officers retired years ago, and may not have had first-hand experience with technology while they were active. Now the investment firm expects them to provide advice on emerging technology that many 20-year-old practitioners are just learning about. It’s not a fair expectation, and will lead to investments in irrelevant technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proximity breeds opportunity. Investors should get involved with practitioners. I’m not suggesting that VCs attend National Training Center rotations, though I do enjoy that mental picture. There are other opportunities to interact with end users; small-scale exercises, trade shows and demonstrations are some.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beware of the moat. The value isn't in the Large Language Model; it’s in the Action Layer. Investors should look for startups who are building &quot;high-side&quot; integrations—companies that have security credentials to plug into actual data. Only then will it become clear how the technology performs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look for the exit. Some &quot;Big Primes&quot; are hardware-heavy and software-poor. They are looking to acquire &quot;Agentic Middleware&quot; to make legacy systems more relevant in an autonomous age. The &quot;Defense Unicorn&quot; of 2026 will be a company that provides the universal brain for antiquated hardware. There are some promising companies focused on exactly this challenge. Whatever is created should be collaborative, to promote and not stifle innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Policy Wonk’s Warning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of AI, policy was concerned about AI’s potential effects on strategic stability. If both the U.S. and a peer competitor deploy Agentic to manage strategic command and control–or frontline skirmishes–we might enter a &quot;Speed of Relevance&quot; trap. When AI reacts to AI, the window for diplomatic de-escalation shrinks from hours to milliseconds, effectively disappearing and devolving into a machine on machine conflict where humans suffer the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To prevent this devolution, there should be a foreign policy shift, a move from Arms Control to Algorithm Control. The next great treaty should not focus on the number of warheads, but the verification of &quot;Human-on-the-loop&quot; safeguards and universal standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Take. &lt;/strong&gt;This where I get to discuss what excites me about this new technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Military Planning.&lt;/strong&gt; Agentic AI will fundamentally change “course of action development” during &lt;a href=&quot;https://defensescoop.com/2025/12/12/socom-agentic-ai-sof-special-operations-forces/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;military planning&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Military Officers, like everyone, suffer from functional fixedness. Their creativity can be limited by their experiences. Agentic will see thousands of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/rethinking-napoleonic-staff&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;potential pathways&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for conducting new missions. I like to think that this will lead to more creative solutions being applied to emerging challenges. Look out executive officers, AI is coming for your jobs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Risk.&lt;/strong&gt; There is a chance that our government becomes reliant on Agentic. The Military plans for everything. I’ve seen Staff Officers plan for how and when to make plans. Reducing planning &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoufancenter.org/intelbrief-2025-august-6/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;to a button click&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; could diminish critical analysis, a fundamental skill for effective leaders, which will have a compounding negative effect on future generations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission Rehearsals.&lt;/strong&gt; Agentic will enable warfighters to rehearse missions based on real time intelligence. Imagine flying a drone simulator where the terrain, the targets, and the weather are all precisely the same as those in the target area of interest. What’s more, Agentic will enable simulated adversaries to react more realistically. Combat Training Centers may be the next casualty of Agentic. I don’t think any soldier will be sad to learn that their NTC rotation is cancelled…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Risk.&lt;/strong&gt; Agentic might get it wrong, leading to gross overestimations–or underestimations–of adversarial capabilities. And what happens when a commander decides to ignore their AI, then suffers a defeat? Punishing the commander in this situation would encourage future leaders to blindly follow Agentic guidance. The government must build rules which preserve and promote &lt;a href=&quot;https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/03/agentic-ai-decision-dominance/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;independent decision authority&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, ensuring that Agentic complements, but does not replace the commander’s judgment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agentic is the first technology that I can recall that doesn't just make our weapons better; it makes our decision-makers faster. For the Procurement Officer, it's a liability to manage; for the VC, it's the ultimate &quot;sticky&quot; SaaS play; and for the Wonk, it’s a terrifying new variable in the balance of power. Current international laws of war are based on human intent and accountability. But it remains legally unclear who is responsible—the developer, the operator, or the commander—when an autonomous agent makes an error. The most pressing requirement now is not for the best new technology, but for our legal and policy frameworks to keep pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Joey Gagnard is a Cipher Brief columnist who regularly shares his perspective on national security and technology via his Iron Triangle column.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Currency Crisis Could Be the Regime’s Downfall</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/iran-protests-rial-currency-economy-crisis/</link>
      <description>Economic disaster has put vast crowds in Tehran’s streets.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Do Chinese Analysts Say About the Thaw With India?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/what-do-chinese-analysts-say-about-the-thaw-with-india/</link>
      <description>Domestic discourse in China frames the relationship as a calculated balancing act to prevent India from aligning firmly with the U.S. – even while Beijing maintains its aggressive stance on security issues.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 Is Already Challenging the U.N.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/united-nations-trump-withdraws-budget-venezuela-world-order/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s mix of aggression and withdrawal is testing the international body.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is GSA’s procurement chief in international negotiations over Ukraine and Gaza?</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/gsas-procurement-chief-attending-negotiations-ukraine-and-gaza/410592/</link>
      <description>Josh Gruenbaum, a financier with no apparent expertise in foreign policy, is a top official at the General Services Administration, which has no role in foreign policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyzstan Under the Khanstitution: 5 Years On</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/kyrgyzstan-under-the-khanstitution-5-years-on/</link>
      <description>Once proud of its reputation as Central Asia’s democratic outlier, Kyrgyzstan now looks like a typical resident of the neighborhood: centralized authority, silenced dissent, and fear of open criticism.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Paradox of Japan’s Anti-Immigrant Sentiments and Demand for Foreign Labor</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-paradox-of-japans-anti-immigrant-sentiments-and-demand-for-foreign-labor/</link>
      <description>Immigrants in Japan have now reached a record high of nearly 4 million, accounting for around 3.2 percent of the country’s total population.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland’s Rare Earths Aren’t All That</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/trump-greenland-rare-earths-critical-minerals/</link>
      <description>The island may not be the treasure trove that some U.S. officials think.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binyamin Netanyahu’s plan to win Israeli—and global—hearts and minds</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/09/binyamin-netanyahus-plan-to-win-israeli-and-global-hearts-and-minds</link>
      <description>Israel’s longest-serving prime minister is determined to regain his nation’s trust and restore its image abroad</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Trump: ‘I don’t need international law’; Senate votes to limit Venezuela action; USAF consolidates PEOs; Marines’ own robot wingman; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-09-2026/410588/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Slain Mother and the Triumph of the Lie</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-officials-lying-about-renee-nicole-good-confers-maga-membership-by-stephen-holmes-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The killing of a 37-year-old Minneapolis mother by federal officials was certainly a tragedy and almost certainly a crime. But the administration’s response is something else: a demonstration that, in Donald Trump’s America, regurgitating obvious lies is how his followers and enablers prove that they belong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economic Roots of Iran’s Protests</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-protests-starting-december-28-response-to-economic-pressures-by-djavad-salehi-isfahani-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The protests now gripping Iran reflect, above all, economic grievances, which planned reforms are likely to exacerbate in the short term. Cash transfers and promises of lower inflation down the line are unlikely to be enough to appease a population battered by years of economic instability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millennials spend more time than past generations with their children</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/09/millennials-spend-more-time-than-past-generations-with-their-children</link>
      <description>America’s child-care gender gap is narrowing rapidly</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Quiet Retreat From North Korean Denuclearization</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/china-north-korea-denuclearization-xi-jinping-lee-kim/</link>
      <description>How Beijing’s gamble could backfire.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Will China’s New Export Controls Impact Japan?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-will-chinas-new-export-controls-impact-japan/</link>
      <description>China has prohibited dual-use goods, including some rare earth elements, from being exported to Japan.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story newsletter: The Donroe Delusion</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/09/cover-story-newsletter-the-donroe-delusion</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manus’ Meta Buyout Tests the Limits of a Transferable China Tech Model for Going Global</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/manus-meta-buyout-tests-the-limits-of-a-transferable-china-tech-model-for-going-global/</link>
      <description>Manus’ acquisition by Meta will be hard to replicated by other Chinese technology firms seeking pathways into the U.S. market.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s new dictator is a regime loyalist—and America’s hostage</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/09/venezuelas-new-dictator-is-a-regime-loyalist-and-americas-hostage</link>
      <description>Delcy Rodríguez called building a socialist state her “personal revenge”. Now Donald Trump wants to “run” her country</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the US Intervention in Venezuela Means for China’s Presence in Latin America</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/what-the-us-intervention-in-venezuela-means-for-chinas-presence-in-latin-america/</link>
      <description>Venezuela is one of China’s closest political and economic partners in Latin America – or it used to be.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan Eyes March 2026 Accession to the WTO</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/uzbekistan-eyes-march-2026-accession-to-the-wto/</link>
      <description>Tashkent’s progress with the WTO accelerated in 2023 and the finish line is in sight.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Overlooked Way to Close Africa’s Health Gaps</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-health-systems-crushing-out-of-pocket-costs-are-preventable-by-ndidi-okonkwo-nwuneli-and-ekhosuehi-iyahen-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although remittances from the African diaspora have grown steadily and consistently, their full potential remains untapped, because they usually fund immediate consumption rather than being pooled to drive systemic change. A new social model would make better use of the same funds, starting with health care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Africa, China’s FM Visit Signals a Predictable Partnership in an Uncertain World</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/for-africa-chinas-fm-visit-signals-a-predictable-partnership-in-an-uncertain-world/</link>
      <description>The annual visit to 4-5 African countries has become traditional – but each year it’s still accompanied by concrete objectives.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Can No Longer Afford Strategic Confusion</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/japan-postwar-strategy-no-longer-viable-by-taniguchi-tomohiko-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Japan’s central challenge is often framed in terms of China’s rise, that is only part of the story. Japan’s postwar strategic framework has become obsolete, and this touches on everything from politics and economics to the country’s alliances and even constitutional matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can China’s Military Actually Fight?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/can-chinas-military-actually-fight/</link>
      <description>It's one of the most consequential questions in the world today – and no one really knows the answer.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia Escalates Its Psychological War Against Finland</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/09/russia-finland-medvedev-stubb-threats-history-winter-war-propaganda-narrative/</link>
      <description>Reminiscent of its propaganda against Kyiv, Moscow is using history to threaten Helsinki.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s New Age of Empire</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-new-era-of-imperialism-costs-for-everyone-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the United States' illegal intervention in Venezuela, there is a palpable sense of uncertainty and foreboding, particularly among America's traditional allies. But it should already be obvious that things will not end well, either for the US or the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Now for the “Rules-Based Order”?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-rules-based-order-must-be-built-anew-by-daron-acemoglu-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By dropping any pretense of defending democracy or human rights through its intervention in Venezuela, the Trump administration has ripped off the mask and shown the US-led global order to be untenable. To rebuild the idea of rules-based international relations, we will need a new philosophical foundation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yankee Go Home, Again</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/venezuela-attack-augurs-a-new-era-of-us-intervention-in-latin-america-by-jorge-g-castaneda-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With his attack on Venezuela, US President Donald Trump channeled the US leaders who sought to “liberate” Spain’s former colonies in 1898. But just as the Spanish-American War produced few real gains in the 20th century, Trump's efforts to revive the Monroe Doctrine in the 21st are more ambitious than realistic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fate of “America First”</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/americas/fate-america-first</link>
      <description>The assault on Venezuela threatens Trump’s promise.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Imperial Age</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/new-imperial-age</link>
      <description>Trump, Venezuela, and a century-old vision of American power.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Total Defense for an Era of Total War</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/total-defense-era-total-war</link>
      <description>How to protect the vulnerable American home front.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strongman Politics and Thailand’s Upcoming ‘Khaki Election’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/strongman-politics-and-thailands-upcoming-khaki-election/</link>
      <description>PM Anutin Charnvirakul's Bhumjaithai party is likely to be the main beneficiary of the polls, which will take place against a backdrop of ongoing border tensions with Cambodia.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Nepal Decided to Support Naga Separatists from India in the UN</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/when-nepal-decided-to-support-naga-separatists-from-india-in-the-un/</link>
      <description>Declassified British Intelligence documents reveal that in the 1960s, the Nepal government decided to offer support to the Naga separatists’ delegation at the U.N.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 04:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysian Prosecutors Drop Charges Against Deputy PM and Key Anwar Ally</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/malaysian-prosecutors-drop-charges-against-deputy-pm-and-key-anwar-ally/</link>
      <description>The Attorney General's Chambers said that it was dropping the case against UMNO's Ahmad Zahid Hamidi in the “the interests of justice.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lao Communist Party Chief Reappointed For Second Term at National Congress</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/lao-communist-party-chief-reappointed-for-second-term-at-national-congress/</link>
      <description>The 12th National Congress saw a partial generational transition from the revolutionary old guard to a crop of younger technocrats.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 10: Sanctioned: The Inside Story of the Sale of Chelsea Football Club</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/suspicious-transaction-report/episode-10-sanctioned-inside-story-sale-chelsea-football-club</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over two billion pounds from the sale of Chelsea FC languishes frozen in a UK bank account. Why is that, and what happens next?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Pakistan Play a Role in Regime Change in Afghanistan?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/can-pakistan-play-role-regime-change-afghanistan</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conditions have changed greatly since the height of Pakistan's influence as an interventionist actor in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Interceptions of Shadow Fleet Vessels and the International Maritime Order</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/news-and-comment/video-commentary/us-interceptions-shadow-fleet-vessels-and-international-maritime-order</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The seizing of the Marinera tanker sends a clear message from the Trump administration that sanctioned shadow fleet vessels might not find haven under the Russian flag.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording: Venezuela’s Crisis: Regional Dynamics and Global Consequences</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/members-event-recordings/recording-venezuelas-crisis-regional-dynamics-and-global-consequences</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An online briefing and question and answer session with our panel of RUSI experts discussing the evolving security implications of the US strikes on Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
