<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>A corruption scandal costs Volodymyr Zelensky his top aide</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/11/28/a-corruption-scandal-costs-volodymyr-zelensky-his-top-aide</link>
      <description>Andriy Yermak amassed enormous power and lots of enemies</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story newsletter: What China will dominate next</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/11/28/cover-story-newsletter-what-china-will-dominate-next</link>
      <description>How we chose this week’s image</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Ready for an Overdue Fed Overhaul</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-fed-needs-an-overhaul-to-confront-the-coming-economic-transformation-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US Federal Reserve officials would rather “stick to their knitting” than confront the complex forces that are reshaping the economy. Unless the next Fed chair shakes the institution out of its complacency, continued policy-induced volatility and intensifying political attacks are all but guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does taping your mouth while you sleep have benefits?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/11/28/does-taping-your-mouth-while-you-sleep-have-benefits</link>
      <description>Proponents say it improves sleep and oral health</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Wants to Join AUKUS. That’s Impossible – and Irrelevant.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/taiwan-wants-to-join-aukus-thats-impossible-and-irrelevant/</link>
      <description>Taiwan doesn’t need AUKUS membership to strengthen Pillar II’s force multiplier effect.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens to Russia’s Ethnic Minorities After the War?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/28/russia-war-minorities-indigenous-ethnic-republics-empire-periphery-colonialism-ukraine/</link>
      <description>Mistreatment, exploitation, and Russia’s own history suggest a precarious postwar future.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Russia Pay for Its War on Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-mobilize-frozen-russian-assets-for-ukraine-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-and-andrew-kosenko-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many European leaders acknowledge, the United States has left Europe (including the United Kingdom and Norway) with no choice but to see to its own defense. Using frozen Russian assets to provide a Reparations Loan to Ukraine is a forceful step in this direction that Europeans could take without US involvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s Yazidi Community Faces the Future With Concern</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/11/28/syria-yazidi-sdf-sharaa-islamic-state-assad/</link>
      <description>Having survived Assad and the Islamic State, Yazidis remain suspicious of Sharaa’s government.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Best to Defend Australia’s Democracy in the Digital Age?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/how-best-to-defend-australias-democracy-in-the-digital-age/</link>
      <description>A recent survey highlighted that less than a third of the Australian population believe that “people in government can be trusted.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Corruption Is the Point</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-corruption-is-the-means-of-destroying-the-system-by-janine-r-wedel-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Donald Trump's use of the presidency to enrich himself is unprecedented in American history, it does have analogues in Russia and other former communist countries. In fact, by appointing incompetent subordinates who owe him everything, Trump recalls a tried-and-tested Stalinist practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Basel Consensus Is Cracking</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/illusion-of-regulatory-unity-is-unraveling-by-howard-davies-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Behind the facade of unity, global banking supervisors are split between fear of over-regulation and concern that easing rules invites a repeat of the 2007-09 financial crisis. With the US rethinking supervision and scaling back enforcement, its break from Basel III is becoming increasingly obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Will the US Debt Reckoning Look Like?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-unsustainable-debt-path-will-probably-end-in-a-painful-fiscal-adjustment-by-jeffrey-frankel-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For now, and in the foreseeable future, fiscal adjustment is a political non-starter in the US, where the prospect of higher taxes or cuts to Social Security and Medicare is a surefire way to lose votes. But this is probably where the country is headed, though it may take a severe fiscal crisis to get there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending Press Freedom in the Age of Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/key-to-saving-journalism-from-ai-misinformation-and-propaganda-by-martin-baron-2025-11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As authoritarian leaders seek to delegitimize independent news and AI blurs the line between facts and falsehoods, journalists around the world are fighting to be heard above a rising tide of misinformation and propaganda. In this environment, news outlets must assert their independence through rigorous reporting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump–Xi and Strategic Recalibration</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/trump-xi-and-strategic-recalibration/</link>
      <description>The phone call and implications for the Indo-Pacific</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s Quiet Coup</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/india/pakistans-quiet-coup</link>
      <description>The making of a new model of military rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Trump Gets Wrong About China</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/what-trump-gets-wrong-about-china</link>
      <description>Only a long-term strategy can counter the threat from Beijing.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belarusian President Lukashenko Begins First Official Visit to Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/belarusian-president-lukashenko-begins-first-official-visit-to-myanmar/</link>
      <description>As they have grown more alienated from the West, relations between the two repressive governments have blossomed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assam’s BJP-led Government Releases Nellie Massacre Reports Ahead of Elections</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/11/assams-bjp-led-government-releases-nellie-massacre-reports-ahead-of-elections/</link>
      <description>The two reports relate to the Nellie massacre of 1983, when mobs attacked villages inhabited by Bengali-origin Muslims, killing over 1,800 people.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
