<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Kelly sues Hegseth over penalties for 'illegal orders' video</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/sen-kelly-sues-hegseth-over-penalties-illegal-orders-video/410632/</link>
      <description>The combat veteran's 46-page suit says Trump administration attempts to punish him violate the First Amendment, separation of powers, due process, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran Escalates Protest Crackdown but Says Open to U.S. Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/12/iran-protests-currency-economy-us-military-intervention-trump/</link>
      <description>“We are not looking for war, but we are prepared for war,” Iran’s foreign minister warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 22:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro’s Trial Follows the Twisted Logic of the War on Terrorism</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/12/venezuela-maduro-war-on-terrorism-abduction/</link>
      <description>The U.S. government wants the power of war without the rights of prisoners.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who will cash in on Venezuelan oil?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/12/who-will-cash-in-on-venezuelan-oil</link>
      <description>Big rewards will require taking big risks</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Manager-Monarch Who Saved Oman</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/12/haitham-bin-tariq-oman-gulf-oil-diplomacy/</link>
      <description>Oman’s new(ish) sultan doesn’t do spectacle. He does spreadsheets. And it’s working.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and the Fed Are Now at War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/12/trump-federal-reserve-chair-jerome-powell-investigation-markets/</link>
      <description>The White House risks gutting the independence of the world’s most important central bank in its quest for cheap money.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Progress Has Been Made on Cleaning up Central Asia’s Uranium Legacy Sites?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/what-progress-has-been-made-on-cleaning-up-central-asias-uranium-legacy-sites/</link>
      <description>Four of seven high priority sites have been remediated, with work underway at a fifth, partially completed but apparently stalled at a sixth, and unfunded at the seventh.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now Comes the Hard Part in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-now-the-hard-part</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Now comes the hard part in Venezuela. Dictator Nicolas Maduro and his wife &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/after-maduro-us-test-venezuela&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;are gone&lt;/a&gt; but the regime is still in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2026/jan/08/maduro-gone-regime-intact-behind-the-scenes&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;power&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Most Venezuelans, particularly in the diaspora, are pleased and relieved. Many are also apprehensive. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration has decided to compel the cooperation of Maduro’s Vice President, Delcy Rodriguez, now interim president. It is not at all assured that she will be a reliable partner. The U.S. decision to work with those still in control was logical even if disappointing to some in the democratic opposition which, after all, won the presidential election overwhelmingly in late July of 2024. The opposition’s base of support dwarfs that of the regime but the military, intelligence services and police are all still loyal to the regime - at least for the time being. The Trump administration believes the cooperation of these elements of the regime will be necessary for the Trump administration to implement its plans for the country without further U.S. police and military actions on the ground. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration has said we will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-run-venezuela&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;taking&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; over the oil sector and President Trump himself has announced his intention to persuade the U.S. private sector to return to Venezuela to rebuild the sector. Oil production in Venezuela has declined by two thirds since Hugo Chavez, Maduro’s predecessor, was elected in 1998. This unprecedented decline was due to incompetent management, undercapitalization and corruption. Had Chevron not opted to stay in the country under difficult circumstances, the production numbers would look even worse. Resurrecting the oil sector will take time, money and expertise. The return of the U.S. oil companies and the infusions of cash that will be required will only happen if an appropriate level of security can be established — and that will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/after-maduro-us-test-venezuela&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;require&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the cooperation of the Venezuelan armed forces and police. Many senior leaders in those sectors are believed to have been deeply complicit in both the abuses and corruption of a government the United Nations said was plausibly responsible for “crimes against humanity.” Two of the regime figures most widely believed to have been, along with Maduro himself, the architects of the Bolivarian regime’s repressive governance are still in power, Minister of the Interior Diosdado Cabello and Minister of Defense General Vladimir Portino Lopez. They will need to be watched and not permitted to undermine U.S. efforts to rehabilitate the oil sector and orchestrate a return to legitimate, popularly supported and democratic government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;There are several considerations that the U.S. will need to keep in mind going forward. First, more than 80 percent of Venezuelans now live below the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wilsoncenter.org/blog-post/venezuela-more-mere-numbers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;poverty&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; line. Their needs must be addressed . Even the shrinking number of Venezuelans who aligned with the regime are hoping to see their lives improve. Between 2013 and 2023, the country’s GDP contracted by around 70 percent, some believe it may have been as much as 75 percent. As most of Venezuela’s licit economy is essentially moribund and the U.S. will be controlling oil exports, the poor will naturally look to the United States for help. Heretofore, the regime employed food transfers to keep the populace in line. That role should move to the NGO community, the church or even elements of the democratic opposition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it will be important to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuelas-key-takeaways&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;secure&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the cooperation of the opposition, notwithstanding the Trump administrations to work with Delcy Rodriguez and company as the opposition represents the majority of Venezuelans inside the country as well as out. It will also be necessary to pay the military and it is not at all clear that the regime elements still in place will have the money to do so once oil receipts are being handled by the United States. If the U.S. is to avoid the mistakes that followed the fall of Saddam Hussein, attending to the needs of the populace and paying the rank and file of the military should be priorities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration should also move as quickly as the security situation permits to reopen the U.S. embassy in Caracas. There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2026/01/09/politics/us-state-department-team-arrives-in-venezuela-for-first-time-since-maduros-capture&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;reporting&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; out of Colombia that the U.S. Charge in Bogota has already made a trip to Caracas to evaluate the situation. This is a good thing. There is no substitute for on-the-ground engagement and observation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which countries are adopting AI the fastest?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/12/which-countries-are-adopting-ai-the-fastest</link>
      <description>Rich populations and tech-friendly governments help</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Job applicants are winning the AI arms race against recruiters</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/12/job-applicants-are-winning-the-ai-arms-race-against-recruiters</link>
      <description>Companies have been hit by a wave of chatbot-generated applications</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Iran’s regime has hidden its brutal crackdown</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/12/how-irans-regime-has-hidden-its-brutal-crackdown</link>
      <description>It has cut off communication, but outsiders might help Iranians get back online</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The High Cost of Trump’s Amateur Diplomats</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-costs-of-amateur-diplomacy-by-jan-werner-mueller-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By sidelining professional diplomats in favor of amateurs who supposedly bring fresh thinking to the world’s most intractable conflicts, US President Donald Trump is channeling a long American tradition of anti-intellectualism. Inevitably, the United States will be made poorer, weaker, and more manipulable by adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: US bombs ISIS in Syria; Iranian protests swell; Execs rebuff oil plan; Meet the Army’s dronemakers; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-12-2026/410612/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro and Noriega: Assessing the Analogies</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/maduro-noriega-analogies</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asked if there were any restraints on his global powers, [President Trump] &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/live/2026/01/08/us/trump-nyt-interview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;answered&lt;/a&gt;: “Yeah, there is one thing. My own morality. My own mind. It’s the only thing that can stop me.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I don’t need international law.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;Nicholas Maduro’s fate seems sealed: he will stand trial for numerous violations of federal criminal long-arm statutes and very likely spend decades as an inmate in the Federal Bureau of Prisons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How this U.S. military operation that resulted in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/after-maduro-us-test-venezuela&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;apprehension&lt;/a&gt; is legally characterized has and will continue to be a topic of debate and controversy. Central to this debate have been two critically significant international law issues. First, was the operation conducted to apprehend him a violation of the Charter of the United Nations? Second, did that operation trigger applicability of the law of armed conflict?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/law-enforcement-rationale-invading-venezuela-050124147.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Trump administration has invoked&lt;/a&gt; the memory of General Manuel Noriega’s &lt;a href=&quot;file://Users/geoffreycorn/Library/Containers/com.apple.mail/Data/Library/Mail%20Downloads/1A15D3D7-C7AB-4C09-9E15-7032C20E9322/A%20similar%20action%20was%20taken%20in%201989%20against%20Manuel%20Noriega.%20He%20was%20arrested,%20indicted,%20convicted%20in%20a%20court%20of%20law,%20served%20in%20prison%20in%20the%20United%20States%20and%20in%20Panama.%20And%20the%20Panamanian%20people,%20the%20American%20people,%20are%20safer%20for%20it.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;apprehension following the 1989 U.S. invasion of Panama&lt;/a&gt;, Operation Just Cause, in support of its assertion that the raid into Venezuela must be understood as nothing more than a law enforcement operation. But this reflects an invalid conflation between a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;objective &lt;/em&gt;with a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;operation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suggesting Operation Just Cause supports the assertion that this raid was anything other than an international armed conflict reflects a patently false analogy. Nonetheless, if - contrary to the President’s dismissal of international law quoted above – international law still means something for the United States - what happens in Panama and to General Noriega after his capture does have precedential value, so long as it is properly understood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallels with the Noriega case?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maduro was taken into U.S. custody &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/venzeula-leader-arrest-maduro-manuel-noriega/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;36 years to the day after&lt;/a&gt; General Manuel Noriega was taken into U.S. custody in Panama. Like Maduro, Noriega was the &lt;em&gt;de facto &lt;/em&gt;leader of his nation. Like Maduro, the U.S. did not consider him the legitimate leader of his country due to his actions that led to nullifying a resounding election defeat by an opposition candidate (in Panama’s case, Guillermo Endara).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like Maduro, Noriega was under federal criminal indictment for narco-trafficking offenses. Like Maduro, that indictment had been pending several years. Like Maduro, Noriega was the commander of his nation’s military forces (in his case, the Panamanian Defense Forces, or PDF).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like Maduro, his apprehension was the outcome of a U.S. military attack. Like Maduro, once he was captured, he was immediately transferred to the custody of U.S. law enforcement personnel and transported to the United States for his first appearance as a criminal defendant. And now we know that Maduro, like Noriega, immediately demanded prisoner of war status and immediate repatriation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is therefore unsurprising that commentators – and government officials – immediately began to offer analogies between the two to help understand both the legal basis for the raid into Venezuela and how Maduro was captured will impact his criminal case. Like how the Panama Canal itself cut that country into two, it is almost as if these two categories of can be cut into valid and invalid categories. Lets start with the invalid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscribe to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;False Analogy to Operation Just Cause&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately following the news of the raid critics – including me – began to question how the U.S. action could be credibly justified under international law?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As two of the most respected experts on use of force law quickly wrote, there did not seem to be any valid legal justification for this U.S. military attack against another sovereign nation, even conceding the ends were arguably laudable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My expectation was that the Trump administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/caribbean-double-tap-counternarcotics-strike&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;would extend its ‘drug boat campaign’ rationale&lt;/a&gt; to justify its projection of military force into Venezuela proper; that self-defense justified U.S. military action to apprehend the leader of an alleged drug cartel that the Secretary of State had designated a Foreign Terrorist Organization. While I shared the view of almost all experts who have condemned this theory of legality, it seemed to be the only plausible rationale the government might offer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It appears I may have been wrong. While no official legal opinion is yet available, statements by the Secretary of State and other officials seem to point to a different rationale: that this was not an armed attack but was instead a law enforcement apprehension operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, as could be expected, Operation Just Cause – the military assault on Panama that led to General Noriega’s apprehension – is cited as precedent in support of this assertion. This effort to justify the raid is, in my view, even more implausible than the drug boat self-defense theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At its core, it conflates a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;objective &lt;/em&gt;with a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;operation. &lt;/em&gt;Yes, it does appear that the objective of the raid was to apprehend an indicted fugitive. But the objective – or motive – for an operation does not dictate its legal characterization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this case, a military attack was launched to achieve that objective. Indeed, when General Cain took the podium in Mar a Lago to brief the world on the operation, he emphasized how U.S. ‘targeting’ complied with principles of the law of armed conflict. Targeting, diversionary attacks, and engagement of enemy personnel leading to substantial casualties are not aspects of a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;operation &lt;/em&gt;even if there is a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;objective.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nor does the example of Panama support this effort at slight of hand. The United States never pretended that the invasion of Panama was anything other than an armed conflict. Nor was apprehension of General Noriega an asserted legal justification for the invasion. Instead, as noted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/assets/nsiad-91-174fs.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; Government Accounting Office report,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;The Department of State provided essentially three legal bases for the US. military action in Panama: the United States had exercised its legitimate right of self-defense as defined in the UN and CM charters, the United States had the right to protect and defend the Panama Canal under the Panama Canal Treaty, and U.S. actions were taken with the consent of the legitimate government of Panama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more complicated issue in Panama was the &lt;em&gt;nature &lt;/em&gt;of the armed conflict, with the U.S. asserting that it was ‘non-international’ as a result of the invitation from Guillermo Endara who the U.S. arranged to be sworn in as President on a U.S. base in Panama immediately prior to the attack. But while apprehending Noriega was almost certainly an operational objective for Just Cause, that in no way influenced the legal characterization of the operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The assertion that a law enforcement objective provided the international legal justification for the invasion is, as noted above, contradicted by post-invasion analysis. It is also contradicted by the fact that the United States had ample opportunity to conduct a military operation to capture General Noriega during the nearly two years between the unsealing of his indictment and the invasion. This included the opportunity to provide modest military support to two coup attempts that would have certainly sealed his fate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With approximately 15,000 U.S. forces stationed within a few miles of his Commandancia, and his other office located on Fort Amador – a base shared with U.S. forces – had arrest been the primary U.S. objective it would have almost certainly happened much sooner and without a full scale invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That invasion was justified to protect the approximate 30,000 U.S. nationals living in Panama. The interpretation of the international legal justification of self-defense to protect nationals from imminent deadly threats was consistent with longstanding U.S. practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Normally this would be effectuated by conducting a non-combatant evacuation operation. But evacuating such a substantial population of U.S. nationals was never a feasible option and assembling so many people in evacuation points – assuming they could get there safely – would have just facilitated PDF violence against them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No analogous justification supported the raid into Venezuela. Criminal drug traffickers deserve non sympathy, and the harmful impact of illegal narcotics should not be diminished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But President Bush confronted incidents of violence against U.S. nationals that appeared to be escalating rapidly and deviated from the norm of relatively non-violent harassment that had been ongoing for almost two years (I was one of the victims of that harassment, spending a long boring day in a Panamanian jail cell for the offense of wearing my uniform on my drive from Panama City to work).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With PDF infantry barracks literally a golf fairway across from U.S. family housing, it was reasonable to conclude the PDF needed to be neutered. Yet even this asserted legal basis for the invasion was widely condemned as invalid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on YouTube? If not, you're missing out on insights so good they should require a security clearance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Noriega was ultimately apprehended and brought to justice. But that objective was never asserted as the principal legal basis for the invasion. Nor did it need to be. Operation Just Cause, in my opinion (which concededly is influenced from my experience living in Panama for 3.5 years leading up to the invasion) a valid exercise of the inherent right of self-defense (also bolstered by the Canal Treaty right to defend the function of the Canal).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nor was the peripheral law enforcement &lt;em&gt;objective &lt;/em&gt;conflated with the nature of the &lt;em&gt;operation.&lt;/em&gt; Operation Just Cause, like the raid into Venezuela, was an armed conflict. And, like the capture of Maduro, that leads to a valid aspect of analogy: Maduro’s status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“However the government wishes to label it, what occurred in late 1989-early 1990 was clearly an &quot;armed conflict&quot; within the meaning of Article 2. Armed troops intervened in a conflict between two parties to the treaty.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That sentence is drawn directly from the opinion by the Federal District Court in response to U.S. opposition to General Noriega’s claim of prisoner of war status. Like Noriega, at his initial appearance in federal court Maduro asserted his is a prisoner of war. And for good reason: the U.S. raid was an international armed conflict bringing into force the Third Geneva Convention, and Maduro by Venezuelan law was the military commander of their armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government’s position on this assertion has not been fully revealed (or perhaps even formulated). But the persistent emphasis that the raid was a law enforcement operation that was merely facilitated by military action seems to be pointing towards a rejection. As in the case of General Noriega, this is both invalid and unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Existence of an armed conflict&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately following news of the raid, the Trump administration asserted it was not a military operation, but instead a law enforcement operation supported by military action. This was the central premise of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cl.usembassy.gov/remarks-at-a-un-security-council-briefing-on-venezuela/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; made at the Security Council by Mike Waltz, the U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations. Notably, Ambassador Waltz stated that, “As Secretary Rubio has said, there is no war against Venezuela or its people. We are not occupying a country. This was a law enforcement operation in furtherance of lawful indictments that have existed for decades.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This characterization appears to be intended to disavow any assertion the operation qualified as an armed conflict within the meaning of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ihl-databases.icrc.org/en/ihl-treaties/gci-1949/article-2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;common Article 2&lt;/a&gt; of the four Geneva Conventions of 1949. That article indicates that the Conventions (and by extension the law of armed conflict generally) comes into force whenever there is an armed conflict between High Contracting Parties – which today means between any two sovereign states as these treaties have been universally adopted. It is beyond dispute that this article was intended to ensure application of the law of armed conflict would be dictated by the &lt;em&gt;de facto &lt;/em&gt;existence of armed conflict, and not limited to &lt;em&gt;de jure &lt;/em&gt;situations of war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pragmatic fact-based trigger for the law’s applicability was perhaps the most significant development of the law when the Conventions were revised between 1947 and 1949. It was intended to prevent states from disavowing applicability of the law through rhetorical ‘law-avoidance’ characterizations of such armed conflicts. While originally only impacting applicability of the four Conventions, this ‘law trigger’ evolved into a bedrock principle of international law: the law of armed conflict applies to any international armed conflict, meaning any dispute between states resulting in hostilities between armed forces, irrespective of how a state characterizes the situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any objective assessment, the hostilities that occurred between U.S. and Venezuelan armed forces earlier this week qualified as an international armed conflict. Unfortunately, the U.S. position appears to be conflating a law enforcement &lt;em&gt;objective &lt;/em&gt;with the assessment of armed conflict. And, ironically, this conflation appears to be premised on a prior armed conflict that doesn’t support the law enforcement &lt;em&gt;operation &lt;/em&gt;assertion, but actually contradicts it: the 1989 invasion of Panama, Operation Just Cause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief applies expert-level context to national and global security stories. Grant yourself full-access to Cipher Brief expert insights, analysis and private briefings in the new year by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a Subscriber+Member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Judge Advocates have been taught for decades that the existence of an armed conflict is based on an objective assessment of facts; that the term was deliberately adopted to ensure the &lt;em&gt;de facto &lt;/em&gt;situation dictated applicability of the law of armed conflict and to prevent what might best be understood as ‘creative obligation avoidance’ by using characterizations that are inconsistent with objective facts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And when those objective facts indicate hostilities between the armed forces of two states, the armed conflict in international in nature, no matter how brief the engagement. This is all summarized in paragraph 3.4.2 of The Department of Defense Law of War Manual, which provides:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Act-Based Test for Applying Jus in Bello Rules.&lt;/strong&gt; Jus in bello rules apply when parties are actually conducting hostilities, even if the war is not declared or if the state of war is not recognized by them. The de facto existence of an armed conflict is sufficient to trigger obligations for the conduct of hostilities. The United States has interpreted “armed conflict” in Common Article 2 of the 1949 Geneva Conventions to include “any situation in which there is hostile action between the armed forces of two parties, regardless of the duration, intensity or scope of the fighting.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No matter what the objective of the Venezuelan raid may have been, there is undeniable indication that the situation involved, “hostile action between” U.S. and Venezuelan armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was an international armed conflict within the meaning of Common Article 2 of the four Geneva Conventions of 1949 – the definitive test for assessing when the law of armed conflict comes into force. To paraphrase Judge Hoeveler, ‘[H]owever the government wishes to label it, what occurred in [Venezuela] was clearly an &quot;armed conflict&quot; within the meaning of Article 2. Armed troops intervened in a conflict between two parties to the treaty.’ Labels are not controlling, facts are. We can say the sun is the moon, but it doesn’t make it so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prisoner of war status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, like General Noriega, Maduro seems to have a valid claim to prisoner of war status (Venezuelan law designated him as the military commander of their armed forces authorizing him to wear the rank of a five-star general). And like the court that presided over Noriega’s case, the court presiding over Maduro’s case qualifies as a ‘competent tribunal’ within the meaning of Article 5 of the Third Convention to make that determination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But will it really matter? The answer will be the same as it was for Noriega: not that much. Most notably, it will have no impact on the two most significant issues related to his apprehension: first, whether he is entitled to immediate repatriation because hostilities between the U.S. and Venezuela have apparently ended, and 2. Whether he is immune from prosecution for his pre-conflict alleged criminal misconduct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article 118 of the Third Convention indicates that, “Prisoners of war shall be released and repatriated without delay after the cessation of active hostilities.” However, this repatriation obligation is qualified. Article 85 specifically acknowledges that, “[P]risoners of war prosecuted under the laws of the Detaining Power for acts committed prior to capture . . .”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article 119 provides, “Prisoners of war against whom criminal proceedings for an indictable offence are pending may be detained until the end of such proceedings, and, if necessary, until the completion of the punishment. The same shall apply to prisoners of war already convicted for an indictable offence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means that like General Noriega, extending prisoner of war status to Maduro will in no way impede the authority of the United States to prosecute him for his pre-conflict indicted offenses. Nor would it invalidate the jurisdiction of a federal civilian court, as Article 84 also provides that,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A prisoner of war shall be tried only by a military court, unless the existing laws of the Detaining Power expressly permit the civil courts to try a member of the armed forces of the Detaining Power in respect of the particular offence alleged to have been committed by the prisoner of war.” As in General Noriega’s case, because U.S. service-members would be subject to federal civilian jurisdiction for the same offenses, Maduro is also subject to that jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This would obviously be different if he were charged with offenses arising out of the brief hostilities the night of the raid, in which case his status would justify a claim of combatant immunity, a customary international law concept that protects privileged belligerents from being subjected to criminal prosecution by a detaining power for lawful conduct related to the armed conflict (and implicitly implemented by Article 87 of the Third Convention). But there is no such relationship between the indicted offenses and the hostilities that resulted in Maduro’s capture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prisoner of war status will require extending certain rights and privileges to Maduro during his trial and, assuming his is convicted, during his incarceration. Notice to a Protecting Power, ensuring certain procedural rights, access to the International Committee of the Red Cross during incarceration, access to care packages, access to communications, and perhaps most notably segregation from the general inmate population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps he will end up in the same facility where the government incarcerated Noriega, something I saw first-hand when I visited him in 2004. A separate building in the federal prison outside Miami was converted as his private prison; his uniform – from an Army no longer in existence – hung on the wall; the logbook showed family and ICRC visits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concluding thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government should learn a lesson from Noriega’s experience: concede the existence of an international armed conflict resulted in Maduro’s capture and no resist a claim of prisoner of war status. There is little reason to resist this seemingly obvious consequence of the operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Persisting in the assertion that the conflation of a law enforcement objective with a law enforcement operation as a way of denying the obvious – that this was an international armed conflict – jeopardizes U.S. personnel who in the future might face the unfortunate reality of being captured in a raid like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it is not hard to imagine how aggressively the U.S. would be insisting on prisoner of war status had any of the intrepid forces who executed this mission been captured by Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is just no credible reason why aversion to acknowledging this reality should increase the risk that some unfortunate day in the future it is one of our own who is subjected to a ‘perp walk’ as a criminal by a detaining power that is emboldened to deny the protection of the Third Convention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China Built AI Dominance on Stolen American Silicon</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/china-ai-dominance-stolen</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/a-worker-is-operating-intelligent-equipment-in-a-workshop-to-produce-power-chip-packaging-and-testing-products-at-jiangsu-suxin.jpg?id=62639792&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C46%2C0%2C46&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Federal prosecutors in Texas, in December, unsealed charges and related details exposing a sprawling scheme that quietly siphoned some of America’s most powerful artificial intelligence chips into China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to court filings, a Houston businessman and his company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/houston-businessman-and-company-plead-guilty-illegally-exporting-advanced-semiconductor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;orchestrated&lt;/a&gt; a $160 million smuggling operation that moved thousands of NVIDIA’s top-tier processors overseas, evading U.S. export controls through falsified shipping records and shell transactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hao Global and its founder, Alan Hao Hsu, pleaded guilty on October 10, 2025, to participating in smuggling and unlawful export activities, including knowingly exporting and attempting to export at least $160 million in Nvidia H100 and H200 GPUs between October 2024 and May 2025. Investigators say the operation was funded by more than $50 million in wire transfers originating from China, and the U.S. has seized over $50 million in Nvidia hardware and cash as part of the broader investigation, with the seizures tied to the overall network, not solely this defendant’s operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The operation reveals a broader strategy: if you can’t build it, take it. With a blend of state-run espionage and corporate infiltration, China has turned technology acquisition into an art form. Their ‘all-of-the-above’ approach has allowed their AI sector to grow even as export bans tighten. By sourcing the hardware from elsewhere, Beijing has made the lack of domestic chip manufacture moot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Corporate Insider Pipeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same month that prosecutors announced the NVIDIA chip smuggling charges, the Department of Justice filed a superseding indictment against Linwei Ding, a former Google software engineer accused of stealing over 1,000 confidential files containing trade secrets related to Google’s AI infrastructure. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/2024/05/01/former-google-software-engineer-charged-stealing-ai-trade-secrets-while&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;indictment&lt;/a&gt;, Ding uploaded the files to his personal cloud account between May 2022 and May 2023 while secretly working for two China-based technology companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is believed that the stolen materials included detailed specifications of Google’s Tensor Processing Unit chips and Graphics Processing Unit systems, as well as the software platform that orchestrates thousands of chips into supercomputers used to train cutting-edge AI models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ding allegedly circulated presentations to employees of his Chinese startup, citing national policies encouraging domestic AI development, and applied to a Shanghai-based talent program, stating that his company’s product “will help China to have computing power infrastructure capabilities that are on par with the international level.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within weeks of beginning the theft, Ding was offered a chief technology officer position at Beijing Rongshu Lianzhi Technology with a monthly salary of approximately $14,800 plus bonuses and stock. He traveled to China to raise capital and was publicly announced as CTO. A year later, he founded his own AI startup, Zhisuan, focused on training large AI models. Ding never disclosed either affiliation to Google.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After Google detected unauthorized uploads in December 2023, Ding vowed to save the files as evidence of his work. Nonetheless, he resigned a week later after booking a one-way ticket to Beijing. Security footage revealed that another employee had been scanning Ding’s access badge to give the appearance that he was working there during extended trips to China. Ding faces up to 175 years in prison on 14 counts: economic espionage and theft of trade secrets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ding has pleaded not guilty to the charges on multiple occasions. He entered a not guilty plea in March 2024 to the original four counts of trade secret theft, and again pleaded not guilty through his attorney, Grant Fondo, in September 2025 to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courthousenews.com/ex-google-employee-pleads-not-guilty-to-stealing-ai-secrets-for-chinese-companies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;https://www.courthousenews.com/ex-google-employee-pleads-not-guilty-to-stealing-ai-secrets-for-chinese-companies/&quot;&gt;expanded&lt;/a&gt; superseding charges — including seven counts each of economic espionage and trade secret theft. Fondo has actively represented Ding in court proceedings, including a successful June 2025 motion to suppress certain post-arrest statements due to alleged Miranda violations, though no extensive public explanatory statements from the attorney or Ding appear beyond these court actions and pleas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The federal trial in San Francisco began in early January 2026, with jury selection reported around January 8, and Ding remains presumed innocent until proven guilty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Powered Cyber Espionage at Scale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The threat escalated dramatically in September 2025 when Anthropic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/news/security-incident-retrospective&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;detected&lt;/a&gt; what it describes as the first fully automated cyberattack using artificial intelligence to breach corporate networks. Chinese state-sponsored hackers conducted the campaign, which Anthropic assessed with high confidence, targeted approximately 30 organizations, including technology firms, financial institutions, chemical manufacturers, and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The attackers manipulated Anthropic’s Claude Code tool into executing 80 to 90 percent of the operation autonomously. Claude’s safety guardrails were bypassed by jailbreaking the system, disguising malicious tasks as routine cybersecurity tests, and breaking attacks into small, seemingly innocent steps that conceal their broader objectives. Once compromised, the AI system independently conducted reconnaissance, identified valuable databases, wrote custom exploit code, harvested credentials, created backdoors, and exfiltrated data with minimal human supervision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The AI made thousands of requests per second—an attack speed that would have been, for human hackers, simply impossible to match,” Anthropic stated in its analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This case is a huge concern for other companies that have almost fully adopted AI in their business operations,” JP Castellanos, Director of Threat Intelligence at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binarydefense.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Binary&lt;/a&gt; Defense, tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. “Instead of just using AI to draft phishing emails or assist human hackers, the perpetrators gave Claude direct instructions to carry out multi-stage operations on its own.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/interpol-cybercrime&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;implications&lt;/a&gt; extend far beyond technical sophistication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“An AI operator doesn’t have to sleep or take breaks moving at machine speed; the agent can do the work of dozens or more hackers, tirelessly and even without error, launching constant attacks that even human defenders would struggle to monitor, let alone counter,” Castellanos explained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chief Geopolitical Officer at Insight Forward, Treston Wheat, also noted the operational tempo represents a fundamental shift.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“AI-enabled operations can run reconnaissance, exploitation attempts, credential harvesting, lateral movement playbooks, and exfiltration workflows in parallel, iterating rapidly across targets,” he tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shift not only changes how operations are conducted but also reveals the hidden supply chains that enable them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeepSeek’s Smuggled Silicon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In early 2025, it became impossible to ignore the connection between black-market chips and stolen IP. It was then that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/expert-qa-inside-chinas-deepseek-ai-miracle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DeepSeek&lt;/a&gt; dropped the R1 model, claiming it could compete with OpenAI’s o1, but for significantly less. This, however, immediately set off alarm bells: How does a company hamstrung by U.S. sanctions move that fast without some serious ‘outside’ help?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports from The Information in December 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/articles/deepseek-is-using-nvidias-banned-blackwell-chips&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that DeepSeek is training its next-generation model using thousands of NVIDIA’s advanced Blackwell chips — processors specifically banned from export to China. The smuggling operation reportedly involves purchasing servers for phantom data centers in Southeast Asia, where Blackwell sales remain legal. After inspection and certification, smugglers allegedly dismantle entire data centers rack by rack, shipping GPU servers in suitcases across borders into mainland China, where the chips are reassembled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2025/12/10/nvidia-report-china-deepseek-ai-blackwell-chips.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;disputed&lt;/a&gt; the reports, stating it had seen “no substantiation or received tips of ‘phantom data centers’ constructed to deceive us and our OEM partners” while acknowledging the company pursues any tip it receives. The chipmaker is developing digital tracking features to verify chip locations, a tacit acknowledgement that there are enough smuggling concerns to warrant technological solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Castellanos described China’s strategy as deliberately dual-track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“China has been very open to being the lead in AI and semiconductors and the need for self-reliance in core technologies,” he said. “But also, externally, China relies on partnering with overseas institutions, building on top of Western open-source technologies, and acquiring advanced technologies through illegal means, such as through theft, smuggling, and forced transfers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The FBI’s Losing Battle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christopher Wray, the former FBI director, testified that the bureau oversees approximately 2,000 active investigations into Chinese espionage operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Chinese hackers outnumber FBI cyber personnel by at least 50 to 1,” Wray &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbi.gov/news/testimony/worldwide-threats-to-the-homeland-2023&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;testified&lt;/a&gt; before the House Appropriations Committee in 2023. “They’ve got a bigger hacking program than every other major nation combined and have stolen more of our personal and corporate data than all other nations—big or small—combined.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That scale reflects a long-running strategy rather than a sudden surge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“U.S. officials say China has long relied on a multi-pronged strategy to lie, to cheat and to steal their way to surpassing us as the global superpower in cyber,” he said. “It’s not just cyber intrusions, we are concerned about, but also human insiders stealing intellectual property. In the realm of AI, this can include insiders siphoning source code, research papers, or semiconductor designs for China.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese approach exploits multiple vectors simultaneously, according to experts. The Ministry of State Security operates human intelligence networks. The People’s Liberation Army’s Strategic Support Force conducts offensive cyber operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/02/06/us/chinas-lavish-funds-lured-us-scientists-what-did-it-get-in-return.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thousand Talents Plan&lt;/a&gt;, for example, then offers Chinese researchers financial incentives to transfer proprietary information to American institutions. By investing in and partnering with ostensibly private companies, state-owned enterprises gain access to sensitive technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export Controls Lag Behind Reality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The export control regime designed to prevent China from accessing advanced chips has proven inadequate in the face of Beijing’s evasion tactics. The Commerce Department’s Bureau of Industry and Security has repeatedly updated restrictions, most recently imposing sweeping &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bis.doc.gov/index.php/documents/about-bis/newsroom/press-releases/3158-2023-10-17-bis-press-release-advanced-computing-and-semiconductor-manufacturing-controls-final&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;controls&lt;/a&gt; in October 2023 on AI chips and semiconductor manufacturing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent Texas case shed light on how these smugglers operate. There was more to it than simply shipping; they used crypto payments and paper-only shell companies to conceal the money trail. To pass customs, they even removed the Nvidia labels from the chips. By the time those processors reached China, they had been bounced through so many different countries that the original paper trail was basically gone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Export controls are not a complete solution to IP theft or technology diffusion. They are best understood as a time-buying and friction-imposing tool,” Wheat observed. “If the objective is to prevent all leakage, that is unrealistic; if the objective is to slow adversary capability development, shape supply chains, and increase acquisition cost and risk, they can be effective when paired with enforcement and complementary measures.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chip industry, analysts caution, is facing a structural nightmare. We’re restricting technology that’s already been stolen and studied. The $160 million operation out of Texas proved just how easy it is to game the system — they lied on customs forms hundreds of times over several months, and it still took nearly a year for authorities to notice anything was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defending at Machine Speed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security experts are calling this the most significant tech transfer in history, and it isn’t happening by accident. By stacking insider theft, cyberattacks, recruitment programs, and smuggling on top of each other, China has found a way to leapfrog ahead in AI. They don’t have the domestic factories to build high-end chips yet, so they’ve bypassed the need for ‘original’ innovation by taking what they need. It’s a massive operation that’s making traditional defense strategies look obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The realistic U.S. approach is not to match China operator-for-operator. It is to win by asymmetry, such as scaling defense through automation, hardening the most valuable targets, and using public-private coordination to reduce attacker dwell time and increase attacker cost,” Wray said in his testimony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Castellanos emphasized that defending against AI-enabled attacks requires matching the adversary’s capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“To have any hope to defend against this, we have to multiply effectiveness through automation and AI, so basically fight fire with fire,” he underscored. “Doing this requires significant investment, new skills, and perhaps most challenging, trust in autonomous defensive AI at a time when many organizations are still learning basic cyber hygiene.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To prevent adversaries from acquiring sensitive technologies, the U.S. Government has, in recent years, implemented targeted responses, such as the Disruptive Technology Strike Force in 2023. Yet, even as FBI investigations increase and new indictments are filed, the fundamental challenge persists. Chinese intelligence services use unlimited resources, legal compulsion over Chinese nationals, and long-term strategic patience to operate in an open society with porous institutional boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s a challenge for policy makers; a multi-layered response and defense in depth is needed to protect the US AI technology base better,” Castellanos added. “Harden insider threat programs, accelerate public and private intelligence sharing, modernize export controls and enforcement, increase the costs or impose costs for the offenders of these attacks and lastly innovate faster to ensure even if China steals today’s tech, the breakthrough is already in the pipeline for tomorrow.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2026 Outlook Calls for Recalibration</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/2026-outlook-investors-policymakers-will-need-to-recalibrate-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The bullish AI narrative that dominated in 2025 is unlikely to continue overshadowing other lingering uncertainties, many of which reflect deeper structural shifts. Traditional factors underlying economic activity will be increasingly sidelined by national-security concerns, geopolitics, and domestic political machinations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Is Iran’s regime about to fall?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/12/the-war-room-newsletter-is-irans-regime-about-to-fall</link>
      <description>Shashank Joshi, our defence editor, examines the country’s steady decay</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering the US-China Economic and Security Commission</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/empowering-the-us-china-economic-and-security-commission/</link>
      <description>If passing legislation to deal with China is a remote prospect, the USCC should focus more on other tools with a higher chance of success.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Supreme Court’s Expansive Interpretation of India’s Terror Law Is Dangerous</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-the-supreme-courts-expansive-interpretation-of-indias-terror-law-is-dangerous/</link>
      <description>A recent ruling could pave the way for the government to term any protest or demonstration, even those that are peaceful, as terrorist acts.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China obsesses over America’s “kill line”</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/12/china-obsesses-over-americas-kill-line</link>
      <description>It is easier to talk about American harshness than Chinese malaise</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Revenge of Global Imbalances</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-revenge-of-global-imbalances-by-barry-eichengreen-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under France’s presidency of the G7, the club of rich countries will focus on major economies’ external deficits and surpluses. While the agenda makes sense politically, the economic case remains to be made.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026: The Outlook for South Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/2026-the-outlook-for-south-asia/</link>
      <description>Michael Kugelman previews the major events to watch: upcoming elections in Bangladesh and Nepal, the India-Pakistan conflict, and ever-volatile relations with the U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tajikistan’s External Debt Grows in Complexity</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/tajikistans-external-debt-grows-in-complexity/</link>
      <description>Growing corporate debt, the never-ending construction of Rogun, and lack of debt management transparency from the government add to the fiscal pressure on the country’s budget.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India Could Lead a Third Way in AI Geo-governance</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/india-could-lead-a-third-way-in-ai-geo-governance/</link>
      <description>India is facing complex choices in navigating China’s state-led control and the US’ chaotic and fragmented AI governance regulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea Denies Accusation of Launching Drones Toward North Korea</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/south-korea-denies-accusation-of-launching-drones-toward-north-korea/</link>
      <description>Pyongyang accused Seoul of sending drones to its territory. Seoul rejected the claim, saying it has no intention to make provocations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Delicate Foreign Policy Balancing Act: Let the Good Deeds Speak for Themselves</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/japans-delicate-foreign-policy-balancing-act-let-the-good-deeds-speak-for-themselves/</link>
      <description>For Takaichi, U.S. President Donald Trump’s decision to capture the president of Venezuela and his fiery rhetoric toward Greenland create a particularly difficult conundrum.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Central Banks Enabling Unsustainable Government Deficits?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-and-other-central-banks-enabling-unsustainable-deficits-by-raghuram-g-rajan-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent developments suggest that the US Federal Reserve's bond purchases are no longer just a &quot;monetary operation,&quot; but an essential component of the US government's fiscal financing. The sooner that the Fed and other similarly situated central banks recognize the trap they have created for themselves, the better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Foreign Policy Needs a Rethink in the Age of Trump</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indian-foreign-policy-needs-a-rethink-in-the-age-of-trump/</link>
      <description>New Delhi needs to go back to the drawing board and figure out how to reframe its relationship with Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Three Options to Turn the Screws on Europe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/12/trump-trade-europe-eu-dollar-depreciation-finance-exchange-rate/</link>
      <description>As the trade imbalance widens, European leaders need to prepare for likely retaliation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ratcheting Up the Pressure on Afghanistan’s Gender Apartheid</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/un-must-pressure-taliban-afghanistan-codify-gender-apartheid-as-a-crime-by-gordon-brown-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite recent efforts to make gender apartheid an international crime and to charge Afghanistan, countries have begun resuming relations with the Taliban regime. The United Nations must accelerate efforts to hold the Taliban accountable for its denial of girls’ and women’s rights, particularly their right to an education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s War Chest in Waiting</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/12/united-states-war-venezuela-military-development-finance-corporation/</link>
      <description>Washington's new tool of statecraft is a $200 billion checkbook.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran at the Edge: Reza Pahlavi, a Nation in Revolt, and the Great Power Endgame</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/iran-at-the-edge-reza-pahlavi-a-nation</link>
      <description>Will the regime fall? A longtime senior special ops strategist lays out the forces in play.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Dwindling Maoist Insurgency</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-subdued-maoist-insurgency-by-investing-in-security-and-development-by-shashi-tharoor-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India’s violent Maoist insurgency – which at its 2013 peak, held considerable influence in 126 districts – appears to be on its last legs. This achievement attests to the power of a holistic and persistent development-driven approach to addressing complex internal security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Lab gives Pacific Army division drone-building capabilities on the front lines</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/01/lightning-lab-gives-pacific-army-division-drone-building-capabilities-front-lines/410607/</link>
      <description>The small group of soldiers can produce gear—and then immediately take feedback to make it better.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 07:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Turnout in Second Phase of Myanmar’s ‘Sham’ Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/low-turnout-in-second-phase-of-myanmars-sham-election/</link>
      <description>Meanwhile, opportunist neighbors seek business ties with junta</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 07:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Greenland Falls</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/how-greenland-falls</link>
      <description>Imagining a bloodless Trump takeover.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of the AI Race</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/myth-ai-race</link>
      <description>Neither America nor China can achieve true tech dominance.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jerome Powell says Donald Trump has launched a criminal investigation against the Fed</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/12/jerome-powell-says-donald-trump-has-launched-a-criminal-investigation-against-the-fed</link>
      <description>The president denies all knowledge. A bizarre fight could get nasty</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 04:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Pledges $45M Assistance to Support Cambodia-Thailand Ceasefire</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/us-pledges-45m-assistance-to-support-cambodia-thailand-ceasefire/</link>
      <description>The announcement came as Michael DeSombre, the U.S. assistant secretary for East Asia and the Pacific, visited both nations for talks related to the border dispute.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rohingya Genocide Victims Finally Confront the Myanmar Military</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/rohingya-genocide-victims-finally-confront-the-myanmar-military/</link>
      <description>The International Court of Justice in The Hague today opens hearings into the genocide case initiated by The Gambia in 2019.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Boarding Russian-Flagged Oil Tanker Breaks Precedent: High Stakes on the High Seas</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/us-boarding-russian-flagged-oil-tanker-breaks-precedent-high-stakes-high-seas</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;If the US no longer abides by rules, how does it expect revisionist states to do so?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia, Malaysia Block Elon Musk’s AI Chatbot Over Generation of Sexualized Images</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indonesia-malaysia-block-elon-musks-ai-chatbot-over-generation-of-sexualized-images/</link>
      <description>The two governments said that there were insufficient safeguards against the Grok chatbot from being used to generate pornographic imagery.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines in 2026: Can Marcos Restore Public Trust?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-philippines-in-2026-can-marcos-restore-public-trust/</link>
      <description>In 2025, Philippine politics was dominated by political feuds and rising public anger at high-level government corruption.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the Contrition From Those Who Took Chen Zhi’s Money?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/where-is-the-contrition-from-those-who-took-chen-zhis-money/</link>
      <description>The alleged online scamming kingpin, now in custody in China, was once feted by Phnom Penh's foreign business elite.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
