<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>The Coast Guard's Mission in the Gray Zone</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-coast-guard-s-mission-in-the-gray-zone</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION&lt;/strong&gt; — U.S. defense planning rests on the assumption that wars are fought abroad, by expeditionary forces, against defined adversaries. For decades, those assumptions held. But today, many of the most consequential security challenges facing the United States violate all three. They occur closer to home, below the threshold of armed conflict, and in domains where sovereignty is enforced incrementally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shift has exposed a chronic mismatch between how the United States defines its defense priorities and how it allocates resources and respect. While defense discourse continues to stubbornly emphasize power projection and high-end conflict, many of today’s challenges revolve around the more modest and rote enforcement of U.S. territorial integrity and national sovereignty - functions that are vital to U.S. strategic objectives yet lack the optical prestige of winning wars abroad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sitting at the center of this gap between prestige and need is the U.S. Coast Guard, whose mission profile aligns directly with America’s most important strategic objectives - the enforcement of sovereignty and homeland defense - yet remains strategically undervalued because its work rarely resembles the celebrated and well-funded styles of conventional warfighting. In an era of increased &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/gray-zone-warfare&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;gray-zone&lt;/a&gt; competition and persistent coercion, the failure to properly appreciate the Coast Guard threatens real strategic fallout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the third decade of the 21st century, U.S. defense planning remains heavily oriented toward expeditionary warfighting and high-end kinetic conflict. Budget conversations still revolve around Ford-class supercarriers, F-35 fighters, and A2/AD penetration. This orientation shapes not only force design and budget allocations, but also institutional prestige and political capital. The services associated with visible combat power, with the Ford-class and the F-35, continue to dominate strategic discourse—even as many of the most persistent security challenges confronting the United States unfold close to home, in the gray-zone, without the need for fifth-generation air power or heavy armor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the most basic level, any nation’s military exists primarily to defend territorial integrity, enforce sovereignty, and protect the homeland. Power projection, forward presence, and deterrence abroad are important—but they are secondary functions derived from the primary purpose of homeland defense. Yet U.S. defense discourse often treats homeland defense as a background condition when it should be revered as the first priority. The result is a blind spot in how security resources are evaluated and allocated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Coast Guard operates at a unique point where law enforcement, military authority, and sovereign enforcement all converge. On any given day, the Coast Guard may board foreign-flagged vessels suspected of sanctions violations, police maritime borders against illicit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-u-s-coast-guards-quiet-drug-war-wins-amid-trumps-caribbean-strikes&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;trafficking&lt;/a&gt;, secure ports that underpin global supply chains, and maintain a persistent presence in contested spaces, like the Arctic, without inviting escalation. The Coast Guard is equipped to intercept illegal fishing fleets, escort commercial shipping through sensitive waterways, and assert jurisdiction in legally ambiguous areas. These activities rarely resemble traditional warfighting, they rarely result in a Hollywood blockbuster, and they can be accomplished without nuclear-powered submarines or intercontinental ballistic missiles. But these are not peripheral activities—they are arguably amongst the most important daily functions the U.S. military undertakes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Distinct among the military branches, the Coast Guard operates under a legal framework that is uniquely suited to today’s security environment. Under Title 14 status, the Coast Guard falls within the Department of Homeland Security, conducting law enforcement and regulatory missions on a daily basis. Yet, when needed, the service can transition to Title 10 status, under the Department of Defense, and operate as an armed service when required. This agility allows the Coast Guard to remain continuously engaged across the spectrum of competition, whether enforcing U.S. law in peacetime, managing escalation in gray-zone encounters, or integrating seamlessly into military operations. Few other elements of U.S. power can move so fluidly between legal regimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, despite such strategic relevance, the Coast Guard suffers from a persistent optical problem. U.S. defense culture has long privileged services and missions associated with visible, kinetic combat—those that lend themselves to clear narratives of victory, sacrifice, and heroism. The Coast Guard’s work rarely fits that cinematic mold. Its success is measured not in territory seized or targets destroyed, but in disruptions prevented, borders enforced, and crises that never materialize. Inherently quiet work with outcomes that reflect a force operating exactly as designed, although without generating institutional prestige or political support. In a system that rewards the loudest and the brightest, the Coast Guard’s quiet enforcement of sovereignty is easy to overlook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing to overlook the value of the Coast Guard carries strategic consequences. Specifically, persistent underinvestment in the Coast Guard weakens maritime domain awareness, reduces sustained presence in key waterways, and narrows the set of tools available to manage gray-zone competition. As adversaries increasingly rely on legal ambiguity, deniable actors, and incremental pressure to test U.S. resolve, gaps in enforcement become opportunities. In this environment, the absence of credible, continuous sovereignty enforcement invites probing behavior that becomes harder to deter over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advocacy for the Coast Guard does not require reassigning prestige, or elevating one service at the expense of others. It is merely an argument for strategic alignment. If territorial integrity, sovereignty enforcement, and homeland defense are truly core national-security priorities, then the institutions most directly responsible for those missions should be treated accordingly. As competition increasingly unfolds in the gray-zone between peace and war, the United States will need forces designed not only to win conflicts—but to prevent them from starting in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 23:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As divisions over Greenland grow, Europe examines its options</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/18/as-divisions-over-greenland-grow-europe-examines-its-options</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s tariff threats force Europeans to count their arrows</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>African trade has been vastly underestimated</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/18/african-trade-has-been-vastly-underestimated</link>
      <description>The continent’s food markets are more dynamic than commonly thought</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why America’s bond market just keeps winning</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/18/why-americas-bond-market-just-keeps-winning</link>
      <description>Vigilantes have shrugged off ballooning debt and attacks on the Fed</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New in SpyWeek: Storms Over Havana Syndrome, Greenland, Iran, Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/new-in-spyweek-storms-over-havana</link>
      <description>Also: France filling Ukraine spy gap, a new NSA boss, Top 10 Agent Flicks</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
