<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Flight tests validate mix-and-match approach to robot-wingman autonomy</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2026/02/flight-tests-validate-mix-and-match-approach-robot-wingman-autonomy/411412/</link>
      <description>The Air Force is using the A-GRA framework on its collaborative combat aircraft.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tulsi Gabbard and the Pro-Kremlin Belgian Businessman</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/tulsi-gabbard-and-the-pro-kremlin</link>
      <description>Gabbard&amp;#8217;s 2024 Vatican visit, arranged by Pierre Louvrier, a Paris-based, pro-Russia financier, triggered a TSA security alert&amp;#8212;not her opposition to Biden-Harris</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNO: ‘I need my stuff on time’</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/cno-i-need-my-stuff-time/411411/</link>
      <description>Adm. Daryl Caudle issued a direct call for transparent contracting with the maritime industrial base.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 02:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EU Don’t Need U.S.?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/12/eu-nato-munich-security-conference-msc-colby/</link>
      <description>Munich readies itself for a European defense renaissance.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Men lie, strategies lie—numbers don’t</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2026/02/national-defense-strategy-quantified/411395/</link>
      <description>The word counts of the new National Defense Strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Osprey makes emergency landing as military rushes to fix elusive mechanical woes</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2026/02/another-osprey-makes-emergency-landing-military-rushes-fix-elusive-mechanical-woes/411400/</link>
      <description>The latest MV-22 mishap was just before the Navy briefed Congress on maintenance progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China Conducting Secret Nuclear Weapons Tests?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-china-conducting-secret-nuclear-weapons-tests/</link>
      <description>A U.S. official suggested in recent comments that Beijing conducted a test back in the summer of 2020. So why is the Trump administration bringing this up now?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU Lacks Market Competitiveness—and Its Leaders Know</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/12/european-union-market-trade-us-china-competition-macron-merz-meloni/</link>
      <description>But European officials remain divided on how best to address U.S. unpredictability and Chinese competition.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeffrey Epstein’s Relationship With High Society</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/12/epstein-files-tooze-trump-clinton/</link>
      <description>Why the elites kept calling even after the sex crimes conviction.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US-NATO exercise rehearses taking out 1,500 targets a day to ‘overwhelm’ an enemy</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/us-nato-exercise-rehearses-taking-out-1500-targets-day-overwhelm-enemy/411396/</link>
      <description>Army’s 56th Multi-Domain Command is looking for electronic warfare-proof munitions, decoy drones.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE’s operation in Minneapolis is about to wind down</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/12/ices-operation-in-minneapolis-is-about-to-wind-down</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s administration claims mission accomplished</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘All the President’s Men’ Is 50—and Still Remarkable</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/12/all-the-presidents-men-50-remarkable/</link>
      <description>This film makes cold calling names from the phone book look as thrilling as Indiana Jones outsmarting the Nazis.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Puzzling Passivity of Russians</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/12/russia-protest-putin-war-iran-ukraine-authoritarianism-democracy-collective-action-rebellion/</link>
      <description>Repression alone cannot explain the vast protest gap between Moscow, Tehran, and Kyiv.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the Peninsula to the Indo-Pacific: The Rebirth of South Korea’s Marines</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/from-the-peninsula-to-the-indo-pacific-the-rebirth-of-south-koreas-marines/</link>
      <description>The quasi-fourth service overhaul is long overdue. But without expanded regional roles, Seoul risks turning a historic reform into an expensive exercise in symbolism.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Is Launching a Regulatory Assault on Drone Users</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/12/united-states-trump-drones-china/</link>
      <description>New restrictions try to shield ICE from being watched from above.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowded field of robot-boat makers vies for Navy's attention</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/crowded-field-robot-boat-makers-vying-navys-attention/411390/</link>
      <description>Industry execs say service leaders are showing real interest—even if they’re not yet buying in bulk.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Takaichi’s Landslide Victory Draws Mixed Responses in South Korea</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/takaichis-landslide-victory-draws-mixed-responses-in-south-korea/</link>
      <description>Takaichi’s tenure got off to a promising start with South Korea, but concerns remain that Japan’s rightward shift might upend the relationship.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make America Trustworthy Again</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-credibility-problem-could-lead-to-rupture-if-not-addressed-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The international order could still avoid a full rupture, but even temporary breaks leave lasting scars. By weaponizing tools designed to manage the global economy through international coordination, President Donald Trump is undermining US credibility and pushing allies to diversify away from American markets – perhaps permanently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Chinese Nationalists Want Russia’s Far East</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-chinese-nationalists-want-russias-far-east/</link>
      <description>Forceful territorial revisionism is unlikely – but China is pursuing its interests in Siberia by other means.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: El Paso, explained; Navy ships collide; Marines’ aviation plan; Estonia’s warning; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-12-2026/411387/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration Is Africa’s Only Way Forward</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/african-union-must-pursue-integration-starting-with-monetary-changes-by-hippolyte-fofack-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only a more united Africa can avoid “diversified dependency,” whereby primary commodities still dominate exports even as trade shifts eastward toward China and India. Heads of state and government convening in Addis Ababa for an African Union summit on February 14-15 must address the continent’s legacy of fragmentation in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Shakeup in Kyrgyzstan Continues to Unfold</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/security-shakeup-in-kyrgyzstan-continues-to-unfold/</link>
      <description>The Border Service has been taken out from under the GKNB and at least five people who signed a letter calling for early presidential elections have been detained.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checks and Balance newsletter: Why 1873 still matters for America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/12/checks-and-balance-newsletter-why-1873-still-matters-for-america</link>
      <description>Jon Fasman, our senior culture correspondent, examines how the backlash to Reconstruction echoes in today’s arguments over race and citizenship</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Mining Companies Leave, African Communities Pay</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/critical-mineral-race-risks-leaving-african-communities-behind-by-christopher-rutledge-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, multinational mining companies have extracted tens of billions of dollars in profits across Africa, while sidestepping environmental and fiscal costs and leaving host communities to foot the bill. Without reliable accountability mechanisms, the clean-energy transition risks following the same trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pro-Taiwan or Anti-China? Parsing US Public Support for Defending Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/pro-taiwan-or-anti-china-parsing-us-public-support-for-defending-taiwan/</link>
      <description>Most Americans support the defense of Taiwan. Is this motivated more by positive views of Taiwan or anti-China sentiment?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Advance in Guatemala</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/chinas-advance-in-guatemala/</link>
      <description>Despite a lack of diplomatic relations, Beijing has been remarkably successful in expanding its economic and even political influence in Guatemala.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomy on the Battlefield</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/autonomy-on-the-battlefield</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE IRON TRIANGLE — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue XX: The Buzz Around Autonomy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to The Iron Triangle, the column serving Procurement Officers tasked with buying the future, the Investors funding the next generation of defense technology, and the Policy Wonks analyzing its impact on the global order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This issue explores the monumental push toward autonomy in defense technology and the fundamental shift required in our understanding of command.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Backdrop: Redefining Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its purest sense, autonomy is the condition of self-government. When we overlay that concept onto military machines and armed drones, the immediate fear is that we are outsourcing the moral weight of life and death to an algorithm. I’ve seen the Terminator series, so I know what you’re thinking. No, you don’t need to learn how to make a pipe bomb. It’s not as bad as you think… maybe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the reality of military command is more nuanced. To understand autonomy in defense technology, I want to first be clear about how the military defines command.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Command is composed of three elements: authority, responsibility, and decision-making. Authority is the delegated power to make decisions and use resources. Responsibility is the legal and ethical obligation for everything a unit does or fails to do. And decision-making is the process of translating high-level intent into actionable orders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autonomy does not replace the commander; it enables the commander to aggregate and disaggregate aspects of Command and Control (C2)&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Specifically, autonomy allows a commander to delegate control to a machine while maintaining command. However simple this sounds, it is a monumental mindset shift for many commanders. To be successful, this will require reshaping some commanders’ understanding of technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To use autonomous systems appropriately, the commander assigns a framework of authority. This authority might be a benign task, such as &quot;Conduct intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance in order to identify the enemy within [defined area].&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the opposite end of the spectrum, such as in high-intensity, peer-conflict scenarios where there is no civilian presence, &quot;Identify and destroy targets in [defined area].&quot; The authorities a commander assigns to autonomous systems will depend heavily on their risk calculations and dozens of other factors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rewards: Why Accept the Risk?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember that all responsibility for the mission remains with the commander. Given the potential risks outlined above, why would a commander accept responsibility for an autonomous system’s performance? Because autonomous systems will be required not only for survival, but to fight and win on a modern, transparent battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operational Tempo (OPTEMPO). Autonomy denies the adversary the ability to reset during what would otherwise be natural lulls in combat operations. It enables a constant and consistent pressure campaign that human operators, limited by fatigue, cognitive bandwidth, and resources, cannot sustain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Force Protection and Attrition. We must shift our thinking toward lifecycle protection. Autonomy allows us to project power and achieve effects without putting a human in the loop–where they are most vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cognitive Decoupling. By reducing the pilot-to-platform ratio from 1:1 to 1:Many, autonomy frees the commander’s mind to focus on the strategic rather than the tactical, effectively reducing cognitive load.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Implications: The Path Forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To move autonomy to battlefield reality, we must address three critical pillars:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low-Cost Near-Exquisite Systems. Commanders cannot get comfortable with autonomy if they are afraid to lose their assets. We must continue to move away from high-cost platforms toward mass-producible, near-exquisite systems that allow for the thousands of training iterations required to build trust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interoperability. A quadcopter built in a Florida garage must immediately work cohesively with a bespoke system from a big defense prime. If autonomous systems cannot operate across-domains, if they aren’t vendor-agnostic, and if they can’t operate as one element of a swarm ecosystem, they aren’t force multipliers; they are a logistics burden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief applies expert-level context to national and global security stories. Grant yourself full-access to Cipher Brief expert insights, analysis and private briefings in the new year by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a Subscriber+Member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;End Vendor Lock-In. Continuous innovation is the only defense against adversarial countermeasures, and rigid multi-year contracts stifle technology iteration. We need a development operations model for hardware, where field feedback is transferred directly to engineers, rapid improvements are made, and systems are re-fielded. Vendors need to be held accountable–by losing profitable contracts–when they fail against this standard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary for the Triangle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Procurement Officer. Stop buying platforms and start buying ecosystems that support delegated authority, scalability, and innovation. Establish criteria for continuously evaluating technology and hold companies accountable. I commend the Department of Defense for acknowledging this need with more flexible contract mechanisms, but more can be done. There are many small, innovative technologies that might make a substantive difference if they are given an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Investor. Look for companies whose technology is not dependent on specific hardware, and for those who are open to rapidly partnering with other OEMs to overcome technical limitations. There are an unprecedented number of small defense technology firms in today’s ecosystem and there will be a consolidation within two-to-five years. If a company insists that every capability is vertically integrated, there is a strong likelihood that they will be outpaced by an up-and-comer or a conglomeration who is more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Policy Wonk. The debate isn't about whether machines will make decisions, but how we legally and ethically define the authority we give them. Setting conditions that promote and reward innovation will de-risk this transition now. We also need to think about the resources we provide the services for training, and how rules of engagement stack against those of our adversaries. This will all lead to better outcomes when it counts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The coming years will be a period of creative destruction for the defense industry. The era of proprietary technology is ending, replaced by an ecosystem where the only constant is change. We must reward the agile and hold the stagnant accountable. Whether it’s a garage-born startup or a legacy prime, the winners will be those who embrace the DevOps of hardware and the radical transparency of interoperable swarms. Autonomy is the catalyst; how we choose to fund, buy, and govern it will determine who leads the global order for the next century.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joey Gagnard is a Cipher Brief columnist who regularly shares his perspective on national security and technology via his Iron Triangle column.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing Up to a Spy: My Run-In with Aldrich Ames</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/standing-up-to-a-spy-my-run-in-with-aldrich-ames</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;I had an unpleasant episode with Aldrich Ames which taught me some life lessons. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was a mid-level CIA analyst working Caucasus and Central Asian issues in the 1990s. My job responsibilities then included reviewing agency participation in conferences located in that part of the world, helping assure the environment was conducive to the type of gathering being proposed and identifying any threats there might be. The reviews were usually noncontroversial and proforma, perfectly suited for a mid-level analyst.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometime, though, in mid 1993, a memo came across my desk from a desk officer in the CIA’s Counter Narcotics Center (CNC) proposing a senior level CNC conference in that part of the world that I worked. I felt strongly there were security risks associated with the gathering that did not justify agency participation. I was also concerned that the host country could not adequately address the conference logistics. I documented my concerns, did not sign off, and moved on, without giving the subject any additional thought. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following day, as I was reading through my cables, I looked up from my computer to find a very unkempt individual, about 20 years my senior with bushy eyebrows and a dirty, wispy looking mustache hovering over me, in essence, violating my personal space. He introduced himself as Aldrich Ames, the individual planning the conference which I had refused to sign off on the day before. He demanded to know how I had the gall to stand in the way of this important conference. I explained to this aggressive individual that I saw no upside to holding such a conference where he had proposed and explained to him my security and logistics concerns. He continued by berating me for not understanding the former Soviet Union. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure, I was in the earlier stages of my career but by then I had an undergraduate and graduate degree in Soviet Studies. I studied in Moscow and St. Petersburg. I wrote my master’s thesis on the role of women in Uzbek politics, participated in several summer workshops at Harvard University and other universities focused on Ukraine and Central Asia, had published articles in academic journals on Central Asia, had spoken on many conference panels regarding Soviet and Former Soviet Union politics, and had just completed a year as part of the CIA Director’s Exceptional Analyst Program studying the history and culture of Azerbaijan and Azeri language. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I stood my ground with Aldrich Ames and politely invited him to leave. Not to be deterred, Ames came back to my desk a few times. I was not there and my cubicle-mates alerted me to the fact that the unkempt man from the CNC was looking for me. He found me at my desk a few weeks later. By then, he was even more surly and patronizing. He told me that he was a senior operations officer and that I was thwarting important operations. I told him to get the Department of Operations to sign off and then come back to me. He then complained to my boss about the stupid analyst. She had my back but as a fairly young analyst, I was shaken by his demeanor and his threats. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Months later I heard that the CNC Conference was happening but maybe somewhere else. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Ames was arrested for espionage on his way to this relocated conference shortly thereafter. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I later came to know that Mr. Ames may have shared my analysis with the Russians. But, I was not in harm's way. More importantly, I remember the families and loved ones of those executed due to Ames’ betrayals and pay tribute to them and the colleagues whose careers he sidetracked. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just another ugly, though inconsequential story in the Aldrich Ames saga. What I learned as an analyst who unwittingly stood up to a spy is to trust your instincts, stand your ground, expertise matters, and that ultimately bad people cannot disguise that they are bad people. And Mr. Ames should have taken my advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world lacks tenor singers. Or does it?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/the-world-lacks-tenor-singers-or-does-it</link>
      <description>A voice that is made, not found</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China’s concert scene has boomed since the pandemic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/12/why-chinas-concert-scene-has-boomed-since-the-pandemic</link>
      <description>Youngsters are yearning for experiences</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s the point of AI in acupuncture?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/12/whats-the-point-of-ai-in-acupuncture</link>
      <description>Traditional Chinese medicine meets modernity</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What China is really up to in the Arctic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/12/what-china-is-really-up-to-in-the-arctic</link>
      <description>Its close co-operation with Russia is alarming many Arctic states</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weekly cartoon</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/12/the-weekly-cartoon</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/12/business</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/12/politics</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The European Onion is a joke whose time has come</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/12/the-european-onion-is-a-joke-whose-time-has-come</link>
      <description>A new model of European integration, without the tears</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Germany rearm its way to growth?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/12/can-germany-rearm-its-way-to-growth</link>
      <description>Defence spending may kickstart economic recovery, but it will take a while</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emmanuel Macron thinks Europe’s crisis demands buying local</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/12/emmanuel-macron-thinks-europes-crisis-demands-buying-local</link>
      <description>Not all European leaders are on board with his remedy</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RFK’s idea of making America healthy starts with making it politically sicker</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/12/rfks-idea-of-making-america-healthy-starts-with-making-it-politically-sicker</link>
      <description>And it will probably end with making it actually sicker</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alabama offers three tricks to fix poor urban schools</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/12/alabama-offers-three-tricks-to-fix-poor-urban-schools</link>
      <description>Adjusted for student poverty, southern states are beating the rest</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The decline of single-earner housebuyers in America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/12/the-decline-of-single-earner-housebuyers-in-america</link>
      <description>A tale of opportunities and costs</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The excruciating quest for a meeting room</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/12/the-excruciating-quest-for-a-meeting-room</link>
      <description>A tale of territorial ambition, power dynamics and water bottles</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private-equity barons have a giant AI problem</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/12/private-equity-barons-have-a-giant-ai-problem</link>
      <description>Their leveraged bets on the software industry may soon cause big trouble</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arm wants a bigger slice of the chip business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/12/arm-wants-a-bigger-slice-of-the-chip-business</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence is causing the chip designer to rethink its winning formula</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s hottest grocery store is also its priciest</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/12/americas-hottest-grocery-store-is-also-its-priciest</link>
      <description>Erewhon is testing just how much wealthy shoppers will pay for chicken soup</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Syria and Iraq cannot reconcile</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/12/why-syria-and-iraq-cannot-reconcile</link>
      <description>Iraqis still find it hard to forgive the Syrian leader’s jihadist past</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A deadly attack shows Nigeria’s security crisis is worsening</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/12/a-deadly-attack-shows-nigerias-security-crisis-is-worsening</link>
      <description>Jihadists and bandits are advancing on the country’s big cities</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Africa’s hottest new museum unravelled</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/12/how-africas-hottest-new-museum-unravelled</link>
      <description>A dispute over returning Benin bronzes to Nigeria is only part of the story</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t welcome Africa’s newest despot</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/12/dont-welcome-africas-newest-despot</link>
      <description>Samia Suluhu Hassan has caused Tanzania’s most dangerous crisis since independence</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central America’s biggest city is eternally snarled with traffic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/12/central-americas-biggest-city-is-eternally-snarled-with-traffic</link>
      <description>Where congestion brings smog, delays and lost productivity</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba’s fate may be in Marco Rubio’s hands</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/12/cubas-fate-may-be-in-marco-rubios-hands</link>
      <description>A more aggressive assault on the island’s communist regime poses difficulties for the secretary of state</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to solve the tenor shortage</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/how-to-solve-the-tenor-shortage</link>
      <description>A voice that is made, not found</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bipartisan Meeting With South Korea’s President Canceled After Opposition Leader Skips Talks</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/bipartisan-meeting-with-south-koreas-president-canceled-after-opposition-leader-skips-talks/</link>
      <description>An hour before the luncheon, the leader of People Power Party abruptly canceled, demonstrating his party’s strong antagonism toward the president and dashing hopes for bipartisanship.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voting Ends in Bangladesh With Steady Turnout in Calm, Festive Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/voting-ends-in-bangladesh-with-steady-turnout-in-calm-festive-atmosphere/</link>
      <description>Around 47.9 percent of voters had cast their votes by 2 p.m. today, according to the Election Commission.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump the Rebel King</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-both-top-law-enforcement-officer-and-criminal-gang-leader-by-slavoj-zizek-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a chief law-enforcement officer who has deployed gangs of criminal thugs to opposition-led cities and sued a government agency that he oversees for $10 billion, US President Donald Trump has taken the exercise of power to its most absurd extreme. He rules a state that he seeks to destroy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korean Intelligence Says Kim Jong Un’s Daughter Being Groomed as ‘Heir Apparent’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/south-korean-intelligence-says-kim-jong-uns-daughter-being-groomed-as-heir-apparent/</link>
      <description>NIS cited Kim Ju Ae’s increased public profile and policy influence, though questions remain over North Korea’s patriarchal succession traditions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO’s Next Test</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/nato-next-test-baltics-suwalki-corridor-by-agnia-grigas-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If NATO is serious about managing the Russian threat identified in its own strategy documents, it must focus its efforts where deterrence is most fragile. Lithuania's plans for a new training ground near the Suwałki corridor are thus a test case for assessing US and European resolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Jeffrey Epstein’s network</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/interactive/international/2026/02/12/inside-epsteins-network</link>
      <description>What 1.4m emails reveal about America’s most notorious sex offender</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia is turning stablecoins into banking infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/12/asia-is-turning-stablecoins-into-banking-infrastructure</link>
      <description>Speculative crypto may be tottering, but stable tokens are finding their feet across the region</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India, Pakistan and Bangladesh are weaponising cricket</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/12/india-pakistan-and-bangladesh-are-weaponising-cricket</link>
      <description>In South Asia, sports is geopolitics by other means</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rich world should beware Brazilification</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/the-rich-world-should-beware-brazilification</link>
      <description>When governments are indebted, high interest rates wreak havoc</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More and more countries are banning kids from social media</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/02/12/more-and-more-countries-are-banning-kids-from-social-media</link>
      <description>But the case for bans is weak and the benefits are uncertain</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Government Must Defend Taxpayers, Not Foreign Investors</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/indian-supreme-court-landmark-ruling-bolsters-case-for-tax-sovereignty-by-jayati-ghosh-and-diego-lluma-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Foreign companies have reaped enormous profits from India’s fast-growing digital economy while paying little or no tax by channeling investments through offshore entities. A landmark Supreme Court ruling challenges this model, but the government’s trade agenda pulls in the opposite direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethnic minorities are driving America’s startup boom</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/12/ethnic-minorities-are-driving-americas-startup-boom</link>
      <description>The covid-19 pandemic set entrepreneurial spirits surging—for some</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China’s central bank won’t save the country from deflation</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/12/why-chinas-central-bank-wont-save-the-country-from-deflation</link>
      <description>It’s not about the exchange rate any more</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese homebuyers are enraged by shoddy building standards</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/12/chinese-homebuyers-are-enraged-by-shoddy-building-standards</link>
      <description>Crooked walls and broken promises are harming China’s property market</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to put a price on a human life</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/12/how-to-put-a-price-on-a-human-life</link>
      <description>As ghoulish as it sounds, it is far better than the alternative</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t ban teenagers from social media</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/dont-ban-teenagers-from-social-media</link>
      <description>Restrictions would do more harm than good</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world’s most powerful woman</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/the-worlds-most-powerful-woman</link>
      <description>Japan’s prime minister has earned a once-in-a-generation chance to remake her country. Will she seize it?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giorgia Meloni’s Visit to Japan and the Japan-Italy Summit</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/giorgia-melonis-visit-to-japan-and-the-japan-italy-summit/</link>
      <description>Addressing challenges in an ever more complex international order.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Japan’s prime minister will use her massive new mandate</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/12/how-japans-prime-minister-will-use-her-massive-new-mandate</link>
      <description>A remarkable election victory will reshape Japanese politics for years to come</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Epstein files tell a story of justice denied</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/the-epstein-files-tell-a-story-of-justice-denied</link>
      <description>The slow progress of prosecutors is reprehensible</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could a BRICS Currency Work?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/brics-currency-by-jim-o-neill-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economists have long dismissed the idea that a BRICS common currency could challenge the US dollar's role in the global economy, and for good reason. But that doesn't mean there couldn't be new common rails for settling trade between countries that want to escape the long arm of the US government.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will India’s Kaladan Project in Myanmar Meet the 2027 Deadline?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/will-indias-kaladan-project-in-myanmar-meet-the-2027-deadline/</link>
      <description>A 109 km stretch in Myanmar’s Chin state remains to be completed. Difficult terrain, inclement weather and violent conflict are some of the challenges ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s SHANTI Act Is a High-stakes Wager on Nuclear Power</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indias-shanti-act-is-a-high-stakes-wager-on-nuclear-power/</link>
      <description>Any future nuclear incident perceived to be linked to diluted liability or weakened oversight would carry severe reputational costs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s NATO Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/trumps-nato-dilemma</link>
      <description>America can’t disengage from the alliance and also lead it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America and China at the Edge of Ruin</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/america-and-china-edge-ruin-lampton-jisi</link>
      <description>A last chance to step back from the brink.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel Is Quietly Annexing the West Bank</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/israel-quietly-annexing-west-bank</link>
      <description>The blunder that will imperil any Mideast peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calls Mount for Recount of Thai Election Amid Claims of Fraud, Irregularities</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/calls-mount-for-recount-of-thai-election-amid-claims-of-fraud-irregularities/</link>
      <description>The opposition People's Party has requested recounts in 18 constituencies, saying that there was &quot;clear evidence of irregularities during the tallying process.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain’s predicament will get worse before it gets better</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/12/britains-predicament-will-get-worse-before-it-gets-better</link>
      <description>With Sir Keir Starmer weakened, the government will drift left</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s New Economic Orthodoxy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesias-new-economic-orthodoxy/</link>
      <description>&quot;Prabowonomics&quot; focuses on social assistance-style provisions rather than the growth-centered development strategies preferred by orthodox economic policy-makers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia Treads a Fine Line Between the US, China, and Thailand</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/cambodia-treads-a-fine-line-between-the-us-china-and-thailand/</link>
      <description>The road ahead will be difficult after Anutin Charnvirakul’s election victory in neighboring Thailand.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police.AI - New Tech Tools for UK Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/policeai-new-tech-tools-uk-law-enforcement</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the National Centre for AI in Policing – dubbed Police.AI – UK policing is stepping up its pursuit of cutting-edge tools, but cost-effective, impactful delivery requires more than a new name.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title/>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia to Sign US Trade Agreement Next Week, Govt Says</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesia-to-sign-us-trade-agreement-next-week-govt-says/</link>
      <description>President Prabowo Subianto is scheduled to attend the inaugural meeting of President Donald Trump's Board of Peace on February 19.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singapore Goes to Space</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/singapore-goes-to-space/</link>
      <description>The city-state is seeking to capitalize on one of its comparative advantages as a regional center of STEM education and research.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What We Know About China’s Secretive Nuclear Submarine Fleet</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-we-know-about-chinas-secretive-nuclear-submarine-fleet/</link>
      <description>With the 09IIIB class and future 09V class, China’s development of nuclear-powered (and nuclear capable) submarines is at an inflection point.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
