<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Air Force’s drone wingmen have started flying with weapons</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/air-forces-drone-wingmen-have-started-flying-weapons/411625/</link>
      <description>Anduril’s collaborative combat aircraft began “captive carry&quot; testing last month.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the Talent Pipeline for America’s Security Future</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/talent-pipeline</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION –&lt;/strong&gt; Public service, at its core, is bigger than government service alone. Serving one’s country takes many forms, and in a time when the&lt;a href=&quot;http://pewresearch.org/short-reads/2025/01/07/what-the-data-says-about-federal-workers/#how-many-federal-workers-are-there&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;federal workforce&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is shrinking, recognizing the breadth of these opportunities is critical. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my roles as an adjunct at Texas A&amp;amp;M’s&lt;a href=&quot;http://bush.tamu.edu/DC/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Bush School&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an alumni council member at the University of Denver’s&lt;a href=&quot;https://korbel.du.edu/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Korbel School&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and a contributing alumnus at the University of Southern California’s&lt;a href=&quot;https://uscgpi.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Global Policy Institute&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I find myself fielding an increasing number of students who are grappling with how to navigate the future. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have been here before. After the Cold War, the so-called “peace dividend” led to&lt;a href=&quot;https://wagner.nyu.edu/files/performance/True%20Size%20Research%20Brief.pdf#:~:text=Although%20most%20of%20the%20decline%20involved%20little,administration%20eventually%20meet%20and%20exceed%20its%20reinventing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;reductions across government&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, yet the need for talented, dedicated individuals remained. Today, too, the demand is high, and the pool of students and young professionals&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/public-sector/our-insights/attracting-gen-z-talent-into-us-public-service&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;aspiring to serve&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; their country is deep. The three universities that have invested in me also continue to invest in carving paths for students to serve in a wide range of roles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government&lt;/strong&gt; itself is the most traditional route. Agencies may be smaller than in the past, yet as the senior generation transitions out,&lt;a href=&quot;https://natsec.usajobs.gov/search/results/?cmco=NatSec&amp;amp;s=relevance&amp;amp;sd=asc&amp;amp;p=1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;opportunities abound&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Indeed, a cursory look reveals many are hiring. Working at the state and local level opens the aperture even wider; I worked for the state of Colorado and interned for the state of California well before I landed at the CIA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching&lt;/strong&gt;, at any level, is an invaluable public service. Educators cultivate the next generation of thinkers, leaders, and professionals, shaping civic knowledge and analytic capacity that are foundational to democratic governance and national security. By equipping students with “&lt;a href=&quot;https://natsec.usajobs.gov/search/results/?cmco=NatSec&amp;amp;s=relevance&amp;amp;sd=asc&amp;amp;p=1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;deeper learning&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,” such as reasoning, problem-solving, and even persistence, teachers cultivate civic-mindedness and ensure that public service endures across generations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonprofits&lt;/strong&gt; also play a vital role. Whether focused on development, security, human rights, environmental protection, or public health, these organizations&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/opub/ted/2024/nonprofits-accounted-for-12-8-million-jobs-9-9-percent-of-private-sector-employment-in-2022.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;employ millions of people&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to perform roles that neither the market nor the government can fulfill. Serving in the nonprofit sector often requires ingenuity, resourcefulness, and a commitment to mission-driven work—traits that translate well into national security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International organizations&lt;/strong&gt; provide a global platform for public service. From the United Nations to regional alliances, these institutions facilitate cooperation, conflict resolution, humanitarian response, and development programs. Working in such settings&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schiller.edu/blog/the-value-of-international-work-experience-in-a-globalized-world/#:~:text=Gaining%20Unique%20Professional%20Skills:%20International,and%20resilience%20are%20increasingly%20valued.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;develops core skills&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, including diplomacy, cross-cultural communication, and policy expertise, all of which are transferable to domestic roles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think tanks&lt;/strong&gt; offer another avenue for impactful service. Analysts and researchers at these institutions produce rigorous, evidence-based insights that&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brussels-school.be/research/publications/beyond-unhelpful-metaphors-influence-think-tanks-us-foreign-and-national&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;influence government policy&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, public debate, and strategic planning, particularly in national security and foreign affairs. Think tanks combine scholarship with real-world impact, allowing professionals to shape the discourse on pressing issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry&lt;/strong&gt; provides opportunities that are increasingly essential to national security. Since joining&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leidos.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Leidos&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a Director and Account Manager in our Intelligence Sector, I have been humbled by colleagues who dedicate their careers to advancing technology and capabilities that the government cannot, and should not, develop on its own. Furthermore,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moodys.com/web/en/us/insights/public-sector/enhancing-national-security-with-public-private-partnerships.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;public-private partnerships&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are critical to maintaining US technological and security advantages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple Attributes Open the Way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our emerging professionals should cultivate a combination of skills, knowledge, and character to pave the way for any of these careers. Excellence, deep expertise, and technology acumen are pillars, particularly as workplace challenges grow more complex and technologically driven. While opinions vary on the most critical traits for young professionals entering public service, I have consistently found a core set of skills and behaviors that open doors to careers. I call them the &lt;strong&gt;Five Cs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critical Thinking&lt;/strong&gt; is perhaps the most foundational skill. Critical thinking is learnable, and educational research shows that structured analysis and&lt;a href=&quot;https://purdueglobalwriting.center/writing-to-think/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;disciplined writing&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are among the most effective ways to develop it. A well-reasoned, well-substantiated paper forces the author to evaluate evidence, challenge assumptions, and construct persuasive arguments—exactly the habits that public service demands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication&lt;/strong&gt;, both written and oral, is inseparable from professional effectiveness. Studies consistently demonstrate that&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/carolinecastrillon/2025/05/14/why-communication-skills-are-your-most-valuable-career-asset/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;strong communication skills&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; correlate with leadership, policy influence, and organizational success.13 Today, AI tools can assist with drafting, but understanding what makes communication compelling remains a human responsibility—one that requires being able to explain &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; something works, not merely that it does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creativity&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/rachelwells/2024/01/28/70-of-employers-say-creative-thinking-is-most-in-demand-skill-in-2024/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;enables professionals&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to solve novel and ill-structured problems. Research on innovation in public organizations shows that creative thinking improves adaptability and problem-solving in complex environments, including national security contexts. Future public servants can nurture creativity through interdisciplinary exposure, experimentation, and tolerance for intellectual risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curiosity&lt;/strong&gt; drives learning, adaptability, and sustained professional growth. Educational and cognitive&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertsmith.com/blog/the-role-of-curiosity-in-career-growth-and-lifelong-learning/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;research links curiosity to deeper knowledge&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; acquisition, improved performance, and long-term expertise development. In a field defined by evolving threats, curiosity is not optional—it is a professional obligation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; is essential in environments where no single individual or institution holds all the answers. Organizational&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallup.com/cliftonstrengths/en/655436/collaboration-at-work.aspx&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;research consistently shows&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that collaborative teams outperform individuals when addressing complex, high-stakes problems. Collaboration transforms individual competence into collective effectiveness, a cornerstone of public service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author's views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 01:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cognitive Battlefield is Now Decisive Terrain</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-cognitive-battlefield-is-now-decisive-terrain</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION --&lt;/strong&gt; Senior policymakers, military leaders, technologists and narrative strategists had one thing on their minds as they gathered in a Reston &lt;a href=&quot;https://information-professionals.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Pinnacle_2026_Agenda_10Feb2026.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conference room&lt;/a&gt; last week - how decision advantage, psychological leverage, and narrative dominance are increasingly capable of determining strategic outcomes. Cognitive warfare - once treated as an adjunct to cyber or information operations - is becoming a primary instrument of power and the implications are profound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clausewitz wrote that the center of gravity in war is the source of an adversary’s strength. In today’s environment, that center of gravity is increasingly ideological and psychological. Unity and will - both domestic and allied - are strategic assets. Information is not merely a supporting function. It’s a weapon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contest unfolding in the gray zone is fundamentally about narrative. Not propaganda in the blunt Cold War sense, but sustained, cumulative influence campaigns that shape how populations interpret reality. These efforts operate across media, social platforms, text messaging networks, gaming environments, and increasingly, AI-driven platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subtle Corrosion Beats Spectacular Attack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most important insights shared last week centered on the cycle of desensitization. Consider the steady drumbeat of cyber intrusions attributed to China or Russia. Each incident sparks temporary outrage, but repetition normalizes the activity. Over time, the public and sometimes policymakers, stop reacting. Strategic corrosion sets in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is cognitive attrition. It does not rely on a single catastrophic blow. Instead, it leverages small, atmospheric messages that accumulate. A fabricated report of a measles outbreak in Ukraine, spread via text messages. Repeated claims that Western institutions are corrupt or incompetent. False narratives injected into local conversations. Individually trivial. Collectively transformative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cumulative effect resembles what some participants described as a “cognitive supply chain”- disinformation introduced through multiple channels, actors, and devices over time, reinforcing itself until it feels like truth. In this environment, the question is not simply whether a narrative is false. It is whether the repetition of that narrative alters perception faster than truth can catch up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If traditional principles of war emphasize mass and maneuver, today’s information battlefield demands speed, scale, and persistence. Speed, because narratives form quickly and harden fast. Scale, because digital transport layers allow messages to reach millions instantly. Persistence, because influence is cumulative. It rewards actors willing to repeat, reinforce, and adapt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Military leaders are increasingly recognizing that communications is not a peripheral function, it is a commander’s business. Every action or inaction is an information operation. Tone, repetition, and secondary amplification matter as much as initial statements. And dominating that narrative requires dominating the transport layers that carry it. That includes terrestrial networks, undersea cables, satellite infrastructure, and increasingly, space-based assets. Space is not peripheral to information warfare; it is foundational.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another critical component to consider is that of attribution. In the cyber domain, attackers benefit from ambiguity. If malicious actors can hide behind plausible deniability or if governments can shield them, deterrence collapses. Credible attribution raises costs. It narrows safe havens. It signals resolve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some countries are beginning to codify this posture. Latvia, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.idea.int/democracytracker/report/latvia/may-2024#:~:text=Parliament%20criminalises%20use%20of%20deep,public%20official%20by%20the%20Parliament.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has criminalized election-related fake news&lt;/a&gt; and deepfakes, recognizing that information manipulation is not abstract speech but a direct threat to democratic integrity. The United States faces a harder question: are our legal and institutional structures optimized for cognitive deterrence? Or are they still calibrated for a previous era of warfare?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rise of Agentic Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the cognitive domain is decisive, technology will be central.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next frontier is not simply artificial intelligence, but agentic architecture - systems capable of augmenting commander decision-making in real time. The goal is not automation for its own sake. It is better recommendations. Faster synthesis. Clearer visibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Architecture matters and open, modular systems are essential. Black boxes are strategically dangerous. Defense institutions need plug-and-play capabilities that allow integration of new tools as threats evolve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reliability, not feature proliferation, should guide procurement – think more Amazon.com rather than bespoke. Outcome-based acquisition must replace programmatic inertia. A culture of velocity must supplant a culture of compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Afghanistan, smaller, foreign terrorist organizations were easier to degrade than deeply embedded, locally rooted movements like the Taliban. Structure mattered. Networks with widespread local integration were far more resilient. The same principle applies to narrative ecosystems. Loosely connected but culturally embedded influence networks are harder to disrupt than centralized propaganda hubs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If adversaries build durable cognitive infrastructure across diaspora communities, digital platforms, and local influencers, countering them requires more than takedowns. It requires building alternative narratives and actions with comparable persistence and legitimacy. Cognitive advantage requires a network of networks approach (think private-public), operating at the intersections of shared security interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural Terrain Is Strategic Terrain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most underappreciated shift in today’s information environment is cultural. Gaming now plays a role similar to Hollywood’s influence after World War II. Streaming platforms dominate storytelling. Media consumption patterns are fragmented and algorithmically curated. Stories remain, as one speaker observed, “the fuel of the human soul.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For decades, institutions like Voice of America succeeded because audiences sought out American content. The positive narrative of opportunity and possibility carried weight. In today’s environment, focusing solely on countering adversaries may be insufficient. Affirmative narratives about democratic resilience, economic opportunity, and alliance strength remain strategic assets. If the center of gravity is ideological, then cultural confidence is not soft power. It is core power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of this is executable without human capital. Building a cognitive arsenal requires building a cognitive workforce - professionals who are fluent in AI, media ecosystems, psychology, geospatial intelligence, and policy. Upskilling is not optional. Institutions must cultivate interdisciplinary talent capable of integrating technology and narrative strategy. They must also accelerate collaboration across government, private sector, and research institutions. And Government is looking to the private sector for training, skill development, and use of advanced technology, methods and applications. The adversary does not operate in stovepipes. Neither can we.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important question raised at that conference in Reston may have been the simplest: Are we structured to enact our own strategy?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States possesses extraordinary technological and intellectual advantages. But advantages unrealized are advantages lost. If cognitive warfare is indeed the new frontier of power, then institutional adaptation- not incremental reform - will determine success. Speed, modularity, reliable attribution, cultural fluency, and decision-centric AI must move from theory to practice. Because in this domain, the battlefield is not a distant theater. It is perception itself. And perception, once shifted, is far harder to reclaim than territory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://information-professionals.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Pinnacle_2026_Agenda_10Feb2026.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pinnacle Conference&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; was hosted by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://information-professionals.org/event/pinnacle-2025/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Information Professionals Association&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nationalcenterfornarrativeintelligence.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The National Center for Narrative Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and The Cipher Brief at the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carahsoft.com/carahsoft-conference-collaboration-center&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carahsoft Conference &amp; Collaboration Center&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carahsoft.com/carahsoft-conference-collaboration-center&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 01:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Force reaches deal with Northrop to expand B-21 production</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/air-force-reaches-deal-northrop-expand-b-21-production/411624/</link>
      <description>The Pentagon wants to spend $4.5 billion in bomber-related reconciliation funds this year alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 203: Fictional intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2026/02/defense-one-radio-ep-203-fictional-intelligence/411586/</link>
      <description>The authors of a new series discuss how they're exploring the future of conflict through short stories.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 23:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Drug Lord’s Killing Sparks Widespread Violence</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/mexico-cartel-leader-oseguera-cervantes-killed-violence-jalisco-el-mencho/</link>
      <description>Local authorities are scrambling to restore order amid a mounting death toll.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 22:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Loves Golden Dome. His Own White House Is Slow-Rolling Spending</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/golden-dome-spending-omb-budget-pentagon-trump-missile-defense-drones/</link>
      <description>Billions in approved spending held up by Office of Management and Budget.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 21:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Cuba Policy Is Backing Mexico Into a Corner</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/cuba-mexico-trump-sheinbaum-oil-tariffs-rubio/</link>
      <description>Washington is putting pressure on Havana’s last lifeline.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killing Mencho</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/killing-mencho</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/the-national-guard-in-mexico-conducts-an-operation-following-the-death-of-nemesio-oseguera-cervantes-el-mencho-leader-of-the.jpg?id=64989132&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C52%2C0%2C52&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIPHER BRIEF REPORTING&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;—&lt;/strong&gt; Exactly who tracked El Mencho, the world’s most wanted and feared drug lord, to a heavily armed safe house in a remote Sierra Madre town is a secret, for now. The&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gob.mx/defensa/prensa/la-secretaria-de-la-defensa-nacional-informa-sobre-una-operacion-para-la-detencion-de-ruben-n-a-mencho&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Mexican government&lt;/a&gt; has revealed only that its air force and special forces commandos descended on a safe house in the quaint Sierra Madre town of Tapalpa early yesterday, encountered gunfire and returned it, killing four cartel gunmen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;El Mencho, whose real name is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/nemesio-ruben-oseguera-cervantes-el-mencho-2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nemesio Rubén Oseguera Cervantes&lt;/a&gt;, is the 59-year-old founder and leader of the Cartel de Jalisco Nueva Generación (CJNG). Cervantes was wounded in the exchange of gunfire, loaded onto a Mexican military aircraft and flown to Mexico City. According to officials, he didn’t survive the flight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials announced that they seized “various weapons and armored vehicles… including rocket launchers capable of shooting down aircraft and destroying armored vehicles” as a result of the raid. Such heavy military-grade weapons don’t just materialize without somebody knowing about them. A lot of people, in fact. Who sold them to Mencho’s paramilitary organization? Where did they originate? Are there others? Officials won’t have the opportunity to interrogate Cervantes about the influential people who were on his payroll as he grew his ultra-violent cartel into a global powerhouse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But according to DEA intelligence, his cartel is worth billions and has a presence in all 50 American states and 40 countries. Some American agents believe the Mexican government never wanted to take him alive. In fact, for most of his career, as he was consolidating his power, Mexican leaders have told the U.S. that their forces were unable to find and arrest him. What changed? Experts believe at least two things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, Mexican leaders finally got fed up with El Mencho’s blood-soaked reign. “The CJNG was public enemy number one” for President Claudia Sheinbaum’s administration, Michael Chavarria, formerly the Drug Enforcement Administration’s senior leader in Guadalajara, the Mexican cartels’ original base of operations, told &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s the one cartel out of favor with President Claudia Sheinbaum, especially as it was responsible for the attempt on the life of Security Secretary Omar Garcia Harfuch, just prior to Sheinbaum’s election.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Garcia Harfuch, an aggressive, outspoken crime-fighter considered to be Mexico’s second most powerful official, survived a cartel assassination attempt in 2020, when he was Mexico City’s police chief. He became the CJNG’s implacable nemesis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, under pressure from President Donald Trump and the U.S. Congress, Sheinbaum and other top officials started collaborating openly with the U.S. military and intelligence community, an unthinkable event just a few years ago. But that changed with the election of Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/insight/us-navy-seals-head-to-mexico-amid-tensions/gm-066358B091?gemSnapshotKey=066358B091-snapshot-0&amp;amp;ocid=bingnewssearch&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U.S. Navy’s Seal Team 2&lt;/a&gt; arrived in Mexico around Feb. 16, ostensibly for a training exercise with Mexican military counterparts aimed at interdicting Chinese shipments of chemical precursors used to make the deadly opioid fentanyl, which has killed hundreds of thousands of Americans. The timing is noteworthy. According to U.S. officials, Navy SEALs trained elite Mexican navy special forces units that captured, among others, infamous drug kingpins&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/02/12/us/what-it-was-like-to-capture-el-chapo-donovan&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Joaquin “El Chapo” Guzman&lt;/a&gt; in 2016 and&lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/drug-lord-rafael-caro-quintero-captured-mexico-dea-7ff3005d4c848697458d73c669a72e6f&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Rafael Caro Quintero&lt;/a&gt; in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those operations and many others, DEA agents posted to Mexico and along the border provided intelligence gleaned from scores of paid informants recruited over decades. Many operations failed, apparently because they were compromised, but enough succeeded to convince President Trump, who declared drug trafficking and illegal migration top national security threats, to order the CIA and other U.S. intelligence agencies to step up their intelligence collections aimed at the Mexican underworld. The CIA reportedly added more drone surveillance flights over the border region as a result. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But sharing intelligence with the Mexican government has always been a fraught enterprise. Some plans were slow walked. For others, operational security was compromised by corruption at every level of the Mexican government. Sheinbaum’s predecessor, leftist Andrés Manuel López Obrador, openly disdained U.S. anti-drug efforts and famously said he would treat the crime cartels with &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/mexico-drug-cartels-migrants-hugs-not-bullets-violence-5cf8bbefe68ea9762a0bdd23868029f3&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“hugs, not bullets.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The CJNG established a nation-wide network of corrupt alliances among federal, state, and local police and regional military – sufficient to afford them a degree of protection,” Chavarria told us. The DEA had recruited plenty of human sources inside Mexico over the decades, but agents complained. The problem was getting the Mexican government to use that intelligence to take action against key cartel lieutenants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have deep experience in national security and something to say? Drop us a note at &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thecipherbrief.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;info@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In December 2024, as the CJNG’s power inside Mexico and around the world expanded precipitously, the Biden administration raised the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/nemesio-ruben-oseguera-cervantes-el-mencho-2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reward&lt;/a&gt; for El Mencho from $10 million to $15 million. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As soon as he took office for the second time, Trump designated the CJNG and other Mexican cartels as foreign terrorist organizations. Trump himself repeatedly pressed Sheinbaum to allow the U.S. military to mount anti-cartel operations deep in Mexican territory. She always refused. Trump and her team were warned that such incursions would inflame Mexican politicians and likely backfire, damaging Sheinbaum’s ability to work with the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The compromise seems to have been that all boots visible on the ground and all triggers pulled would be strictly Mexican, while, behind the scenes, U.S. law enforcement, military and intelligence community personnel would provide “intelligence support,” as White House spokesperson &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/PressSec/status/2025751007594971346?s=20&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Karoline Leavitt&lt;/a&gt; posted yesterday on X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though El Mencho has been declared dead, U.S. security experts say the war on the cartels is not even close to being over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“He died like a dog,” Rep. &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/RepDanCrenshaw/status/2025656536488370579?s=20&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dan Crenshaw, R-Tex.,&lt;/a&gt; a Navy SEAL veteran who has led Congressional anti-cartel initiatives, posted on X yesterday. “Cause for celebration – absolutely - but not a victory lap. Now, more than ever, it is critical to keep the pressure on the Mexican cartels.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DEA veterans say that El Mencho will be quickly replaced by one of his key lieutenants, probably his stepson, Juan Carlos Valencia Gonzalez, 41, known as El R-3, El JP, Tricky Tres or simply 03. He inherits narco DNA, not just from Mencho, a farm boy-turned-enforcer but, even more importantly from the Valencia clan, who are narco royalty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“El Mencho married into the Valencia family, taking Rosalinda Gonzalez Valencia as his wife,” says Chavarria, an expert on the Valencias and author of the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3OWwrBs&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Junior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, about a DEA penetration of the cartels. “This is a common practice among drug trafficking families – designed to solidify loyalty and to protect against betrayal. Narco intermarriages were and are regularly encountered in Mexico’s underworld.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The operation against Mencho is more about cracking the idea that powerful cartel leaders operate with impunity than bringing about the downfall of a cartel,” says Carlos Olivo, formerly DEA’s agent in charge in Guadalajara and assistant agent in charge in the key border city of El Paso. “Mencho had near absolute control in that area of Jalisco and for that to be penetrated and successful shows us that a willing partner can indeed turn the tide in Mexico,” he told &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Olivo, an ex-Marine who led a DEA team hunting Mencho until recently and is now writing a book about the CJNG, warns that taking down the kingpin and his successors is “just one pillar. Corrupt politicians and banking and business sectors must be next.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the stakes in the billions and powerful, respected families involved in the country’s politics, banking and business sectors, can cleaning up Mexico’s institutions will take more than firepower and good intelligence. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“For us Americans, reality won’t change,” says Chavarria. “Same drugs coming across, because of our demand. Same violence in Mexico. Wash, rinse, repeat. It is a small skirmish victory in a prolonged drug war. There will be more Menchos. On a positive note, however, no kingpin can last forever. They can run but they cannot escape their eventuality. Kingpins fall.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Russia’s fatalities compare with Ukraine’s</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/02/23/how-russias-fatalities-compare-with-ukraines</link>
      <description>After four years of fighting, our modelling reveals a grim toll</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: What is Donald Trump’s aim for Iran?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/23/the-war-room-newsletter-what-is-donald-trumps-aim-for-iran</link>
      <description>Shashank Joshi, our defence editor, analyses the president’s options</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 19:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for Trump’s Trade War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/trump-tariffs-trade-deals-supreme-court/</link>
      <description>The Supreme Court ruling has thrown the U.S. president’s tariff strategy and trade deals into chaos.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 19:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba Isn’t Headed for Collapse</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/cuba-trump-sanctions-economy-poverty/</link>
      <description>The Havana regime is used to managing bad times.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 18:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where the DHS shutdown could start to hurt</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/23/where-the-dhs-shutdown-could-start-to-hurt</link>
      <description>So far the budget impasse has caused little public outcry. That may soon change</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 18:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France’s far left reckons with the murder of a far-right activist</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/23/frances-far-left-reckons-with-the-murder-of-a-far-right-activist</link>
      <description>Quentin Deranque’s death forces the left to confront its extremists</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replacement B-52 test engine deliveries expected in 2027</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/replacement-b-52-test-engine-deliveries-expected-2027/411594/</link>
      <description>The new F130 engines aim to keep the Cold War-era bomber flying through the 2050s.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the Gulf States, Investment in AI Is Partly About U.S. Protection</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/gulf-states-investment-ai-american-protection-qatar-uae-saudi/</link>
      <description>Saudi Arabia, Qatar, and the UAE hope to become artificial intelligence hubs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Firefights across Mexico; Iran situation, still unclear; Tariff decision shakes foreign policy; What to expect at AFA symposium; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-23-2026/411602/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea Shows Justice Can Protect Democracy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/south-korea-yoon-sentence/</link>
      <description>The life sentence for Yoon Suk-yeol’s coup attempt should be a model for other states.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal’s Gen Z Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/nepals-gen-z-election/</link>
      <description>Biswas Baral discusses the Gen Z Revolution, the new crop of favorites – headed by Kathmandu Mayor Balendra Shah – and the fate of the old political forces.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing the Evolution of Russian Hybrid Warfare</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/gray-zone-russia</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/a-mural-depicting-a-serviceman-with-a-z-letter-patch-a-tactical-insignia-of-russian-troops-in-ukraine-on-his-uniform-holding-a.jpg?id=64982949&amp;amp;width=980&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KREMLIN FILES/ANALYSIS: &lt;/strong&gt;Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022 did not emerge from a strategic vacuum. It was the culmination of over a decade of experimentation in hybrid warfare, and of increasingly rigid assumptions inside Russia’s intelligence services. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Crimea and the Donbas in 2014, through Syria and a series of covert and deniable operations across Europe and the Middle East, Moscow refined a model of conflict built on scripted roles for its security services and their proxies. Yet the same intelligence culture that enabled early gains with hybrid war in Georgia, Ukraine and elsewhere, also fostered deeply flawed prognostications about the utility of force and Russia’s ability to project power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second in a two-part series on Russian gray zone, or hybrid warfare. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-kremlin-files-russias-way-to-the-gray-zone&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;In the first article,&lt;/a&gt; Wiswesser analyzes the evolution of hybrid warfare and its practice in the decades leading up to Russia’s intervention in Ukraine in 2014.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s errors ultimately propelled it into a catastrophic all-out war in Ukraine in 2022. This article, which continues a study of Russia’s path to and through the Gray Zone, argues that tracing the evolution of Russian hybrid warfare through the lens of its intelligence services and their miscalculation is not merely an exercise in post-mortem analysis but a critical step toward more effectively deterring future Russian aggression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the intervention in Ukraine in 2014, Russia’s so-called “non-contact” or gray warfare doctrine had its first major operational test for Russia, marking it’s most significant use of hybrid warfare. From their perspective, the Russian intelligence services (RIS) and its military succeeded in stunting the actions of Europe and the U.S. when Russia took large portions of the Donbas and Crimea utilizing “little green men.&quot; These were Russian GRU (military intelligence elite units), other Russian military units, and intelligence proxies acting in the interests of the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Russian strategists, non-contact war was effective, and these conflicts laid the groundwork for the planning of Putin’s siloviki and “organs” of power—the FSB, GRU, and Russian Armed Forces - for a much larger invasion of Ukraine just 8 years later. Studying the run-up to Russia’s full-scale invasion in 2022, and its hybrid war plan, can help better prepare NATO for the subsequent potential Russian aggression against the Baltics or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014-2015: Donbas, Crimea, and Syria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second decade of this century, as Russia’s debates over non-contact warfare continued within its military and intelligence agencies, planning started to counter what Russia viewed as undue influence from the West in the Caucasus, Central Asia, and most notably, Ukraine. It was the latter that Russia and Putin always considered unfinished business. Russian planners—initially a small group of Kremlin Siloviki and their staff from various ministries—were aware that their military was not prepared for a full-scale war with NATO and the West. Nevertheless, Moscow believed they controlled the narrative and that gaps in reforms of their military and air force could be offset by the RIS conducting sabotage, subversion, cyber warfare, and recruiting key defectors within the Ukrainian government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ukraine interventions and insurgencies of 2014 carried out by Russia in the Donbas and Crimea were classic non-contact operations using reflexive control and malicious influence through the media. Russia’s narrative was circulated among sympathetic European politicians and elsewhere. The story of little green men and whether they “were or weren’t Russian troops” was propagated through active measures. This and other false stories about supposed Ukrainian fascism and atrocities gained significant traction, especially within Central Asian countries and among Russia’s allies. The narrative effectively prevented any unified response by the West and Europe until the occupation of Crimea and large parts of the Donbas became a fait accompli. For Russia, it was a major success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, with a major deployment to Syria to support and back President Assad, the Russian Aerospace Forces (renamed the VKS in 2015) gained valuable experience for its combat squadrons. In Syria, they practiced precision strikes, a key part of non-contact warfare, and demonstrated greater precision (than in Georgia) in the use of air power during strikes. Additionally, in Syria, RIS units like GRU Spetsnaz conducted operations embedded with various factions and partners on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This deployment gained momentum on the heels of the 2014 Ukrainian operations. It was a classic blend of gray zone operations between intelligence and military units. Syria was also seen as a chance for Russia to bleed green units in preparation for larger wars to come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Africa during this same period, Putin’s former cook, then an oligarch, Yevgenniy Prigozhin, used the Wagner Group, a private army, to prop up regimes friendly to Russia. Wagner was one of dozens of private military companies, also known as&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hybridcoe.fi/publications/handbook-on-the-role-of-non-state-actors-in-russian-hybrid-threats/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;non-state actors, that Russia was using and continues to use to achieve strategic aims&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. They acted as mercenaries to repress citizens and dissent, intervening as henchmen for hire across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, there was one overarching strategic goal that Putin and all his services focused on—Ukraine. For Russia and its intelligence services in particular, Ukraine remained unfinished business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukraine War Plans: Prepping the Battlefield&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Russia prepared in the years leading up to the full-scale invasion in 2022, it relied on its version of hybrid warfare, its doctrine of non-contact warfare, and all that it involved: active measures, cyber operations, and efforts to influence the media through reflexive control. In planning, they aimed to combine these measures with a limited air campaign and a significant ground invasion that appeared sufficient on paper but lacked professional soldiers, trained units, and the crucial 3-to-1 (or more) force ratio needed to succeed against Ukraine’s professional military.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s thinking was enabled by and reinforced from decades of theory on non-contact war, their successes in both Georgia and Ukraine in 2014, and their belief they could pull off an occupation of and complete overthrow of the democratic government of Ukraine. Faulty prognostications by the RIS made Putin sure it would all work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the lead-up to the Ukraine invasion in 2022, all three of Russia's main intelligence agencies—the FSB, SVR, and GRU—played prominent roles in Putin's planning and execution of the invasion. These agencies always viewed Ukraine and other former Soviet republics, which they call the “near abroad,” as extensions of Russia. The RIS never accepted its independence and couldn't see Ukraine, in particular, as a separate nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSB, despite primarily being an internal agency, played an outsized role in planning the &quot;special military operation&quot;—the term they later used to describe the full invasion of Ukraine. The FSB Fifth Service was responsible for “operational information” and was prominent in both 2014 and the invasion eight years later. As the main source of intelligence analysis for President Putin, the FSB Fifth Service provided him with a steady flow of inaccurate reports, which he readily accepted. Many of those same FSB officers were infamously reported in the Russian blogosphere as having “picked out their apartments&quot; in Kyiv before the invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSB believed Russia could win in Ukraine. To weaken the battlefield, the FSB used influence operations across Russian-language and international media, working alongside their SVR/GRU colleagues. They were confident it could be effective because, to some extent, they succeeded in 2014 in muddying the waters about the nature of that conflict and how the international community should respond (or unfortunately, not). The West and NATO appeared hesitant to act and were unprepared. For the RIS, they thought it was a &quot;win&quot; they could replicate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSB planned a continuation of these tactics in 2022, aiming to confuse the international focus long enough to ensure a quick victory and regime change in Ukraine. U.S. intelligence sharing and increased NATO awareness thwarted this, at least in part. The Foreign Service (the SVR) supplemented these active measures with its own networks of cooperative journalists, corrupt parties or politicians abroad, and what the SVR calls &quot;useful idiots,&quot; whom it could employ as witting or unwitting accomplices to help spread the Russian narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some experts in the West bought into this narrative, commenting across many media outlets on Russia’s “overwhelming force ratios” along the main axes of advance. Western generals and experts echoed Moscow’s position, repeatedly stating that “unfortunately, Ukraine can’t win.” Early in the war, Russian messaging worked in its favor once again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russia’s Military/Intelligence Failures in Ukraine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After practicing Russian military maneuvers in “Zapad” (West in Russian) exercises for several years, in early 2022, Zapad 2022 became the cover for the gathering of forces for the full-scale invasion. But this time, the West—Europe and the U.S.-- were better prepared. U.S. intelligence was shared directly with NATO and Ukraine. Ukraine was readied, and Russia was put on notice that it would not succeed in another gray war followed by an invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time, and unlike many negative predictions even in the West, the Ukrainians would fight, and Russia would bleed. When the Russians were forced to fight, they fought terribly, incompetently, and it has cost them over a million casualties as the war neared its fourth year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are important lessons to learn from Russia’s numerous failures in its operations in Ukraine. This article mainly focuses on intelligence services and hybrid warfare. For the Russian army, however, the widespread use of conscripts and their poor integration into battalion tactical groups with “kontraktniki” (contract soldiers) meant the BTGs were largely effective only on paper. Huge convoys showcasing significant “force ratios” were intended to intimidate Ukraine. Still, their equipment was not ready for combat deployment (for example, the many stories of underinflated tires and trucks running out of gas). The Russian Aerospace Forces lacked sufficient combat-trained pilots with the necessary experience in air campaigns to sustain a prolonged engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the intelligence services, Ukraine would starkly reveal their shortcomings. Russian Military Intelligence, the GRU planned for substantial roles in what they thought would be a quick victory in 2022. GRU Spetsnaz, or special operations units, were used in the 2022 invasion to a fault, thrown into frontal assaults for which these (claimed) elite elements were not designed. They became cannon fodder literally when the Russian battalion tactical groups (BTGs) could not carry out their planned roles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with other infamous units, the GRU’s Unit 29155 distinguished itself with assassinations and attempted ones, not only in Ukraine but across Europe. They were also behind the 2018 attack on defector Sergey Skripal. But most of their early operations, including attempts allegedly to carry out a fast coup to overthrow President Zelensky, failed. RIS hit squads and teams from the GRU and FSB were sent in to stage what they planned as a coup, following an airborne assault--which also failed--at Hostomel airport outside Kyiv.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other such operations in the Donbas were thwarted by Ukrainian intelligence. There were special operations units from the FSB deployed throughout Ukraine, including their teams &quot;Alpha&quot; and &quot;Vympel.&quot; These FSB units and others were particularly active in the occupied East. Their crimes, including assassinations of local Ukrainian leaders, atrocities against civilians, and torture, are well documented and continue to the present. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSB, SVR, and GRU all promised Putin and his planners that they could conduct successful cyber operations to stun and disrupt the Ukrainian response in early 2022. These attacks were blunted primarily by the Ukrainians' own cyber defense capabilities and by early intelligence warnings from the West about the invasion. One example of attempted but failed Russian gray-zone ops is the FSB's Center 16, which is broadly responsible for signals intelligence and intercept operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Center 16 hires&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-crime-uber-krysha&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;criminal hackers for the state&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an example again of non-state actors (NSAs). The FSB and other RIS units believed they could bring Ukraine to its knees with heavy cyber attacks on the government, and that these NSAs could play a significant role, including Russian organized crime groups. The planned cyber and criminal-assisted coup against Ukraine, like the broader invasion, failed. The RIS's predictions of success were again overly optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions: New Gray Zone War Without End&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2022, the Ukrainians have fought heroically and successfully defended their nation. Western support has played a key role, and that support should continue. But studying why Russia thought it could win and their doctrine and experience on the same, is key for our country and our allies preparing for the next war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the basis for the 2022 invasion, which includes Russia’s doctrine and history, is crucial. Russian war plans relied on the same concepts developed by figures like Sliphchenko, Gareev, and&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2017/09/05/gerasimov-doctrine-russia-foreign-policy-215538/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Chief of Staff Valeriy Gerasimov regarding non-contact warfare&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (as detailed in the first article of this series): a permanent front engaged in information warfare, sabotage, and other actions just below the threshold of actual war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the West, we should study our Russian adversaries in their own language, their military writings, culture, and traditions, so we can better counter them. Herein lie the lessons of Russian non-contact warfare, their understanding of hybrid tactics, and why they believed they could win—and still do. These lessons are critically important to prevent the next aggression by Russia. A recent&lt;a href=&quot;https://cepa.org/comprehensive-reports/war-without-end-russias-shadow-warfare/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;study by the Center for European Analysis&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; highlights that Russia’s strategy involves constant escalation against Europe and the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Russian victory—or even a frozen conflict on Moscow’s terms—would validate a decade-long experiment in revisionism by stealth and force. It would signal to allies and adversaries alike that escalation works, that borders are negotiable, and that democratic societies lack the endurance to defend the order they claim to lead. Helping Ukraine prevail is therefore not an act of charity or sentiment; it is a strategic necessity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the United States and its allies, the lesson is clear. Supporting Ukraine through to a just and durable outcome is inseparable from preparing for the next evolution of the Russian gray zone. That means investing in deterrence across domains, hardening democratic institutions against subversion, confronting malign influence early rather than episodically, and abandoning the illusion that stability can be purchased through restraint. A nation founded on the belief that freedom is an inalienable right cannot afford strategic ambiguity about whether it will defend those who fight for the same principle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gray zone is already contested terrain. The question is not whether conflict will continue, but whether the West is prepared to meet it with clarity, resolve, and the will to win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;---------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United States Is Dangerously Misreading Iran</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/trump-iran-war-misreading-khamenei-strategy-nuclear/</link>
      <description>Washington can start a war, but it may not be able to control the escalation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Did Tajik President Emomali Rahmon Disappear To? And Why Does It Matter?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/where-did-tajik-president-emomali-rahmon-disappear-to-and-why-does-it-matter/</link>
      <description>Rahmon surfaced after an apparent 17-day absence on February 14. His stepping out of the limelight stirred up rumors of ill health.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rotten tail of China’s property bust</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/23/the-rotten-tail-of-chinas-property-bust</link>
      <description>The government wants to spread the pain as widely as possible</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elbridge Colby and the Reordering of the Indo-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/elbridge-colby-indopacific-trump-china/</link>
      <description>The influential Pentagon official is narrowing choices available to U.S. allies.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Japan Must Help Counter China’s Presence in the Pacific</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-japan-must-help-counter-chinas-presence-in-the-pacific/</link>
      <description>From elite capture to organized crime, China’s influence is growing in Micronesia. Japan is uniquely positioned to help combat this trend.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Little Clarity on Legality of Trump’s Foreign Aid Shutdown One Year After</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/trump-foreign-aid-usaid-lawsuits-legal/</link>
      <description>Lawsuits to reinstate frozen foreign aid have been hampered by questions of standing, jurisdiction, and legal technicalities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New US Tariffs, Same Problems for Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/new-us-tariffs-same-problems-for-japan-south-korea-and-taiwan/</link>
      <description>The U.S. Supreme Court’s tariff ruling only adds uncertainty for the U.S. partners in East Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China, ASEAN, and Beyond: The UK Strategy for the Indo-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/china-asean-and-beyond-the-uk-strategy-for-the-indo-pacific/</link>
      <description>“Euro-Atlantic security and prosperity depends on a free and open Indo-Pacific,” writes U.K. Minister for the Indo-Pacific Seema Malhotra.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelations of Chinese Nuclear Tests Mark Start of a New Era</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/revelations-of-chinese-nuclear-tests-mark-start-of-a-new-era/</link>
      <description>While China is expanding its nuclear arsenal at a dramatic pace, Russia and the U.S. are also testing new delivery platforms.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Must Not Abandon Its Climate Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-must-remain-global-climate-leader-cbam-ets-by-catherine-wolfram-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump has revoked the legal basis for regulating greenhouse-gas emissions in the US. But German Chancellor Friedrich Merz’s comments about possibly revising the EU Emission Trading Scheme could be more damaging, because Europe’s carbon-pricing framework is finally inducing other countries to act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Was a Kazakh Lawyer Stripped of His License?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-was-a-kazakh-lawyer-stripped-of-his-license/</link>
      <description>Murat Adam tried to defend the rights of his client, an editor under fire, and found himself in the state’s crosshairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Sheikh Hasina’s Awami League Returning to Politics Under New Leadership?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-sheikh-hasinas-awami-league-returning-to-politics-under-new-leadership/</link>
      <description>Party offices in some districts have been reopened, and national and party flags are being raised.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The killing of Mexico’s most powerful narco will please Donald Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/23/the-killing-of-mexicos-most-powerful-narco-will-please-donald-trump</link>
      <description>But it risks provoking terrible violence in Mexico</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A European Solution for Germany’s China Challenge</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/merz-visit-to-china-must-demonstrate-european-unity-by-daniela-schwarzer-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;German Chancellor Friedrich Merz's upcoming visit to China comes at a pivotal moment. China's export prowess is driving a national debate about lagging competitiveness, and that debate is taking place alongside the European Union's efforts to devise a unified China strategy at a time when the United States appears increasingly unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rejoice! Private equity is taking over America’s small businesses</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/23/rejoice-private-equity-is-taking-over-americas-small-businesses</link>
      <description>Its ghoulish reputation is ill-deserved</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt Restructuring Is Senegal’s Best Bet</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/senegal-should-pursue-debt-restructuring-as-soon-as-possible-by-abdoulaye-ndiaye-and-martin-kessler-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Senegal does not have any pain-free options for escaping its intensifying debt crisis. But absent large volumes of cheap liquidity, attempting to repay its debts at all costs would likely prove costlier than biting the bullet and initiating debt-restructuring negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Four-Year Failure of Imagination</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/russia-ukraine-war-invasion-four-years-putin-military-strategy-failure/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Front Line Is Preparing for War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/russia-ukraine-war-nato-europe-poland-baltic-states-finland-putin-military/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performative Negotiations to Humor Trump</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/us-russia-ukraine-trump-putin-negotiations-four-years-peace-deal/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Putin Sold a False Win in Ukraine to Trump</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/trump-putin-russia-ukraine-war-casualties-cost-territory-gains-negotiations-peace-deal/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Years on, Europe Is Taking Over</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/russia-europe-war-ukraine-nato-military-aid-defense-security-eu/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An MQ-20 drone just teamed up with an F-22 for mock combat missions</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/02/mq-20-drone-just-teamed-f-22-mock-combat-missions/411595/</link>
      <description>The drone was able to “exchange messages” with the pilot about patrols, maneuvers, and more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Scenarios for Europe as Trump Talks to Putin</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/russia-ukraine-war-four-years-trump-putin-negotiations-europe-eu-economics-sanctions/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Ukraine’s Economy Has Defied the Odds</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/six-reasons-ukraine-economy-has-not-collapsed-by-tatyana-deryugina-et-al-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four years of grueling war have devastated Ukraine’s infrastructure, displaced millions of people, and pushed its economy to the brink. But sound policy, a surge in defense spending, sustained international aid, and restored air and sea access have stabilized demand and brought GDP close to prewar levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Ukrainians Don’t Believe in Lasting Peace</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/russia-ukraine-war-four-years-peace-negotiations-deal-security-guarantees/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia and Europe Are Now Strategically Joined</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/russia-ukraine-war-asia-china-india-japan-nato-geopolitics/</link>
      <description>Eight thinkers on four years of Russia’s war against Ukraine.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destruction of a Lake – a Ramsar Site – in India’s Northeast</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/destruction-of-a-lake-a-ramsar-site-in-indias-northeast/</link>
      <description>Construction activity, effluents and sewage are destroying the Deepor Beel in Assam.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 08:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Election in the Eyes of the Japan Innovation Party</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/japans-election-in-the-eyes-of-the-japan-innovation-party/</link>
      <description>The outcome has decidedly mixed implications for the LDP’s junior partner.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timor-Leste’s Case Against Myanmar: A Question of Priorities</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/timor-lestes-case-against-myanmar-a-question-of-priorities/</link>
      <description>It is commendable that Dili is showing solidarity with the people of Myanmar – but a failed prosecution could end up undermining the principle of universal jurisdiction.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Midterm Threats Recall a Bleak Chapter in American History</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/23/trump-midterm-election-threats-jim-crow-voting/</link>
      <description>Illiberalism has been part of the national culture since the founding.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s Long Road to Recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/venezuela/venezuelas-long-road-recovery</link>
      <description>An economic revival can’t happen without a political transformation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Navy Seizes Cambodian Fishing Boat in Disputed Waters</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/thai-navy-seizes-cambodian-fishing-boat-in-disputed-waters/</link>
      <description>Phnom Penh denounced the capture of the vessel and its crew as “an unauthorized incursion” into Cambodian territorial waters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 03:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modi Government Strikes Hard on Indian Workers</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/modi-government-strikes-hard-on-indian-workers/</link>
      <description>Earlier, government permission was required to sack 100 employees or more. Now, no permission is required for sacking up to 300 employees.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 03:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Murderer Released in Indonesia, but His Legal Woes May Just Be Beginning</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/american-murderer-released-in-indonesia-but-his-legal-woes-may-just-be-beginning/</link>
      <description>Tommy Schaefer, who was convicted for the 2014 murder of socialite Sheila von Wiese-Mack, is likely to face further charges once back on U.S. soil.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s Aggression in Ukraine Will Persist Through 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/russias-aggression-ukraine-will-persist-through-2026</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Showing Russia that Ukraine can sustain its resistance while expanding the costs on the Kremlin is the only path towards a settlement on durable terms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanctions: A War of Attrition Between Russia and The West</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/news-and-comment/video-commentary/sanctions-war-attrition-between-russia-and-west</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;For four years, sanctions have been a war of attrition between policy makers in the West and those in Russia trying to circumvent them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US to Remove Vietnam From Export Control List, Government Says</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/us-to-remove-vietnam-from-export-control-list-government-says/</link>
      <description>The move is a sign of growing strategic trust, but trade is likely to remain a point of friction in relations between Hanoi and Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 23:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
