<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Will Trump’s Luck Run Out if He Attacks Iran Again?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/trump-iran-attack-nuclear-former-generals-petraeus-venezuela/</link>
      <description>Four former generals break down the risks of a U.S. attack.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 01:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A stay-calm plan to save the world</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/24/a-stay-calm-plan-to-save-the-world</link>
      <description>Alas, almost no foreign leader is as reasonable as Finland’s president, Alexander Stubb</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Russia-Ukraine War Enters Its Fifth Year</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/russia-ukraine-war-fourth-anniversary-peace-talks-zelensky-putin/</link>
      <description>Little progress has been made in ending Europe’s biggest conflict since World War II.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Warned Ukraine Not to Strike American Investments in Russia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/ukraine-demarche-us-state-department-russia-oil-attack-novorossiysk/</link>
      <description>Kyiv’s ambassador to Washington said a Ukrainian attack on Novorossiysk triggered the reprimand.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Next Cyber Crackdown</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/china-cybercrime-draft-law-internet-great-firewall/</link>
      <description>A sweeping draft law could test the balance between control and economic growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where AI Thinks the US-Iran Conflict is Going</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/where-ai-thinks-the-us-iran-conflict</link>
      <description>Some options are more probable than others, says Microsoft's Bing Copilot, but Trump&amp;#8217;s state of mind is the wild card.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Iran Battle Plan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/petraeus-trump-iran-miiltary-options-battle-plan/</link>
      <description>David Petraeus on the military options and intelligence likely being presented at the White House.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Force test pilots used tactical AI to evade a missile</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/02/air-force-test-pilots-used-tactical-ai-evade-missile/411659/</link>
      <description>A Skunk Works project pushed pilots to give artificial intelligence control in the cockpit.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 21:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United States Has Grand Plans in the Caucasus</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/iran-armenia-azerbaijan-united-states/</link>
      <description>Washington is trying to build up Armenia and Azerbaijan as regional allies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 21:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisionist History – Aliens, Secrets and Conspiracies</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/revisionist-history-aliens</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION –&lt;/strong&gt; Over a decade ago, I was a public official and was at one of our commission meetings on the coast of California. A fellow commissioner and I decided to take a long lunchtime walk along the coast. As we chatted, we realized we had both worked on several of the same very classified programs. His involvement was in acquisition and finance, while mine was more deeply connected to the engineering development of the project and hands-on with the operators on site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Got Our Advanced Technology From Aliens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;While we both were discreet about not talking about specifics, we recognized the projects we had worked on. So you can imagine my surprise when he turned to me and casually said, “You know this technology came from aliens.” I laughed, thinking that obviously he must be joking. But as we continued walking he continued on, claiming, “You know the equipment you worked on and stuff that followed came from our secret alien investigation site at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.military.com/off-duty/2020/12/18/6-urban-legends-about-wright-patterson-air-force-base.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wright Patterson Air Force Base&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. All we did was reverse engineer Alien technology.” This time I stopped in my tracks and looked at him to see if he was smiling. I was puzzled as he looked dead serious. He explained that there was no possible way we could be doing what we were doing using existing technology. Before I changed the subject I asked him how he knew this, he replied with absolute sincerity, “I was head of acquisition on the program. I was briefed on the project. That’s what they told us and they swore us to secrecy.“&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really didn’t know how to process this. He was really a smart and level-headed guy. In fact he was the mayor at the time of Rancho Palos Verde. It took me a mile or two into our walk to rethink everything I knew about the project (even then it had been in decades past), including having sat with a few of the engineers (some strange, but not aliens) as they were designing the system (with me trying to keep up with the revised blueprints in document control), and then watching the system being built and assembled. While it had required incredibly creative engineering, and applying technology on a scale so massive no commercial company could afford it, this system was built by smart people with no aliens involved. But he was equally convinced they were. Over our time together on the commission we took more walks, had lots more to talk about, but we never broached the subject again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, for the next few years, I puzzled on how he could have been so sure of something that I was sure was completely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Did Tell Them It Was Aliens&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Fast forward 15 years, and my world view of that conversation was upended when I read in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/ufo-us-disinformation-45376f7e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the Department of Defense had been running a disinformation campaign, briefing finance and acquisition people that the technology for these classified programs &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; coming from aliens. (Take a minute and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/ufo-us-disinformation-45376f7e&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;read the article&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of a sudden our coast-side conversation from a decade and a half ago made sense to me. Most of our most compartmentalized programs have different levels of what was called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Need_to_know&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;need to know&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.” I never paid much attention as I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special_access_program&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;read all the way into&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the technical and operational details of these programs. I vaguely knew that others got fewer details, but as I was just discovering, &lt;em&gt;others had received active disinformation&lt;/em&gt;. In a few cases, security officers were even using fake photos and documents to create the Alien cover-story for secret-weapons programs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out my fellow commissioner had been briefed by the U.S. government that it was Aliens, and he went to his grave believing it so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you going to believe me or your lying eyes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;What’s interesting is what happened after the news came out that the Alien story was government disinformation. A large percentage of people who were briefed, now “doubled down” and believed “we got the technology from Aliens” even more strongly – believing the new information itself was a coverup. Many dismissed the facts by prioritizing how they felt over reality, something we often see in political or religious contexts. (“Are you going to believe me or your lying eyes?”)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wondered how my friend would have reacted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secrecy, Disinformation, and a Higher Power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;While on its face this is an amusing story about secrecy, it’s really about the intersection of the secrecy’s impact on society and its role in misinformation, manipulation, the creation of cynicism and mistrust, and our need to believe in a higher power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manipulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;An example of secrecy used for manipulation in the 20th century was when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://warfarehistorynetwork.com/article/opening-the-venona-files/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;National Security Agency Venona &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;project &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venona_project&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;unmasked Soviet spies&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S. Even though this was one of the nation’s most secret programs, the FBI leaked its findings to Joe McCarthy and Richard Nixon. They used this classified knowledge to manipulate the American public, fueling McCarthyism and Richard Nixon’s career. 50 years later, when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsa.gov/Helpful-Links/NSA-FOIA/Declassification-Transparency-Initiatives/Historical-Releases/Venona/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Venona&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was made public historians substantively revised the history of U.S. Cold War politics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century Social Media misinformation (e.g. Chinese and Russian influence campaigns, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QAnon&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Qanon&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; conspiracies) will look like toys next to the AI-driven manipulation that’s about to come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cynicism and mistrust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Secrecy created 75 years of cynicism and mistrust, when the U.S. began launching highly classified reconnaissance balloons (story &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2010/01/28/balloon-wars/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;here&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), and later the U-2 and SR-71 spy planes. These top secret projects gave rise to decades of UFO sightings. Instead of acknowledging these sightings were from classified military projects the Department of Defense issued cover stories (“you saw weather balloons”) that weren’t believable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Governments and companies have always kept secrets and used misinformation and manipulation. However, things stay secret way too long – for many reasons – some reasonable (we’re still using the same methods – reconnaissance technology, tradecraft, or, it would harm people still alive – retired spies, etc) or not so reasonable (we broke U.S. or international laws – &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COINTELPRO&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;COINTELPRO&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or it would embarrass us or our allies – Kennedy assassination, or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epstein_files&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Epstein files&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Secrecy increases the odds of conspiracy beliefs. Because evidence can’t be checked, contradictions can’t be audited, a government “cover-up” becomes a plausible explanation. People don’t tolerate “I don’t know” for long when stakes are high (stolen elections, identity, national crises, the meaning of life, or what happens when we die). That vacuum gets filled by the most emotionally satisfying model: a hidden “higher power” concealing information and controlling events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Just as social media replaced traditional news sources, AI-driven summaries of current events are likely to replace our understanding of the world around us. What happens to trust when AI manipulates human’s tendency to embrace conspiracy theories? Who will define the truth in the brave new world?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And by the way, I’m still pretty sure we didn’t get it from Aliens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This piece was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2026/02/10/revisionist-history-aliens-secrets-and-conspiracies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steve Blank here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2026/02/10/revisionist-history-aliens-secrets-and-conspiracies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2026/02/10/revisionist-history-aliens-secrets-and-conspiracies/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who's reading this? 500K+ dedicated national security professionals. Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 21:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Elections Secure Nepal’s Youth Revolution?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/nepal-elections-revolt-youth-gen-z/</link>
      <description>With a generational shift in power possible, the old guard is fighting back.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 20:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Western Civilization’ is a MAGA Dog Whistle</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/western-civilization-is-a-maga-dog-whistle/</link>
      <description>Rubio is wrong to cite it as the basis for the U.S. alliance with Europe.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 20:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil’s high court is caught up in a vast scandal</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/24/brazils-high-court-is-caught-up-in-a-vast-scandal</link>
      <description>Some of the world’s most powerful judges have an over-cosy relationship with the business and political elite</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 19:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s California’s 250th birthday, too</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/24/its-californias-250th-birthday-too</link>
      <description>Kind of</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 18:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For AI labs, Pete Hegseth’s Pentagon brings opportunities—and risks</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/24/for-ai-labs-pete-hegseths-pentagon-brings-opportunities-and-risks</link>
      <description>Silicon Valley’s approach to defence is back under the spotlight</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pete Hegseth wages war on Anthropic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/24/pete-hegseth-wages-war-on-anthropic</link>
      <description>Should AI labs unquestioningly obey the Pentagon’s orders?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pete Hegseth goes to battle with Anthropic</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/24/pete-hegseth-goes-to-battle-with-anthropic</link>
      <description>Should AI labs unquestioningly obey the Pentagon’s orders?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Farm and Food Exports Hit New High As Trade Patterns Shift</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/japans-farm-and-food-exports-hit-new-high-as-trade-patterns-shift/</link>
      <description>Amid tariffs and geopolitical headwinds, Japan's trade data shows new patterns emerging – led by food products, tourism-linked consumption, and advanced manufacturing.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meanwhile: Afghan Terrorists Stirring New India-Pakistan Tensions</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/meanwhile-afghan-terrorists-stirring</link>
      <description>Taliban&amp;#8217;s India alliance inflames Pakistan, raising fear of new war, threats to West</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Africa newsletter: An interview with Zambia’s president</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/24/analysing-africa-newsletter-an-interview-with-zambias-president</link>
      <description>John McDermott, our chief Africa correspondent, talks to Hakainde Hichilema</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Trump Waging War on Somali Immigrants?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-somalia-obsession-racist-vision-of-america-by-adekeye-adebajo-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s fixation on Somali immigrants is not arbitrary; it is part of a broader campaign to demonize non-white immigrants as criminals and civilizational threats. But that narrative depends on ignorance of Somali integration and of America’s own role in Somalia’s collapse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get rich in modern China</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/24/how-to-get-rich-in-modern-china</link>
      <description>It is now the nongchaoer making it big</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Competing views on Iran; $151B spending plan; 44th boat strike; B-21 production deal; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-24-2026/411640/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The High Price of Political Paranoia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-trump-xi-paranoia-undermines-their-countries-interests-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more centralized a political system is, the more likely it is that national interests and goals will take a backseat to the leader’s personal whims, desires, and insecurities. Versions of this dynamic are currently playing out in Russia, China, and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for China’s EV Stocks as Weak Demand Triggers Sell-Offs?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/whats-next-for-chinas-ev-stocks-as-weak-demand-triggers-sell-offs/</link>
      <description>Cooling domestic demand and soaring raw material costs are weighing down Chinese electric vehicle companies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bosses should not hold their breath for a Trump tariff refund</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/24/bosses-should-not-hold-their-breath-for-a-trump-tariff-refund</link>
      <description>The process will be slow and politically fraught</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Not a Lost Cause</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/europe-trump-rubio-munich-trade-tariffs-india-latin-america/</link>
      <description>The continent’s economic strength and liberal values can be an asset in a multipolar world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Needs More Than Creativity on Hong Kong – It Needs Action</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/america-needs-more-than-creativity-on-hong-kong-it-needs-action/</link>
      <description>Members of Congress have both the authority and responsibility to act by passing the bipartisan Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office Certification Act.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The war against PDFs is heating up</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/24/the-war-against-pdfs-is-heating-up</link>
      <description>Will the file type survive the AI revolution?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Takaichi Draws a Red Line on Nuclear Sharing Amid Japan’s Security Review</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/takaichi-draws-a-red-line-on-nuclear-sharing-amid-japans-security-review/</link>
      <description>The prime minister’s latest comments suggest a dual-track strategy: strengthening Japan’s conventional capabilities and defense industry while drawing a firm line against nuclear weapons.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Korea’s Demographic Crisis Has Come for Its Military</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/south-korea-military-women-demographics-conscription-military/</link>
      <description>The country’s military is becoming desperate for troops—and may eventually force women to serve.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ‘Resting’ Generation and South Korea’s Youth Recession</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-resting-generation-and-south-koreas-youth-recession/</link>
      <description>As entry-level jobs contract and firms prioritize experience, a growing number of young South Koreans have given up on looking for work altogether.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUKUS Quietly Moving Ahead With Arrival of British Sub in Australia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/aukus-quietly-moving-ahead-with-arrival-of-british-sub-in-australia/</link>
      <description>By integrating industrial bases and operational practices, Australia and the U.K. are signalling that their partnership is not a relic of history but central to their contemporary strategies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindutva Groups in India Effectively Outlawed Valentine’s Day</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/hindutva-groups-in-india-effectively-outlawed-valentines-day/</link>
      <description>Using vigilante violence, these militant organizations are forging a new form of law and order that conforms to their strict religious beliefs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Economics of the Supreme Court’s Tariff Ruling</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/economic-consequences-supreme-court-striking-down-trumps-tariffs-by-stephen-s-roach-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US Supreme Court has ruled that President Donald Trump’s tariffs are unconstitutional, effectively positioning the rule of law as the ultimate arbiter of a terrible economic policy. This sends an important message: US policies may not be personalized by the whims of a vindictive and uninformed wannabe autocrat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Russia’s War Effort Signals Strategic Decline</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russias-war-ukraine</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION —&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Despite claims of battlefield momentum in Ukraine, the data shows that Russia is paying an extraordinary price for minimal gains and is in decline as a major power. Since February 2022, Russian forces have suffered nearly 1.2 million casualties, more losses than any major power in any war since World War II…After seizing the initiative in 2024, Russian forces have advanced at an average rate of between 15 and 70 meters per day in their most prominent offensives, slower than almost any major offensive campaign in any war in the last century. Meanwhile, Russia’s war economy is under mounting strain, with manufacturing declining, slowing growth of 0.6 percent in 2025, and no globally competitive technology firms to help drive long-term productivity.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s a quote from &lt;em&gt;Russia’s Grinding War in Ukraine&lt;/em&gt;, a Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) analysis brief by Seth G. Jones and Riley McCabe, released January 27, which says that “a close look at the data suggests that Russia is hardly winning [its war against Ukraine],” and, even more interestingly, that “Russia is increasingly a declining power.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jones, President of CSIS’ Defense and Security Department, and McCabe, Associate Fellow in CSIS’, Warfare, Irregular Threats, and Terrorism Program, not only assess that “Russia’s overall progress on the battlefield, especially in the last two years, fall decisively short of Moscow’s goal to militarily conquer Ukraine,” but also that “Russia’s economy is showing signs of strain, and long-term productivity looks bleak.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the Jones/McCabe analysis of the military situation and below look at their view of Moscow’s economic situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While saying assessing casualties and fatalities in wartime is difficult and imprecise, and various sides have incentives to inflate or shrink the numbers for political purposes, Jones/McCabe write that “According to CSIS estimates, Russian forces suffered nearly 1.2 million battlefield casualties, which include killed, wounded, and missing, between February 2022 and December 2025…There were roughly 415,000 Russian casualties in 2025 alone, with an average of nearly 35,000 casualties per month. In addition, there were roughly 275,000 to 325,000 Russian battlefield fatalities between February 2022 and December 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to the past, the CSIS analysis showed, “Russian battlefield fatalities in Ukraine are more than 17 times greater than Soviet fatalities in Afghanistan during the 1980s, 11 times greater than during Russia’s First and Second Chechen Wars in the 1990s and 2000s, respectively, and over five times greater than all Russian and Soviet wars &lt;em&gt;combined&lt;/em&gt; since World War II.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CSIS team attributes the high Russian casualties and fatalities to such things as “Russia’s failure to effectively conduct combined arms and joint warfare, poor tactics and training, corruption, low morale, and Ukraine’s effective defense-in-depth strategy in a war that favors the defense.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specifically the CSIS analysis says, “Russia’s attrition strategy has accepted the costs of high casualties in hopes of eventually wearing down Ukraine’s military and society. On the battlefield, Russia has utilized dismounted infantry to wear down and attrit Ukrainian lines, along with small first-person view (FPV) drones, artillery, glide bombs, and other stand-off weapons. Russian units have routinely conducted advances using small squads of troops, often poorly trained, that are supported by armored vehicles or light mobility vehicles. Higher Russian headquarters frequently order these forces to advance toward Ukrainian positions to conduct reconnaissance by drawing fire. If Ukrainian positions are positively identified, Russian soldiers may be sent forward to attack positions, which are further mapped and then targeted with artillery, FPV drones, and glide bombs. These tactics have led to high fatalities and casualties.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ukraine side is also given credit for “their defense-in-depth strategy in a war that has largely favored the defender. Ukraine has used trenches, dragon’s teeth (anti-tank obstacles), mines, and other barriers—along with artillery and drones—to attrit advancing Russian soldiers and vehicles. The eastern front line, for instance, continues to be saturated with drones. As a result, vehicle movement is difficult within 15 kilometers of the front line. Infantry soldiers must instead march to their positions for 10 to 15 kilometers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One result has been Russia’s slow rate of advance. According to the CSIS analysis, “Russia’s gains since it took the initiative in January 2024 are far smaller than the large territorial shifts seen earlier in the war. At the peak of the initial invasion in March 2022, Russian forces seized roughly 115,000 square kilometers in less than five weeks, but by April 2022, Ukraine had retaken more than 35,000 square kilometers. By November 2022, Ukraine had retaken approximately 75,000 square kilometers, including through successful counteroffensives around [the Ukraine cities] Kharkiv and Kherson.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the Russian economy has held up better than expected following U.S. and other Western country sanctions imposed after Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, strain on its economy is starting to show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CSIS analysis says, “In 2025, Russian manufacturing declined at its fastest rate since March 2022, with contractions in output and new orders, a rising labor shortage, and a decrease in input buying.&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;Overall, Russian manufacturing suffered seven consecutive months of contraction in 2025, with production levels declining for ten consecutive months. In addition, consumer demand weakened and inflation was high.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jone/McCabe write there is also a labor crunch, a drop in oil revenues with lower global prices, with 2025 economic growth slowing to 0.6 percent, while the International Monetary Fund estimates that Russia’s growth would remain slow, at 0.8 percent, in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CSIS team also says Russia faces a capital problem. Unable to borrow on international markets, the Kremlin has borrowed at home and raised taxes to finance the Ukraine war. Roughly half its budget is spent on the armed forces, the military-industrial complex, domestic security, and debt service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“While the war sustains jobs and industrial activity,” the CSIS team says, “it produces few lasting assets or productivity gains. Higher taxes burden the civilian economy, which is already suffering from double-digit interest rates and significant labor shortages. Tank factories are working overtime, but automobile producers have cut shifts.” Ammunition, uniforms, and fortifications contribute to current GDP, but they do not improve long-term welfare or capital formation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Jones/McCabe, “Russia also faces one of the most severe demographic challenges among major economies, with a shrinking and aging population, low birth rate, high mortality rate (especially among working-age men), and high rate of emigration among skilled workers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One example where the CSIS analysis finds Russia falling behind is in Artificial Intelligence (AI). It points out that Russian President Vladimir Putin once predicted, “Artificial intelligence is the future not only of Russia but of all of mankind. . . . Whoever becomes the leader in this sphere will become the ruler of the world.”&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;But it then states, “Russia today is a bottom-tier AI power. It ranks 28 of 36 countries in the overall strength and development of its AI ecosystem—or AI ‘vibrancy’ -- according to Stanford University. The top-performing Russian AI model trails even older iterations of OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Google’s Gemini.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even worse, not a single Russian company is among the top 100 technology companies in the world by market capitalization, while the U.S. leads the pack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for the space race, where Russia was once a leader, Roscosmos, the state corporation in charge of the Russian space program, carried out only 17 orbital launches in 2025, according to the CSIS analysis. That compares to 193 U.S. orbital launches and 92 by China. Russia’s space industry also suffered an accident in December 2025 that caused severe damage to the launch pad Russia uses for sending astronauts and cargo to the International Space Station. In addition, a 2018 Soyuz rocket carrying two astronauts failed as it headed to space; the emergency abort system carried the two to safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has also been a decline inside Russia in popular support inside Russia for the war. According to polls cited by CSIS, in May 2023, 57 percent of Russians believed that most people in their inner social circle supported the war, compared to 39 percent who opposed the war. By October 2025, 55 percent of Russians in their inner social circle opposed the war, compared to 45 who supported the war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All thi, however, has not appeared to have affected Putin, who, according to the Jones.McCabe analysis “remains undeterred by the high casualty and fatality rates, and Russia’s economic downturn is unlikely to bring the Kremlin to the negotiating table—at least on terms that would be acceptable to Ukraine or Europe.” They say, “Putin may be willing to accept the high casualty and fatality numbers because most of these soldiers are from such regions as the Far East and North Caucasus—and not politically vital areas for him, such as Moscow and St. Petersburg.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Jones/McCabe analysis finds, “President Putin and the Russian government have been adept in conducting an aggressive disinformation campaign that has convinced some policymakers, including in Washington, that Russian victory is inevitable, despite substantial evidence to the contrary.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CSIS team attributes that to Russia having “boosted its funding for state-run media in 2026 by roughly 54 percent, indicating a commitment to intensified information warfare. The Kremlin’s propaganda machine is designed to sustain domestic support for the regime and its war against Ukraine, as well as to convince key foreign audiences that the war has been successful and needs to continue.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perils of Premature Automation</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/premature-ai-adoption-in-developing-economies-could-hinder-development-by-mark-alexandre-doumba-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developing countries would be wise to pursue deliberate sequencing before embracing automation. That is because embedding AI in fragmented and outdated administrative systems and sectors with stagnant productivity will most likely eliminate middle-skill jobs without creating new engines of growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Ukraine Is Still Standing</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/ukraine-russia-war-civic-resistance-civil-society-volunteers-democracy-protests/</link>
      <description>Civic resistance underpins the country’s defense—and its democracy, too.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing Has a Data Problem</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/effective-housing-policy-requires-global-standardized-data-infrastructure-by-rosanne-haggerty-and-ruby-bolaria-shifrin-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lack of basic tools to track and understand housing has resulted in a patchwork of individual programs and little clarity on whether any of them meet basic access and affordability needs. The promise of AI, which requires structured, standardized inputs, makes addressing this data-infrastructure gap more urgent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Russia’s War Has Devastated Civilian Life in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/02/24/how-russias-war-has-devastated-civilian-life-in-ukraine/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the tiny town of Krasnopillia in rural Ukraine, the stillness of the night is shattered by the whine of a Russian drone. Seconds later, a community hospital bursts into flames. Sparks and debris rain down across the skeletons of trees as the fire sends plumes of smoke into the pitch-black sky. Dozens of people [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/02/24/how-russias-war-has-devastated-civilian-life-in-ukraine/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How Russia’s War Has Devastated Civilian Life in Ukraine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India-Brazil Bond Deepens With Critical Minerals Pact</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/india-brazil-bond-deepens-with-critical-minerals-pact/</link>
      <description>The two countries have also agreed to double existing bilateral trade to $30 billion by 2030.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon’s spending plan doubles down on land, air, sea robots</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/02/pentagons-spending-plan-doubles-down-land-air-sea-robots/411628/</link>
      <description>A look at new tech efforts in the Pentagon’s $151 billion reconciliation allocation plan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ayatollah Khamenei’s Politics of Martyrdom</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/iran-ayatollah-khamenei-martyrdom-surrender-war-united-states-trump/</link>
      <description>Iran's leader is unlikely to ever accept surrender to the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duterte Finally Faces ICC Reckoning for His ‘War on Drugs’</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/duterte-icc-court-hearing-war-drugs/</link>
      <description>The trial has already become a domestic political football.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Tehran’s Two-Tiered Internet Is so Dangerous</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/24/tehran-internet-tiered-connectivity-shutdown/</link>
      <description>Authoritarian regimes elsewhere are taking note.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Iran Will Escalate</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/why-iran-will-escalate</link>
      <description>U.S. military strikes and the risk of a quagmire.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Iran Will Escalate</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/middle-east/why-iran-will-escalate</link>
      <description>U.S. military strikes and the risk of a quagmire.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s National Security Reckoning</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/japan/japans-national-security-reckoning</link>
      <description>How Tokyo is adjusting to a more dangerous world.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s New Export: Aircraft Debt</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/chinas-new-export-aircraft-debt/</link>
      <description>COMAC's aircraft exports have brought healthy competition to a stagnant global aviation duopoly, but how they are financed should raise some concerns.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newly Elected Myanmar Parliament to Convene in mid-March, Junta Says</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/newly-elected-myanmar-parliament-to-convene-in-mid-march-junta-says/</link>
      <description>After their initial meetings, the two houses of parliament will reconvene to select a new president who will take office in April.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording: Ukraine: Prospects for Peace, Four Years After Russia’s Invasion</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/members-event-recordings/recording-ukraine-prospects-peace-four-years-after-russias-invasion</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An expert panel discussion on the prospects for peace, four years after Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 12: The Elder Moltke: Preparing for Victory in 1800s Prussia</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/talking-strategy/episode-12-elder-moltke-preparing-victory-1800s-prussia</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot;&gt;How did Prussia turn from a beaten underdog into the leader of a united Germany following its victories of the 19th century?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should Europe Start Talking to Russia?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/should-europe-start-talking-russia</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;How to negotiate with Putin, and what to discuss?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Years After Russia’s Invasion of Ukraine: Can the Stalemate Be Broken?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/news-and-comment/video-commentary/four-years-after-russias-invasion-ukraine-can-stalemate-be-broken</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With Russia and Ukraine rapidly adapting to and imitating each other's technical innovations, it seems no side has been able to gain a decisive edge in the conflict after four years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Crime: Could a New Protocol Help Us Follow the Money?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/environmental-crime-could-new-protocol-help-us-follow-money</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As discussions advance on an additional protocol to the UN Convention against Transnational Organized Crime, greater focus is needed on the possible benefits for efforts to trace the illicit profits behind cross-border environmental offending.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duterte Played Central Role in Drug War Killings, ICC Prosecutors Claim</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/duterte-played-central-role-in-drug-war-killings-icc-prosecutors-claim/</link>
      <description>The court's deputy prosecutor said that the former Philippine leader was “at the very heart” of a plan to “neutralize alleged criminals, including through murder.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakh Journalists are Being Fined for Surveying Public Opinion on the Upcoming Referendum</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/kazakh-journalists-are-being-fined-for-surveying-public-opinion-on-the-upcoming-referendum/</link>
      <description>As Kazakhstan prepares to vote on crucial constitutional changes, media workers are being fined for asking the public about the vote.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Photos: Rohingya Refugees Watch Their World Burn – Again and Again</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/in-photos-rohingya-refugees-watch-their-world-burn-again-and-again/</link>
      <description>Repeated fires in the refugee camps have become a deadly pattern, leaving already displaced families with nothing.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
