<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Milan-26: India’s Maritime Diplomacy Comes of Age</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/milan-26-indias-maritime-diplomacy-comes-of-age/</link>
      <description>The “naval trifecta” in Visakhapatnam underlines India’s hard and soft power alike.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Protests Have Ended. The State’s Terror Campaign Has Not.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/irans-protests-have-ended-the-states-terror-campaign-has-not/</link>
      <description>Tens of thousands of people are being held in secret detentions sites.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How dangerous is Donald Trump’s “endangerment” decision?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/13/how-dangerous-is-donald-trumps-endangerment-decision</link>
      <description>It removes a cornerstone of climate regulation</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facing the Elephant in Munich</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/munich-security-conference-msc-merz-germany-trump-europe/</link>
      <description>Europe is not tiptoeing around Trump anymore.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Chapter for Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/bangladesh-parliamentary-elections-bnp-tarique-rahman-sheikh-hasina/</link>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party claims victory in the country’s first parliamentary elections since its 2024 Generation Z-led uprising.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is This What an Economic Bubble Looks Like?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/is-this-what-an-economic-bubble-looks-like/</link>
      <description>AI investment is soaring, but returns remain uncertain.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe to America: ‘We Are Looking for New Partners’</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/msc-europe-looking-for-new-partners-american-tariff-trade/</link>
      <description>FP’s all-star panel at the Munich Security Conference.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Deportations and Extraditions, Kazakhstan Continues Pursuit of Fled Russians</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/with-deportations-and-extraditions-kazakhstan-continues-pursuit-of-fled-russians/</link>
      <description>With its move toward extraditing Russian activist Yulia Yemelyanova, Kazakhstan restates its efforts to keep politically sensitive individuals at a distance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Defensive Democracy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/defensive-democracy-authoritarianism-history-liberalism/</link>
      <description>What is at stake today is not whether democracy can spread but whether it can survive at all.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting China’s Winter Olympics Rise</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/winter-olympics-milan-cortina-china-medals-soft-power-xi/</link>
      <description>How Beijing has navigated sports and soft power, from Lake Placid to Milan Cortina.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/news-quiz-thailand-election-netanyahu-trump-gaza-bad-bunny-super-bowl/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Feb. 7: Bangladesh, Barbados, and Thailand vote; Netanyahu goes to Washington; and Bad Bunny wows with his Super Bowl halftime show.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Park Chan-wook’s Murderous Comedy of Corporate Manners Is a Masterpiece</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/no-other-choice-film-lay-off-murder-park-chan-wook/</link>
      <description>‘No Other Choice’ shows a man’s world collapsing—with deadly results.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem With Representative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/helene-landemore-representative-politics-democracy-politicians-citizen-rule/</link>
      <description>What if elections aren’t the be-all and end-all?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Demise of the Washington Post Is a Global Problem</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/washington-post-bezos-democracy-us-global-media-politics/</link>
      <description>What Jeff Bezos’s actions signal to news outlets around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the shingles vaccine slow ageing?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/13/can-the-shingles-vaccine-slow-ageing</link>
      <description>The evidence is surprisingly strong</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Addis Ababa-Djibouti Railway: Still Growing 8 Years Later</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-addis-ababa-djibouti-railway-still-growing-8-years-later/</link>
      <description>Two years after the handover to local control, the China-built railway is not done transforming the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the Monroe Doctrine to Maduro: The Precedent Problem in U.S.</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/monroe-doctrine-the-precedent-problem</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;More than a century ago, Elihu Root warned that American power was outrunning the institutions meant to govern it. Root held unique authority on this question. As both Secretary of War and Secretary of State under Theodore Roosevelt, he helped design the institutions and doctrines that carried the United States from a continental republic into the role of a global actor. He professionalized the Army after the Spanish-American War, imposed civilian and legal structure on an expanding military, and spent much of his career attempting to bind America’s power to durable norms before habit hardened into entitlement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That project matters again. In January, the Trump administration carried out an operation that resulted in Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro being taken into U.S. custody and transferred to Florida to face federal narcoterrorism charges. The action was legally defensible under existing statutes and drew intense attention at home, dividing domestic opinion. It was also the kind of operation Root would have recognized as dangerous—not because it violated the law, but because it normalized the use of military force as an instrument of policy once legal justification could be established.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Root confronted this problem directly in 1906, when he offered a sentence that has since been quoted far more often than it has been examined: “The United States is practically sovereign on this continent, and its fiat is law upon the subjects to which it confines its interposition.” Read in isolation, the line can sound jingoistic, a blunt declaration of national entitlement. Root intended something narrower and more cautionary. He was describing a condition of power, not endorsing it. The sentence reflected his concern that American dominance exercised without discipline would weaken its own legitimacy. For Root, it always mattered that America acted within the law—but legality could not substitute for judgment. Once law became a post-hoc justification rather than a governing constraint, it would serve power instead of limiting it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Root understood this danger because he had helped build the system he was warning against. The Monroe Doctrine, as originally conceived in 1823, was framed as a barrier against European intervention in the Western Hemisphere. It was defensive in character. The Roosevelt Corollary, which Root helped construct in 1904, transformed that posture into an assertion of U.S. authority to intervene when Washington judged instability intolerable. The logic was that disciplined American supervision was preferable to either European intervention or regional chaos. In practice, this produced a system of ongoing intervention that stopped short of formal empire while exercising many of its functions—military occupations in Haiti and the Dominican Republic, repeated interventions in Nicaragua and Cuba, and coercive diplomacy justified in the language of order and stability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The consequences of that arrangement soon became visible. Root spent the latter part of his career arguing for international arbitration, multilateral institutions, and legal frameworks that would constrain American power even as the country grew stronger. He won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1912 for that work. But his warning proved easier to admire than to heed. Over time, his diagnosis of American dominance flattened into justification and extended well beyond its original hemispheric frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recognize the appeal of that logic because I once believed in it. In my twenties, working in Washington on national security issues at the end of the Cold War and into the early 2000s, I believed that the freedoms we enjoyed in the United States were a privilege that should not be exclusive, and that American power could and should be used to defend and extend the political conditions that made those freedoms possible. I sometimes imagined an America less burdened by the expectation that every use of power required a moral narrative alongside it—more openly transactional, less apologetic. I was a neocon before it mattered, and perhaps even MAGA before it was born. Iraq forced a reckoning, in part because it revealed how easily power justified by necessity could outrun foresight, legitimacy, and responsibility for what followed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Maduro case, the debate in Washington quickly narrowed to whether the seizure could be defended legally. That question is necessary, but incomplete. The rule of law is the foundation of democratic authority, yet legality alone cannot carry the weight of wise judgment. A government can act within the law and still act unwisely, weakening the norms it depends on once power alone is no longer sufficient. American power should be used to confront injustice, and non-military tools are often preferable to force. The question is not whether to act, but how routinely power is applied once legality becomes its own justification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Maduro episode is unlikely to be the last application of this logic. Attention inside the administration has already shifted toward Cuba, where Washington is applying pressure through fuel interdiction, secondary sanctions, and emergency authorities framed as enforcement rather than intervention. These measures are calibrated, legally grounded, and short of war. They represent controlled intervention rather than unconstrained power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That distinction matters—but it does not resolve the underlying risk. The Caracas operation involved the direct use of military force against a sitting head of state. Cuba involves economic pressure and interdiction. Root would have recognized the difference. He also would have understood how the former creates permission structures that make escalation from the latter more likely. The logic that validates measured coercion in Cuba is the same logic that justified seizing Maduro. Each action establishes precedent for the next. The question is not whether any single measure crosses a line, but whether the accumulation of incremental steps creates a system in which restraint becomes optional rather than structural.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a deeper tension at work. If the United States treats spheres of influence as an acceptable norm in its own hemisphere, it becomes harder to reject similar claims elsewhere. Vladimir Putin’s arguments about near-abroad authority rest on a logic the United States weakens when it asserts special prerogatives rooted in power rather than principle. The cases are not morally equivalent. Putin’s interventions in Ukraine and Georgia involve territorial conquest and the erasure of sovereignty in ways American actions in the hemisphere do not. But the structure of the argument is similar enough that adversaries will exploit the parallel and allies will notice the inconsistency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Root understood that sovereignty without discipline invites decay. The question before us is not whether America can act this way. Clearly, it can. The question is whether doing so strengthens the order it claims to lead or erodes it through accumulated precedent. Power exercised without restraint rarely remains exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Root’s warning was never about weakness. It was about the difference between authority and dominance, between leadership that endures and power that exhausts itself. A century later, we are testing that distinction again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Path From Energy Dependence</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-energy-dependence-must-become-electro-state-by-navneeraj-sharma-and-arvind-subramanian-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that geopolitical wrangling increasingly shapes international trade dynamics, India must reduce its dependence on imported energy to maximize its strategic autonomy. While it could invest more in hydrocarbons, the far better option is to become a renewables-powered electro-state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the High-Stakes U.S. Pressure Campaign on Iran</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/inside-the-high-stakes-u-s-pressure-campaign-on-iran</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/at-sea-in-this-handout-provided-by-the-u-s-navy-uss-gerald-r-ford-cvn-78-f-a-18e-f-super-hornets-assigned-to-strike-fight.jpg?id=64425268&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;height=800&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT INTERVIEW – &lt;/strong&gt;U.S. officials say a second aircraft carrier will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/12/us/politics/uss-ford-venezuela-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;deployed&lt;/a&gt; to the Middle East amid the administration’s efforts to pressure Iran to agree to restrictions on its nuclear program. The USS &lt;em&gt;Gerald R. Ford&lt;/em&gt; is expected to join the USS &lt;em&gt;Abraham Lincoln&lt;/em&gt; in a significant build-up of U.S. military force in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Trump said this week that he does believe the U.S. will be able to reach a deal with Tehran but warns that if talks fail, the outcome could turn far more severe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After meeting with the president in Washington this week, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is less optimistic about a deal, telling reporters on Thursday that “...I expressed general skepticism about any agreement with Iran, but I said that if an agreement is reached, it must include the elements that are important to Israel: not only the nuclear program, but also the ballistic missiles, and also the Iranian proxies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Iran’s national security chief Ali Larijani is warning that Tehran would strike U.S. bases in the region if it is attacked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt; spoke with former National Intelligence Manager for Iran at ODNI Norm Roule about what is likely to come next. Roule, who is also a Cipher Brief Expert, travels regularly to the region for meetings with senior leaders. We spoke with him in this exclusive interview about the risks and opportunities facing the U.S. with regard to Iran and what he believes Iran is likely to do first if the U.S. does launch a military attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;expert-block-container expert-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Norman T. Roule&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.rbl.ms/56514528/origin.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;expert-name&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule&quot;&gt;Norman T. Roule&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;expert-original-about&quot;&gt;
          Norman Roule is a geopolitical and energy consultant who served for 34 years in the Central Intelligence Agency, managing numerous programs relating to Iran and the Middle East. He also served as the National Intelligence Manager for Iran (NIM-I)\n at ODNI, where he was responsible for all aspects of national intelligence policy related to Iran.
    	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;THE INTERVIEW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: The U.S. is continuing to deploy military assets to the Middle East. How are you assessing the opportunities given where talks with Tehran are at the moment? What do you see as realistic U.S. objectives? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You’re correct to start with a focus on objectives. This will give us targets to assess risks and opportunities, as well as the report card against which the success of any strategy must be judged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A number of these are included in the Trump Administration’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/2025-National-Security-Strategy.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/2025-National-Security-Strategy.pdf&quot;&gt;December 2025 National Security Strategy&lt;/a&gt;: avoid involvement in a costly regional war or nation-building, ensure that regional sea lanes and choke points remain open, and maintain stable energy markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Islamic Republic, every Administration – indeed the entire international community – has agreed that Tehran must cease the oppression of its people, must not be allowed to develop a nuclear weapon, its missile programs must be constrained, and its malign regional adventurism and support for terrorism must end. This latter set of ambitions has been part of not only this administration’s Iran strategy but also of the first Trump administration's strategy. Former Secretary of State Mike Pompeo’s May 2018 Twelve-Point &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/clip/public-affairs-event/secretary-pompeo-lays-out-strategy-against-iran/4730391&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Speech&lt;/a&gt; on Iran highlighted each of these goals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the current approach addresses areas where there are different views on the balance between nonproliferation and broader regional issues, and on whether to resolve the nuclear issue first and address other issues later, or to handle them together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice once famously reminded a group that policymaking is done in a reality where we must remember that we are a country and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stanforddaily.com/2019/03/27/condoleezza-rice-discusses-biggest-threats-to-democracy-with-other-hoover-fellows/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;https://stanforddaily.com/2019/03/27/condoleezza-rice-discusses-biggest-threats-to-democracy-with-other-hoover-fellows/&quot;&gt;not an NGO&lt;/a&gt;. National interests, security, and power drive foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humanitarian goals will be important in our policies, but they won’t be the primary driver. Ours is not the first generation to face the challenge of how far we should go to encourage and militarily support those who courageously stand against tyrants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Woodrow Wilson faced this dilemma as White Russian armies fought the Bolsheviks in 1918-1920. Several presidents were pressed to respond as Germans, Czechs, Hungarians, and other protestors valiantly stood up against heavily armed Soviet occupiers in the 1940s, 50s, and 60s. It’s easy to say we should do more, but these decisions are never clear. In this case, there have been many calls for military action, and it is easy to understand the rationale, watching the regime’s cruelty against the courage of Iranian protestors. But it is also unclear exactly what we are to attack, for how long, how we would measure success, whether the results would justify the ramifications of dealing with Iran’s military retaliation and lastly, whether the moment for such action has passed. Every presidential advisor would try to address these questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But if policy choices regarding Iran involve profound risks, the events of this month show that kicking the can down the road is no less dangerous. Inevitably, the can gets heavier with every kick and the road gets shorter. There is absolutely nothing regarding the Iran threat today that hasn’t been predicted for years. The international community refused to risk the price of hard actions against Iran, and elected to use repeated attempts at diplomacy, corrosive sanctions (which were effective in limiting Iranian capabilities) and until June 2025, increasingly empty threats of military action to constrain Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In terms of opportunities, the Administration has been consistent in its focus on four priorities with regard to Iran. The most recent has been humanitarian and involves the U.S. threat of military action against the regime if it continues using widespread murderous force against Iranian protestors. No one can deny the horrific and bloody crimes committed by this regime during the recent unrest. The violence has subsided along with the protests, albeit widespread arrests and detentions continue. The President has claimed that his threats of military action limited Iran’s use of violence and stopped Iran from hanging large numbers of protestors. Some certainly argue that we should have used military action to aid the protesters, but this raises the question I mentioned earlier and related issues about whether we had sufficient assets in the area to address potential “Day After” consequences. This is a question with no single clear answer. However, our use of diplomatic, economic, and military pressure to prevent regime violence against protesters is appropriate and consistent with our national values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: The White House is now focused on Iran’s nuclear, missile, and regional threats. Talk to us about why this is a priority and whether the current moment is an opportunity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s start with Iran’s nuclear program. The June 2025 Twelve-Day War severely degraded – at least for now – Iran’s nuclear weapons capability. But that capability can be rebuilt, and if Iran has any enrichment capacity, especially one not under international supervision, they can try to produce weapons-grade enriched uranium. But if Iran doesn’t agree diplomatically not to rebuild these capabilities and to provide the International Atomic Energy Agency with the access it requires, we should steel ourselves to the requirement that the Israelis or we will need to repeat the June 2025 military strikes when Iran chooses to rebuild.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, we have the Iranian ballistic missile threat. The unclassified &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dia.mil/Portals/110/Documents/News/golden_dome.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;https://www.dia.mil/Portals/110/Documents/News/golden_dome.pdf&quot;&gt;May 2025 Defense Intelligence Assessment&lt;/a&gt; stated that Iran’s space-launch vehicle program could give it the capability to build as many as sixty intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs) by 2035.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran’s repeated use of ballistic missiles against multiple countries makes it reasonable for Israel to be concerned about the long-term size and direction of this program as well. Iran’s missile program is not currently a threat to Western Europe. If Iran builds ICBMs, this, of course, changes. The idea that anyone would allow a country with Iran’s political, military, and nuclear history to build dozens of potentially nuclear-tipped ICBMs within nine years should not be acceptable. It would also be too easy to imagine a scenario in which Iran and North Korea joined forces to threaten the U.S. Homeland. So, we either compel Iran to change the course of its ballistic missile program, work with Europe to build a costly missile shield, or destroy that program militarily now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last, Iran’s Quds Force remains operational and has begun to repeat what will be a several-year campaign to reconstitute its regional proxy program. This is not the first time the Quds Force has been required to rebuild a regional program amid great risk to the regime. In fact, it’s the third time since 2003.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By any traditional measure, the Islamic Republic represents a failed revolutionary state ruling a disillusioned and angry population. In many ways, it resembles the final years of the Soviet Union: an ossified regime whose ideology is dismissed even by its most ardent supporters. The regime retains power through repression, coercion, corruption, and a multi-layered system of lucrative patronage that its most potent supporters would lose in any reformed government. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The administration’s rhetoric and actions make a reasonable case that the current moment should be tested to see whether, with further pressure – which could include military action – the regime would sacrifice these malign activities in exchange for sanctions relief that would allow the Islamic Republic to survive. This won’t satisfy those who seek regime change, but it does parallel Washington’s approach to Venezuela. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: How would you assess Iran’s losses to date?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; By any measure, Iran’s losses have been extraordinary, consequential, and unprecedented in modern history for a country of its size, regional influence, and global economic impact in the energy market. The last two years have been crowded with examples of the collapse of its political, economic, and national security architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In terms of leadership, the regime has endured the death of President Ebrahim Raisi, who was highly likely to be Supreme Leader Khamenei’s choice. His passing was followed by a historic low turnout in elections that led to the Pezeshkian presidency. Pezeshkian failed to deliver on his economic promises. His tenure has included the dismissal or resignation of two vice presidents, two cabinet officials, and other senior officials. He spends much of his time apologizing to the Iranian people for the government's failures, hoping this tactic will win him popular support. It’s somewhat understandable in that the economic complaints that ignited Iran’s recent nationwide unrest occurred in a country that has endured months of shortages of water, electricity, natural gas, and refined products, which forces the repeated closure of schools, government offices, and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The World Bank estimates that one-third of Iranians (25-26 million) are below the poverty line. Annual inflation reached 43 percent in December 2025. The rial, which fell to 1.43 million to the dollar before the unrest, just reached 1.63 million to the dollar and appears to have no bottom. U.S. Secretary of the Treasury Scott Bessent’s comments on recent U.S. expanded sanctions in response to Iran’s handling of protests underscores Washington’s intent to use whatever economic tools it can to pressure Tehran.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: If you’re looking at this in terms of Iran’s own national security, how does it look?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In terms of national security, the picture is bleak. Over the past two years, Israel killed the commanders of Iran’s primary proxy partners and destroyed the group's strategic capacity. Russia and China proved to be of no help in the June War, nor could they stop the reimposition of United Nations Security Council Sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The loss of Syria and Venezuela cost Iran its closest external allies, reducing its regional and global political reach. The June War was a profound defeat for Iran’s air defenses and intelligence services. Israel and the U.S. easily destroyed key elements of Iran’s hugely expensive nuclear program, an effort that has cost billions of dollars and for which Iran has endured decades of political and economic isolation. The conflict cost Tehran many of its most experienced military and nuclear personnel, and left Iran with billions of dollars in damage to its nuclear and missile infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, Iran’s murderous killing of protestors and internet shutdown starkly illustrated that the most successful aspect of the regime’s national security investments remains its tools of oppression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: Many have described Tehran today as weak. Yet the regime keeps surviving protests. Its missile programs are considered a potential threat, and policymakers are worried about its capacity to threaten the Strait of Hormuz, impacting energy markets. What’s your take on this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The regime is weaker in many areas, but it is more accurate to say that the regime has never been more fragile and is strategically weaker than it has been in decades. All of this is known to Iran’s Supreme National Security Council. But they can also list strengths they believe will help them survive. I would rather not list these publicly but suffice it to say that key elites and security elements remain unified, disciplined, and responsive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the government’s deep national unpopularity is a fact, it can’t be ignored, as a substantial portion of the population remains uncommitted to its overthrow, and some are committed to its survival rather than supporting the opposition. Externally, it may have no reliable state allies, but nor does it face an international coalition. The U.S. is its primary adversary. What it achieves against Washington will shape its relations with the world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran may not be able to compete with the U.S. militarily, but that has always been the case. Its leaders know that they must be able to threaten an asymmetric response: regional and global economic destruction by missile, drones, and cyber-attacks will immediately begin should the U.S. attack Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This list should leave your readers with the sense that these men believe the best days of the regime are ahead. That would imply stupidity, which is not a characteristic that gets one through Iran’s national security shark pool of political and policy challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They wake every morning, knowing that their domestic political and economic realities make another cycle of nationwide anti-regime unrest inevitable. The Supreme Leader will be 87-years old on April 19. His eventual passing will trigger the final transition to the regime’s post-revolutionary generation and they have had years to prepare for this moment. But his passing, which could occur at any time, could create a new crisis. And of course, if an actual military conflict with the U.S. takes place, the survival of the regime, and the personal survival of those in Iran’s leadership could be in question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: How are you assessing the impact of the Trump administration’s approach right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The structure of the Trump administration’s strategy remains strategically conventional. The administration’s primary goal is a diplomatic outcome that avoids a conventional war or an episode that leaves Iran empowered and U.S. credibility damaged. Hence, the likelihood of a dramatically powerful military attack on Iran remains high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The administration has made no secret of its buildup of one of the most powerful offensive air, missile, and air defense capabilities in history. Israel has also threatened military action. The President is also reportedly considering dispatching another aircraft carrier task force to augment his offensive capabilities further. The way this force has been deployed thus far shows that it is part of the pressure campaign and that the President has not yet authorized military operations. Of course, this last point could change at any time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The administration has deployed a senior diplomatic team and urged regional partners to press Iran to engage with the U.S. to reach a deal. The administration has loudly announced new economic pressure on Iran and of course, deployed a massive military force. All of this is meant to pressure Iran’s leaders into making concessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the subject of timelines. This current process is likely to last until the president and his advisors believe they have exhausted diplomacy. If the administration continues to believe it must strategically change Iran’s nuclear, missile, and Qods Force, then military action becomes a very high probability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Predicting this timeline is impossible as it is shaped by Iran’s decisions, partner input, U.S. political conditions, and even unexpected events, such as a sudden spike in unrest within Iran, the sudden death of the Supreme Leader, etc. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: What about Iran’s response?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Iran needs to conduct multiple actions simultaneously to reduce the pressure on the regime and improve its chance of long-term survival. These steps include ending the protests, improving its military capabilities, and developing a diplomatic strategy to delay a U.S. military strike. But in the near term, Tehran remains unlikely to give Washington what it wants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domestically, Tehran must ensure and demonstrate leadership and unity among security forces. The country’s leadership will continue to comprise a spectrum of trusted actors. Security forces will aggressively seek to locate and detain anyone believed to have been part of the recent unrest and anyone who they believe has engaged in unauthorized contact with Western opposition or media, and expedite trials to show that the regime’s control remains strong. The regime will seek opportunities to project an atmosphere of normalcy and, as we have already seen, organize pro-regime rallies and events to show that it has its own base of support. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Externally, the regime will seek to project defiance and confidence. Its primary diplomatic goal will be to buy time and prevent coalitions from forming, so it will seek negotiations, indirectly whenever possible, and will always focus on the most complicated issue: the nuclear program. Its public comments on the talks will be positive and vague. This has been its usual practice because doing so has a positive impact on the value of the rial to the dollar and supports the regime’s propaganda on diplomacy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should expect Tehran to maintain oil production and maybe even try to increase floating storage on shadow-fleet assets in Asia to allow it to meet contracts during any short-term conflict with the U.S. If it feels it needs to close the Strait of Hormuz, it has multiple ways of doing so, but we shouldn’t be surprised if the U.S. military has multiple options for dealing with that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, it will prepare missile and cyber operations both to signal deterrence and to survive any U.S. and possibly combined U.S.-Israel attack. In the absence of a credible air defense, its deterrence rests on a public diplomacy narrative that it stands ready to launch broad attacks against every U.S. base in the region, Israel, and to close the Strait of Hormuz and perhaps attack oil export facilities, damaging the international oil market, if the U.S. attacks. Iran hopes these statements will spark debate in the U.S. and diplomatic pressure from the international community against Washington over an attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscribe to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confidence, Interoperability, and the Limits of U.S. Decision Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/confidence-interoperability-and-the-limits-of-u-s-decision-systems</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;In recent months, U.S. policy debates have increasingly acknowledged that the decisive contests of the 21st century will not be fought primarily on conventional battlefields. They will be fought in the cognitive domain, through influence, perception, legitimacy, and decision velocity. This recognition is important and depends on an adequate technical and institutional layer to deliver durable strategic advantage. Cognitive advantage cannot be declared. It must be engineered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the United States does not lack data, expertise, or analytic talent. What it lacks is decision-shaping architecture capable of producing consistently high-confidence strategic judgment in complex, adaptive environments. The result is a persistent gap between how confident U.S. decisions appear and how reliable they are - especially in Gray Zone conflicts where informal networks, narrative control, and societal resilience determine outcomes long before failure becomes visible. Afghanistan was not an anomaly. Nor will it be the last warning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Confidence Illusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In U.S. national security discourse, the phrase “high confidence” carries enormous weight. It signals authority, rigor, and analytical closure. Yet extensive research into expert judgment, including studies of national-security professionals themselves, shows that confidence is routinely mis-calibrated in complex political environments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judgments expressed with 80–90 percent confidence often prove correct closer to 50–70 percent of the time in complex, real-world strategic settings. This is not a marginal error. It is a structural one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem is not individual analysts. It is how institutions aggregate information, frame uncertainty, and present judgment to decision-makers. While pockets of analytic under confidence have existed historically, recent large-scale evidence shows overconfidence is now the dominant institutional risk at the decision level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent U.S. experience from Iraq to Afghanistan suggests that institutional confidence is often declared without calibration, while systems lack mechanisms to enforce learning when that confidence proves misplaced. In kinetic conflicts, this gap can be masked by overwhelming force. In Gray Zone contests, it is fatal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Afghanistan: Studied Failure Without Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Few conflicts in modern U.S. history have been studied as extensively as Afghanistan. Over two decades, the U.S. government produced hundreds of strategies, assessments, revisions, and after-action reviews. After the collapse of 2021, that effort intensified: inspector general reports, departmental after-action reviews, congressional investigations, and now a congressionally mandated Afghanistan War Commission. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volume of analysis is not the problem. The problem is that these efforts never coalesced into a unified learning system. Across reports, the same lessons recur misjudged political legitimacy, overestimated partner capacity, underestimated informal power networks, ignored warning indicators, and persistent optimism unsupported by ground truth. Yet there is no evidence of a shared architecture that connected these findings across agencies, tracked which assumptions repeatedly failed, or recalibrated confidence over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lessons were documented, not operationalized. Knowledge was archived, not integrated. Each new plan began largely anew, informed by memory and narrative rather than by a living system of institutional learning. When failure came, it appeared suddenly. In reality, it had been structurally prepared for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reports Are Not Learning Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This distinction matters because the U.S. response to failure is often to commission better reports. More detailed. More comprehensive. More authoritative. But reports - even excellent ones - do not learn. Learning systems require interoperability: shared data models, common assumptions, feedback loops, and mechanisms that measure accuracy over time. They require the ability to test judgments against outcomes, update beliefs, and carry lessons forward into new contexts. Absent this architecture, reports function as historical records rather than decision engines. They improve documentation, not confidence. This is why the United States can spend decades studying Afghanistan and still enter new Gray Zone engagements without demonstrably higher confidence than before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asking the Wrong Questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The confidence problem is compounded by a deeper analytic flaw: U.S. systems are often designed to answer the wrong questions. Many contemporary analytic and AI-enabled tools optimize for what is verifiable, auditable, or easily measured. In the information domain, they ask whether content is authentic or false. In compliance and due diligence, they ask whether an individual or entity appears in a registry or sanctions database. In governance reform, they ask whether a program is efficient or wasteful. These questions are not irrelevant, but they are rarely decisive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gray Zone conflicts hinge on different variables: who influences whom, through which networks, toward what behavioral effect. They hinge on informal authority, narrative resonance, social trust, and the ability of adversaries to adapt faster than bureaucratic learning cycles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A video can be authentic and still strategically effective as disinformation. An individual can be absent from any database and still shape ideology, mobilization, or legitimacy within a community. A system can appear efficient while quietly eroding the functions that sustain resilience. When analytic systems are designed around shallow questions, they create an illusion of understanding precisely where understanding matters most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOGE and the Domestic Mirror&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This failure pattern is not confined to foreign policy. Recent government efficiency initiatives-often grouped under the banner of “Department of Government Efficiency” or DOGE - style reforms - illustrate the same analytic tendency in domestic governance. These efforts framed government primarily as a cost and efficiency problem. Success was measured in budget reductions, headcount cuts, and streamlined processes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What they largely did not assess were system functions, hidden dependencies, mission-critical resilience, or second-order effects. Independent reviews later showed that efficiency gains often disrupted oversight and weakened essential capabilities - not because reform was misguided, but because the wrong questions were prioritized. DOGE did not fail for lack of data or ambition. It failed because it optimized what was measurable while missing what was decisive. The parallel to national security strategy is direct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Gray Zone Conflicts Punish Miscalibration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gray Zone conflicts are unforgiving environments for miscalibrated confidence. They unfold slowly, adaptively, and below the threshold of overt war. By the time failure becomes visible, the decisive contests - over legitimacy, elite alignment, and narrative control - have already been lost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adversaries in these environments do not seek decisive battles. They seek to exploit institutional blind spots, fragmented learning, and overconfident decision cycles. They build networks that persist through shocks, cultivate influence that survives regime change, and weaponize uncertainty itself. When U.S. decision systems cannot reliably distinguish between what is known, what is assumed, and what is merely believed, they cede cognitive advantage by default.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What “90 Percent Confidence” Actually Means&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This critique is often misunderstood as a call for predictive omniscience. It is not. According to existing standards, No system can achieve near-perfect confidence in open-ended geopolitical outcomes. But research from forecasting science, high-reliability organizations, and complex systems analysis shows that high confidence is achievable for bounded questions - if systems are designed correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Narrowly scoped judgments, explicit assumptions, calibrated forecasting, continuous feedback, and accountability for accuracy can push reliability toward 90 percent in defined decision contexts. This is not theoretical. It has been demonstrated repeatedly in domains that take learning seriously. What the U.S. lacks is not the science or the technology. It is the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Advantage Requires Cognitive Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central lesson of Afghanistan, Gray Zone conflict, and even domestic governance reform is the same: data abundance without learning architecture produces confidence illusions, not advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cognitive advantage is not about thinking harder or collecting more information. It is about building systems that can integrate knowledge, test assumptions, recalibrate confidence, and adapt before failure becomes visible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until U.S. decision-shaping systems are redesigned around these principles, the United States will continue to repeat familiar patterns - confident, well-intentioned, and structurally unprepared for the conflicts that matter most. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The warning is clear. The opportunity remains with Yaqin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: DHS shutdown likely; US troops leave al-Tanf; CNO’s plea to industry; Crowded robot-boat market; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-13-2026/411425/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migration Can Provide the Manpower for European Defense</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/europe-immigration-military-russia-ukraine-munich-population-security/</link>
      <description>Creating a pathway to citizenship in return for military service will help Europe stand on its own.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s Liberal Party Has a New Leader, But the Same Headaches</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/australias-liberal-party-has-a-new-leader-but-the-same-headaches/</link>
      <description>Outgoing party leader Sussan Ley left Angus Taylor his first hurdle – and it’s a high one.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Double Whammy for Assam’s Miya Muslims</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/a-double-whammy-for-assams-miya-muslims/</link>
      <description>Political exclusion of Assam’s Bengal-origin Muslims has been adversely impacting their health conditions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s ‘Rat People’: When Education Can’t Deliver on Its Promises</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/chinas-rat-people-when-education-cant-deliver-on-its-promises/</link>
      <description>The number of Chinese who believe that “hard work is rewarded” has collapsed among those born in the 1980s and 1990s.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pacific Youth, Climate Justice, and the Myth of Political Change in Fiji</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/pacific-youth-climate-justice-and-the-myth-of-political-change-in-fiji/</link>
      <description>The year ahead will show whether Fiji’s political old guard can cede to a new generation, or if it will merely continue feeding on the aspirations of the young.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Alone Won’t Stop Lassa Fever</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/west-african-countries-must-be-prepared-for-lassa-fever-vaccine-by-oyeronke-oyebanji-and-virgil-lokossou-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three promising Lassa fever vaccine candidates are in clinical development, one of which could be licensed in the next decade. But to ensure a swift and effective rollout, West African countries must start planning now to determine who should receive it, how to deliver it, and how to finance and regulate it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why North Korea Is Unlikely to Renew Cooperation at Kaesong</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-north-korea-is-unlikely-to-renew-cooperation-at-kaesong/</link>
      <description>The Lee administration may be hoping to resume cooperation at the Kaesong Industrial Complex. But Pyongyang is just not interested.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Colby’s Northeast Asia Tour Tells Us About the Future of Japan-Korea-US Trilateral Deterrence</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-colbys-northeast-asia-tour-tells-us-about-the-future-of-japan-korea-us-trilateral-deterrence/</link>
      <description>Colby’s visits to South Korea and Japan served to reinforce the Trump administration’s Indo-Pacific vision, in which allies’ shoulder “their fair share” of collective defense.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Bangladesh’s old guard build a new democracy?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/13/can-bangladeshs-old-guard-build-a-new-democracy</link>
      <description>The country’s first real election in 18 years is won by a familiar face</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Germany’s Trump Policy Make Sense?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/germany-trump-merz-strategy/</link>
      <description>Friedrich Merz has his own strategy for dealing with the U.S. president, but the verdict is not yet in.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Course Correction for Pakistan’s Space Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/a-course-correction-for-pakistans-space-ambitions/</link>
      <description>Ultimately, SUPARCO’s contemporary relevance is defined by its alignment with Pakistan’s existential challenges: climate resilience, precision agriculture, and national security.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honduras Shows How the US Is Limiting China’s Diplomatic Gains in Central America</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/honduras-shows-how-the-us-is-limiting-chinas-diplomatic-gains-in-central-america/</link>
      <description>As Honduras openly reconsiders its ties with the PRC, it highlights the strong pull still exerted by the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk’s $1.25 Trillion Mirage</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/musk-spacex-xai-merger-produced-predictably-specious-valuation-by-yanis-varoufakis-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More often than not, share prices are rigged, which is why they are a dreadful predictor of profitability even on average, and why they have become the primary instrument for transferring wealth upwards. The SpaceX-xAI merger tells much of this sorry tale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Human Toll of Trump’s Cuba Policy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/us-cuba-trump-oil-blockade-energy-fuel-crisis/</link>
      <description>Washington wants political change in Havana. Ordinary people are paying the price.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Avert the Tragedy of Great-Power Politics</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/europe/how-avert-tragedy-great-power-politics</link>
      <description>Germany knows the costs of a world governed by power alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s SHANTI Bill Unlocks Nuclear Investment</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indias-shanti-bill-unlocks-nuclear-investment/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Central Asia Still Russia’s Backyard?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-central-asia-still-russias-backyard/</link>
      <description>Paternalistic hot takes from Russian commentators regarding Central Asia are nothing new. What’s different these days is that Central Asia has grown up – and stepped out of Russia’s shadow.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Risks of Simplifying US Bank Supervision</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/federal-reserve-loosens-capital-requirements-easing-bank-oversight-despite-risks-by-amit-seru-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Federal Reserve has recently begun to overhaul its approach to bank oversight, raising the bar for enforcement and leaning more heavily on data-driven tools. These changes could impede regulators’ ability to identify emerging risks at a time when the US financial system faces hidden losses and structural weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-alignment as Leverage: Sri Lanka and the India-Pakistan T20 Flare-up</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/non-alignment-as-leverage-sri-lanka-and-the-india-pakistan-t20-flare-up/</link>
      <description>Pakistan said that in solidarity with Bangladesh, it would boycott the cricket match against India in Colombo. Then Sri Lanka walked in to provide all actors with an off-ramp.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexico’s Grim Development Prospects</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/mexico-amlo-scheinbaum-diminished-economic-prospects-by-santiago-levy-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mexico's low and falling growth is not the result of macroeconomic instability, a lack of investment, insufficient labor, or poor export performance. Rather, it stems from low productivity, an unnecessarily large informal sector, and the ruling party's persistent failure to address the problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of American Hegemony</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/despite-social-rot-american-economic-hegemony-may-persist-longer-than-expected-by-jonathan-levy-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Political elites across the ideological spectrum agree that US President Donald Trump’s attacks on democratic institutions mark a historical turning point. Yet despite the chaos that has defined his second presidency, the foundations of America’s economic hegemony remain largely intact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Must Make AI Firms Pay for Training Data</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-make-ai-firms-pay-for-training-data-to-save-journalism-by-anya-schiffrin-and-roberta-carlini-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI summaries and chatbots are siphoning traffic from news sites, but the current process for demanding compensation – suing tech firms – is slow, expensive, and unfair. The European Union must act now to implement a fixed payment scale, before more media outlets go under and tech firms become too powerful to regulate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP Wins Election, Tarique Rahman to Take Oath as Bangladesh’s Next Prime Minister</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/bnp-wins-election-tarique-rahman-to-take-oath-as-bangladeshs-next-prime-minister/</link>
      <description>Although the BNP has secured a two-thirds majority, it faces several challenges, including stabilizing the law and order situation in the country and reviving the economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Japanese Remilitarization Would be Good for India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-japanese-remilitarization-would-be-good-for-india/</link>
      <description>Their geopolitical interests converge for the most part, except in their attitudes toward Russia, and they have a common strategic imperative to counter China.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Defense Ministry Clears Purchase of 114 Rafale Fighter Jets</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indias-defense-ministry-clears-purchase-of-114-rafale-fighter-jets/</link>
      <description>This will cost India more than $280 billion, the price for each aircraft having risen by 60 percent since 2015.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Gaza Gambit: Peacekeeping Mission Meets Political Reality</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesias-gaza-gambit-peacekeeping-mission-meets-political-reality/</link>
      <description>Prabowo Subianto's administration will be forced to fulfill the requirements of the U.N. operation while managing domestic public opinion.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arms Control Was Once Trump’s Signature Issue</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/13/trump-nuclear-order-arms-control/</link>
      <description>What is needed in this multipolar nuclear era is a president with the vision of his younger self.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Divided Opposition</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/iran/irans-divided-opposition</link>
      <description>Only a unified movement can threaten the regime.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Trilemma</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/ai-trilemma</link>
      <description>How to regulate a revolutionary technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cambodian Reporter Detained After Photographing Raid on Scam Center</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/cambodian-reporter-detained-after-photographing-raid-on-scam-center/</link>
      <description>The government's treatment of reporters covering Cambodia's cyber-fraud epidemic raises questions about the nature of its current anti-scam crackdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 04:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Vietnam’s Non-Alignment Foreign Policy Requires Thailand’s Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/why-vietnams-non-alignment-foreign-policy-requires-thailands-cooperation/</link>
      <description>Mainland Southeast Asia’s strategic equilibrium ultimately rests on the mutually reinforcing foreign policy approaches of Hanoi and Bangkok.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s Election Commission Is Next of Kin to Chaos</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/thailands-election-commission-is-next-of-kin-to-chaos/</link>
      <description>The election body that presided over Sunday's shambolic election has a long track record of systemic dysfunction and support for military rule.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Russia Turns Gamers into Fighters</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/how-russia-turns-gamers-fighters</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Kremlin’s weaponization of video games for recruitment and influence is no longer a theoretical risk. To protect the digital commons, the West must treat gaming as a core frontier of contemporary hybrid warfare.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam’s To Lam to Attend ‘Board of Peace’ Summit Next Week</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/vietnams-to-lam-to-attend-board-of-peace-summit-next-week/</link>
      <description>The Vietnamese leader is reportedly also seeking a meeting with President Donald Trump to discuss trade and tariffs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
