<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Why Iran’s Regime Didn’t Collapse</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/iran-regime-collapse-islamic-republic-structure/</link>
      <description>The Islamic Republic was built to withstand sustained unrest.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lisa Cook’s job at the Federal Reserve looks safe</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/21/lisa-cooks-job-at-the-federal-reserve-looks-safe</link>
      <description>The justices sound sceptical about Donald Trump’s move to dismiss her</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Talks Greenland at Davos, Announces ‘Framework’ Deal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/donald-trump-world-economic-forum-davos-speech-greenland/</link>
      <description>The U.S. president said he and the NATO secretary-general “formed the framework of a future deal” but provided few details.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Prepared to Create Its Own Army</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/trump-europe-standing-army-greenland-threats/</link>
      <description>As the United States blusters and threatens, European leaders are making tough choices.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The true danger posed by Donald Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/21/the-true-danger-posed-by-donald-trump</link>
      <description>Despite a tactical retreat, great risks remain</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New U.S. Tariffs Imperil Indian-Backed Port in Iran</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/india-iran-afghanistan-chabahar-port-infrastructure-investment-trump-tariff/</link>
      <description>An infrastructure project between Afghanistan, Iran, and India gets caught in Trump’s crosshairs—again.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s grab for Greenland makes no sense</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/21/donald-trumps-grab-for-greenland-makes-no-sense</link>
      <description>It would harm America’s security and its economy</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Army unveils new tank—five years early</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2026/01/army-unveils-new-tankfive-years-early/410833/</link>
      <description>Built largely of commercial parts, the first M1E3s will head out for testing this summer, the Army’s chief of staff said.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Supreme Court Hears Oral Arguments in Trump-Lisa Cook Case</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/united-states-supreme-court-case-trump-lisa-cook-fed/</link>
      <description>Firing central bank governors may prove to be a red line.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TikTok is still a danger. America no longer cares</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/21/tiktok-is-still-a-danger-america-no-longer-cares</link>
      <description>The app will be owned by allies of the president but retain ties to China</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American decay versus American dynamism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/21/american-decay-versus-american-dynamism</link>
      <description>Only a decline in corporate America’s vigour will dent the country’s dominance of financial markets</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American decay versus American dynamism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/21/american-decay-versus-american-dynamism</link>
      <description>Only a decline in corporate America’s vigour will dent the country’s dominance of financial markets</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Got an idea for reforming defense acquisition? The Pentagon’s all ears.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/got-idea-reforming-defense-acquisition-pentagons-all-ears/410832/</link>
      <description>“We need radically different ideas,” says assistant defense secretary.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kremlin Files: Russia’s Way to the Gray Zone</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-kremlin-files-russias-way-to-the-gray-zone</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/two-men-in-a-serious-conversation-one-in-a-suit-the-other-in-a-military-uniform.jpg?id=63002583&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C44%2C0%2C44&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE KREMLIN FILES / COLUMN — &lt;/strong&gt;(Note: This is the first in a two-part &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-surveillance-state&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;series&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Russian gray zone, or hybrid warfare. In a future article, the author will address the continued evolution of Russian hybrid warfare and its practice in the years immediately leading up to and through Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian hybrid warfare, often referred to in the West as “gray zone” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/gray-zone-warfare&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;conflict&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, has transitioned from theoretical concept to prominent headlines, particularly following the invasion of Ukraine and the Kremlin’s campaigns of sabotage, disinformation, and targeted intelligence actions across Europe and the U.S. What defines Russian-style gray warfare, or hybrid war? What are its doctrinal roots, and how well do these foundations align with assumptions in Western security discussions? To explore these questions, this article analyzes the writings of Russian military thinkers and the views of Russian military and intelligence agencies—covering their terminology, doctrines, and their evolving grasp of non-kinetic conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gray zone operations in the West are generally seen as actions that influence the course of a conflict or harm an adversary without crossing into direct kinetic attacks. For Russia, at the core of the gray zone is the concept of “non-contact war” (&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;bezkontaktnaya voina&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), which is part of a larger doctrinal framework under which gray warfare, also called “new generation warfare” by the Russians, falls. This is not a new concept in Russian military thinking, but it has developed over decades. By examining its evolution over the past thirty years through Russian sources and military thinkers, we can better understand how Moscow uses these concepts today—and how they influence the conflicts we may face now and in the future, enabling the U.S. and our allies to respond more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two main components of Russian gray warfare. Russians rarely use the term hybrid war, which exists in Russian only as a borrowed term from English. The first concept is non-contact warfare—the concept of preparing and softening the battlefield, then minimizing ground engagements for their troops whenever possible. The second concept is Russian intelligence active measures, also known as measures of support. This is also an old idea in Russian intelligence circles, but one that has been expanded and intensified in recent decades, incorporating new elements such as cyber operations and cognitive warfare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will briefly discuss each of these concepts below, along with Russia’s gray-zone developments up to its deployments into Ukraine in 2014. In the second part of this series, we will analyze Russia’s doctrine as it was applied in the years immediately leading up to and through the full-scale invasion of Ukraine, while also considering another key factor for Russia—their ability to evolve and adapt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Contact Warfare: Origins and Russian Military Necessities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-contact warfare developed from what the Russian General Staff and other military thinkers called sixth-generation warfare. The concept grew from the “reconnaissance strike complex” theory and the so-called “revolution in military affairs” at the end of the Cold War. As the Soviet Union disintegrated and the U.S. demonstrated overwhelming air power with NATO and other allies during the Persian Gulf war, former Soviet and Russian generals were not fools. They understood they could not keep pace with the new advancements in air warfare and the technological edge of NATO weapons systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian General Staff thinkers recognized that the Russian Air Force could not match TTPs (techniques, tactics, and procedures), the number of pilot training hours, or the advanced systems that the U.S. and NATO could field, especially given their significantly reduced military budget following the Soviet Union's collapse. This operational shortfall was further emphasized by the targeted bombing campaigns and overwhelming force deployed by U.S./NATO forces in the Balkan campaigns of the mid-1990s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscribe to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, Russian military planners recognized they could not keep pace. NATO airpower and the reach of the alliance into all sorts of regions and conflict zones posed a significant challenge for the Russian military and its intelligence services. One of the lessons they understood was that massed tank formations alone would not win wars in the 21st century. Throughout the 1990s and into the early 2000s, several important writings were produced by prominent Russian general staff figures, such as Generals Slipchenko and Gareev, as well as the future Chief of Staff of the Russian military and currently the commander of the Russian forces in the Ukraine war, Valeriy Gerasimov.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slipchenko is credited in Russia with coining the phrase “sixth generation warfare” more than twenty years ago. According to Slipchenko, this new form of warfare signified a shift from nuclear-based conflict (which he called “fifth generation”) toward information-enabled, precision-strike, so-called non-contact wars (he authored a book with that same title). These wars would be fought at a distance, relying on airpower, command, control, intelligence, surveillance, reconnaissance (C4ISR), and long-range precision strikes, rather than large ground forces. He and Gareev published a book in Russia in 2004 titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Future Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which became influential in many Russian military circles. In this work, Slipchenko and Gareev emphasized the importance of studying non-contact warfare and firmly stated that Russia must adapt to it, or else “Russia would not survive.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During that same period, Russia’s Air Force struggled significantly in the 1990s and 2000s to adopt precision-guided munitions (PGMs). Russia never fully integrated them or appropriately trained them on their use, which was evident in its prolonged conflicts with Chechen separatists. Most ground-attack operations during that period, from the mid to late 1990s, relied on “dumb bombs” and massed artillery on the battlefield. This resulted in the Russian air force’s poor performance in the 2008 Georgian conflict, when an outmanned Georgian military embarrassingly shot down several Russian fighter-bombers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2008, responding to Georgia launching an incursion to retake South Ossetia, Russia responded with overwhelming force, sending an entire army to occupy swaths of Abkhazia, Ossetia, and also northern Georgia from Poti to Gori and the edges of Tbilisi. But while their force ratios led to quick success on the ground, the Russian air force did not perform as well in the air. In addition to air losses to ground-based air defense and friendly fire, Russian precision strikes did not go off as planned. Russia’s performance could be summed up as ineffective from the air. They were not able to project over-the-horizon warfare in the ways that Russian military planners had envisioned for non-contact war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first widespread and successful use of Russian PGMs would come still later, mostly during Russia’s involvement in Syria, where Russian squadrons were rotated for training and gained exposure to actual combat. Before that, many pilots had not experienced any combat outside of Chechnya.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s Air Force underwent a series of reforms due to these failures. It was reorganized and renamed the Russian Aerospace Forces (the VKS) in 2015 as a result of many of these reforms, or what were claimed to be reforms. When the full-scale invasion happened in 2022, Russia’s VKS, like much of its military, was still trying to evolve from its targeted reforms and these earlier developmental challenges. They attempted a limited shock-and-awe offensive but failed miserably in areas such as battle damage assessment and other key aspects of a true air campaign (the second article in this series will touch on these issues in more detail).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, military reforms and adaptations in the Russian Air Force were not meant to stand alone. Russian kinetic actions were intended to be supported by other elements in non-contact warfare, aimed at softening the battlefield and undermining an adversary’s ability to fight. Prominent among these were active measures focused on information operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active Measures, Measures of Support, and Non-state Actors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning to Russian arms doctrine, Slipchenko and other figures on the General Staff argued that, in the post–Cold War world, especially after observing the 1991 Gulf War and the dominance of US airpower, massing military forces was no longer effective. The world saw how Saddam’s large army, with thousands of tanks and armored vehicles, was destroyed from the air. Slipchenko claimed that future wars will focus on disrupting enemy systems, including military, economic, social, and other so-called “information means.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was not a new concept for Russia and its intelligence agencies—the FSB, GRU, and SVR (collectively the Russian intelligence services or RIS). The RIS would play a key role by using a well-known Russian technique—active measures, or as the RIS calls them today, measures of support. These tactics aim to weaken the enemy's ability to fight through malign influence, political interference, and disinformation. The Russians use state agencies and means, like their intelligence services, but also so-called non-state actors, like organized crime, private mercenaries, hacker groups, and many others, to carry out these and other hybrid actions as proxies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doctrinal approach of gray war, or new generation warfare, was gaining attention in Russia just as Putin's reign started. His rule coincided with the growing influence of the RIS within the government. It was natural for the RIS to take on roles the military was not equipped to perform, and Putin was quick to authorize them. One of the first tests for their active measures and gray war was Russia’s brief war with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fpri.org/article/2025/03/russian-influence-operations-in-georgia-a-threat-to-democracy-and-regional-stability/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Georgia&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2008. As noted above, and while their military’s performance was mixed, their intelligence services were very active in the information arena. Russia flooded international media with its version of events. Their still-growing “RTV” news network promoted stories of atrocities they claimed were committed by the Georgian military. Europe and the U.S. were caught off guard and unprepared by the conflict; there was little to no meaningful response to Russia’s military actions, and no high costs or reprisals. It was a lesson Russia would remember.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After Georgia in 2008, while reforms were introduced in the air force in particular, the doctrinal debates continued. Building on Slipchenko’s ideas, writers from the General Staff, such as General Chekinov and General Bogdanov, further developed the doctrine they called “new-generation warfare.” Their work emphasized scripted roles in conflict for the information-psychological struggle, subversion, and cyber operations, while traditional large-scale combat operations became, by comparison, less prominent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the current Russian Chief of Staff,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/02/world/europe/russia-hybrid-war-gerasimov.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Valeriy Gerasimov, gave a speech in which he also advocated for a constant “second front” of information operations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; against Russia’s enemies to weaken their ability to wage war. This speech and a later article became known in some circles in the West as the “Gerasimov doctrine,” although it was never officially called that in Russia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gerasimov’s speech and article focused on shifting Russia's attention to countering the so-called “color revolutions” that occurred in the first decade of this century in Ukraine, Georgia, and Kyrgyzstan. They were, and still are, viewed as a direct threat to Russia’s national security and to Putin’s dictatorship. Russia cannot tolerate functioning democracies and freedom on its borders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By combining Gerasimov’s contributions with those of Slipchenko, Gareev, and others, the Russian military developed a concept of non-contact warfare that planned for long-range strikes executed after weakening the enemy through non-kinetic means. They de-emphasized large ground formations because, according to the theory, they should not be necessary. Russian measures of support are designed to weaken an adversary through disinformation, misinformation, malign influence on politics, and other methods. This would become the battle plan the Russians would attempt to implement in Ukraine in 2014 (and again, with adjustments, in 2022).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As cyber has taken a greater role in society and the mass media, the Russian grey zone approach has also increasingly included RIS cyber operations and online media manipulation to support “reflexive control,” an old Russian intelligence concept from the 1960s. The term reflects the notion of influencing an adversary to act in a desired way without the enemy’s awareness. Gerasimov and the military, along with leaders of the RIS, knew from Russia’s poor performance in Georgia that they were not ready for war with NATO or any strong peer-level adversary. They needed help to weaken any adversary with a capable armed force before actual war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Syria and Ukraine would be the new testing grounds for this concept in practice, with a heavy reliance on the intelligence services to help prepare the battlefield before and through the military’s engagement. Their perceived successes in both theaters would, over time, convince the Russian intelligence services, its military, and most importantly, President Putin that Russia was ready for a much larger task— an attack on and seizure of the entire territory of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Young Africans Are Being Lured Into Russia’s War Machine</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/russia-war-ukraine-african-recruits-tricked-front-lines/</link>
      <description>The Kremlin may be using Africans as suicide bombers in Ukraine, reports suggest.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Minneapolis is at the centre of Donald Trump’s immigration crackdown</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/21/why-minneapolis-is-at-the-centre-of-donald-trumps-immigration-crackdown</link>
      <description>The administration is tormenting, and testing, a unique political culture</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defense Business Brief: Thales’ frigate pivot + 2026 lookahead with Leonardo DRS</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/defense-business-brief-thales-frigate-pivot-2026-lookahead-leonardo-drs/410830/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satellites encased in wood are in the works</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/21/satellites-encased-in-wood-are-in-the-works</link>
      <description>Timber is cheaper and better than alloys, and may be less polluting</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To disperse their spores, truffles rely on animals eating other animals</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/21/to-disperse-their-spores-truffles-rely-on-animals-eating-other-animals</link>
      <description>It is a gruesome business</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where’s all that Golden Dome money going? Lawmakers want to know</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/wheres-all-golden-dome-money-going-lawmakers-want-know/410828/</link>
      <description>Appropriations bill would give Pentagon two months to detail its spending on the sprawling missile-defense program.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new study highlights the brain’s role in immune health</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/21/a-new-study-highlights-the-brains-role-in-immune-health</link>
      <description>It truly is a question of mind over matter</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The remarkable recovery of Narendra Modi</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/21/the-remarkable-recovery-of-narendra-modi</link>
      <description>Despite an electoral reverse in 2024, the prime minister now seems as dominant as ever</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Protect Greenland, Europe Kicks Into High Gear</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/trump-greenland-eu-nato-response-france-germany-denmark/</link>
      <description>The continent is finally showing some strategic resolve. Will it last?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Congress Sidesteps Greenland Debate in Defense Spending Bill</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/congress-greenland-defense-spending-bill-trump-nato-military/</link>
      <description>Lawmakers opted against using the power of the purse to forbid forcible annexation of Greenland.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Davos Speech Heralds a New World Disorder</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/davos-greenland-trump-carney-speeches/</link>
      <description>U.S. president toys with NATO leaders in call for “immediate negotiations to discuss the acquisition of Greenland.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s bond-market tremble reflects a fiscal-monetary clash</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/21/japans-bond-market-tremble-reflects-a-fiscal-monetary-clash</link>
      <description>As investors worry about budgetary laxity, the central bank prepares for more rate hikes</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Election in Sight, Takaichi Promises a New Era of Spending in Japan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/with-election-in-sight-takaichi-promises-a-new-era-of-spending-in-japan/</link>
      <description>Takaichi wants public approval to undertake major policy changes – including ending the era of “excessive fiscal austerity.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Imperialism Without Alibis</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/donald-trump-imperalism-without-alibis-by-ricardo-hausmann-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By asserting control over Venezuela’s primary sources of revenue, US President Donald Trump has replaced the moral rhetoric of his predecessors with a 21st-century version of colonial-era indirect rule. The result is a country that retains the symbols of self-government but functions as an American protectorate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Says He ‘Won’t Use Force’ to Acquire Greenland</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/trump-davos-speech-transcript-greenland-nato-denmark-use-force/</link>
      <description>In his speech in Davos, Trump asked for the territory and said only the United States could defend it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Trump’s Greenland fixation undermines alliance; Cui bono?; Lawmakers set flat defense budget; How AI went DOD; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-21-2026/410821/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vice Presidents Usually Disappoint After Calamity Strikes</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/venezuela-vice-presidents-rodriguez/</link>
      <description>Delcy Rodríguez is the latest spare politician to be thrust into a top job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropy Must Dive Deeper to Save the Ocean</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/philanthropy-can-help-unlock-financing-necessary-to-protect-ocean-health-by-shaun-seow-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite growing pressure on marine ecosystems, ocean-health projects often remain underdeveloped because funding, policy, and implementation fail to move in sync. Philanthropy can help change that by aligning priorities, absorbing early risks, and providing the coordinating capacity that enables promising ideas to scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How North Korea Uses an 80-Year-Old Youth Group to Control Society</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-north-korea-uses-an-80-year-old-youth-group-to-control-society/</link>
      <description>The Socialist Patriotic Youth League offers a window into how the North Korean authorities uses state-run organizations to govern.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Does Trump’s Greenland Grab Mean for Taiwan?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/what-does-trumps-greenland-grab-mean-for-taiwan/</link>
      <description>Questions are being raise worldwide, including in Taiwan, about the credibility of U.S. economic, security, and other commitments under a more openly transactional “Donroe Doctrine.”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Supreme Leader Is Trapped</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/khamenei-iranian-regime-trapped-between-internal-revolt-and-external-war-by-pegah-banihashemi-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has built a system that survives only through repression. Yet now, a man who has never been willing to retreat confronts a dilemma from which there is no clean exit: continued internal war against his own people, or an external war that exposes his regime's fragility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Pax Silica to Hypergravity: Central Asia’s Place in the New Technological Era</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/from-pax-silica-to-hypergravity-central-asias-place-in-the-new-technological-era/</link>
      <description>Geographically and politically, the region – and Kazakhstan in particular – is positioned as a natural bridge between emerging technological blocs.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Isn’t Worried About New US Sanctions on Iran</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-china-isnt-worried-about-new-us-sanctions-on-iran/</link>
      <description>China is the largest importer of Iranian oil, and it always has a tried-and-tested toolkit for evading sanctions enforcement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singapore vs. Switzerland for Asia’s Wealthy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/singapore-vs-switzerland-for-asias-wealthy/</link>
      <description>Insights from Marcin Dadura.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World India Must Budget For</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-world-india-must-budget-for/</link>
      <description>America’s AI-fueled boom and China’s export-led model are showing signs of strain. For India, the implications are weaker global demand, tougher trade conditions, and limited room for easy external growth in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A Rupture in the World Order’</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/mark-carney-speech-davos-trump-canada-full-text-transcript-read/</link>
      <description>Read Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney’s forceful speech at Davos rebuking Trump’s world order.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICFAI Group: Shaping India’s Future Through Quality Education</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/icfai-group-shaping-indias-future-through-quality-education/</link>
      <description>The institution's commitment to accessibility, innovation and industry collaboration is transforming leadership in India's higher education landscape.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Military Can’t Fix Iran’s Opposition</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/the-u-s-military-cant-fix-irans-opposition/</link>
      <description>Washington can intervene militarily, but any regime change strategy needs to start in Iran itself.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Billionaire Raj in India, Consolidated Elite in Pakistan Rule the Roost</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/billionaire-raj-in-india-consolidated-elite-in-pakistan-rule-the-roost/</link>
      <description>What is missing in both countries is the organized capacity of the majority to force redistribution onto the political agenda.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Authoritarian Illusion</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democracy-is-still-useful-because-lack-of-accountability-blinds-authoritarians-by-jacques-attali-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The debate and uncertainty that are intrinsic to democracies have started to look like weaknesses alongside the order and continuity promised by authoritarian regimes. But democracy is resilient and keeps returning in different forms, simultaneously obsolete and ahead of its time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Far Do China’s Ambitions Reach?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/china-united-states-trump-foreign-policy-competition/</link>
      <description>The answer is global—and has big implications for U.S. policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Needs a New Security Framework</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-nato-cannot-guarantee-security-return-to-old-western-eu-necessary-by-carl-bildt-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent developments have made clear that neither NATO nor the European Union is fully suited to meet the mounting challenges that Europe faces. They have also strengthened the case for reviving the old Western European Union, by institutionalizing the “coalition of the willing” that France, Germany, and the UK have already forged.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan Weighs Trump’s ‘Board of Peace’ Invitation Amid International Caution</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/pakistan-weighs-trumps-board-of-peace-invitation-amid-international-caution/</link>
      <description>Islamabad wouldn't want to back a setup that undermines the U.N. or pokes at Beijing's diplomatic, economic, or security interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Japan and the Philippines Are Hedging Against China Together</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/21/japan-philippines-defense-pact-china-south-sea/</link>
      <description>Beijing’s response to the latest agreement was predictably spiky.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea Can Stand Up to China</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/south-korea-can-stand-china</link>
      <description>With its allies, Seoul has enough leverage to push back.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Grievance</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/power-grievance</link>
      <description>What history reveals about authoritarianism’s animating force.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Interim Governments Use the Law to Silence the Press</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/when-interim-governments-use-the-law-to-silence-the-press/</link>
      <description>640 journalists were targeted by Bangladesh’s interim government last year, a think tank report said. Do transitional democracies do more harm than good?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 115: Can the Transatlantic Alliance Survive the Trump Presidency?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/global-security-briefing/episode-115-can-transatlantic-alliance-survive-trump-presidency</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As US–European relations face renewed strain under President Trump, this episode explores what the crisis means for NATO, European security and the UK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Reform to Results: Incentives, Culture and the UK’s Military Intelligence Services</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/reform-results-incentives-culture-and-uks-military-intelligence-services</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The UK is consolidating dispersed intelligence services under a new defence-led Military Intelligence Services construct to optimise performance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western leaders navigate a lonely world</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/20/western-leaders-navigate-a-lonely-world</link>
      <description>China cannot and will not save mid-size American allies from Donald Trump</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canadian soldiers are subject to Donald Trump’s orders</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/20/canadian-soldiers-are-subject-to-donald-trumps-orders</link>
      <description>As the American president becomes more aggressive, this is becoming a problem</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan’s Anti-corruption Emergency: What Comes After a Decade of Reform?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/uzbekistans-anti-corruption-emergency-what-comes-after-a-decade-of-reform/</link>
      <description>Uzbekistan’s declaration of an anti-corruption “state of emergency” signals a turning point in its decade-long reform efforts toward a system-based model of control and prevention.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shutdown odds plummet after House and Senate strike bipartisan deal on 2026 funding bills</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/shutdown-odds-plummet-after-house-and-senate-strike-bipartisan-deal-remaining-funding-bills/410820/</link>
      <description>If the full Congress approves, the Defense Department would get $838.7 billion, a sub-1% increase.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
