<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Boeing takes $565m hit on KC-46 tanker</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/boeing-takes-565m-hit-kc-46-tanker/411004/</link>
      <description>Despite the “bad contract,” the company remains optimistic about negotiating future deals.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonus Episode: Greenland: A Flashpoint in Transatlantic Relations</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/global-security-briefing/bonus-episode-greenland-flashpoint-transatlantic-relations</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greenland crisis has damaged goodwill and trust between the US and Europe and has undermined perceptions of US reliability and trustworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Military Purge Rocks the CCP</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/china-military-purge-generals-pla-xi-jinping-zhang-youxia-liu-zhenli/</link>
      <description>The targeting of two top generals bodes poorly for China’s military readiness.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lots of world leaders are attacking Europe. Why?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/27/lots-of-world-leaders-are-attacking-europe-why</link>
      <description>Often, Europe-bashing is best explained by domestic politics in America, China and beyond</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India, EU Clinch Long-Delayed Trade Deal Amid Trump’s Tariff War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/india-european-union-eu-free-trade-deal-trump-tariffs/</link>
      <description>The agreement highlights a wider global trend to diversify markets away from the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s national defense strategy is unlike anything that’s come before it</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/trumps-national-defense-strategy-unlike-anything-s-come-it/410999/</link>
      <description>It touts an end to interventionism and regime change, despite adventurism in Venezuela and Greenland.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Congress can rein in ICE—and start to redeem itself</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/27/how-congress-can-rein-in-ice-and-start-to-redeem-itself</link>
      <description>Senator Susan Collins of Maine has a historic chance to lead</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The West and Ukraine are capsizing Russia’s shadow fleet</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/27/the-west-and-ukraine-are-capsizing-russias-shadow-fleet</link>
      <description>And sinking its oil revenues in the process</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republicans are waking up to the awful optics in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/27/republicans-are-waking-up-to-the-awful-optics-in-minneapolis</link>
      <description>A partial government shutdown over the president’s immigration campaign looks likely</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Pressure Needed to Secure Congo’s Peace</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/congo-rwanda-peace-critical-minerals-trump/</link>
      <description>Despite White House-brokered accords, the war in eastern Congo is getting worse</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Force mum on details of Mideast exercise amid military buildup</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/air-force-mum-details-mideast-exercise-amid-military-buildup/410990/</link>
      <description>Similarly, details of a NORAD exercise in Greenland this month were not disclosed.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How porn stars can survive in the age of AI</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/27/how-porn-stars-can-survive-in-the-age-of-ai</link>
      <description>A dispatch from the world’s premier porn conference</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Board of Peace Will Help Strong Countries Dominate Weak Ones</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/trump-board-peace-strong-countries-dominate-weak-israel-gaza/</link>
      <description>In Gaza, it will legitimize Israeli land grabs and ethnic cleansing.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Uzbekneftegaz Chairman Reportedly Detained</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/former-uzbekneftegaz-chairman-reportedly-detained/</link>
      <description>Uzbek media reports that Bakhodir Siddikov, until mid-December head of Uzbekistan’s state oil and gas company, has been taken into custody amid a corruption investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind China’s race to build aircraft-carriers</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/27/behind-chinas-race-to-build-aircraft-carriers</link>
      <description>It will soon have more carriers in the Pacific than America</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Developing Countries Can Make the Most of AI</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-developing-countries-can-make-the-most-of-ai-by-shamika-sirimanne-and-taffere-tesfachew-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since deploying AI for specific purposes costs a fraction of what it takes to build a new model from scratch, the technology offers developing countries a new opportunity to &quot;leapfrog&quot; to the next stage of industrialization. But success will depend on overcoming three major constraints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to tell if Venezuela is heading for democracy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/27/how-to-tell-if-venezuela-is-heading-for-democracy</link>
      <description>The regime is opening up the economy, but its political moves lack credibility</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Border Patrol boss out of MN; Misinformation pushback; Carrier reaches CENTCOM; Tariffs pledged on US shipbuilding partner; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-27-2026/410977/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Give Democracy a Chance in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/venezuela-democratic-prospects-unlike-afghanistan-and-iraq-by-andres-velasco-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to restore democracy to Venezuela, US President Donald Trump has teamed up with, in his own words, a &quot;corrupt, criminal, illegitimate regime.&quot; But achieving stability and recovering Venezuela's lost prosperity is incompatible with maintaining a dictatorship that destroyed both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Trump Should Think About the Arctic</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/conley-trump-arctic-greenland-nato/</link>
      <description>Acquiring Greenland has been a costly distraction from longer-term challenges posed by Russia and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Biggest Energy Bet Isn’t in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-pax-silica-initiative-consequential-shift-in-us-foreign-policy-by-sarah-ladislaw-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US intervention in Venezuela and seizure of its oil may dominate headlines, but a more consequential shift in US energy policy is unfolding off-camera. Unlike the “Donroe Doctrine,” the emerging Pax Silica alliance reflects an understanding that competing with state-led economies requires international cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The case for optimism in South Africa</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/27/the-case-for-optimism-in-south-africa</link>
      <description>After a lost decade, economic prospects may be brightening</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying ‘Less-Lethal’ Weapons Used By DHS Agents in US Immigration Raids and Protests</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/resources/2026/01/27/less-lethal-weapons-guide/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date on our latest investigations, join Bellingcat’s WhatsApp channel here. Federal agents have frequently used so-called “less-lethal” weapons against protesters, including impact projectiles, tear gas and pepper spray, since the Trump administration’s nationwide immigration raids began last year.  The use of less-lethal weapons (LLWs) has been controversial. While designed to incapacitate or [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/resources/2026/01/27/less-lethal-weapons-guide/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Identifying ‘Less-Lethal’ Weapons Used By DHS Agents in US Immigration Raids and Protests&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong Must Not Be Forgotten in China-UK Talks</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/hong-kong-must-not-be-forgotten-in-china-uk-talks/</link>
      <description>While in China this week, Starmer must directly challenge Beijing on its treatment of Hong Kong and of Hong Kongers living abroad, particularly those who now live in Britain.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RCEP Was a Major Breakthrough, But It Still Needs Work</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/rcep-was-a-major-breakthrough-but-it-still-needs-work/</link>
      <description>With RCEP’s first general review scheduled for 2026, this is a timely opportunity to assess its relevance and potential amid profound global uncertainty today.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laying Anchor Into Chinese Overseas Ports</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/laying-anchor-into-chinese-overseas-ports/</link>
      <description>Given the stakes, it is critical to chart a better course through China’s overseas ports presence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BRICS Holds a Maritime Exercise at the Indo-Atlantic Crossroads – Without India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/brics-holds-a-maritime-exercise-at-the-indo-atlantic-crossroads-without-india/</link>
      <description>China led the exercise, South Africa hosted it, and India sat it out.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Trump’s 2026 National Defense Strategy Approaches Taiwan and China</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-trumps-2026-national-defense-strategy-approaches-taiwan-and-china/</link>
      <description>The new strategy pairs &quot;denial defense&quot; with a strategic silence on Taiwan to maximize executive leverage. Yet this design rests on a dangerous gamble.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Sea Rivalries Risk Unraveling the Horn of Africa</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/sudan-united-arab-emirates-saudi-arabia-ethiopia-trump-red-sea/</link>
      <description>If Sudan’s civil war spreads to Ethiopia, it will be a humanitarian and strategic disaster.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s  Best Tools for Countering Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-europe-should-respond-to-trump-tariff-threats-by-daniel-gros-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;European exporters depend more on the US market than American exporters do on Europe, which means the EU is poorly positioned for a tit-for-tat tariff war with the US. But with targeted export tariffs, taxes on royalties, and the elimination of US Treasuries' risk-free status, the EU could hit the US where it hurts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taliban Introduce New Criminal Code in Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/taliban-introduce-new-criminal-code-in-afghanistan/</link>
      <description>At first glance, the criminal code appears to be a typical legal framework. But the state’s goal is not to protect citizens, but to control them.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International Pressure Forced China to Shift on Uyghur Camps</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/international-pressure-forced-china-to-shift-on-uyghur-camps/</link>
      <description>From initial denials, through later partial acknowledgment and “legalization,” to rapid downsizing and eventual formal closure, the Chinese government’s handling of the re-education camps in Xinjiang suggests a series of unintended shifts.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea Fires Multiple Ballistic Missiles</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/north-korea-fires-multiple-ballistic-missiles/</link>
      <description>The January 27 missile launch marks the North’s second missile test this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Board of Peace Cracks the BRICS Wall</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/trump-board-of-peace-brics-united-nations-china-russia-global-south/</link>
      <description>The myth of a global south resisting U.S. hegemony melted away in Davos.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Update on Venezuela, Post Maduro Apprehension</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/an-update-on-venezuela-post-maduro-apprehension</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Turmoil in Minneapolis and the unprecedented friction within NATO over President Trump’s effort to secure control over Greenland have, predictably, displaced headlines about Venezuela in much of the daily press. But there have been at least a number of important statements from the U.S. and one disturbing statement, reportedly, by Venezuela’s interim president since the U.S. apprehended Maduro and his wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;”Now, this is not the end. This is not even the beginning of the end”&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Winston Churchill, 1942&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On January 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, in a press conference, President Trump said he was considering a role for Venezuela’s democratic opposition leader, Nobel laureate Maria Corina Machado. This was a very encouraging statement. The opposition has the support of the vast majority of Venezuelans. As has been widely reported and well documented, they won the July 24 national election by an enormous margin despite regime efforts to undermine their campaign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maria Corina Machado is the leader of the opposition and a national hero. She is committed to rebuilding her country’s democracy and to reconstructing Venezuela’s dysfunctional and corruption-ridden economy. She is pro-American, pro-private sector and open to foreign direct investment.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regime, now being led on an interim basis by Delcy Rodriquez, held on to power after the July 2024 vote through intimidation. The Venezuelan public knows this. And, despite assurances of cooperation to President Trump, there are already signs that the character of this authoritarian regime’s approach to governance has not changed. The regime moved quickly after the U.S. removed Maduro to squelch public expressions of relief that Maduro had been taken into U.S. custody. Left to their own devices, Delcy Rodriquez and company will do everything in their power to consolidate their hold on power. Indeed, this is clear from Rodriguez’s recent public statement that she has had “enough already of Washington’s orders over Venezuelan politicians.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Integrating Maria Corina Machado into the transition process would reassure her supporters and help to counter the impression that the U.S. is indifferent to the plight of the Venezuelan democratic opposition. It would also contribute to the establishment of the kind of security on the ground that the American oil majors have said must be achieved before they commit to the immense investments necessary to resurrect the country much diminished and dilapidated oil sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Trump says the U.S. will manage the receipts for Venezuelan oil sales and direct some of that money back into Venezuela. Good but these funds should be channeled mostly into the hands of the opposition rather than the regime. Indeed, the last thing that should be done with the oil receipts is giving them to the regime. The regime’s managerial incompetence and corrupt practices are precisely what caused the effective collapse of the economy! As I and others have noted in the past, oil production in Venezuela has shrunk by two thirds since Hugo Chavez was elected. Things got even worse under Nicolas Maduro. The Venezuelan economy contracted by around 70 percent between 2013, when Maduro assumed the presidency, and 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration’s decision to work with remaining elements of the Maduro regime’s leadership cadre was and remains understandable. The U.S. wants to avoid the mistakes we made after the fall of Saddam Hussein in Iraq. The regime’s remaining leaders, however, are never going to be willing partners in the reconstruction of, Venezuela if that means empowering their adversaries – as Delcy Rodriguez’s recent comment makes clear. They are counting on the U.S. losing interest or being distracted by other crises. The United States needs to be prepared to counter this heretofore unstated impression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. considered this a criminal regime before Maduro was apprehended. Rodriquez and the ministers of Defense and Interior were all a part of Maduro’s inner circle. They are miscreants who will revert to their previous patterns of repression and malfeasance absent close vigilance by the U.S. and the democratic opposition. This is why President Trump’s decision to get American diplomats back into the country and name a tough, experienced ambassador to lead the Venezuelan interest section presently located in Bogota was so important. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. has a long list of issues to work through with the Rodriquez team. Following Maduro’s capture, Rodriguez, on behalf of the regime, agreed to work with the U.S. to avoid further U.S. military action. We will need to watch carefully to be assured that commitments are met. We should also communicate persuasively that the U.S. is willing to act forcefully again if the circumstances warrant it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Editor@thecipherbrief.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/a&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is driving gold’s relentless rally?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/27/what-is-driving-golds-relentless-rally</link>
      <description>The ancient asset is attracting new investors</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Trump’s New ‘Board of Peace’</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/inside-trumps-new-board-of-peace</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION &lt;/strong&gt;— “Donald J. Trump shall serve as inaugural Chairman of the Board of Peace, and he shall separately serve as inaugural representative of the United States of America…The Chairman [Trump] shall have exclusive authority to create, modify, or dissolve subsidiary entities as necessary or appropriate to fulfill the Board of Peace’s mission…The Chairman [Trump] shall at all times designate a successor for the role of Chairman. Replacement of the Chairman [Trump] may occur only following voluntary resignation or as a result of incapacity, as determined by a unanimous vote of the Executive Board, at which time the Chairman’s [Trump’s] designated successor shall immediately assume the position of the Chairman and all associated duties and authorities of the Chairman.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those are quotes from the charter of the new, so-called Bureau of Peace (BOP) established by President Trump and signed January 22, at Davos, Switzerland by Trump for the United States and the leaders or representatives of 19 other countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On January 16, White House announcement of BOP said the organization would provide “strategic oversight, mobilizing international resources, and ensuring accountability as Gaza transitions from conflict to peace and development.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, six days later the BOP charter that President Trump released at Davos described its purpose in Chapter I this way: “The Board of Peace is an international organization that seeks to promote stability, restore dependable and lawful governance, and secure enduring peace in areas affected or threatened by conflict.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No mention of Gaza, as BOP’s sole focus, but rather the far broader “areas affected or threatened by conflict.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;BOP’s expansion to a worldwide peacekeeping role provides President Trump with a new way to involve himself in international affairs, not just while he is U.S. President, but even after he leaves the White House.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will discuss below how President Trump sees all this happening and what it may mean. First, however, it’s worth seeing how BOP’s charter, gives its Chairman, Trump, total power over the organization even beyond what’s mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example,, the charter says. “Membership in the Board of Peace is limited to States invited to participate by the Chairman…Each Member State shall serve a term of no more than three years from this Charter’s entry into force, subject to renewal by the Chairman…The Executive Board shall be selected by the Chairman…shall serve two-year terms, subject to removal by the Chairman and renewable at his discretion…[and] shall be led by a Chief Executive nominated by the Chairman and confirmed by a majority vote of the Executive Board…Decisions of the Executive Board shall be made by a majority of its members present and voting, including the&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chief Executive. Such decisions shall go into effect immediately, subject to veto by the Chairman at any time thereafter.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, Chairman Trump, under the charter, shall convene BOP meetings, establish their locations, must approve the agendas and the persons from all states attending those meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individually, the charter says Chairman Trump, “acting on behalf of the Board of Peace, is authorized to adopt resolutions or other directives, consistent with this Charter, to implement the Board of Peace’s mission.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Chairman, Trump can also “dissolve [BOP] at such time as the Chairman considers necessary or appropriate, or at the end of every odd-numbered calendar year&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;unless renewed by the Chairman&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;no later than November 21 of such odd-numbered calendar year.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The charter says, “The Executive Board shall provide for the rules and procedures with respect to the settling of all assets, liabilities, and obligations upon [BOP’s] dissolution,” but remember, decisions of the Executive Board are “subject to veto by the Chairman at any time.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, the BOP charter gives Trump total control over the organization and all its activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At last Thursday’s press conference introducing BOP, Trump said, “This Board [BOP] has the chance to be one of the most consequential bodies ever created and it's my enormous honor to serve as its chairman. I was very honored when they asked me to do it. We had an idea to do it, and then they came. They said, &quot;You be the chairman.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump never explained who “they” were.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although 50 nations had been invited to join BOP, only 19 showed up to attend last Thursday’s announcement. Major Western allies, such as Canada, France and Germany have balked and voiced concerns that the body is designed to replace the United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump, who just recently had the U.S. withdraw from many U.N. organizations, said at last Thursday BOP press conference, “I've always said the United Nations has got tremendous potential, has not used it, but there's tremendous potential in the United Nations and you have some great people at the United Nations, but so far it hasn't.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He repeated, “There's tremendous potential with the United Nations and I think the combination of the Board of Peace with the kind of people we have here coupled with the United Nations can be something very, very unique for the world, for the world.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that the Trump approved as the BOP seal something in gold that’s very similar to that of the U.N. seal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump’s son-in-law Jared Kushner, who helped put together BOP and is a founding member of its Executive Board, said at last Thursday’s event, he had put together a plan for rebuilding Gaza with the help of the U.N. as the Security Council had originally voted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then Kushner added, “We've worked very, very well with them, this is why you need a new organization like the Board of Peace to work with the U.N.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kushner specifically thanked U.N.’s Under-Secretary-General for Humanitarian Affairs and Emergency Relief Coordinator, Tom Fletcher, who it turns out gave an interview to &lt;em&gt;Sky News&lt;/em&gt; at the time of the BOP announcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fletcher insisted, “The U.N. is not going anywhere…We’ve got to get out there, end wars, save lives, and we’re doing that.” Asked if Trump’s organization would replace the U.N., Fletcher responded, “Now I think we’re seeing America wanting to play a part in ending some of these conflicts and they want us [the U.N.] to be as effective as we can be.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fletcher then gave a description of what I judge he sees as Trump’s different way of looking at how he, Trump, works with world leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Fletcher said. “There’s a difference between the old school statecraft that’s familiar to many people here at Davos and a sort of real estate craft, which is coming into this conversation now, which is more transactional. It’s very focused on results, not process. It’s focused on personal relationships and not always institutions. Yes, there’s an aspect of cliff-hanger and jeopardy to it. We never quite know what’s coming next, but it is part of the conversation. And if it can save lives and it ends wars then that is fine.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me that is roll-the-dice diplomacy – in effect gambling on national security and foreign policy outcomes. Remember, Trump’s Atlantic City ventures that started in the 1980s. By 2004, all three Trump casinos and Trump Hotels &amp; Casino Resorts Inc. were bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump, has rolled the dice on Venezuela, let’s see how that turns out. And hopefully, BOP won’t be like Trump’s casinos, although right now it does not look to me like a good gamble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Editor@thecipherbrief.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/a&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Middle East Has Two New Rival Teams</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/saudi-uae-middle-east-coalitions-teams/</link>
      <description>The competition between Abrahamic and Islamic coalitions is reshaping the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fascism by the Book</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fascism-by-the-book-by-yanis-varoufakis-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who thinks that fascism had been vanquished for good in the mid-20th century should look to Minnesota and other American cities. In Donald Trump's America, and perhaps coming to other countries soon, the panoply of fascism's strategies requires remarkably little updating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s War Economy Lifeline: Inside the Sanctions Evasion Network</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russias-war-economy-lifeline-inside-the-sanctions-evasion-network</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/18-january-2026-russia-moscow-the-kremlin-and-the-skyscraper-district-of-the-city-glow-in-the-afternoon-sun.jpg?id=63292808&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C53%2C0%2C54&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Nearly three years into the most comprehensive sanctions regime ever imposed on a significant economy, Russia’s defense industrial base has not just survived — it has expanded at a rate that has stunned Western officials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In spite of Western import controls, Moscow maintains wartime levels of military production by using shell companies, third-country middlemen, and financial workarounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In early 2026, the war will enter its fourth year, and Russia will still have access to&lt;a href=&quot;https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/00594bef40bc4148b16dc7267172d033&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;critical&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;battlefield technology that was banned by Western authorities. These components power the Lancet loitering munitions hitting Ukrainian positions, Kalibr cruise missiles striking infrastructure, and electronic warfare systems jamming NATO communications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout 2025, Russia&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-nato-weapons-production-us-germany/33482927.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;produced&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; an estimated 250,000 artillery shells monthly — 3 million annually — according to NATO intelligence, while manufacturing over 1.5 million drones and more than 2,400 cruise and ballistic missiles per year. President Vladimir Putin&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-boosted-weapon-production-22-times-since-start-of-ukraine-war-putin-9998154&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;claimed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in April that Russia’s defense industry more than doubled production of weapons, communications, reconnaissance, and electronic warfare systems over the previous year, with ammunition production increasing more than 22-fold since 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte also assessed in January 2025 that Russia has fully switched to a “war economy” and produces, in three months, the weapons and&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nato.int/en/news-and-events/events/transcripts/2025/05/21/joint-press-conference-1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;ammunition&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that the European Union makes in a year; a production advantage enabled by sanctions-evasion networks spanning three continents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Evasion of Western restrictions has helped Russia ramp up production of certain military equipment and munitions, such as cruise and ballistic missiles, to a greater degree than Western governments initially expected,” John Hardie, Deputy Director of the Russia Program at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Turkey-UAE-China Triangle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three countries have emerged as critical nodes in Russia’s procurement network. Over the past year, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, and China continued to dominate Russia’s sanctions evasion infrastructure, collectively&lt;a href=&quot;https://hir.harvard.edu/fortune-hunting-russia-and-sanctions-evasion/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;accounting for&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 86.2 percent of total battlefield goods shipments and 78.6 percent of critical components shipments to Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trade patterns reveal how entrenched these channels have become, and how enforcement efforts under the Trump administration have&lt;a href=&quot;https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/cbp-10342/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;largely stalled&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In the first nine months of his administration, President Trump imposed no new sanctions on Russia and declined to join the UK, EU, and other allies in targeting Russian evasion networks. Only in October 2025, after canceling peace talks with Putin, did the Trump team&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cov.com/en/news-and-insights/insights/2025/08/trump-administration-imposes-secondary-tariffs-on-india&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;impose&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; its first direct sanctions on Russia, targeting oil giants Rosneft and Lukoil while threatening secondary sanctions primarily against India, despite China being the largest importer of Russian oil globally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“China is by far the most important enabler of that evasion,” Hardie explained. “China serves as both a direct supplier of critical inputs — such as CNC machines, microelectronics, and nitrocellulose — as well as a jurisdiction for Russian illicit procurement of Western products.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;China remains the dominant supplier, accounting for&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uscc.gov/research/chinas-facilitation-sanctions-and-export-control-evasion&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;up to 90 percent&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of Russia’s microelectronics imports. By August last year, Beijing exported a record 328,000 miles of fiber-optic cable and nearly $50 million worth of lithium-ion batteries to Moscow in a single month. According to Germany’s Foreign Ministry, up to&lt;a href=&quot;https://carnegieendowment.org/europe/strategic-europe/2025/11/china-is-the-weak-link-in-europes-ukraine-strategy?lang=en&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;80 percent&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of Russia’s sanctions circumvention now involves Chinese entities. Russia is paying the price for this dependence: Chinese suppliers&lt;a href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2025/11/29/russia-economy-china-trade-markup-sanctioned-goods-ukraine-putin/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;charged Russia&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; an 87 percent markup on sanctioned goods between 2021 and 2024, compared to just 9 percent from other suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the UAE has become the primary transshipment hub, with electronic component exports to Russia growing more than fifteenfold since the invasion. Dubai-based companies supply everything from aviation parts to Starlink terminals, which Russian forces&lt;a href=&quot;https://carnegieendowment.org/2024/03/11/why-russia-has-been-so-resilient-to-western-export-controls-pub-91894&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;buy for around $2,200&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; each. By mid-2024, UAE imports of EU airplane parts hit 23.6 million euros — a&lt;a href=&quot;https://carnegieendowment.org/russia-eurasia/politika/2024/09/russia-eu-sanctions-trade?lang=en&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;fifteenfold jump&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — while Turkey’s climbed by a third to 12.7 million euros, even as Russia’s direct purchases fell to zero.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Asia’s Shell Company Explosion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Central Asian states have become essential transit corridors, with Kazakhstan and Kyrgyzstan serving as primary hubs. Throughout 2025, these channels have&lt;a href=&quot;https://lansinginstitute.org/2025/12/01/kazakhstans-expanding-role-in-russias-sanctions-evasion-architecture/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;grown more sophisticated&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; rather than diminished. From 2021 to 2022, Kyrgyzstan’s exports to Russia exploded by 250 percent, with machinery exports to Russia&lt;a href=&quot;https://thediplomat.com/2025/06/china-kyrgyzstan-and-the-quiet-construction-of-a-sanctions-resistant-trade-corridor/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;spiking&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by 41,000 percent — a figure that “cannot be attributed to market demand” but represents “economic statecraft hidden in plain sight,” according to analysis published in June 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian buyers keep setting up shell companies in Kazakhstan to purchase electronics and drones from Europe, China, and the United States, then ship them home to Russia’s defense industry. Throughout 2025, Kazakhstan&lt;a href=&quot;https://lansinginstitute.org/2025/12/01/kazakhstans-expanding-role-in-russias-sanctions-evasion-architecture/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;became&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; one of Moscow’s primary backdoors for sanctioned goods. Moreover, Russian marketplace OZON has invested significantly in logistics infrastructure across Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, and Armenia to consolidate parallel-import cargo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversions are obvious. Landlocked Kyrgyzstan&lt;a href=&quot;https://carnegieendowment.org/russia-eurasia/politika/2024/09/russia-eu-sanctions-trade?lang=en&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;continues&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; importing EU maritime navigation equipment with no plausible domestic use — equipment destined for Russian naval systems. Over the course of last year, Western authorities intensified enforcement. In June, the UK&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.business-humanrights.org/en/latest-news/uk-warns-businesses-in-georgia-armenia-kazakhstan-uzbekistan-kyrgyzstan-aiding-russia-evade-sanctions-will-be-sanctioned-themselves/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;warned&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; businesses in five countries that those aiding sanctions evasion would face sanctions themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In October, the EU’s 19th sanctions package&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.matheson.com/insights/the-european-unions-19th-sanctions-package-against-russia-key-takeaways/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;targeted&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; eight financial institutions in Tajikistan, Kyrgyzstan, the UAE, and Hong Kong for facilitating circumvention, while four banks in Belarus and Kazakhstan were designated for using Russian payment infrastructures. In January 2025, the UK published enhanced&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lexology.com/library/detail.aspx?g=d6303d4b-469e-4c5b-9c53-3566391ff873&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;guidance&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; identifying 15 high-risk countries, including Armenia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, China, the UAE, and Turkey, for which exporters must conduct enhanced due diligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When asked how difficult it is to distinguish legitimate trade from sanctions evasion in Central Asia, Ambassador Daniel Fried, a forty-year career diplomat and Distinguished Fellow at the Atlantic Council, acknowledged the complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Such action is labor-intensive but worth the effort,” he tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “We should go after the most impactful technologies and targets.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Yuan Lifeline: Russia’s Financial Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Chinese yuan props up Moscow’s parallel financial system. As of November 2025, 99.1 percent of Russia-China trade settles in rubles and yuan — up from less than 2 percent before the invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When&lt;a href=&quot;https://politicstoday.org/russia-and-china-settle-99-of-trade-in-national-currencies/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;major&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Chinese banks like Ping An and Bank of Ningbo stopped accepting Russian payments in mid-2024, smaller regional banks stepped in to fill the gap. These “burner banks” can shut down and reopen under new names if sanctioned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The workaround was part of a broader effort to rewire Russia’s financial system away from the West.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The share of Western currencies in Russian trade&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intereconomics.eu/contents/year/2025/number/2/article/china-russia-cooperation-economic-linkages-and-sanctions-evasion.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;decreased&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from 87 percent to 18 percent between January 2022 and December 2024. Yuan and ruble filled the gap, eliminating Western oversight from the financial system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Energy exports remain the bedrock. Beijing became the anchor buyer for Moscow’s hydrocarbons, with crude oil shipments exceeding&lt;a href=&quot;https://merics.org/en/china-russia-dashboard-facts-and-figures-special-relationship&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;108 million tonnes&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2024 — a 30 percent increase since 2022. The Power of Siberia pipeline is reaching full capacity of 38 billion cubic meters annually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China-Russia bilateral trade&lt;a href=&quot;https://merics.org/en/china-russia-dashboard-facts-and-figures-special-relationship&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;hit&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; $245 billion in 2024, more than double 2020 levels, with 99.1 percent now&lt;a href=&quot;https://politicstoday.org/russia-and-china-settle-99-of-trade-in-national-currencies/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;settled&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in yuan and rubles as of late 2024, creating a sanctions-resistant corridor completely insulated from dollar oversight. Though trade dipped slightly in early 2025 — Russian officials projected&lt;a href=&quot;https://russiaspivottoasia.com/russia-china-2025-bilateral-trade-to-exceed-us220-billion/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;around&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; $220 billion for the year due to market adjustments — the financial architecture remains entrenched, with the yuan accounting for&lt;a href=&quot;https://cepa.org/comprehensive-reports/going-steady-china-and-russias-economic-ties-are-deeper-than-washington-thinks/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;99.8 percent&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of Moscow Exchange foreign currency trading after summer 2024 U.S. sanctions targeted the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Enforcement Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are structural limitations to Western enforcement. The EU&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epc.eu/publication/sanctions-at-a-crossroads-developing-eu-leadership-amid-an-uncertain-transatlantic-alliance/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;lacks&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the capacity to check each and every export to a third country. Washington’s secondary sanctions strategy aims to catch violators, but effectiveness is uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fried suggested targeted measures to disrupt these supply chains. Western enforcement faces structural limitations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Targeted sanctions and penalties from the Commerce Department,” he noted. “These are labor-intensive and only partially successful at best, but partial success can have an impact.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The January 2025 sanctions&lt;a href=&quot;https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy2761&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;package&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; targeted nearly 400 entities across more than 20 jurisdictions. Throughout 2024,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnas.org/publications/reports/sanctions-by-the-numbers-2024-year-in-review&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;70 percent&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of U.S. designations were Russia-related, with almost 33 percent targeting entities outside Russia — China accounting for 36 percent of third-country designations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is not to say Western sanctions and export controls are useless,” Hardie underscored. “They do make life harder and more expensive for the Russian defense industry. And they have a greater effect on products with obvious military uses, e.g., radiation-hardened “hips for satellites. Sanctions also hamper Russian defense exports, which are an important source of revenue for the Russian defense industry.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese compliance is particularly complex. Beijing publicly respects Western sanctions yet operates on a principle of “everything not banned is allowed.” Smaller Chinese companies and regional banks keep supplying Russia while staying just within the letter of Chinese law. Beijing tolerates the arrangement as long as it doesn’t constitute a technical violation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardie noted that enforcement strategies must be sustained to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Aggressive, consistent sanctions enforcement — i.e., designating third-country companies and banks supporting the Russian defense industry — is important and should be coupled with diplomatic pressure on foreign governments to crack down on sanctions busting,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, political will appears inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Whereas the Biden Treasury Department routinely issued Russia sanctions enforcement packages, the Trump administration hasn’t issued a single one,” Hardie observed. “The Trump administration is especially reluctant to punish Chinese entities involved in Russia sanctions evasion, as it doesn’t want to strain relations with Beijing.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardie also emphasized the role of the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Western companies need to be good corporate citizens and invest in strong due diligence, which isn’t always the case,” he said. “One idea FDD has been working on is to require U.S. companies to perform’ enhanced due diligence for shipments of sensitive goods to countries known to be high-risk jurisdictions for Russian evasion.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The result is a war economy that has adapted to intense pressure. Russia has expanded its defense industry despite sweeping sanctions, leveraging enforcement gaps, asymmetries in global trade, and non-Western intermediaries that facilitate transactions for profit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, analysts warn that structural strains are increasing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“While there is evidence for both trends, the stresses on the Russian economy are becoming larger,” Fried noted. “The Soviet experience is instructive; the USSR managed to continue its priority programs through the end, but the overall economy deteriorated little by little, and then all at once.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For these gaps to be closed, secondary sanctions risk must be dramatically increased, import quotas must be imposed on third countries, or Russia must be granted access to critical technology at a higher cost and with greater complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hardie, however, warned against relaxing pressure at a critical moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When you need leverage to get Moscow to accept a peace deal, that’s hardly a smart time to make life easier for the Russian war machine,” he added. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Political Logic of Trump’s Violent Lawlessness</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ice-killings-minnesota-moral-horror-but-also-shows-trumps-political-logic-by-timothy-snyder-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The moral horror of ICE and Border Patrol agents executing US citizen observers is enough to denounce the Trump administration’s campaign of cruelty in Minnesota. But it is also important to recognize how it reflects the political logic of turning an entire country into a lawless border zone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 09:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why US-Indonesia Relations Stagnated in 2025</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-us-indonesia-relations-stagnated-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Southeast Asia's most populous nation remains a blind-spot for the second Trump administration.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam’s To Lam Stakes His Ascent on Rapid Growth</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/27/vietnam-to-lam-communist-party-growth-myanmar-election/</link>
      <description>He has boosted the private sector and fired tens of thousands of civil servants.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 06:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortress Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/ukraine/fortress-ukraine</link>
      <description>How a&amp;nbsp;coalition of the willing can rearm Kyiv without Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geopolitics in the Age of Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/geopolitics-age-artificial-intelligence</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Warship Pays First Port Call at Cambodia’s Ream Naval Base</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/us-warship-pays-first-port-call-at-cambodias-ream-naval-base/</link>
      <description>The USS Cincinnati's five-day visit reflects the rapid positive turn that U.S.-Cambodia relations have taken over the past several years.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are China’s New Wolf Warriors Really Fighting For?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/what-are-chinas-new-wolf-warriors-really-fighting</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The recent return of China’s ‘wolf warrior’ diplomats has more to say about domestic pressures than about external challenges to China’s rise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia Takes Delivery of First French-made Rafale Fighter Jets</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indonesia-takes-delivery-of-first-french-made-rafale-fighter-jets/</link>
      <description>The three aircraft are the first portion of Indonesia’s $8.1 billion order for 42 new fighters from the French defense manufacturer Dassault.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impeachment and Plunder Raps Filed Against Philippines’ Top Leaders</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/impeachment-and-plunder-raps-filed-against-philippines-top-leaders/</link>
      <description>Both President Ferdinand Marcos Jr. and his estranged vice president, Sara Duterte, are under increasing pressure after a year of outrage and protest.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Decade of Questionable Governance at the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/a-decade-of-questionable-governance-at-the-asian-infrastructure-investment-bank/</link>
      <description>As the AIIB marks ten years of operations, concerns persist about how the Beijing-dominated multilateral institution handles governance and human rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our latest index of Europe’s priciest cities for renters</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/26/our-latest-index-of-europes-priciest-cities-for-renters</link>
      <description>The average earner struggles to afford rent in all but eight of the places we looked at</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
