<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>USAF consolidates some acquisition program offices into mission-focused groups</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/usaf-consolidates-some-acquisition-program-offices-mission-focused-groups/410569/</link>
      <description>But many of the new “portfolio acquisition executives” were already leading multi-mission efforts.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 23:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Imperialist Military</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/trump-imperialist-military-venezuela-greenland-colombia-cuba-mexico-iran/</link>
      <description>‘America First’ is starting to look like ‘America Everywhere.’</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ‘Donroe Doctrine’ Makes No Sense</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/donroe-doctrine-trump-venezuela-empire/</link>
      <description>Even a generous reading results in a heap of contradictions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Will Latin America Move Forward From the Maduro Raid?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/us-venezuela-strikes-maduro-capture-brazil-mexico-colombia/</link>
      <description>No one in the region is saying “TACO” now.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Senate Advances Measure to Curb Trump’s Venezuela Campaign</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/senate-war-powers-vote-trump-venezuela-republicans-kaine/</link>
      <description>The early procedural success indicates that lawmakers may have reached their limits on Trump’s expansive interpretation of Article 2 powers.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Xi Jinping Make China Spend?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/china-domestic-consumption-spending-demands/</link>
      <description>The leadership knows lack of domestic demand is a problem—but may not have the tools to fix it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. to Withdraw From Dozens of International and U.N. Entities</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/us-trump-withdraw-un-agencies-climate-change-women-democracy/</link>
      <description>Trump says the entities “operate contrary to U.S. national interests, security, economic prosperity, or sovereignty.”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. to Quit 66 International, U.N. Entities</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/us-trump-withdraw-un-agencies-climate-change/</link>
      <description>Trump says the entities “operate contrary to U.S. national interests, security, economic prosperity, or sovereignty.”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Greenland Threats Paper Over a Lack of Arctic Strategy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/trump-greenland-arctic-threats-war-russia-china/</link>
      <description>U.S. efforts to counter Russia and China need allies, not targets.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Umar Khalid and the Erosion of Indian Justice</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/umar-khalid-and-the-erosion-of-indian-justice/</link>
      <description>Khalid’s case is a stark example of how the Modi government weaponizes anti-terror laws to indefinitely silence Muslim voices and crush dissent.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why overdose deaths are falling in America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/08/why-overdose-deaths-are-falling-in-america</link>
      <description>Researchers point to a grocers’ favourite</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uzbekistan Reimposes Gas Station Restrictions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/uzbekistan-reimposes-gas-station-restrictions/</link>
      <description>For the second time in a month, Uzbek authorities have restricted hours at methane filling stations due to a drop in gas pipeline pressure.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marine Corps picks industry team to create a robot wingman of its own</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/01/marine-corps-picks-industry-team-create-robot-wingman-its-own/410549/</link>
      <description>Northrop will integrate systems on Kratos’ XQ-58 Valkyrie drone.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Saudi Arabia-UAE Dispute Is About More Than Just Yemen</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/saudi-arabia-uae-dispute-yemen-sudan/</link>
      <description>The divide is forcing countries across the region to take sides.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Venezuela Change Trump’s Approach to War?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/trump-approach-to-war-venezuela-conflicts/</link>
      <description>The author of FP’s ‘10 Conflicts to Watch’ on a violent start to 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Major Economies’ Prospects in 2026</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/policy-will-have-little-impact-on-the-performance-of-china-the-us-and-europe-in-2026-by-daniel-gros-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Political leaders tend to claim credit when the economy performs well and to pursue frantic reforms when it does not. But short-term policy measures will have little impact on the forces shaping the prospects of the world’s major economies today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Offshore banks to hold seized-oil profits; Pay caps for defense CEOs; Army’s flight-school outsourcing, snagged; Right-to-repair urged; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-08-2026/410545/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lebanon Is Disarming Hezbollah. The U.S. and Israel Can Do More to Help.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/lebanon-hezbollah-israel-litani-disarmament/</link>
      <description>The Lebanese Armed Forces have a unique opportunity to assert meaningful sovereignty over their country.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Hobbesian World Order</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-attack-on-venezuela-implies-a-shift-toward-hobbesian-power-politics-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With its Venezuela operation, the US has effectively given China an open invitation to invade Taiwan, vindicated Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, and set the stage for more illegal US military actions. Large and rising powers – such as Germany, India, and Japan – must work together to affirm and enforce rules of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Kremlin Files: Russia, the Modern Surveillance State</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-surveillance-state</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/a-view-of-the-general-office-of-the-fsb-kgb-building-on-january-23-2006-in-moscow-russia.jpg?id=62639578&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C8%2C0%2C9&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT OPINION / PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Ask any Russian intelligence officer about “&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;naruzhka&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,” and you’ll see them nod knowingly. It’s the term for physical, trailing surveillance: watchers on the street who follow targets, track meetings, and report patterns. The Russians are experts at it, and they have been for centuries, dating back to the Tsarist Secret police, the Okhrana, and even further to Ivan the Terrible’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;oprichniki&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the brutal enforcers of his regime. Surveillance is a subject that dominates Russian society and Russian espionage, and it also dictates how Russian intelligence officers (RIOs) conduct counter-surveillance and surveillance detection. The Russian intelligence services (RIS) still lean heavily on surveillance as both a protective and offensive tool. Given such an all-compassing presence in Russian society, the term &quot;surveillance&quot; and its connotations in Russia are worth exploring to better understand Russia, its state, society, and our adversaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russians have a saying, “the walls have ears,” and sometimes follow it with “and the streets have eyes.” Studying in Russia in the early 1990s as an exchange student, I was repeatedly warned by my friends with this expression. It was their way of telling our group of American students that no matter how welcome we felt— and Russians have some of the best hospitality in the world when you are welcomed by them— the state was still suspicious. We came to understand very quickly that there were minders among us: Russian students and professors who reported on us back to the FSB, the successor of the KGB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of our group of students were even “soft-pitched.” For example, in one case, a fellow student with a military background was asked whether he would like to meet with the FSB to discuss how interesting the Russian internal security service was (not exactly a soft approach, really). These blunt and clumsy attempts went unanswered, but the point was clear: the state was not just watching; they were operationally targeting our group of future soldiers, researchers, academics, and in at least one case, a future CIA officer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscribe to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Sign up for free today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has studied or lived in Russia over the past three decades no doubt has had similar experiences. But the bar of intimidation has risen dramatically in recent years. With dissidents, journalists, and even athletes targeted for intimidation, beatings, arrest, and even murder, there is no safe haven in Russia any longer for foreign citizens. They are used as targets to be entrapped for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/01/world/who-are-detainees-russia-us-prisoner-swap-intl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;hostage exchanges&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with the West. The goal is to swap civilians for RIOs for the latter to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russias-intelligence-services-after-the-war-will-they-be-held-accountable-for-their-failures&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;escape their failings&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when arrested and convicted abroad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russians live in a state of constant fear, especially with the war in Ukraine, since opposition to the war, in any form, is now threatened by jail time. Anyone who may be a threat to the regime is subjected to overwhelming surveillance of their person, electronic communications, and contacts. The FSB has many resources at its disposal, including access to all ISPs and phone companies by law. In the early 2000s, the Russian Duma quietly passed laws giving the FSB access to all communication companies in Russia without the need for any warrants. It was the first step in creating their modern surveillance state and an early sign under Putin that democracy was dying.&lt;br /&gt;Inside Russia, surveillance teams from the FSB number in the many thousands. Their origins lie in the old KGB 7th directorate. Still, their mission remains the same: monitor diplomats, suspected foreign intelligence officers, journalists, NGO workers, businesspeople, and ordinary Russians who cross the regime’s lines. The teams are, unfortunately, among the very best in the world at surveillance, given their long history of practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surveillance schools in Leningrad (St. Petersburg), in particular, were known as the best in the Soviet Union during the Cold War. Young surveillance team members from the KGB, GRU, and other services of the Soviet Union were trained in the art of on-foot and vehicle surveillance, effective radio communications, and spotting intelligence tells of possible espionage operations. Today, it is no different. The FSB, in particular, devotes considerable resources to surveillance work in Moscow and across Russia in every major city of its vast surveillance apparatus. They are increasingly assisted by technology and a vast array of cameras across the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Russia, all universities, think tanks, and defense contractors, have assigned security officers, what the Russians call an “OB,” who monitor the foreign contacts, make Russians report on their foreign friends, and even many of their Russian ones. The OB is usually an FSB officer, but if not, they are a cooptee of the service, reporting directly to a UFSB or a regional office across Russia. The OBs, in turn, enlist networks of agent-reporters who are only too eager to report on the travel, potential misdeeds, disloyalty to the regime, or other offenses of all those they monitor. Russia today has a network of informers to rival Stasi East Germany, Nazi Germany under the Gestapo, or any other despotic regime, including North Korea and China of today (both of whom, admittedly, may also contend for the gold and silver on despotic modern surveillance states, together with Russia).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The all-encompassing nature of the Russian surveillance state, which includes monitoring by city cameras (supplemented by drones now too), communications, and in-person surveillance, makes it clear that RIS surveillance is not confined to diplomats or foreigners suspected of intelligence affiliation. Academics, journalists, and corporate leaders can find themselves under observation or pressure when Moscow sees strategic value in them. Awareness of surveillance indicators—and how to respond—remains essential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, for decades, Westerners traveling to Russia as academics, athletes, NGO workers, and others have been naïve on this score. The refrain is frequently that “I am no one of interest, they’ll leave me alone.” The RIS never did and never will. The pressure for the Russian services, in particular the FSB, to prove worthy of their giant bureaucracy and corrupt budget means they will manufacture spy cases when they can’t find real ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They map the routines of foreign officials, political or business leaders. Their goal is to decide if those targets are viable recruits, potentially, or targets for other operations, like extortion, “direct action,” or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-intelligence-kill-murder-putin&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;assassination attempts&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Russia and abroad. This leads to another underappreciated aspect of Russian intelligence and espionage that permeates their society: setups, tricks, and double-agent operations, which the Russians call “operational games.” (That will be the topic of a future “Kremlin Files” column in &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Russian surveillance, the warning remains clear, and the potential risks are stark. Unfortunately, for all the beauty to be found in Russian history, its cultural sites and heritage, and with their people, traveling to the Russian surveillance state under this corrupt and authoritarian regime holds incredible risk for foreigners, and even for Russian citizens themselves. It will not change until the RIS no longer has the dominant role in society. Laws and checks on power don’t exist in the Russian services. Surveillance, in fact, guides the functioning of the Russian state, and the streets continue to have eyes- everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America chases down the shadow fleet serving Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/08/america-chases-down-the-shadow-fleet-serving-venezuela</link>
      <description>Donald Trump is determined to enforce its oil blockade</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the US Air Force’s Quicksink Bomb the ‘Silver Bullet’ to Blunt a Taiwan Invasion?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/is-the-us-air-forces-quicksink-bomb-the-silver-bullet-to-blunt-a-taiwan-invasion/</link>
      <description>The USAF’s B-2 or B-21 stealth bombers, armed with large numbers of cheap Quicksink bombs, could wreak havoc on a Chinese invasion fleet.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Jungle Rules</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-foreign-policy-preying-on-weak-and-vulnerable-by-ian-bremmer-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The nature of US foreign policy under the current administration is now clear. America will unilaterally exercise power wherever Donald Trump thinks he can get away with it, uncoupled from the norms, bureaucratic processes, alliance structures, and multilateral institutions that once gave American leadership legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyz Deputy Prime Minister Suggests a Review of Visa-Free Scheme for Americans</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/kyrgyz-deputy-prime-minister-suggests-a-review-of-visa-free-scheme-for-americans/</link>
      <description>Following the imposition of visa bonds for Kyrgyz travelers to the United States, a Kyrgyz politician has suggested Bishkek reassess its visa-free program for Americans.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lee’s First Visit to Beijing: A Nuanced Restoration of China-South Korea Ties</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/lees-first-visit-to-beijing-a-nuanced-restoration-of-china-south-korea-ties/</link>
      <description>Seoul and Beijing are back on track in reviving their bilateral ties, while conveying their own messages on the North Korea and Taiwan issues.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Media Transparency Strengthens Geopolitical Stability in East Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-social-media-transparency-strengthens-geopolitical-stability-in-east-asia/</link>
      <description>The simple step of displaying geographic locators has pulled back the curtain on foreign disinformation operations in Japan and Taiwan.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France is paralysed, and everyone is to blame</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/08/france-is-paralysed-and-everyone-is-to-blame</link>
      <description>The budgetary impasse is just one symptom of collective political uselessness</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI is transforming the pharma industry for the better</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/08/ai-is-transforming-the-pharma-industry-for-the-better</link>
      <description>It is changing the way drugs are discovered and tested</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Japan have a “foreigner problem”?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/08/does-japan-have-a-foreigner-problem</link>
      <description>Yes—but it is not what populist politicians say it is</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media are making it easier for cults to recruit and control members</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/08/social-media-are-making-it-easier-for-cults-to-recruit-and-control-members</link>
      <description>The internet has replaced door-to-door evangelists with online influencers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Europe is rediscovering the virtues of cash</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/08/why-europe-is-rediscovering-the-virtues-of-cash</link>
      <description>In a world of payment apps and digital euros, the coin is staging a modest comeback</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latvia is needlessly alienating its Russian-speakers</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/08/latvia-is-needlessly-alienating-its-russian-speakers</link>
      <description>Shutting down Russian-language broadcasting is a gift to the Kremlin</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energetic abroad, Emmanuel Macron faces a mess at home</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/08/energetic-abroad-emmanuel-macron-faces-a-mess-at-home</link>
      <description>France’s sorry spectacle of another year without a budget</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kosovo’s election shows its democracy is solid</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/08/kosovos-election-shows-its-democracy-is-solid</link>
      <description>Albin Kurti’s win improves relations with the EU, though not with Serbia</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Russian drone has revived a Ukrainian nuclear nightmare</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/08/a-russian-drone-has-revived-a-ukrainian-nuclear-nightmare</link>
      <description>But who is prepared to pour even more money into making the country safe?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problem with promotions</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/08/the-problem-with-promotions</link>
      <description>The Peter principle is alive and well</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI frenzy is creating a big problem for consumer electronics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/08/the-ai-frenzy-is-creating-a-big-problem-for-consumer-electronics</link>
      <description>Prices are rocketing for an essential component</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the age of the vodcast</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/08/welcome-to-the-age-of-the-vodcast</link>
      <description>Audio shows are switching on their cameras in search of new audiences</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany’s industrial conglomerates are breaking up to stay alive</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/08/germanys-industrial-conglomerates-are-breaking-up-to-stay-alive</link>
      <description>Economic woes are accelerating a trend of divestments</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Thailand rein in its “mafia monks”?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/08/can-thailand-rein-in-its-mafia-monks</link>
      <description>Lurid scandals have rocked the country’s powerful Buddhist institutions</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The teenage girl who may rule North Korea</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/08/the-teenage-girl-who-may-rule-north-korea</link>
      <description>Even her name is a matter of debate</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s not just China’s total population that’s falling</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/08/its-not-just-chinas-total-population-thats-falling</link>
      <description>The number of people in China’s towns and cities is in decline</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China and Taiwan both see lessons in America’s raid on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/08/china-and-taiwan-both-see-lessons-in-americas-raid-on-venezuela</link>
      <description>It won’t change China’s calculus but is a case study for “decapitation” strikes</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media are helping cults to recruit and control members</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/01/08/social-media-are-helping-cults-to-recruit-and-control-members</link>
      <description>The internet has replaced door-to-door evangelists with online influencers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What John Thune is for</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/08/what-john-thune-is-for</link>
      <description>The Republican majority leader in the Senate is under pressure</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s most novel train project is too deadly</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/08/americas-most-novel-train-project-is-too-deadly</link>
      <description>The government may be more responsible than the operator</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weekly cartoon</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/08/the-weekly-cartoon</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/08/business</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/08/politics</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Museveni era is nearing its end</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/08/the-museveni-era-is-nearing-its-end</link>
      <description>But it is time, not elections, that Uganda’s president most fears</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudi Arabia has its first boozy new year—sort of</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/08/saudi-arabia-has-its-first-boozy-new-year-sort-of</link>
      <description>Who exactly is allowed to get sloshed?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Beijing Won’t Be Emboldened by the ‘Venezuela Precedent’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-beijing-wont-be-emboldened-by-the-venezuela-precedent/</link>
      <description>China’s coercion threshold is set by its own internal logic – not by external “precedents.”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Strengthening RFA Is a Strategic Imperative for US Policy on North Korea</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-strengthening-rfa-is-a-strategic-imperative-for-us-policy-on-north-korea/</link>
      <description>Expanding access to independent information is essential for U.S. security interests, human rights objectives, and long-term regional stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela and the Future of the West</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-venezuela-intervention-forces-rest-of-west-to-clarify-priorities-by-jim-o-neill-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With 2026 barely underway, Donald Trump has pulled the rug out from under anyone who still believed in the salvageability of the old international order. The midnight US raid to capture Venezuela’s president, Nicolás Maduro, confirms that we are in a new era, and the question now is how the rest of the world will respond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethnic conflict festers on India’s eastern frontier</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/08/ethnic-conflict-festers-on-indias-eastern-frontier</link>
      <description>Manipur is a warning for the rest of the country</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix America’s Broken Arsenal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/08/defense-industrial-base-arsenal-hegseth-trump/</link>
      <description>The defense establishment has severe knowledge gaps about its own, aging industrial base.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What “Pluribus” reveals about economics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/08/what-pluribus-reveals-about-economics</link>
      <description>A hit Apple TV show offers useful lessons</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do not mistake a resilient global economy for populist success</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/08/do-not-mistake-a-resilient-global-economy-for-populist-success</link>
      <description>Protectionism is failing to revive manufacturing</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Donald Trump’s world, the strong take what they can</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/08/in-donald-trumps-world-the-strong-take-what-they-can</link>
      <description>That will be bad for America—and everyone else</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump asserts control over Venezuela—and all the Americas</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/08/donald-trump-asserts-control-over-venezuela-and-all-the-americas</link>
      <description>But the president’s claim of dominance over the western hemisphere may backfire</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of Prediction Markets</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/times-person-of-the-year-shows-limits-of-prediction-markets-by-erin-lockwood-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question of which bets on &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt;’s 2025 Person of the Year should pay out ignited furor on Kalshi and Polymarket, two major prediction markets. By reaching diametrically opposed conclusions, these platforms underscored the indispensable role of human interpretation in settling event contracts, despite claims of automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam’s growth is fast—but fragile</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/08/vietnams-growth-is-fast-but-fragile</link>
      <description>The economy is unduly reliant on a handful of conglomerates</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Europe’s biggest pension funds are dumping government bonds</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/08/why-europes-biggest-pension-funds-are-dumping-government-bonds</link>
      <description>Dutch reforms will push up borrowing costs across the continent</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Alliance of Political Newcomers Seeks to End Old Parties’ Monopoly in Nepal</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/an-alliance-of-political-newcomers-seeks-to-end-old-parties-monopoly-in-nepal/</link>
      <description>A popular mayor, a former TV star and an ex-chief of Nepal’s electricity board have joined hands to fight the old guard in the upcoming elections.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War That Outgrew Sudan</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/sudan/war-outgrew-sudan</link>
      <description>Middle East rivalries are turning a local war into a regional crisis..</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Silicon Valley Gets Wrong About National Security</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/what-silicon-valley-gets-wrong-about-national-security</link>
      <description>Defense tech innovation requires government intervention.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Tin Mining Crackdown Brings Order, Consolidates Power</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indonesias-tin-mining-crackdown-brings-order-consolidates-power/</link>
      <description>Seized assets are being placed under the control of a state-owned giant at the heart of a sprawling corruption scheme.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Pakistan’s Powerful Generals Panicking Over an Op-ed Article?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-are-pakistans-powerful-generals-panicking-over-an-op-ed-article/</link>
      <description>In a climate of economic and political uncertainty, even a single article in a newspaper with a modest circulation is now viewed as a potential spark for mass unrest.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar Junta Readies Second Phase of Controversial General Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/myanmar-junta-readies-second-phase-of-controversial-general-election/</link>
      <description>One hundred more townships will go to the polls on Sunday in an election that has been roundly condemned as a &quot;sham.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s Economy Set For Tough Year in 2026, Central Bank Says</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/thailands-economy-set-for-tough-year-in-2026-central-bank-says/</link>
      <description>The current stagnation contrasts with the dynamic state of the Vietnamese economy, which is on track to leapfrog Thailand as soon as this year.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cambodia’s Prince Bank Founder Deported to China For Alleged Cyber Crimes</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/cambodias-prince-bank-founder-deported-to-china-for-alleged-cyber-crimes/</link>
      <description>Chen Zhi’s extradition follows U.S. federal indictment and the capture of Venezuela’s President Nicolas Maduro.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “terrorist” killed by ICE was a mum in her SUV</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/08/the-terrorist-killed-by-ice-was-a-mum-in-her-suv</link>
      <description>A killing in Minneapolis is part of a dangerous pattern</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farming is Critical to UK National Security</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/farming-critical-uk-national-security</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The UK believes in a whole-of-society approach to national security. Agriculture has both a traditional and a novel role to play in protecting the country.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Sanctions to the Scrapyard: Confronting a Growing Environmental Threat</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/sanctions-scrapyard-confronting-growing-environmental-threat</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sanctions are blocking end-of-life vessels from being scrapped thus creating an environmental time bomb – but there is a simple fix.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Anwar’s Two-Term Limit for PMs a Good Idea?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/is-anwars-two-term-limit-for-pms-a-good-idea/</link>
      <description>Despite the superficial appeal of the Malaysian leader's proposal, term limits aren’t really the political cure that they purport to be.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defense Business Brief: US-made biotech; Rocketdyne; Hegseth’s industry tours</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/defense-business-brief-us-made-biotech-rocketdyne-hegseths-industry-tours/410537/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump chases down the shadow fleet serving Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/07/donald-trump-chases-down-the-shadow-fleet-serving-venezuela</link>
      <description>America seizes two oil tankers, including one flying a Russian flag</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump chases down the shadow fleet serving Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/07/donald-trump-chases-down-the-shadow-fleet-serving-venezuela</link>
      <description>America is determined to enforce its oil blockade</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America chases down the shadow fleet serving Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/07/america-chases-down-the-shadow-fleet-serving-venezuela</link>
      <description>Donald Trump is determined to enforce its oil blockade</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s defiant front</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/07/ukraines-defiant-front</link>
      <description>The country’s defensive cordon could yet be bargained away</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
