<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Japan lost its climate leadership – and now Australia can help</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/japan-lost-its-climate-leadership-now-australia-can-help</link>
      <description>Japan’s largest supplier of coal and LNG has just pledged to transition from fossil fuels – creating both tension and opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republicans Criticize Hegseth for Deadly Caribbean Double Strike</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/republicans-criticize-hegseth-caribbean-strike/</link>
      <description>Bipartisan lawmakers are demanding congressional probes into the defense secretary’s handling of a deadly boat strike.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu Just Admitted He’s Unfit to Lead Israel</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/netanyahu-pardon-request-israel/685116/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>In attempting to call off his corruption trial, Netanyahu didn’t incriminate himself, but he did something just as damning.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia bets on old laws to manage new AI risks</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/australia-bets-old-laws-manage-new-ai-risks</link>
      <description>Relying on legacy laws may seem pragmatic, but other countries are racing ahead with purpose-built AI regulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Fire Highlights Hong Kong’s Predicament</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/hong-kong-apartment-fire-china-political-freedoms/</link>
      <description>The tragedy confirmed to many locals that the city’s freedoms have vanished.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Favorite Role? Foreign-Policy Czar.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/trumps-favorite-role-foreign-policy-czar/</link>
      <description>In diplomacy, the U.S. president always seems to follow his own transactional view of human affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin’s Threats Against Europe Undermine Russia-Ukraine Peace Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/putin-witkoff-kushner-russia-ukraine-peace-talks-moscow/</link>
      <description>Moscow remains opposed to surrendering its territorial ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin Meets With Witkoff, Kushner to Discuss Ukraine Peace Plan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/putin-witkoff-kushner-russia-ukraine-peace-talks/</link>
      <description>Moscow remains opposed to surrendering its territorial ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpworld thinks Europe has betrayed the West</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/12/02/trumpworld-thinks-europe-has-betrayed-the-west</link>
      <description>Centrist governments across the continent rightly sense a trap</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Minerals That Drive Trump’s Global Agenda</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/the-minerals-that-drive-trumps-global-agenda/</link>
      <description>From Canada to Pakistan, an interest in critical minerals is a through line in the White House’s foreign policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIs could turn opinion polls into gibberish</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/02/ais-could-turn-opinion-polls-into-gibberish</link>
      <description>Large language models can answer surveys and pass the tests to check that a respondent is human</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Venezuela Fixation Is Not About the Oil</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/trump-venezuela-fixation-oil-regime-change-maduro/</link>
      <description>There are lots of reasons why the Trump administration is angling for regime change in Caracas, but heavy oil isn’t one of them.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renminbi Internationalization Is Closing the Climate Finance Gap</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-panda-dim-sum-ftz-bonds-closing-gap-left-by-dollar-by-ma-jun-and-sean-kidney-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through a trifecta of fast-growing markets for renminbi-denominated bonds, China is showing that it can support domestic sustainability projects across the Global South. With the United States and other traditional creditors stepping back, Chinese finance is filling the vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chris Waller, not Kevin Hassett, should lead the Federal Reserve</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/02/chris-waller-not-kevin-hassett-should-lead-the-federal-reserve</link>
      <description>President Trump is about to make the wrong appointment</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of peace talks, Russia’s battlefield advances remain slow</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/12/02/ahead-of-peace-talks-russias-battlefield-advances-remain-slow</link>
      <description>Even at an accelerated recent pace, seizing Ukraine’s eastern regions would take more than two years</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADB’s Emphasis on Critical Minerals Sparks Fear in Philippines</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/adbs-emphasis-on-critical-minerals-sparks-fear-in-philippines/</link>
      <description>The ADB’s new program fits right into the Philippine government’s plans for transition mining – to the detriment of Indigenous communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Pakistan Adapt to Climate Disaster?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/pakistan-climate-finance-gap-funding-cop30-adaptation/</link>
      <description>Three years ago, the country became a poster child for climate justice. Now, it faces a steep learning curve to secure the funding it needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Chinese Workers Killed in 2 Attacks in Tajikistan Along Afghan Border</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/5-chinese-workers-killed-in-2-attacks-in-tajikistan-along-afghan-border/</link>
      <description>In one of the attacks, a drone was reportedly used to drop grenades on Chinese workers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Just Transition for Land</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/unccd-mobilize-financing-for-just-land-transition-by-andrea-meza-murillo-and-bradley-hiller-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Annual economic losses linked to desertification, land degradation, and drought amount to $878 billion – far more than the investments needed to mitigate their impact. Only by using innovative financing mechanisms and collaborating more effectively can a just transition to a sustainable and resilient land economy be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High stakes in India’s refusal to send former Bangladesh PM to trial</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/high-stakes-india-s-refusal-send-former-bangladesh-pm-trial</link>
      <description>A carefully worded extradition treaty means New Delhi can hedge its bets, but it should be prepared for blowback.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative Destruction Should Not Spare Commercial Banks</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cbdcs-great-potential-but-opposed-by-traditional-banks-by-katharina-pistor-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New technologies offer new opportunities to revamp payment and credit systems, making them not only more efficient but also safer. It would be a shame if these were foregone because banks believe that they have a right to a business model that they inherited from political compromises struck centuries ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s National AI Plan Has Just Been Released. Who Exactly Will Benefit?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/australias-national-ai-plan-has-just-been-released-who-exactly-will-benefit/</link>
      <description>The plan’s primary goal seems to be attracting international data center investment – even at the cost of abandoning regulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India-China Engage in War of Words Over Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/india-china-engage-in-war-of-words-over-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <description>Chinese officials detained an Indian national for 18 hours at Shanghai airport, claiming that her Indian passport was not valid as she is from Arunachal Pradesh.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a 42-year-old Massacre Is Returning to Roil Assam’s Politics</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-a-42-year-old-massacre-is-returning-to-roil-assams-politics/</link>
      <description>The long-suppressed Tiwari Commission report on the 1983 Nellie massacre has finally been released, but early responses suggest it may ignite debate on demographic change rather than accountability for one of India’s deadliest episodes of mass violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Latest Earthquake Was a Warning Sign: Bangladesh Isn’t Ready</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-latest-earthquake-was-a-warning-sign-bangladesh-isnt-ready/</link>
      <description>The recent M5.5 earthquake occurred outside the better known seismic hazard zones and is a wake-up call to boost preparedness.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can America Win the New Race for Scientific Leadership?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-race-for-scientific-leadership-talent-china-more-proactive-than-us-by-nancy-qian-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even as China and the United States compete for scientific leadership, the Trump administration has slashed investment in research and tightened immigration rules. If the US has truly entered a second Cold War, it should repeat the strategy that helped it win the first one: expanding the scientific frontier at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toy Seller’s Legal Battle Shines Spotlight on China’s Ultra Strict Gun Rules</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/toy-sellers-legal-battle-shines-spotlight-on-chinas-ultra-strict-gun-rules/</link>
      <description>A merchant selling “gel blasters” is the latest person to face serious criminal charges for possession of seemingly harmless guns.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is the PPP Still Defending Yoon Suk-yeol?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-is-the-ppp-still-defending-yoon-suk-yeol/</link>
      <description>A year after the illegitimate declaration of martial law, the conservative People Power Party is still justifying Yoon’s decision.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkic or Central Asian? Azerbaijan’s Entry Tests the Region’s Identity</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/turkic-or-central-asian-azerbaijans-entry-tests-the-regions-identity/</link>
      <description>What, exactly, is “Central Asia” today?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Taiwan Views the China-Japan Spat</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-taiwan-views-the-china-japan-spat/</link>
      <description>A war of perceptions over framings of Japanese Prime Minister Takaichi is taking shape in Taiwan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America is foolishly waving goodbye to thousands of Chinese boffins</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/02/america-is-foolishly-waving-goodbye-to-thousands-of-chinese-boffins</link>
      <description>Hostile policies and attacks on science are driving them back into China’s arms</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deeper into the Public Procurement Goldmine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/public-procurement-most-underused-driver-of-economic-growth-by-ricardo-hausmann-and-yariv-gabay-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Public procurement is one of the world’s most powerful yet underused industrial-policy tools. Rather than treating procurement as a routine administrative task, policymakers must harness it to guide innovators toward developing and scaling solutions to complex societal challenges, from infrastructure to climate resilience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Did Not Do a ‘Kissinger’ to Split Europe From America</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/china-europe-russia-ukraine-war-peace-trump-us-geopolitics/</link>
      <description>Europe would have given almost anything for peace, but Beijing had a different calculus.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The G20 Must Follow Through on Debt Relief</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/g20-must-improve-common-framework-for-debt-treatment-restructuring-by-olusegun-obasanjo-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Governments across Africa, Asia, and Latin America have been forced to cut spending on education, health care, and infrastructure to keep funds flowing to foreign creditors, undermining global stability and prosperity. To break this vicious cycle, G20 leaders must urgently revamp the Common Framework for Debt Treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia’s Borneo Election Spells Trouble for Anwarjos</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/sabah-election-results-borneo-east-malaysia/</link>
      <description>“Sabah for Sabahans” undermines the country’s precarious ethno-political balance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Pakistan Army Can’t Afford to Eliminate Imran Khan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-the-pakistan-army-cant-afford-to-eliminate-imran-khan/</link>
      <description>Eliminating the immensely popular leader would not end the crisis; it would unleash one that the Pakistani state may not survive.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to fix Defence? Start by cutting bureaucratic bloat</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/want-fix-defence-start-cutting-bureaucratic-bloat</link>
      <description>Same people, same jobs, new structure – but somehow performance will improve. This story has been told before.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Promise—and Limits—of a Free Press</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/promise-and-limits-free-press</link>
      <description>Journalists alone cannot stave off autocracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The West’s Last Chance</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/wests-last-chance</link>
      <description>How to build a new global order before it’s too late.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami’s 5-hour Work Plan for Women: A Patriarchal Ploy?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/bangladesh-jamaat-e-islamis-5-hour-work-plan-for-women-a-patriarchal-ploy/</link>
      <description>Many Bangladeshis believe that this is a strategy of the Jamaat to send working women back home.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand Extradites Prominent Montagnard Rights Activist to Vietnam</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thailand-extradites-prominent-montagnard-rights-activist-to-vietnam/</link>
      <description>The extradition of Y Quynh Bdap, 33, is a sign of a growing crackdown on Vietnamese refugees and asylum seekers in Thailand, rights groups say.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to Brunei’s Land Ownership Laws Stoke Concerns, Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/changes-to-bruneis-land-ownership-laws-stoke-concerns-uncertainty/</link>
      <description>Non-citizens, including established ethnic Chinese families, face the downgrade of freehold titles – some inherited over generations – into 30-to-60-year leases.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 01:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
