<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Defense Business Brief: Exec order fallout; $1B rocket-maker deal; Acquisition changes, and more</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/defense-business-brief-exec-order-fallout-1b-rocket-maker-deal-acquisition-changes-and-more/410699/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe has three options for defending Greenland</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/14/europe-has-three-options-for-defending-greenland</link>
      <description>Fending off Donald Trump may yet prove agonisingly difficult</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European allies dispatch military reinforcements to Greenland</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/european-allies-dispatch-military-reinforcements-greenland/410697/</link>
      <description>A White House meeting produced plans for a U.S.-Denmark working group, but no change to Trump's designs on the island.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran Facing Hard Choices as Unrest Spreads</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/iran-facing-hard-choices-as-unrest</link>
      <description>Repression apparatus spread thin as nationwide protests threaten to evolve into economic disruption&amp;#8212;the key to regime&amp;#8217;s survival</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 23:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I ‘did not expect to be told to build a battleship,’ Navy’s surface warfare director says</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/i-did-not-expect-be-told-build-battleship-navys-surface-warfare-director-says/410692/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s priorities are forcing the service to rethink its shipbuilding plans.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Golden Dome excuse for Greenland grab is ‘detached from reality,’ experts say</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/trumps-golden-dome-excuse-greenland-grab-detached-reality-experts-say/410693/</link>
      <description>Longstanding diplomatic agreements and an existing U.S. base already enable military expansion.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s High-Stakes Play in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/pakistan-middle-east-diplomacy-arms-sales-iran-sudan-libya-saudi-arabia-turkey-gaza/</link>
      <description>How Islamabad is capitalizing on the current geopolitical moment.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jerome Powell punches back</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/14/jerome-powell-punches-back</link>
      <description>The administration’s latest attack on America’s central bank has not gone well</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Russia Is Supporting Iran’s Repression</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/iran-russia-moscow-khamenei-putin-protests/</link>
      <description>Moscow is providing the military equipment and internet technology that Tehran is deploying against protesters.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s crusade against usury reaches Wall Street</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/14/donald-trumps-crusade-against-usury-reaches-wall-street</link>
      <description>His fight against high interest rates could get messy</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 22:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Iran Execute Protesters Despite U.S. Intervention Threats?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/iran-protests-erfan-soltani-execution-trump-us-intervention-starlink/</link>
      <description>As the death toll climbs, it remains unclear whether Tehran will bow to the White House’s warnings.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Suspends Immigrant Visa Processing for 75 Countries</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/trump-immigration-crackdown-visa-processing-75-countries/</link>
      <description>Trump is escalating his immigration crackdown as he gears up for a second year back in office.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Saks Fifth Avenue’s owner went bust</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/14/how-saks-fifth-avenues-owner-went-bust</link>
      <description>The posh department-store group has itself to blame</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is passive investment inflating a stockmarket bubble?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/14/is-passive-investment-inflating-a-stockmarket-bubble</link>
      <description>A widely circulated working paper suggests so</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A private memo from central banks to governments</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/14/a-private-memo-from-central-banks-to-governments</link>
      <description>You come at the king (of finance), you best not miss</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk’s X Is in Deep Trouble Over Deepfake Porn</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/musk-x-twitter-grok-csam-deepfake/</link>
      <description>Grok is being used to make abusive and illegal images.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Claims About Nigeria Strikes Don’t Hold Up</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/us-nigeria-strikes-lakurawa-trump-minerals/</link>
      <description>The Christmas attack did not target the Islamic State, observers say.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same-sex sexual behaviour in primates is a survival strategy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/14/same-sex-sexual-behaviour-in-primates-is-a-survival-strategy</link>
      <description>It promotes harmony among those living in harsh environments, says new study</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hotter still, and hotter</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/14/hotter-still-and-hotter</link>
      <description>More worrying news about the climate</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 was third hottest year on record</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/14/2025-was-third-hottest-year-on-record</link>
      <description>It should have been a relatively cool year; it was anything but</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why child prodigies rarely become elite performers</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/14/why-child-prodigies-rarely-become-elite-performers</link>
      <description>Hot-housing promising youngsters works—but not as well as you might think</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Pauses Immigrant Visa Processing for 75 Countries, 13 in Asia-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/us-pauses-immigrant-visa-processing-for-75-countries-13-in-asia/</link>
      <description>The Asian countries apparently impacted include Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Cambodia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Laos, Mongolia, Myanmar, Nepal, Pakistan, Thailand, and Uzbekistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s not just the Fed. Politics looms over central banks everywhere</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/14/its-not-just-the-fed-politics-looms-over-central-banks-everywhere</link>
      <description>But can the public stomach higher inflation?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNO argues against sending an aircraft carrier toward Iran</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/cno-argues-against-sending-aircraft-carrier-toward-iran/410677/</link>
      <description>Adm. Daryl Caudle said he is already concerned about Ford’s extra time in SOUTHCOM.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EU-Mercosur Deal Is a Hedge Against the Donroe Doctrine</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/eu-mercosur-trade-deal-trump-donroe-doctrine/</link>
      <description>As the United States pursues gunboat diplomacy, Europe and South America are choosing cooperation instead.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Peace Deal Means Nothing for the Congolese</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/drc-m23-trump-peace-deal/</link>
      <description>Many of those living under the rule of the M23 militia prefer to keep it that way.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To power up growth, India must be rewired</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/14/to-power-up-growth-india-must-be-rewired</link>
      <description>Soon it will need as much electricity as Europe</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why an American Attack on Iran Would Backfire</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/american-attack-iran-backfire-trump-protests/</link>
      <description>Trump has threatened strikes in support of anti-regime protesters.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Reality is that Russia is Signaling Minimal Desire for Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-russia-peace</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/a-man-looks-at-a-damaged-residential-building-in-kyiv-ukraine-after-a-massive-drone-and-missile-attack-by-russia-jan-9-2026.jpg?id=62804849&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C53%2C0%2C54&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;As Russia continues it's brutal bombardment of Ukrainian cities, talks between Moscow and the U.S. to end the war appear on very different trajectories.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;White House envoy Steve Witkoff is reportedly planning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2026-01-14/witkoff-and-kushner-seek-to-visit-moscow-for-putin-meeting-soon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;another trip&lt;/a&gt; to Moscow to meet with Russian President Vladimir Putin as Moscow's winter attacks continue unabated.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, Russia &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-one-dead-kharkiv-ukrainian-officials-say-2026-01-12/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; hundreds of drones and dozens of missiles on cities across Ukraine, killing at least four people and striking critical energy and heat infrastructure. In the capital, Kyiv, residents are facing temperatures as low as 10 degrees farenheit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/major-russian-strike-targets-ukraines-power-grid-in-freezing-temperatures&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;without electricity or water&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On December 30, 2025, Moscow claimed a Ukrainian drone attack targeted Russian President Vladimir Putin's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/12/29/europe/russia-claim-ukrainian-drone-attack-putin-residence-intl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;residence&lt;/a&gt;. Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov threatened his country's military would launch &quot;retaliatory strikes&quot; and said Moscow's &quot;negotiating position will be revised” in ongoing talks. Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky rejected the claimed drone attack as “a complete fabrication”, and sources say the CIA assessed that Ukraine was not targeting the Russian leader's residence in the attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Trump said in December that the U.S. was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/zelenskiy-meet-trump-florida-talks-ukraine-peace-plan-2025-12-28/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;very close&lt;/a&gt;” to a deal. So, what's happening?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throughout the latest push for peace, Russia seems to conveniently reset the clock, demanding further talks as it continues its bombardments and assaults across Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This Russian strike sends an extremely clear signal about Russia’s priorities,” Zelensky said in a post &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/2003378962714497042&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;on X&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; referring to a strike on December 23 that killed three people and injured 12. Zeleneky condemned the attack “ahead of Christmas, when people simply want to be with their families, at home, and safe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That strike came just days after Putin told Russian defense ministry officials that Moscow will persist in its mission to “liberate its historic lands” and achieve its war goals “&lt;a href=&quot;https://kyivindependent.com/in-further-disregard-for-peace-putin-calls-european-leaders-little-pigs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;unconditionally&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” — by negotiations for an agreement in Moscow’s favor, or through continued war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The continued Russian attacks and Putin’s bellicose language underscore a pattern that has defined Russia’s position on “peace” throughout its full-scale invasion of Ukraine: not budging from maximalist demands, blaming Kyiv for the lack of progress, and leveraging Western fears of escalation to World War Three.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hardline from Putin comes as Ukraine has offered significant concessions, including Ukraine &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/zelenskiy-demands-dignified-peace-us-ukraine-officials-meet-berlin-2025-12-14/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;dropping NATO membership ambitions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for at least the time being, as well as a potential withdrawal of Ukrainian troops from the east and the creation of a demilitarized “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;free economic zone&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.” The latest reports say Russia still wants more, including more stringent restrictions on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-24/russia-to-demand-changes-to-us-peace-plan-seen-as-starting-point?srnd=homepage-americas&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;size of Ukraine’s military&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Ukrainians have been saying for over a year that they are ready to come to an agreement. They are ready to be realistic and compromise,” Glenn Corn, a former senior CIA Officer told &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. “It’s the Russians that are not doing that. It’s the Russians that continue to push maximalist demands and that continue to scuttle the peace process — not the Ukrainians.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the eyes of seasoned intelligence professionals who have studied Putin's actions for decades, the continued attacks despite peace talks are hardly surprising. “Putin has never been sincere about a negotiated solution to his ‘Special Military Operation,’” said Rob Dannenberg, former Chief of CIA’s Central Eurasia Division.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia is also continuing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0l0k4389g2o&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;offensive pushes&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on multiple fronts, including in the regions it claimed to annex - Kherson, Zaporizhzhia, Luhansk and Donetsk, where the embattled strategic city of Pokrovsk is - as well as in the northern Kharkiv region. Experts warn Putin’s ambitions go far beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We've got Putin on the other side of it and the reality is he has not taken one single step towards a temporary ceasefire or a peace deal whatsoever,” General Jack Keane (Ret.), who served as Vice Chief of Staff of the U.S. Army and is a trusted advisor to President Donald Trump, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fox News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “Where he is, he still believes that eventually he's going to break the will and resolve of the United States and the Europeans and the Zelensky government and he will eventually have his way here,” Keane said, adding that Putin’s ultimate war goal is to “topple the government of Ukraine and expand into Eastern Europe.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Tested Playbook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia has long used the pretense of openness to negotiations as a tool to deceive, delay, and fracture Western support for those Moscow is targeting. The pattern was visible in Georgia in 2008 and again in Crimea in 2014, when Moscow signaled willingness to talk even as it consolidated military gains on the ground, buying time and weakening Western responses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I always use the example of Syria during the Civil War when they [Russian forces] were killing members of the Syrian opposition while they were drinking wine and coffee with American and European interlocutors in Europe, claiming that they were trying to find an agreement,” Corn told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, behind any Russian statement of openness to engagement and dialogue, Putin has continued to assert that Ukraine is part of Russia, that the government of Zelensky is illegitimate, and that Russian forces can achieve victory on the battlefield to justify his stonewalling — despite mounting costs for Russia and limited territorial gains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;“Putin’s strategy has been consistent: advance &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-narratives-ukraine&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;false narratives&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; adopt a non-negotiable maximalist position and make ever-increasing demands for concessions; take deliberate actions to erode U.S., Ukrainian, and NATO resolve and perceived options; employ implicit and explicit threats and intimidation; and offer false choices,” former CIA Senior Executive Dave Pitts&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Taken together, these represent Russian ‘reflexive control’—a subset of cognitive warfare and a strategy designed to persuade adversaries to voluntarily adopt outcomes favorable to Russia,” Pitts told us. “In the face of unreasonable sovereignty and territorial demands placed on Ukraine and none placed on Russia, an emboldened and confident Putin will now likely demand even more.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Hesitant West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How did we get here? Some experts say a long-running pattern of Western hesitation in keeping Russia in check has emboldened Moscow. It’s not hard to remember that at the start of the full-scale invasion, Western countries were slow to provide full military support to Ukraine, concerned about a possible wider escalation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Retired General Philip Breedlove, former NATO Supreme Allied Commander, told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/breedlove-middle-east-ukraine-authoritarians&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “We have taken precious little action to stop the fight in Ukraine and we still find ourselves saying, ‘We're not going to do that because we've got to give peace a chance and we don't want to escalate the problem.’ And that formula is not working now and has not worked for 11 years.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have virtually enabled the Russian war on Ukraine by our lack of action in a more severe way. Many of us from military backgrounds say that we have built sanctuary for Russia. From that sanctuary, we allow them to attack Ukraine.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts warn that while the goal should be, as President Donald Trump has said, “to stop the killing,” awarding concessions to a Kremlin that has yet to drop its maximalist war aims is not the solution. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Trump Administration’s desire to end the violence in Ukraine is commendable, but not at the price of setting the stage for the next war by giving victory to the aggressor,” Dannenberg told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-peace-deal&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Road Ahead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With peace talks ongoing, it is proving difficult to come up with a deal that does not force Ukraine to give too much while ensuring the proposal does not push Russia to reject the deal outright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But beyond the negotiating table, experts say there are ways to pressure Putin to peace. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine is not waiting, continuing strikes on Russian energy infrastructure to curb energy export revenues that fund Moscow’s war machine, and bringing the cost of the war back to ordinary Russians. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the U.S. and Europe, major sanctions on Russia - including new measures against &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/do-oil-sanctions-still-work&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Russian oil giants&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Rosneft and Lukoil - are already in place and reportedly starting to take their toll, but experts say stronger enforcement is needed to make them truly bite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maintaining military aid to Ukraine is also essential. In mid-December, Congress passed a defense bill that authorizes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/legal/government/us-congress-passes-massive-defense-bill-that-includes-support-ukraine-europe-2025-12-17/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;$800 million for Ukraine&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - $400 million in each of the next two years - as part of the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative, which pays U.S. companies to produce weapons for Ukraine's military. President Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/dec/18/trump-ndaa-military-spending&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;signed the measure into law&lt;/a&gt; on December 18. Meanwhile, while Europeans failed to agree to use frozen Russian assets to back a loan for Ukraine, the EU agreed to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2025/12/23/exclusive-how-the-deal-to-get-ukraine-a-90-billion-eu-loan-was-sealed&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;90 billion euro loan&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; over the next two years, backed by the bloc’s budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Trump Administration should demonstrate its displeasure at Russia’s clear disregard for any so-called peace process by fully enforcing all existing sanctions, providing Ukraine with long-range weapons, and declaring that peace negotiations are suspended until Russia demonstrates it is serious about these negotiations,&quot; General Ben Hodges, former Commanding General of U.S. Army Europe, told &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. &quot;Otherwise, the President’s efforts and those of his negotiators are clearly a waste of time and headed nowhere.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;European countries have also fortified post-war pledges to Ukraine. Britain and France have committed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c17zee20qpzo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sending troops&lt;/a&gt; to a peacekeeping mission -- if a peace deal is reached. Experts U.S. intelligence, command and control, and logistics support is needed to give any European effort credibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impact will be felt far beyond Ukraine, and long after the guns there go silent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“For the United States, the best outcome will come from taking the longer, harder road that denies any reward for Russia’s illegal invasion, forces Putin to make reasonable concessions, and sustains the long-term sovereignty and independence of Ukraine,” Pitts said. “That longer, harder road also leads to stronger U.S. national security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vladimir Putin also appeared to reject any progress in ceasefire discussions. “The strategic initiative is completely &lt;a href=&quot;https://semafor.com/s/o4pNCpPAYG?email=emasucol@thecipherbrief.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;in the hands of the Russian forces,&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cut&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Putin said that Russia is facing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyivindependent.com/putin-admits-russia-faces-gas-shortage-amid-ukraines-strikes-on-energy-infrastructure/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;gas shortage&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While he did not say why, the comment notably came amid Ukraine’s campaign to target Russian refineries, pipelines and other energy infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In what could be seen as tacit support for Ukraine’s tactic, the Trump administration recently approved an $825 million sale of extended-range missiles to Ukraine. The State Department said this includes 3,350 &lt;a href=&quot;https://aviationweek.com/defense/missile-defense-weapons/us-innovation-hurries-new-cruise-missile-ukraine&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;ERAM missiles&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which have a range of 250 miles, and 3,350 GPS units, missile containers, and other necessary equipment. The package is funded via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nato.int/cps/en/natohq/news_237131.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;financing&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from Denmark, the Netherlands, and Norway, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/ukraine-us-weapons-sale-trump-russia-74e01123c0067d5fc160141e0cabf207&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;some help&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from U.S. foreign military financing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Europe, there is stalwart support for Ukraine, with around 26 countries of the so-called Coalition of the Willing committing last week to sending troops to Ukraine or training the Ukrainian military to help guarantee Ukraine’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-witkoff-europe-61ae60275a00cb442c743181df13b785&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;postwar security&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, of course, there is the option for the U.S. to act on its threat of sanctions if Russia does not move to an equitable peace deal. President Trump said on Sunday he is ready to move to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/trump-ready-phase-two-russia-sanctions-over-ukraine-conflict-2025-09-07/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;second phase&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of sanctions on Russia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The U.S. President has threatened Russia with ‘crushing’ sanctions. But Putin played ‘rope-a-dope’ and instead got a summit and postponement of sanctions for his efforts,” Dannenberg said. “President Trump has now set another deadline. The time for deadlines is over. It is time for action. … Let Ukraine take the war to the Russian Federation and make it visible to the people of Russia what is happening. If Putin doesn’t like it, let him end the war and withdraw from Ukrainian territory.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “Such killings now, when real diplomacy could have already begun long ago, are a deliberate crime and a prolongation of the war,” Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said in a post on social media after the latest Kyiv strike.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mounting Frustration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;President Trump has expressed frustration with this charade from the Kremlin, especially given his investment in efforts to broker a peace deal. The U.S. President has complained that he is “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/world/russias-largest-drone-attack-yet-hits-ukraine-government-building-4e3e46d4?gaa_at=eafs&amp;amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAgmZUuKDUlv7RNaF5WdtLC5o3pi80OQ7eE_4JFmCs9sizo496xuhQTnrl92Ogs%3D&amp;amp;gaa_ts=68bdb7fb&amp;amp;gaa_sig=thIkQFWy26_u46aZW3ZQ6ovaIk1DwWYgJP2soa4mnbhmTcojk1NYSoRt7VhZG7uYcrEFQd9yaKJs3uYonpEWkQ%3D%3D&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;very disappointed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;” in Putin since he “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/video/trump-says-putin-talks-nice-and-then-he-bombs-everybody-b085000bd3bb4847837a5349204a7315&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;talks nice and then he bombs everybody&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;After the August 28 strikes on Kyiv, White House press secretary &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Karoline Leavitt &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;said Trump “was &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/trump-shrugs-off-russias-assault-on-kyiv-and-europes-outrage-00534585&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;not happy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; about this move, but he was also not surprised.” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leavitt noted: “These are two countries that have been at war for a very long time. Russia launched this attack on Kyiv, and likewise, Ukraine recently dealt a blow to Russia’s oil refineries.” That was in reference to the recent spate of Ukrainian drone attacks at Russian &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/27/frustrated-russians-grapple-with-fuel-crisis-as-ukraine-attacks-oil-refineries&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;oil and gas infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The difference there, experts say, is that Ukraine is targeting energy infrastructure to curb the revenues of Russia’s energy exports, which fuel its war machine. Russia has been striking Ukrainian infrastructure throughout the war, in addition to bombing Ukrainian civilians.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia on Sunday struck Ukraine with the largest aerial assault of the war so far. Ukraine’s air force said Russia launched over 800 drones and fired 13 missiles in the attack, marking the most drones used against Ukraine in a single night. The bombardment killed at least five people across Ukraine and struck a landmark government building in Kyiv, Ukraine’s Cabinet of Ministers, for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This attack is just the latest in a series of Russian assaults. On August 28, Russian drones and missiles &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-kyiv-attack-23e051f1b7e93308f99b6fdfdd8949f2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;leveled a residential tower&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg3y7m2gz0o&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;damaged European Union diplomatic offices&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Kyiv. Attacks in previous days destroyed &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyivindependent.com/explosions-rock-ukrainian-cities-as-russia-again-launches-large-scale-attack/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;energy infrastructure&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; across Ukraine. Meanwhile, Russia has pushed further on the frontlines, entering the central Dnipropetrovsk region for the first time in the war. Russian Defense Minister &lt;strong&gt;Andrei Belousov &lt;/strong&gt;claimed that the Russian army has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-defence-minister-says-his-forces-have-sped-up-rate-their-advance-ukraine-2025-08-29/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;accelerated its rate of advance&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The relentless assault is nothing new to Ukraine, but what makes the most recent attacks stand out is that they come amid a major U.S. and European push for peace. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On August 16, President Trump hosted Putin in Alaska to discuss how to end the fighting. Some analysts described this as the best opportunity the Russian leader had for a diplomatic offramp. Putin instead chose not to budge from his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/china/putins-demand-ukraine-give-up-donbas-no-nato-no-western-troops-sources-say-2025-08-21/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;maximalist demands&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about Ukrainian sovereignty and territory and even floated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/china/russias-lavrov-outlines-terms-ukraine-peace-big-power-security-guarantee-no-nato-2025-08-24/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;post-war scenarios&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which are unacceptable to Kyiv, such as having &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/china/russias-lavrov-outlines-terms-ukraine-peace-big-power-security-guarantee-no-nato-2025-08-24/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Russia be a security guarantor&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Putin continues to pound Ukraine. “At best he is ‘softening up’ the Ukrainian people so that they will be increasingly eager for a settlement - any settlement - to the war,” &lt;strong&gt;Ralph Goff&lt;/strong&gt;, a former six-time CIA station chief, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “At worst he is firmly set on destroying Ukraine militarily, economically and politically no matter the cost.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent attacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;August 20-21: &lt;a href=&quot;https://understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-august-21-2025&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Russia launched third largest strike of the war&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;574 drones, 6 ballistic missiles, 33 cruise missiles&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine downed 546 drones, 1 ballistic missile, and 30 cruise missiles&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;11 locations were struck, many in western Ukraine including the U.S. electronics manufacturer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-zelenskyy-putin-trump-security-92ee89feba2224f140429bcb573e61f9&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;At least one killed, dozens injured&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strike was likely planned for some time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;August 26-27: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-august-27-2025&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Russia targets energy infrastructure&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;95 drones launched, 74 drones downed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;9 locations across northern, eastern, and southern Ukraine hit&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Caused power outages for more than 100,000 households&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Part of a larger campaign to degrade Ukrainian energy infrastructure ahead of Winter&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;August 28: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-kyiv-attack-23e051f1b7e93308f99b6fdfdd8949f2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Kyiv is struck&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;598 drones, 33 missiles&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;At least 21 killed, 48 wounded at 33 different locations across the city&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;European Union Mission to Ukraine facility &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/28/world/europe/ukraine-russia-strikes.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;damaged&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;British Council facility severely damaged&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;That Kyiv strike drew widespread outrage in particular.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The continued attacks even amid the peace proces show insincerity of pUtin in talks. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump too has recognized this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump “was not happy about this move, but he was also not surprised,” Leavitt said, reiterating that the president wants the bloodshed to stop but blamed both countries for the lack of progress in negotiations. “These are two countries that have been at war for a very long time. Russia launched this attack on Kyiv, and likewise, Ukraine recently dealt a blow to Russia’s oil refineries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/trump-shrugs-off-russias-assault-on-kyiv-and-europes-outrage-00534585?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/28/trump-shrugs-off-russias-assault-on-kyiv-and-europes-outrage-00534585?utm_source=chatgpt.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump “expressed frustration over the lack of progress in negotiating peace between Ukraine and Russia, signaling he will pause his involvement in the peace effort.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/08/23/trump-ukraine-frustration/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/08/23/trump-ukraine-frustration/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump noted frustration over Putin’s “friendly discussions followed by aggressive military actions,” and warned of “very big consequences” if a peace effort fails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2025/08/25/us-news/trump-claims-good-conversation-with-putin-since-monday-talks-but-no-details-on-ukraine-meeting-as-russia-keeps-striking/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://nypost.com/2025/08/25/us-news/trump-claims-good-conversation-with-putin-since-monday-talks-but-no-details-on-ukraine-meeting-as-russia-keeps-striking/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Going to be bad for Russia... …if Putin doesn't agree to Ukraine talks; says ‘very serious what I have in mind’&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-08-26/trump-warns-of-economic-war-if-putin-doesn-t-pursue-peace?embedded-checkout=true&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-08-26/trump-warns-of-economic-war-if-putin-doesn-t-pursue-peace?embedded-checkout=true&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump complained last month that Russian President Vladimir Putin “ talks nice and then he bombs everybody.” But the latest attack on Kyiv drew no public condemnation from the Trump administration, with White House press secretary Karoline Leavitt noting that Ukraine has been striking Russian oil refineries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-attack-putin-trump-47e0fa10cded79063cf8cb9db7a2bcb7&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-attack-putin-trump-47e0fa10cded79063cf8cb9db7a2bcb7&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EXperts agree:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROB DANNENBERG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Putin has never been sincere about a negotiated solution to his Special Military Operation. He considers Ukraine part of Russia and Zelensky illegitimate. So with whom should he negotiate in his mind? Putin is even less inclined to negotiate since he has come to believe (incorrectly in my view) that he can win the war militarily. He allows the pretense of negotiation to create confusion and distraction in supporters of Ukraine in the West. Thereby, delaying military and economic support for Ukraine. By and large this strategy has worked thus far. Anchorage and its aftermath should have provided clarity that Putin is insincere about negotiations with Ukraine. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RALPH GOFF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The increased intensity of Russia strikes on cities across Ukraine - the Ukrainians recorded nearly 600 drones and 31 missiles of various types during the night of 27-28 August - clearly indicate Vladimir Putin has no real interest in agreeing to a ceasefire at present. Meanwhile, Russian ground forces literally inching their way forward in numerous sectors of the front- albeit at tremendous human cost - reportedly now of over 1,000,000 Russian soldiers killed, captured or seriously wounded ( by comparison around 15,000 Soviet Soldiers were killed in a decade of war in Afghanistan) - clearly indicate that Putin is not overly concerned with losses to Russia. Thus, it's hard to predict where Putin is going with this. At best he is &quot; softening up&quot; the Ukrainian people so that they will be increasingly eager for a settlement - any settlement - to the war. At worst he is firmly set on destroying Ukraine militarily, economically and politically no matter the cost. Meanwhile, neither the US administration nor our European Allies have developed and presented a cogent strategy for either continuing the war or seeking an armistice. Putin, who has never really been held accountable by any US administration or by the Europeans , has no real reason to stop at this time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GLEN CORN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They will continue to launch strikes, try and take territory while they're going to a negotiation negotiating table. So they've done that. The tactic they've used in the past, and I always use the example of Syria during the Civil War when they were killing members of the Syrian opposition while they were drinking wine and coffee with American and European interlocutors in Europe, claiming that they were trying to find an agreement.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Damage to Ukraine:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The United Nations currently estimates that as of 31 December 2024, the total cost of reconstruction and recovery in Ukraine is $524 billion (€506 billion) over the next decade, which is approximately 2.8 times the estimated nominal GDP of Ukraine for 2024.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2025/02/25/updated-ukraine-recovery-and-reconstruction-needs-assessment-released?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2025/02/25/updated-ukraine-recovery-and-reconstruction-needs-assessment-released?utm_source=chatgpt.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jul/10/concern-ukraine-will-be-split-up-reconstruction-talks?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jul/10/concern-ukraine-will-be-split-up-reconstruction-talks?utm_source=chatgpt.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More than three years into Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, the war has already inflicted over $175 billion in direct damage to the country’s buildings and infrastructure, according to the latest estimates from the World Bank. This marks a $23 billion increase in damage compared to the previous year’s assessment. The data comes from the fourth Ukraine Rapid Damage and Needs Assessment (RDNA4), which covers the period from February 24, 2022, to December 31, 2024.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/chart/34614/estimated-cost-of-direct-war-damage-in-ukraine/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;https://www.statista.com/chart/34614/estimated-cost-of-direct-war-damage-in-ukraine/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part of problem: Western inaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breedlove&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remain deterred. In the press you hear people talking about this war being three and a half years long. This war is over 11 years long. It started in the spring of '14 when I was still serving as the Supreme Allied Commander of Europe, and it hasn't stopped. It was hot for a few years and then it went warm. Russians were killing Ukrainians and Ukrainians were killing Russians on the line of contact. And then, after some six years or so of that warm war on the line of contact, Russia re-invaded, and I call this the third phase of the 11-year-long war.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This war has covered four presidents, Obama, Trump twice and Biden once, and all four of them have been nearly and completely deterred from the very beginning. We, as we always do in the military, offered options for how to address this conflict in Ukraine back in 2014. And the answer was, &quot;We're not going to take any action because the war will escalate if we take action.&quot; Well, we gave them options from very small movements to larger more bellicose movements, they chose none of them and here we are. What we do know is we did not take action for fear of escalation. We were deterred and we didn't take action and Russia escalated anyway. And so our lack of action ended up in the escalation of the problem by the Russians. And that has repeated itself through four administrations for the past 11 years. We are still deterred. We have taken precious little action to stop the fight in Ukraine and we still find ourselves saying, &quot;We're not going to do that because we've got to give peace a chance and we don't want to escalate the problem.&quot; And that formula is not working now and has not worked for 11 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have virtually enabled the Russian war on Ukraine by our lack of action in a more severe way. Many of us from military backgrounds say that we have built sanctuary for Russia. From that sanctuary, we allow them to attack Ukraine. If you can think of a map, up in the northwest corner of the map is Belarus all the way to the east around through Russia all the way to the south, into the Black Sea and west across the Black Sea. We have allowed Russia to attack Ukraine from nearly 300 degrees on the map, and we still cannot determine that we should allow Ukraine to fire back deeply into Russia with our kit.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution: pressure on Russia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CORN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;““So what does this mean for the US and for Europe? I think this now, it's just a sign that, I mean, I've said this before, I've written it. I give President Trump a lot of credit for trying to find a solution for this very serious problem. But I think now is the time where the only thing that Putin is going to understand, and the only way that he will stop doing what he's doing is if he feels pain.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“He understands that there is a serious consequence for him and the people around him for what he is doing, and the only thing that's going to make him be anything close to sincere is when he understands that he's dealing with interlocutors that are very serious and that are willing to stand up and respond forcefully for this type of aggressive action, which is insulting to those people, including our president, who have tried to negotiate a ceasefire and a peace agreement.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctions, ukraine air defenses, kick out children of russian oligarchs studying in us, london, paris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DANNENBERG:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The U.S. President has threatened Russia with “crushing” sanctions. But Putin played “rope-a-dope” and instead got a summit and postponement of sanctions for his efforts. President Trump has now set another deadline. The time for deadlines is over. It is time for action. The only path that has not been tried (but has only been threatened) is to put maximum pressure on Putin and the Russian Federation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s how we get there: first, the President should immediately authorize the advancement of pending legislation in the U.S. Congress on sanctions on Russia and purchasers of Russian hydrocarbon products.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, the President should use his authority to advance the sale or “lend lease” of military support for Ukraine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third, the U.S. should remove any restrictions on Ukrainian use of weapons systems already provided or already committed to help Ukraine defend itself. Let Ukraine take the war to the Russian Federation and make it visible to the people of Russia what is happening. If Putin doesn’t like it, let him end the war and withdraw from Ukrainian territory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And fourth, the U.S. should restore maximum diplomatic isolation of Russia and publicly call out Russia as the aggressor in this conflict.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this context, the success President Trump had ending the Armenia-Azerbaijan conflict should be leveraged to reduce Russian influence in the Republic of Georgia, long a bastion of pro-U.S. sentiment but recently put under a cloud of Russian interference.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let the loss of influence in the Caucasus be added to the list of Putin’s strategic failures. Put it on the list right next to Finland and Sweden joining NATO.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctions alone won’t influence Putin, but sanctions, renewed military and financial support for Ukraine, renewed diplomatic isolation, and strategic leverage on Russia’s periphery might.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The path ahead should be clear to the U.S. President, who must now know that he can’t trust Putin. The Russian president is the enemy of the U.S. in every fiber of his being and it’s time for him to pay the price of his folly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breedlove&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanctions have never changed Putin's actions on the battlefield. Sanctions have hurt Russia. Sanctions have hurt the Russian people. Sanctions have hurt the Russian economy. All those things are true, but they have never changed Russian actions on the battlefield. And so, we either need to double and triple the really crushing sanctions and take all of the frozen Russian money and use it to help Ukraine. We've got to physically stop the Russian shadow fleet from moving oil around the world. There's a whole host of things we could do that would truly bring Russia to their knees and we haven't done it.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note on security guarantees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breedlove: “It's a confusing issue about what America is going to do or not do in any possible peace-enforcement capacity. The best move right now, not under a NATO hat, because clearly, Mr. Putin believes he's in charge and he said there will be no NATO involvement, but if NATO or European Union nations were to volunteer for a coalition of the willing presence in Ukraine, then that's what, I think, needs to happen. We need the big nations- the UK, the French, the Germans, to step up but they're waiting and watching for American leadership. Is America going to be that backbone and offer what the president talked about in his post-talk news conference and so forth? We need for all of that to happen. We need for America to make a decision to supply air power, command and control, intelligence, surveillance, reconnaissance, et cetera, those non-boots on the ground capabilities. And then, we need the European nations who've already intimated they may be willing to provide boots on the ground to get in there and get a stoppage of the fighting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr. Putin’s entire objective however is to keep kicking the can to the right, run right up to the red line, wave a bright shiny object, get another red line, run right up to the red line, wave another shiny object, get another deadline. He is very good and has had great success at moving our red lines to the right.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FROM THE UKRAINIAN EMBASSY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the night of August 28 (starting from 19:30 on August 27), the enemy launched a massive strike on the territory of Ukraine using attack UAVs, air-launched and ground-launched missiles – a total of &lt;strong&gt;629 aerial attack assets&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;598 Shahed-type attack UAVs&lt;/strong&gt; and decoy drones of various types launched from Kursk, Bryansk, Millerovo, Orel, Shatalovo, Primorsko-Akhtarsk (Russia), and Hvardiiske (temporarily occupied Crimea);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Kh-47M2 &quot;Kinzhal&quot; aero-ballistic missiles&lt;/strong&gt; from the airspace of Lipetsk and Voronezh regions (Russia);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9 Iskander-M/KN-23 ballistic missiles&lt;/strong&gt; from Bryansk and Voronezh regions (Russia);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 Kh-101 cruise missiles&lt;/strong&gt; from the airspace of Saratov region (Russia).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;main target of the Russian strike was Kyiv&lt;/strong&gt;, where the majority of drones and missiles were directed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Odesa region, due to missile threats and the “transit” flight of Shahed groups, the first air raid alert lasted from &lt;strong&gt;23:00 to 01:18&lt;/strong&gt;. The second alert was from &lt;strong&gt;03:52 to 06:02&lt;/strong&gt; – exactly when the Russians launched aero-ballistic, ballistic, and cruise missiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to preliminary data, as of 09:00, Ukrainian air defense forces shot down/suppressed &lt;strong&gt;589 aerial targets&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;563 Shahed-type UAVs&lt;/strong&gt; and decoy drones of various types;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Kh-47M2 &quot;Kinzhal&quot; aero-ballistic missile&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 Iskander-M/KN-23 ballistic missiles&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 Kh-101 cruise missiles&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall effectiveness of air defense is estimated at &lt;strong&gt;approximately 93%&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Against Shaheds – &lt;strong&gt;94%&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Overall against missiles – &lt;strong&gt;83%&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Against cruise missiles – &lt;strong&gt;90%&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Against ballistic and aero-ballistic missiles – &lt;strong&gt;72%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;President of Ukraine Volodymyr Zelenskyy on “X”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, as our people are dealing with the consequences of one of the most large-scale Russian terrorist attacks, we see yet another attempt by Hungarian officials to portray black as white and to shift the blame for the ongoing war onto Ukraine. In Ukraine, we responded positively to all proposals from the world regarding a ceasefire and real diplomacy, and the only one who rebuffed them was Russia. Unfortunately, there has still been no fair reaction from Hungary to such behavior by Russia. Nor has there even been sympathy expressed over the deaths of our people – just last night alone, in Kyiv, Russian drones and missiles took the lives of 17 people, including 4 children. Yet every day we hear new accusations against Ukraine coming from Hungary. Hungarian officials have gone so far as to attempt to discriminate against members of the Hungarian community in Ukraine for their participation in the defense of our state and our people. If Hungary has indeed closed entry into Hungary and the entire Schengen zone to one of Ukraine’s military commanders, who is an ethnic Hungarian and a citizen of Ukraine, this can only cause outrage. I have instructed the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Ukraine to clarify all the facts and respond accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1961047854639935814&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1961047854639935814&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right now in Kyiv, first responders are clearing the rubble of an ordinary residential building after a Russian strike. Another massive attack against our cities and communities. Killings again. Tragically, at least 8 people have already been confirmed dead. One of them is a child. My condolences to all their families and loved ones. People may still be trapped under the rubble. Dozens are wounded. These Russian missiles and attack drones today are a clear response to everyone in the world who, for weeks and months, has been calling for a ceasefire and for real diplomacy. Russia chooses ballistics instead of the negotiating table. It chooses to continue killing instead of ending the war. And this means that Russia still does not fear the consequences. Russia still takes advantage of the fact that at least part of the world turns a blind eye to murdered children and seeks excuses for Putin. We expect a reaction from China to what is going on. China has repeatedly called for not expanding the war and for a ceasefire. Yet this is not happening because of Russia. We expect a reaction from Hungary. The death of children should definitely stir far greater emotions than anything else. We expect a response from everyone in the world who has called for peace but now more often stays silent rather than taking principled positions. And it is definitely time for new, tough sanctions against Russia for everything it is doing. All deadlines have already been broken, dozens of opportunities for diplomacy ruined. Russia must feel accountable for every strike, for every day of this war. Eternal memory to all victims of Russia!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1960934028321685907&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1960934028321685907&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prime minister of Ukraine Yulia Svyrydenko on “X”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of now, already 14 people are known to have been killed as a result of the Russian attack, including 3 children. The horrific and deliberate killing of civilians, again. The Russians are not choosing to end the war, only constant expansion of atrocities. Overnight in Kyiv, dozens of buildings were hit: residential houses, office centers, civilian enterprises. Among them also the building where the European Union Delegation to Ukraine is located. Russians now believe that they have paralyzed Ukraine's allies with feigned plans for &quot;negotiations&quot; and endless delays that only serve as methods to buy time with the true goal only of preventing sanctions. It is crucial now that the world responds firmly. Russia must be stopped. New and stronger sanctions are needed. The Russians understand only strength and pressure. For every strike, Moscow must feel the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Svyrydenko_Y/status/1960995612989563198&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/Svyrydenko_Y/status/1960995612989563198&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/u&gt;There are currently over 500 rescue workers and 1,000 police officers engaged in rescue efforts across Kyiv in the aftermath of yet another brutal Russian missile and drone attack on our capital city. With the possibility that the death toll may still rise, there are already at least 8 confirmed dead – among them 1 kid – and dozens injured after an assault that lasted more than nine hours. Russians targeted residential buildings, shopping areas, a school: purely civilian targets. Russia has merely used the good intentions of Ukraine's allies to buy more time, to expand the killing – simply mass murder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Svyrydenko_Y/status/1960936422937858118&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/Svyrydenko_Y/status/1960936422937858118&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minister of Foreign Affairs of Ukraine Andrii Sybiha on “X”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the barbaric Russian strike on the Ukrainian capital, it was important to visit, together with heads of 55 foreign diplomatic missions, the site of one of the strikes, a ruined residential building in the Darnytskyi district. This is a site of a horrible war crime. At least 14 innocent civilians were killed by Russian terrorists here, including four children. One of the kids was born under Russian strikes in 2022 and killed by the Russian strike this morning. I am grateful to my colleague, Minister of Internal Affairs Igor Klymenko, who briefed foreign diplomats on the casualties and recovery efforts. It is critical that the world sees Russian terror and takes action to stop this barbarism. I thank all foreign diplomats who joined us today in commemorating the victims of Russian strikes. Russia is a terrorist state. We count on strong international responses and action to increase pressure on Russia, including new tough sanctions, and strengthen support for Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/andrii_sybiha/status/1961010371046834689&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/andrii_sybiha/status/1961010371046834689&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We insist on strong international reactions to Russia’s brutal strike on Kyiv and other cities. Russia killed at least 8 people, including a child, and targeted civilian infrastructure. Whatever Putin said in Alaska, his real actions reject diplomacy, dialogue, and peace efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/andrii_sybiha/status/1960945855780765705&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/andrii_sybiha/status/1960945855780765705&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a residential home in Kyiv ruined by Russia. People may still be under the rubble. This horrific sight proves that Putin will only stop when faced with pressure and strength. We urge public condemnation and action: new sanctions on Russia and strengthening for Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/andrii_sybiha/status/1960945881366098006&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/andrii_sybiha/status/1960945881366098006&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Head of the Office of the President of Ukraine Andriy Yermak on “X”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything you need to know about the terrorist state, Putin, and their so-called “desire” for peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/AndriyYermak/status/1960894814313992619&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/AndriyYermak/status/1960894814313992619&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kyiv city center. Ordinary residential buildings were damaged as a result of a Russian attack on the city. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/AndriyYermak/status/1960981276703236533&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/AndriyYermak/status/1960981276703236533&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Kyiv, Russia has already killed 15 people, including 4 children. &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/AndriyYermak/status/1961014915176505695&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/AndriyYermak/status/1961014915176505695&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of the UCCRO on the latest Russian terrorist attacks against Ukrainian cities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the night of August 27–28, 2025, the Russian state once again launched terrorist attacks against the cities of Kyiv, Zaporizhzhia, and other Ukrainian towns. As a result of missile and drone strikes, civilians — including children — were killed and wounded. Residential buildings and civilian infrastructure, including a kindergarten, were destroyed or damaged; hundreds of people lost their homes, and thousands of Ukrainians endured the terror of nighttime assaults.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dictatorial Russian regime has once again exposed its inhumane nature and its criminal, genocidal policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We strongly condemn the latest terrorist attacks carried out by the Russian Federation against Ukrainian cities and villages, which once again confirm its nature as a terrorist state. Any support now extended to the Russian Federation is, in fact, support for murderers and criminals, and carries with it undeniable moral responsibility. Money earned through business with Russia today is stained with the blood of innocent victims, and that blood cries out to Heaven for just retribution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We extend our deepest condolences to the families of the victims and pray for all those who have suffered at the hands of Russian terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also take this opportunity to express our profound gratitude to all religious leaders, believers of different denominations, and people of goodwill for their unwavering support of the Ukrainian people, for their prayers for an end to Russian military aggression, and for their commitment to the establishment of a just and lasting peace for Ukraine and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vrciro.ua/en/statements/statement-by-the-ukrainian-council-of-churches-and-religious-organizations-on-the-latest-russian-terrorist-attacks-against-ukrainian-cities&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://vrciro.ua/en/statements/statement-by-the-ukrainian-council-of-churches-and-religious-organizations-on-the-latest-russian-terrorist-attacks-against-ukrainian-cities&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNITED24 Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;«Russian forces deliberately targeted a residential building with a &quot;doube-tap&quot; strike during the latest attack, CCTV footage shows. After the first missle struck, moments later a second one hit the same building.» &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/United24media/status/1960954631049089344&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/United24media/status/1960954631049089344&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ukrainian railways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results of the overnight Russian attack. This train was supposed to depart today to take passengers to Kharkiv. &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Ukrzaliznytsia/status/1960991006381195299&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://x.com/Ukrzaliznytsia/status/1960991006381195299&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is Putin Silent on Venezuela?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-putin-thinks-of-the-us-operation-in-venezuela-by-nina-l-khrushcheva-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Russian President Vladimir Putin certainly does not relish appearing weak, nor does he want to risk exacerbating tensions with the US. But his willingness to be pushed around has its limits, and it is entirely possible that Donald Trump's administration will prove pushy enough to find out what those limits are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s State Capitalism, by the Numbers</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/trump-state-capitalism-equity-stakes-list-companies/</link>
      <description>The companies and sectors where the U.S. president has taken a government stake.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spain’s judiciary is caught up in a bitter political war</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/14/spains-judiciary-is-caught-up-in-a-bitter-political-war</link>
      <description>The government decries charges of corruption as “lawfare”</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Strategy Behind Trump’s Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/trump-western-hemisphere-national-security-strategy-geopolitics-china-russia-venezuela-greenland-spheres-of-influence/</link>
      <description>Ignore the critics. The logic of consolidation that defines the new National Security Strategy is eminently sensible.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With Its New Laws, Australia’s Government Is Tackling Hate Speech Quickly, But Not Properly</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/with-its-new-laws-australias-government-is-tackling-hate-speech-quickly-but-not-properly/</link>
      <description>In its rush to respond to the Bondi terrorist attack, the government risks entrenching legislation that raises more questions than it answers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s Use of Transnational Repression to Crush Dissent</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/pakistans-use-of-transnational-repression-to-crush-dissent/</link>
      <description>The Pakistani state and its powerful military establishment have resorted to increasingly drastic measures to deter critics from voicing their opposition, wherever they may be in the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Greenland discussions; Russian sabotage in Europe; ‘Ideological tuning’ in DOD AI; Some leave Al Udeid; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-14-2026/410674/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dangerous Fallout of Trump’s Retreat to the Hemisphere</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/trump-western-hemisphere-venezuela-greenland-national-security-strategy-geopolitics-russia-china/</link>
      <description>The revolution in U.S. foreign policy will lead to a much less stable world.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As the US Turns Transactional, the EU Has a Critical Role in Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/as-the-us-turns-transactional-the-eu-has-a-critical-role-in-myanmar/</link>
      <description>The European Union now stands as the only major international actor still meaningfully committed to Myanmar’s democratic opposition.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Gangster’s-Eye View of Global Power</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-donroe-doctrine-fuels-instability-and-jeopardizes-global-economy-by-jayati-ghosh-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the heart of US President Donald Trump’s foreign policy is the belief that the world can be carved up among major powers, with the United States free to act with impunity in its “backyard.” In reality, this approach is bound to fuel instability, fracture markets, and undermine America’s economic interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World Minus One Will Be a Mess</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/world-minus-one-trump-multilateralism-united-nations-treaties/</link>
      <description>Multilateral cooperation will struggle to survive in Washington’s absence.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Japan’s Largest Opposition Party Complete Its Rightward Shift?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/can-japans-largest-opposition-party-complete-its-rightward-shift/</link>
      <description>The Constitutional Democratic Party is seeking moderation to stay alive. But it may be too late.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Blueprint for Cambodia-Thailand Peace: A Cambodian Perspective</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/a-blueprint-for-cambodia-thailand-peace-a-cambodian-perspective/</link>
      <description>A Cambodian scholar offers recommendation on how to build a lasting peace between Cambodia and Thailand.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Blueprint for Cambodia-Thailand Peace: A Thai Perspective</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/a-blueprint-for-cambodia-thailand-peace-a-thai-perspective/</link>
      <description>A Thai scholar offers recommendation on how to build a lasting peace between Cambodia and Thailand.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korean Special Prosecutor Seeks Death Penalty for Yoon Suk-yeol</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/south-korean-special-prosecutor-seeks-death-penalty-for-yoon-suk-yeol/</link>
      <description>More than a year after his illegitimate declaration of martial law, the former president is now facing a death sentence for insurrection.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Two Largest Economies Should Slow Their Investment Race</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-quest-for-technological-supremacy-clashes-with-other-economic-goals-by-moreno-bertoldi-and-marco-buti-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States and China are locked in a race for technological dominance, fueled by unprecedented investment. But this quest clashes with other economic objectives like lower inflation and financial stability, leaving both economies exposed to domestic pressures and global spillovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Labeling Muslim Brotherhood “Chapters” as Terrorist Groups Is Problematic</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/muslim-brotherhood-terrorist-designation-problematic</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;The White House this past November issued a Presidential action statement designating certain Muslim Brotherhood “chapters” as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/11/designation-of-certain-muslim-brotherhood-chapters-as-foreign-terrorist-organizations-and-specially-designated-global-terrorists/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;terrorist&lt;/a&gt; organizations. On Tuesday, the U.S. State Department and U.S. Treasury Department announced the designations of the Lebanese, Jordanian, and Egyptian chapters of the Muslim Brotherhood as terrorist organizations. The Egyptian and Jordanian chapters received a Specially Designated Global Terrorist (SDGT) designation. The Lebanese chapter received both the SDGT designation and a Foreign Terrorist Organization (FTO) designation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2019, Washington, responding to mounting pressure by Egyptian President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi, decided to brand the Egyptian Muslim Brotherhood (MB) a terrorist organization. There was no mention of “chapters” outside Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having followed the MB and interviewed many of its members for years during my government service, I published an article in 2019 questioning the underlying assumptions of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lobelog.com/trumps-disastrous-plan-for-the-muslim-brotherhood/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/a&gt;. This article is a revised version of my 2019 piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I argued in the 2019 piece that the administration’s decision at the time did not reflect a deep knowledge of the origins of the Muslim Brotherhood and its connection to Muslim societies and political Islam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 2025, the leaders of the United Arab Republic, Jordan, Bahrain, and Lebanon pressured the administration to label the MB a terrorist group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian Muslim Brotherhood was founded by schoolteacher Hassan al-Banna in 1928 in response to two fundamental realities: First, Egypt was under the influence of British colonialism embodied in the massive British military presence near the Suez Canal. Second, under the influence of the pro-Western corrupt monarchy lead first by King Fuad and later by his son King Faruk, the MB’s founder believed that Muslim Egypt was drifting away from Islam. Egypt of course is the home of Al-Azhar University, the oldest Muslim academic center of learning in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Al-Azhar University represents the philosophical and theological thought of the three major Schools of Jurisprudence in Sunni Islam—the Hanafi, the Maliki, and the Shafi’i Schools. The fourth and smallest School of Jurisprudence—the Hanbali—is embodied in the Wahhabi-Salafi doctrine and is prevalent in Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Al-Banna’s two founding principles were: a) Islam is the solution to society’s ills (“&lt;em&gt;Islam hua al-Hal”&lt;/em&gt;), and b) Islam is a combination of Faith (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt;), Society (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;unya&lt;/em&gt;) and State (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;awla&lt;/em&gt;). He believed, correctly for the most part, that these principles, especially the three Arabic &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;s, underpin all Sunni Muslim societies, other than perhaps the adherents of the Hanbali School.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past 98 years, the Muslim Brotherhood has undergone different reiterations from eschewing politics to accepting the authority of Muslim rulers to declaring war against some of them to participating in the political process through elections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Certain MB thinkers and leaders over the past nine decades, including the Egyptian Sayyid Qutb, the Syrian Muhammad Surur, and the Palestinian Abdullah Azzam, adopted a radical violent view of Islamic jihad and either allied themselves with some Wahhabi clerics in Saudi Arabia or joined al-Qa’ida. The organization itself generally stayed away from violent jihad. Consequently, it would make sense to label certain leaders or certain actions as terrorist but not the entire group or the different Islamic political parties in several countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early 1990s, the Egyptian MB rejected political violence and declared its support for peaceful gradual political change through elections, and in fact participated in several national elections. While Islamic Sunni parties in different countries adopted the basic theological organizing principles of the MB on the role of Islam in society, they were not “chapters” of the MB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are free standing Islamic political groups and movements, legally registered in their countries, which often focus on economic, health, and social issues of concern to their communities. They are not tied to the MB in command, control, or operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examples of these Sunni Islamic political parties include the AKP in Turkey, the Islamic Action Front in Jordan, Justice and Development in Morocco, al-Nahda in Tunisia, the Islamic Constitutional Movement in Kuwait, the Islamic Movement (RA’AM) in Israel, PAS in Malaysia, PKS in Indonesia, the Islamic Party in Kenya, and the National Islamic Front in Sudan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During my government career, my analysts and I spent years in conversations with representatives of these parties with an eye toward helping them moderate their political positions and encouraging them to enter the mainstream political process through elections. In fact, most of them did just that. They won some elections and lost others, and in the process, they were able to recruit thousands of young members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on these conversations, we concluded that these groups were pragmatic, mainstream, and committed to the dictum that electoral politics was a process, and not “one man, one vote, one time.” Because they believed in the efficacy and value of gradual peaceful political change, they were able to convince their fellow Muslims that a winning strategy at the polls was to focus on bread-and-butter issues, including health, education, and welfare, that were of concern to their own societies. They projected to their members a moderate vision of Islam. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labeling the Muslim Brotherhood and other mainstream Sunni Islamic political parties as terrorist organizations could radicalize some of the youth in these parties and opt out of electoral politics. Some of the party leaders would become reticent to engage with American diplomats, intelligence officers, and other officials at U.S. embassies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washington inadvertently would be sending a message to Muslim youth that the democratic process and peaceful participation in electoral politics are a sham, which could damage American national security and credibility in many Muslim countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Question for India’s Budget in 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-big-question-for-indias-budget-in-2026/</link>
      <description>In 2025, India mastered economic stability, but the transition from a $4 trillion to a $5 trillion economy will not be determined by how well risks are contained.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Iran’s Popular Resistance Exposes the Taliban’s Deepest Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-irans-popular-resistance-exposes-the-talibans-deepest-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <description>The ongoing protests in Iran have the Taliban in Afghanistan worried. In Iran’s streets, the Taliban see the seeds of their own undoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel Wants Hezbollah’s Weapons by Any Means Necessary</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/14/israel-hezbollah-weapons-disarmament-resolution-1701/</link>
      <description>The Lebanese Armed Forces have made progress on disarmament—but Israel is thinking of finishing the job.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Anti-Moral Morality</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-might-makes-right-worldview-rules-out-moral-progress-by-peter-singer-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump now claims that the only thing that will stop him from doing as he pleases on the world stage is his own morality. Whether the world accepts Trump’s reversion to the unbridled dominance of great powers will determine the course of international relations for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uber Krysha: How Russia Turns Crime into Power—and Poison</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-crime-uber-krysha</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;Current discussion of Russian &quot;hybrid warfare&quot; tends to revolve around concepts like disinformation, proxy militias, cyber operations, sabotage, and psychological manipulation designed to fragment, confuse, and demoralize Russia's opponents—and the respective roles these play in Russian military and national security doctrine. Yet one essential dimension remains underdeveloped in the broader debate: the organic integration of criminal structures and methods into Russia's strategic toolkit. Russia's system does more than merely operate in a &quot;gray zone.&quot; It has become a gray state, sustained by an &quot;&lt;em&gt;Uber Krysha&lt;/em&gt;,&quot; a super-protection racket in which the Kremlin fuses its security apparatus with organized crime to project influence and intimidation both at home and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The enabling mentality behind this fusion can be directly tied to Russia's pre-revolutionary period. Although no longer ideologically communist, Russia's current ruling elite, led by President Vladimir Putin, has very much inherited the Bolsheviks' comfort with adopting criminal methods in the pursuit of regime objectives. Before 1917, Lenin's Bolshevik Party &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.labrujulaverde.com/en/2024/04/when-lenin-and-stalin-robbed-the-bank-of-tiflis-in-1907/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;financed its operations partly through armed robberies&lt;/a&gt; justified as the expropriation of bourgeois wealth for the sake of the proletarian struggle. The Bolsheviks were revolutionary in ideology but gangster in practice, rationalizing robbery and violence not as moral lapses, but as necessary transgressions—crime rebranded as virtue in the service of power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, during the early years of the USSR, the communist regime was defiantly, even boastfully, dismissive in its rejection of “bourgeois” legal norms. Its November 1918 decree &lt;em&gt;On Red Terror&lt;/em&gt; (yes, it was called that) is a good case in point. It formally authorized the secret police, the Cheka, to summarily arrest and execute perceived opponents of the revolution without trial, which it proceeded to do in the tens of thousands. In doing so, the new revolutionary state openly and unapologetically signaled to its people and to the world that it would not be bound by the ordinary moral limits of civilized life. Terror was not a regrettable excess, but a management tool. This was not moral confusion, it was moral disregard elevated to state policy, with a legacy that has left a deep imprint on the political DNA of contemporary Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even as the Soviet state engaged in its bloody ideological experiment, common criminality thrived in the workers' paradise. The inefficient Soviet economic system brought chronic scarcity, which, as it does everywhere, spawned smuggling and black-market behaviors. The state imposed tight controls, but the security services did not shy away from making expedient use of criminal gangs as instruments of control to help impose a brutal order among inmates in its sprawling GULAG camp system, or using petty thieves and prostitutes to report on dissidents and foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Soviet Union collapsed, however, these controls dissolved, and the roles suddenly reversed. In 1991 the Soviet security apparatus imploded, and many KGB and GRU officers migrated to the emerging oligarchic and criminal economy left in its wake. There they became security chiefs, &quot;political technologists,&quot; oil traders, and gangsters, using their skills and muscle to help these entities provide a &quot;krysha&quot; (roof)—similar in meaning to &quot;protection&quot; in Western mafia parlance—by combining inside connections, intelligence tradecraft, violence, and financial engineering. When Putin—himself a KGB veteran whose purview over foreign trade and city assets as St. Petersburg’s Deputy Mayor brought him into contact with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamestown.org/newsweek-details-putins-alleged-organized-crime-ties/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;port rackets, fuel schemes, and the Tambov crime syndicate&lt;/a&gt;—rose to the presidency in 1999, he re-asserted state primacy not by dismantling this nexus, but by mastering it. Putin's Kremlin in effect became the &lt;em&gt;Uber Krysha&lt;/em&gt;, the ultimate protection roof above the oligarchs, security chiefs, and crime bosses. The bargain was clear: enjoy your wealth and impunity, but serve the state—effectively Putin—when called. Loyalty was enforced not by law or shared purpose, but by leverage, fear, and mutual criminal exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;What took place after 1991, however, was more than merely a case of inverted and re-inverted primacy. The unprecedented circulation of cadres that occurred during this period fostered a profound organizational and behavioral cross-pollination between intelligence, oligarchic, and criminal elements resulting in a qualitatively new and insidious mutation that is today’s Russia—Putin's Russia. The 1990s saw an &lt;a href=&quot;https://eurasiainstitutes.org/files/file/ceers_wp_post_soviet_organized_crime.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;outflow of KGB and GRU officers&lt;/a&gt; who &quot;pollenated&quot; the criminal/oligarchic economy with their tradecraft, tools, and government connections. Putin’s reconsolidation of state power in the 2000s then saw a return flow creating a &quot;reverse-pollination&quot; as ex-intelligence officers brought their new underworld relationships, financial channels, and expanded operational flexibility back to the security services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among contemporary scholars, the historian and journalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalinitiative.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Mark-Galeotti-Gangsters-at-war-Russias-use-of-organized-crime-as-an-instrument-of-statecraft-GI-TOC-November-2024.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mark Galeotti stands out&lt;/a&gt; as the leading theorist and interpreter of this phenomenon, pointing out how modern Russia's power projection depends on cultivating deniability through criminal intermediaries. Galeotti's concept of the Kremlin as a &quot;political-criminal nexus&quot; and his description of its global &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecfr.eu/publication/crimintern_how_the_kremlin_uses_russias_criminal_networks_in_europe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;crimintern&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/a&gt; offers a crucial corrective to more conventional security studies frameworks. Where others see diffusion of state control as a weakness, Galeotti sees design—a pragmatic outsourcing of coercion and corruption to actors who maintain loyalty through mutual dependence. In this arrangement, the lines between mafia, mercenaries, business, and ministries are blurred.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia's asymmetric tactics abroad leveraging smuggling networks, compromising criminal entanglement (kompromat), cyber hacking, illicit financing, and global shadow operations by semi-private mercenary groups, like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gjia.georgetown.edu/2025/03/24/russia-in-africa-private-military-proxies-in-the-sahel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wagner Group and the Africa Corps&lt;/a&gt;, extend this logic internationally. &lt;a href=&quot;https://newlinesinstitute.org/strategic-competition/how-russia-uses-organized-crime-for-espionage/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Liaisons between the Russian intelligence and crime groups across Europe&lt;/a&gt; also give Moscow access to local networks for espionage, intimidation, and assassinations that can act faster, at lower cost, and with more deniability than professional intelligence officers. But while most analysts tend to focus on this as a blending of tools—military, intelligence, cyber, informational— Galeotti’s insight is sharper: the blend itself is criminal in nature, structurally fusing coercion, corruption, and deceit into a governing logic—&lt;strong&gt;not as a breakdown of state power, but as its deliberate expression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;Yet you will never find this asymmetric dimension acknowledged in Russian doctrinal writings despite its widespread exploitation in Russian actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Policymakers in the Western democracies struggle mightily to wrap their minds around this phenomenon. Their siloed agencies—CIA for HUMINT, NSA for SIGINT/cyber, DOD for military, and FBI for crime, etc.—operate under strict legal separations between these domains to protect civil liberties. Effective in their respective arenas, they are vulnerable when adversaries operate across boundaries. Russia’s mafia-state collapses these distinctions and thrives in the weeds, exploiting moral disregard and legal ambiguity to create jurisdictional confusion and cognitive overload that stymie efforts at response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;And yet for all its advantages, the inherent pathologies of this criminal-state fusion contain the seeds of its own decay. Its reliance on criminal intermediaries corrodes institutional coherence. Loyalty is transactional, not ideological, and emptied of moral meaning. The fates of figures like Yevgeniy Prigozhin and various siloviki-linked oligarchs demonstrate how rapidly beneficiaries can become threats once their ambitions outgrow the tolerance of the Center. Moreover, by incentivizing enrichment over competence, criminal methods undermine professionalism within the military, intelligence services, government bureaucracy, and the private sector. Corruption pervades procurement, logistics, and governance, eroding capacity even as it funds loyalty. This was clearly evident in the shocking underperformance of Russia's military and intelligence operations in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internationally, what appears cunning in the short term produces isolation in the long term. Russia's growing reputation as a mafia state alienates legitimate partners, of which it now has few, and hollows out whatever moral legitimacy it once had. Putin's &lt;em&gt;Uber Krysha&lt;/em&gt; model is unsustainable in the long run because it requires continuous motion. It cannot stand on genuine law or trust, only perpetual leverage and fear, with tools that must be continuously re-coerced. The Russian people and others who are caught in its reach exist in an environment of moral blackmail that breeds cynicism rather than solidarity. Galeotti's moral edge, implicit in his scholarship, lies in showing that the criminal state is not merely a threat to others, it is a tragedy for Russia itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To fully understand Russian asymmetric warfare today, we must appreciate its blending of the state and criminal domains and recognize that Moscow hasn't simply rewritten the rules of war for the gray zone, it has blurred the lines between law and criminality and has itself become a gray state. It is the malignant ethos of this new Russian &lt;em&gt;Uber Krysha&lt;/em&gt; state—the normalization of moral disregard—that, more than any cyber weapon or troll farm, has become its most dangerous export.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cuba’s regime is in dire straits</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/14/cubas-regime-is-in-dire-straits</link>
      <description>After the capture of Nicolás Maduro, the regime which controls the island is particularly vulnerable</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Enters the Slop War</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-fight-against-x-opening-salvo-of-war-for-democratic-debate-by-cori-crider-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inundated with manipulative slop that has warped public debate, the European Union has begun to confront the threat that social media platforms pose to democratic life. The fight ahead is not about free speech, as the United States contends, but about whether governments can rein in platforms that profit from disorder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Decade of Bridges: UWC Changshu China at 10</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/a-decade-of-bridges-uwc-changshu-china-at-10/</link>
      <description>Founder and Chairman Mark Jiapeng Wang reflects on how a personal turning point evolved into a global learning community shaping China’s next generation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Supreme Court seems friendly towards trans bans in women’s sports</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/14/the-supreme-court-seems-friendly-towards-trans-bans-in-womens-sports</link>
      <description>But some justices sound hesitant to impose the rule nationwide</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trouble With Regime Change</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/trouble-regime-change</link>
      <description>What history teaches about when and how to pursue it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bosnia’s Unfinished Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/europe/bosnias-unfinished-peace</link>
      <description>Growing turmoil in the Balkans threatens European security.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layered Ambiguity: US Cyber Capabilities in the Raid to Extract Maduro from Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/layered-ambiguity-us-cyber-capabilities-raid-extract-maduro-venezuela</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The US operation to remove Maduro succeeded despite fundamental ambiguity about what cyber delivered but that opacity has strategic consequences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Global Security Initiative in South Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-global-security-initiative-in-south-asia/</link>
      <description>South Asia’s strategic location, fragmented politics, and regional rivalries make it an ideal testing ground for the GSI’s flexible, norm-driven approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Feasibility of Kazakhstan’s Digitalization Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-feasibility-of-kazakhstans-digitalization-ambitions/</link>
      <description>Tokayev is committed to making Kazakhstan “fully digital within the next three years,” but what exactly does that mean, and are the government and people of Kazakhstan ready?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI We Need for Sustainable Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-potential-to-improve-infrastructure-investment-and-construction-by-bertrand-badre-and-saurabh-mishra-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even as governments pour trillions of dollars into roads, power grids, data centers, water systems, and housing, the construction industry has yet to leverage the efficiency gains that AI and digitalization have to offer. Given how important the sector will be for sustainable development, this must change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
