<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Kelly’s lawyers say Pentagon is attempting to violate his constitutional rights</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/us-sen-mark-kellys-lawyers-say-pentagon-attempting-violate-his-constitutional-rights/410964/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 10: Britain’s Preparation for War: Professor Sir Hew Strachan</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/talking-strategy/episode-10-britains-preparation-war-professor-sir-hew-strachan</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Britain was not ready for the First World War but some key, if embryonic, plans and capabilities proved vital. Sir Hew Strachan discusses the lessons for today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress hurtles toward partial shutdown after Alex Pretti killing in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/congress-hurtles-toward-partial-shutdown-after-alex-pretti-killing-minneapolis/410960/</link>
      <description>Senate Democrats want new limits on federal agents in a compromise bill to fund the Defense Department before Friday's deadline.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navy shipbuilding stands to get $27 billion in funding in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/navy-shipbuilding-stands-get-27-billion-funding-2026/410959/</link>
      <description>Compromise spending bill reflects a $6.5 billion increase over the president’s budget request for shipbuilding—and corrects One Big Beautiful Bill accounting miscalculations.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slippery Slopes</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/slippery-slopes</link>
      <description>I confess I was temporarily disabled by the latest outrageous events in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis ICE Shooting Tests Limits of Trump’s Immigration Crackdown</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/26/minneapolis-ice-shooting-protests-alex-pretti-renee-good-immigration/</link>
      <description>Protests, legal challenges, and bipartisan backlash are converging on the administration’s tactics.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They're Coming for Our Kids: How Extremists Target Children Online</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/they-re-coming-for-our-kids</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—&lt;/strong&gt;  September is National Preparedness Month - when we check our emergency kits, review evacuation routes, and prepare for natural disasters. But this year, as I sat in conference rooms at the Eradicate Hate Global Summit in Pittsburgh, I couldn't stop thinking about a different kind of storm brewing in our communities. One that doesn't announce itself with weather alerts or sirens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It targets our children in their digital third spaces - Discord servers where they chat with friends, Instagram feeds where they scroll for hours, Reddit forums where they seek community, gaming platforms where they unwind, and the sprawling ecosystem of social media where teenagers spend most of their waking hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, teenagers accounted for up to two-thirds of ISIS-linked arrests in Europe, with children as young as 11 involved in recent terrorist plots. But Islamic extremists aren't the only ones hunting in these digital spaces. White supremacist groups, neo-Nazi organizations, and other far-right movements have turned every corner of the internet where young people gather into potential recruitment centers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What unites these predators across the ideological spectrum isn't their beliefs - it's their understanding that vulnerable children make easy targets. And while they've perfected their hunting techniques, we've dismantled our defenses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The State Department issued a call for proposals in July 2025 to fund programs preventing terrorists from recruiting young people online. One month later, they canceled the entire initiative due to funding cuts. The very expertise needed to design and manage such responses had been dismantled when my office - the Office of Countering Violent Extremism - was shuttered along with similar prevention teams across the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're watching the storm approach, and we're sending the meteorologists home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Hunting Grounds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every platform where teenagers gather has become a recruitment center for extremist movements. Neo-Nazi groups use gaming chats to spread white supremacist messaging. Islamic extremists exploit social media algorithms to target vulnerable youth. Far-right militias recruit through conspiracy theory forums. Anti-government extremists find followers in survivalist communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tactics mirror those used by online predators - build trust, isolate targets, gradually introduce radical ideas, and exploit vulnerabilities. A teenager struggling with social isolation logs into Discord seeking connection and community. Instead, they find recruiters who validate their frustrations while slowly introducing conspiracy theories, hate-filled content, and calls for violence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The progression is methodical. First comes the meme that seems edgy but harmless. Then the private message offering &quot;real truth&quot; about current events. Next, the invitation to a smaller, more exclusive group where radical content flows freely. Finally, the encouragement to take action—whether spreading propaganda, targeting individuals, or planning violence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These aren't random encounters. Extremist recruiters study adolescent psychology, identifying kids who show signs of depression, social anxiety, or family conflict. They understand that teenagers are naturally questioning authority and seeking identity—normal developmental phases that can be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History's Warning Signs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This exploitation of youth isn't new - only the technology has changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hitler Youth movement systematically recruited children through youth organizations. The Red Army Faction in 1970s Germany drew from disaffected university students. The Irish Republican Army found fertile recruiting ground among marginalized teenagers in Belfast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What these historical cases teach us is that extremist movements succeed when they fill voids left by failing institutions. When young people can't find meaning, purpose, or belonging through legitimate channels, they become vulnerable to those offering simple explanations for complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today's digital environment amplifies these vulnerabilities exponentially. Where previous extremists recruited face-to-face in specific locations, online recruiters can reach millions simultaneously, test messaging in real-time, and operate across borders with minimal detection risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Programs We Dismantled&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prevention infrastructure dismantled over the past year wasn't theoretical—it was saving lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the State Department, our team worked with tech companies to identify recruitment tactics and develop content policies that protected legitimate speech while removing extremist material. We helped content moderators recognize subtle grooming techniques that avoid automated detection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Center for Prevention Programs and Partnerships at DHS built relationships with schools and community organizations to identify early warning signs. Their approach was therapeutic, not punitive—providing intervention resources that addressed underlying issues rather than criminalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the FBI, specialized teams tracked recruitment networks and distinguished between teenage edginess and genuine threats. The Department of Health and Human Services funded research into psychological vulnerabilities that informed prevention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All shared common principles: early intervention beats prosecution; community solutions work better than federal enforcement; understanding radicalization psychology is essential for prevention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Disinformation Amplifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What makes today's threat environment particularly dangerous is how disinformation amplifies extremist recruitment while major platforms fail to enforce their own policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I write this, Houthi-linked arms dealers openly sell weapons on verified X accounts, advertising Kalashnikovs and equipment marked &quot;Property of U.S. Govt.&quot; The Tech Transparency Project identified 130 Yemen-based accounts advertising weapons, some with verification checkmarks. X even ran advertisements beneath these posts, generating revenue from terrorist-linked content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A teenager exposed to election fraud conspiracies becomes more susceptible to political violence messaging. Young people fed disinformation about minority communities become easier targets for white supremacist recruitment. Disinformation serves as a gateway drug to radicalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cost of Inaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Pittsburgh summit, I heard from parents whose children had been radicalized online, officers investigating cases without prevention resources, and community leaders watching young people disappear into digital hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One mother found extremist content on her 14-year-old son's computer. When she sought help, local resources that might have provided intervention had lost federal funding. A police officer described investigating a high school attack plot that might have been prevented if early warning systems remained operational.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These costs are measured in broken families, traumatized communities, and young lives destroyed by preventable radicalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Preparedness Really Means&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We don't wait for hurricanes before planning—we build early warning systems and maintain emergency capabilities. The same logic should apply to extremist recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need systems detecting concerning behavioral changes before they become threats. We need intervention addressing psychological vulnerabilities before recruiters exploit them. We need community responses providing support when families encounter these issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The good news: we know what works. Community-based prevention programs have demonstrated success in interrupting radicalization. EXIT programs in Germany and Sweden help individuals leave extremist groups through mentorship and psychological support. The Against Violent Extremism network connects former extremists with at-risk youth. Montreal's Centre for the Prevention of Radicalization Leading to Violence has successfully intervened in over 1,000 cases through family counseling and community partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Path Forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebuilding prevention infrastructure requires immediate action and long-term commitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congress must restore funding for prevention programs at State, DHS, FBI, and HHS. These aren't luxury programs—they're essential public safety capabilities protecting vulnerable citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We must rebuild scattered expertise by bringing prevention professionals back from think tanks, universities, and private companies through sustained investment commitments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need stronger partnerships between agencies, tech companies, schools, and communities. Prevention works best at multiple levels simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parents and educators need training to recognize early warning signs. This means providing basic digital literacy and threat awareness to identify concerning behavioral changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, we need counter-messaging strategies competing with extremist propaganda for young people's attention—empowering communities to tell better stories about identity, purpose, and belonging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Field Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prevention vs. Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Preventing one radicalized individual costs approximately $30,000. Investigating, prosecuting, and incarcerating them after violence costs over $3 million—not counting human costs to victims and communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Resilience:&lt;/strong&gt; The most effective programs work through trusted institutions—schools, religious organizations, sports teams, youth groups. Federal resources can support but can't replace local relationships and trust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reader Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check Your Circle:&lt;/strong&gt; Talk with young people about their online experiences—not to interrogate, but to understand their digital worlds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Local Programs:&lt;/strong&gt; Find prevention resources in your community. School counselors and youth organizations often spot concerning trends before law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice Digital Hygiene:&lt;/strong&gt; Model good information consumption. Fact-check claims before sharing them. Ask questions about sources when your teen shows you &quot;shocking&quot; content. Demonstrate critical thinking by saying &quot;That sounds concerning—let's look up where this information comes from&quot; rather than immediately reacting emotionally. Young people learn more from observation than instruction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I flew home from Pittsburgh, I thought about my children and their digital world. The threats they face aren't visible from satellites or predictable through models. They emerge from the intersection of human psychology and technology in ways we're only beginning to understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But September's preparedness lessons still apply: early warning, community response, and sustained vigilance. The storms targeting our children won't announce themselves with sirens, but they can be detected, understood, and prevented—if we're willing to invest in the tools and expertise necessary to protect what matters most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cipher Brief Expert Dexter Ingram also publishes on Substack &lt;a href=&quot;https://dexteringram.substack.com/p/ive-tracked-terrorist-networks-for?utm_campaign=post-expanded-share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&amp;amp;triedRedirect=true&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Code Name: Citizen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/dec/23/pope-leos-world-day-peace-opportunity-put-words-action/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Venezuela Coup and Cuba Threats Are Old U.S. Habits</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/26/trump-latin-america-intervention-maduro-history-smedley-butler/</link>
      <description>Interfering in Latin American affairs is Washington’s bread and butter.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Déjà Vu</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/26/minneapolis-deja-vu_trump-border-police-killing/</link>
      <description>In its response to protests, the U.S. evokes repressive regimes around the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Next FATF Test: Can the West Demand Results from Pakistan?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-next-fatf-test-can-the-west-demand-results-from-pakistan</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— &lt;/strong&gt;In the shadow of Mexico City's historic Palacio de Bellas Artes, global financial watchdogs will convene in February 2026 for the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) Plenary and Working Group Meetings. In conference rooms far removed from South Asia’s violence, Pakistan will once again present itself as a responsible counterterrorism partner, armed with compliance reports, legislative amendments, and assurances of reform. On paper, Pakistan’s financial regulations increasingly resemble those of many developing democracies. On the ground, however, the networks that finance and enable terrorism continue to adapt and operate with troubling resilience. The widening gap between form and function is precisely what Western policymakers must confront as FATF prepares its next round of assessments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Compliance Illusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan’s removal from the FATF grey list in 2022 was widely portrayed as a&lt;a href=&quot;https://mofa.gov.pk/pakistan-exits-fatfs-grey-list&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;success story&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Officials pointed to new anti-money laundering laws, terrorist financing prosecutions, and institutional reforms as evidence of a course correction. FATF itself&lt;a href=&quot;http://fatf-gafi.org/en/publications/Mutualevaluations/Fur-pakistan-2022.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;acknowledged&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; technical improvements, yet it also emphasized that effectiveness, not legislation, remains the ultimate benchmark. That distinction has proven critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open-source reporting and documented financial intelligence patterns suggest that terrorist organizations such as Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM) and Lashkar-e-Taiba (LeT) have not been dismantled but rather modernized.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dnaindia.com/world/report-pakistan-backed-lashkar-e-taiba-jaish-e-mohammad-s-new-tactics-for-anti-india-activities-exploiting-gaza-war-for-terror-financing-recruiting-3196528&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Recent documents&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reveal how these UN-designated outfits exploit humanitarian crises, such as the Gaza conflict, to funnel funds into terror activities. Under the guise of aid appeals and mosque reconstructions, figures like Hammad Azhar, son of JeM leader Masood Azhar, and Azhar’s brother Talha al-Saif orchestrate campaigns&lt;a href=&quot;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/defence/pakistan-based-jem-launches-rs-3-91-billion-fundraising-drive-after-losses-during-operation-sindoor/articleshow/123434708.cms?from=mdr&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;using digital wallets&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; like EasyPaisa, SadaPay, and JazzCash, aggregating micro-donations and cryptocurrencies to evade detection. These efforts aggregate micro-donations and cryptocurrency transfers, often employing fragmented wallet structures and chain-hopping across platforms to avoid detection. Funds have&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/months-after-operation-sindoor-setback-pak-terror-outfit-jaish-raises-funds-to-rebuild-2774256-2025-08-20&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;reportedly supported&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; militant infrastructure, including the establishment of more than 300 Mosques and the reconstruction of locations historically linked to LeT training facilities damaged during India’s 2025 Operation Sindoor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pattern reflects more than opportunism. Pakistan’s legal framework may align with FATF’s 40 recommendations on paper, but operational enforcement remains deeply inconsistent. Sanctioned individuals such as Hafiz Talha Saeed have&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/hafiz-saeed-son-talha-saeed-lahore-rally-pm-modi-pahalgam-terror-attack-india-pak-tensions-2720626-2025-05-06&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;led public rallies&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Lahore under police protection, issuing threats against Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi. In 2025, senior Pakistani legislature Rana Muhammad Qasim Noon&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/India/pak-rebuilding-muzaffarabad-terror-camp-destroyed-in-operation-sindoor-minister-visits-site/ar-AA1PHdR0?cvid=6908a8eda8264964b07b806b1720fa36&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;reportedly visited&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; militant-affiliated reconstruction sites alongside local officials, revealing overt collaboration between state and non-state actors. Recruitment drives&lt;a href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/post-operation-sindoor-major-pakistan-terror-groups-shifting-base-to-afghanistan-border/articleshow/124008707.cms&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;disguised as religious gatherings&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, often coordinated with Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam networks, have featured speeches praising Osama bin Laden and al Qaeda, delivered by JeM commander Masood Ilyas Kashmiri at facilities such as Markaz Shohada-e-Islam in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Together, these cases point to a long-standing “management” model of extremism. Militant groups are not dismantled but rebranded, with political fronts such as&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/new-party-face-of-mumbai-attacks-mastermind-hafiz-saeeds-banned-group-to-participate-in-pakistan-general-election/article67812218.ece&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;the Pakistan Markazi Muslim League&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contesting elections while violence is normalized as a political instrument. As Greece-based policy analyst Dimitra Staikou has&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.europawire.eu/pakistan-when-the-state-does-not-fight-terrorism-but-manages-it/eu-press-release/2026/01/09/15/48/56/167603/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;argued&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, this model exports instability through regional alignments and shields militancy behind formal democratic processes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Mexico City Matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The February 2026 FATF meetings come at a moment when Pakistan’s engagement with the United States and Europe is deepening even as its internal security situation deteriorates. Militant violence has&lt;a href=&quot;https://crss.pk/three-quarters-of-2025-nearly-as-violent-as-entire-2024/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;surged significantly&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, driven by attacks from the Tehrik-e-Taliban Pakistan and Baloch insurgent groups. Rather than prompting a clean break with all forms of militancy, this instability risks reinforcing the proxy logic that FATF scrutiny is meant to dismantle. For Western policymakers, the danger lies in conflating cooperation with convergence in security priorities. Intelligence sharing, access agreements, or economic partnerships do not necessarily reflect aligned counterterrorism priorities. As I&lt;a href=&quot;https://millichronicle.com/2025/10/58400.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;argued previously&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Milli Chronicle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Pakistan’s strategic incentives continue to reward selective tolerance of militant actors, particularly those oriented toward India. FATF’s effectiveness framework exists to test whether states are willing to disrupt these incentives, not simply mask them with procedural compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FATF’s&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fatf-gafi.org/en/publications/Methodsandtrends/comprehensive-update-terrorist-financing-risks-2025.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;2025 Comprehensive Update&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Terrorist Financing Risks underscores the urgency. The report highlights a marked increase in hybrid digital methods, consistent with Pakistan-linked entities shifting from banks to fintech platforms to evade oversight. Although Pakistan exited the grey list in 2022 after four years of economic strain, FATF President Elisa de Anda Madrazo&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aninews.in/news/world/europe/exit-from-greylist-not-bulletproof-fatf-warns-pakistan-against-terror-financing20251025044030/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;warned&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in October 2025 that the removal was “not bulletproof,” citing unregulated digital transactions as a continuing vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mexico City should therefore serve as a turning point. US and EU delegations should press for outcome-based evaluations focused on sustained investigations, verifiable asset seizures, and the dismantling of facilitation networks. Particular scrutiny must be directed toward digital payment systems, informal charities, and micro-donation models that exploit regulatory blind spots. Western governments should also coordinate more closely to monitor cross-border flows linked to high-risk jurisdictions, ensuring that Pakistan’s reforms translate into measurable disruption rather than rhetorical reassurance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion: Choosing Substance Over Stability Theater&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pakistan will argue that renewed scrutiny risks destabilizing a fragile state. That argument has been persuasive before, and it has failed before. Stability built on tolerated militancy is not stability at all; it is deferred risk. Western capitals should therefore anchor their engagement around two imperatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, international partners should move beyond accepting legislative reforms and instead condition high-level diplomatic, security, and economic engagement with Pakistan on verifiable enforcement outcomes. This means tying cooperation to demonstrable actions such as sustained terrorist-financing prosecutions, asset freezes against UN- and US-designated individuals, and the disruption of digital fundraising networks linked to groups like JeM and LeT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, Washington and Brussels should treat Pakistan-linked terrorist financing as a transnational financial integrity threat, not a regional security issue. This requires enhanced monitoring of fintech platforms, mobile wallets, charities, and micro-donation systems used by diaspora-linked networks in Europe and North America. FATF has repeatedly warned that terrorist groups increasingly exploit digital payments and new financial technologies to evade traditional controls. The EU and US should expand joint typology sharing, require higher due-diligence thresholds for transactions linked to high-risk jurisdictions, and protect activists and journalists targeted by&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.timesofisrael.com/repression-without-borders-how-pakistan-silences-critics-overseas/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;transnational repression&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tied to Pakistan’s security apparatus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Mexico City, Pakistan will speak in the language of compliance and reform. Beyond the conference halls, the true test will be whether the networks that finance violence are finally dismantled or quietly allowed to endure. If Western governments choose substance over symbolism, this moment can mark a turning point. If not, the paperwork will pass, and the risks will return—more adaptive, more opaque, and more dangerous than before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia is Targeting Civilians in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-is-targeting-civilians-in-ukraine</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;The United Nations Human Rights Monitoring Mission in Ukraine &lt;a href=&quot;https://ukraine.ohchr.org/en/2025-deadliest-year-for-civilians-in-Ukraine-since-2022-UN-human-rights-monitors-find&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;reported&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that 14,383 civilians were killed in Ukraine, 673 of them children, as of late 2025. Russia has intensified attacks on Ukraine’s power grid, generating facilities, and heating infrastructure, in efforts to disrupt electricity, heat, and water services – especially in winter. Clearly, Russia is targeting Ukraine’s civilian population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mayor of Kyiv, Vitali Klitschko, recently told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/kyiv-has-only-half-electricity-it-needs-mayor-says-2026-01-16/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reuters&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Kyiv, with a population of 3.6 million people, has only about half the electricity that it needs as it faces its most severe wartime energy crisis, following waves of Russian attacks on its infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Russia’s invasion of Ukraine enters its fourth year, Ukrainian casualties are estimated at around 400,000, with civilian casualties rising, according to the United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Laws of War are clear: intentionally targeting civilians is prohibited; civilians should never be the objective of an attack. Even more specifically, a combatant should avoid or reduce harm to civilian infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Criminal Court has accused Russian President Vladimir Putin of war crimes for the unlawful deportation and transfer of Ukrainian children from occupied territories to Russia, while a few UN entities, and other civilian organizations monitoring the war in Ukraine, maintain that Mr. Putin is also guilty of the indiscriminate bombing of civilian infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s clear: Russia has repeatedly &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-zelenskyy-drones-missiles-electricity-cc5f4542e0a5d3c05b948d4e0c64984f&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;targeted&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ukraine’s power grid, generation facilities, and heating infrastructure, aiming to disrupt electricity, heat, and water services – especially in winter. These attacks are not isolated to the Kyiv, but, rather, part of a large, coordinated plan to target all regions in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine has reported tens of thousands of energy infrastructure facilities have been damaged since 2022, damaging generation plants, substations, heating plants, and transmission lines. And at least 18 major combined heat and power plants have been destroyed or seriously damaged, according to the International Atomic Energy Agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian strikes have left hundreds of thousands of people with no central heating during sub-zero weather, a widespread development throughout Ukraine. Indeed, officials and humanitarian groups are warning that millions of Ukrainians are at heightened risk this winter due to lack of heat, electricity, and water amid the intense cold. UN officials described the situation as a worsening humanitarian crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia has systematically targeted civilian energy and heating infrastructure, not just military sites, with repeated missile and drone strikes aimed at power plants, grids, and heating systems, affecting thousands of facilities. The result is widespread blackouts and heating loss for civilians, especially during harsh &lt;a href=&quot;https://united24media.com/war-in-ukraine/weaponizing-winter-the-unrelenting-toll-of-russian-energy-strikes-on-kyivs-civilians-continues-15205&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;winter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with sub-zero temperatures, creating a serious humanitarian situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Putin’s strategy is to target civilians with the intensification of bombings against Ukraine’s infrastructure that provides heat, water, and electricity to the Ukrainian people. These are violations of the Laws of War, and the International Criminal Court should immediately commence with hearings on Russia’s indiscriminate bombing of civilian infrastructure, resulting in the death of thousands of Ukrainian civilians. Clearly, Mr. Putin is targeting Ukraine’s civilian population, a war crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joseph R. DeTrani&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The author is the former associate director of national intelligence. All statements of fact, opinion or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the U.S. government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying U.S. government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This column by Cipher Brief Expert Ambassador Joseph DeTrani was first published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2026/jan/20/russia-targeting-ukrainian-civilians/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Washington Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute federal agents for using excessive force?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/26/can-minnesota-prosecute-federal-agents-for-using-excessive-force</link>
      <description>The “supremacy clause” is at issue</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why AI won’t wipe out white-collar jobs</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/26/why-ai-wont-wipe-out-white-collar-jobs</link>
      <description>The technology will expand their scope and raise their value</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Generals Fall, Xi Jinping’s Anti-Corruption Campaign Is Eating Itself</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/26/xi-generals-zhang-youxia-anti-corruption-china/</link>
      <description>With childhood friends and top leaders in the firing line, the system is frozen with fear.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ryanair might be the world’s most successful airline</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/26/ryanair-might-be-the-worlds-most-successful-airline</link>
      <description>The low-cost carrier is flying high</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Three ways Donald Trump could strike Iran</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/26/the-war-room-newsletter-three-ways-donald-trump-could-strike-iran</link>
      <description>Shashank Joshi, our defence editor, analyses America’s options</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Did Mongolia Join Trump’s Board of Peace?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-did-mongolia-join-trumps-board-of-peace/</link>
      <description>While the United States' democratic allies stayed away, the Zandanshatar administration become a founding member of the new body.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hizbullah, Iran’s most powerful proxy, has been humbled</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/26/hizbullah-irans-most-powerful-proxy-has-been-humbled</link>
      <description>The militia is still a force in Lebanese politics, but its ability to menace abroad has been severely weakened</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China fears a flood of unemployed workers in rural areas</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/26/china-fears-a-flood-of-unemployed-workers-in-rural-areas</link>
      <description>Fading ambition may pose a bigger problem</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA Is Destroying the Culture that Built the West</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-trump-destroying-culture-that-built-the-west-by-j-p-singh-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The rise of the West is a simple story to tell culturally: It’s about Europe moving toward openness, cosmopolitanism, intellectual freedom, transparent rules, and, above all, institutional checks and balances. US President Donald Trump negates these values at every turn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s liberals face a difficult election</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/26/thailands-liberals-face-a-difficult-election</link>
      <description>The momentum is now with the energetic new prime minister</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Feds kill again in Minnesota; National Defense Strategy drops; New USAF deployment concept; Space Force wants more troops; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-26-2026/410936/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bloody Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/minneapolis-ice-killings-political-turning-point-for-us-by-daron-acemoglu-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The killings of two innocent civilians –&amp;nbsp;both US citizens – by federal immigration agents in Minneapolis this month may mark a turning point for the United States. The energy and solidarity among people supporting their immigrant neighbors and protesting ICE’s brutal tactics herald a defining showdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Davos 2026: Entering an Age of Contested Orders</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/after-davos-2026-entering-an-age-of-contested-orders/</link>
      <description>There is no longer a single, unified Western position, but three distinct visions of order – American, European, and Asian – each shaped by different threat perceptions and strategic priorities.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting the ‘Normal Country’: Will Japan Continue Its Pacifist Path?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/revisiting-the-normal-country-will-japan-continue-its-pacifist-path/</link>
      <description>Does Takaichi’s embrace of “normal country” status signal a possible revival of Japanese militarism?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Does Europe Go From Here?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-trump-greenland-resolution-lessons-to-take-from-davos-by-mark-leonard-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beyond showcasing Donald Trump's &quot;neo-royalist&quot; style of politics, this year's annual gathering of the global elite in Davos revealed deeper, structural changes that will shape political and business leaders’ decision-making for years to come. Europeans, in particular, must absorb the right lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which European cities are least affordable for renters?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/26/which-european-cities-are-least-affordable-for-renters</link>
      <description>Our Carrie Bradshaw index takes a trip to the continent</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Carrie Bradshaw index of Europe’s priciest cities for renters</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/26/our-carrie-bradshaw-index-of-europes-priciest-cities-for-renters</link>
      <description>The average earner struggles to afford rent in all but eight of the places we looked at</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stifling the “Spirit of Dialogue” at Davos</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/world-economic-forum-meeting-davos-appeases-trump-ignores-climate-change-by-hippolyte-fofack-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Economic Forum chose “A Spirit of Dialogue” as the theme for this year’s meeting in Davos. But, to secure US President Donald Trump’s participation, the organization agreed to avoid “woke” topics such as the energy transition, preventing any meaningful exchange on the urgent need for climate action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy’s ‘Global Mediterranean’ Turns to the Indo-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/italys-global-mediterranean-turns-to-the-indo-pacific/</link>
      <description>Italy is seeking to anchor its role through key partnerships across an increasingly interconnected geopolitical space, in which national and economic security overlap.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Agreement Expands on the France-New Caledonia Bougival Accord</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/new-agreement-expands-on-the-france-new-caledonia-bougival-accord/</link>
      <description>The Elysée-Oudinot Accord, reached between France and five parliamentary groups from New Caledonia, augments the 2025 Bougival Accord. But a date for the necessary referendum has not been set yet.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s Answer Might Be Kosovo</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/26/ukraine-russia-donetsk-land-swap-peace-talks-kosovo/</link>
      <description>A peace plan from the Balkans could solve the hardest negotiations with Russia.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Defense Strategy Signals Shift in Korea Defense, Pushing Seoul to Lead</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/us-defense-strategy-signals-shift-in-korea-defense-pushing-seoul-to-lead/</link>
      <description>The new National Defense Strategy limits the U.S. conventional role to prioritize China while demanding South Korea take primary responsibility for North Korean threats.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan Is Betting on Predictability in an Unpredictable Region</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/kazakhstan-is-betting-on-predictability-in-an-unpredictable-region/</link>
      <description>In contrast to ad hoc constitutional resets seen elsewhere in the post-Soviet space, Tokayev’s approach relies on pre-emptive institutional engineering.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alliance of the Betrayed: The Quiet Rise of India-EU Relations</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/alliance-of-the-betrayed-the-quiet-rise-of-india-eu-relations/</link>
      <description>President Trump’s hostile and erratic foreign policy actions accelerated the India-EU relationship – including a long-awaited FTA.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checks and Balance newsletter: Can US attorneys answer to the president and the law?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/26/checks-and-balance-newsletter-can-us-attorneys-answer-to-the-president-and-the-law</link>
      <description>The clash over Donald Trump’s appointees risks becoming a circus, says Charlotte Howard, our New York bureau chief</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tariffs Are More Destructive Than You Think</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariffs-costs-and-damage-to-economy-greater-than-many-understand-by-sebnem-kalemli-ozcan-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s interconnected global economy, tariffs produce outcomes that are very different from what traditional economic models would predict. Rather than causing only limited and temporary distortions, tariffs can generate persistent inflation, significant output losses, and damaging international spillovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Dilemma: To Be or Not to Be Part of Trump’s Board of Peace</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indias-dilemma-to-be-or-not-to-be-part-of-trumps-board-of-peace/</link>
      <description>Given that the Board doesn’t have prominent representation so far, India could negotiate endorsement for a price.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Kent State Taught the Country About State Violence</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/26/kent-state-violence-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>Renee Good and Alex Pretti’s killings in Minneapolis have brought back memories of government escalation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case for Upending World Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/case-upending-world-trade</link>
      <description>How Trump’s vision echoes America’s traditional approach.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Personalist Global Order</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/personalist-global-order</link>
      <description>When individual whims drive great-power policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India Scraps 10-minute Delivery by Food and Grocery Delivery Platforms</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/india-scraps-10-minute-delivery-by-food-and-grocery-delivery-platforms/</link>
      <description>To meet the deadline, delivery workers were often putting their lives at risk to speed through India’s chaotic and crowded roads.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drugs Trafficking in Venezuela is an Ocean Away From the Capture of Maduro</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/drugs-trafficking-venezuela-ocean-away-capture-maduro</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The impact of Maduro’s capture will be negligible on Venezuela’s cocaine-trafficking.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We Have No Choice’: The Rise of Civilian Militias in Indian-ruled Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/we-have-no-choice-the-rise-of-civilian-militias-in-indian-ruled-kashmir/</link>
      <description>India is effectively placing the burden of counterinsurgency on untrained, ill-equipped local civilians.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe is aiming to sign a long-awaited free-trade deal with India</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/25/europe-is-aiming-to-sign-a-long-awaited-free-trade-deal-with-india</link>
      <description>One way to show America and China that also-rans have options, too</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
