<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Trump lambastes defense CEOs over pay, stock buybacks</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/trump-lambastes-defense-ceos-over-pay-stock-buybacks/410533/</link>
      <description>The president also pushed for a $1.5-trillion defense budget.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right-to-repair fight could make or break US troops’ robot-war plans</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/right-repair-fight-could-make-or-break-us-troops-robot-war-plans/410532/</link>
      <description>Contracts that prevent battlefield repair, mods are hindering troops’ lethality, operators and experts say.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right-to-repair fight could make or break US troops’ robot-war plans</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/01/right-repair-fight-could-make-or-break-us-troops-robot-war-plans/410532/</link>
      <description>Contracts that prevent battlefield repair, mods are hindering troops’ lethality, operators and experts say.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE’s deportation campaign turns deadly</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/08/ices-deportation-campaign-turns-deadly</link>
      <description>A killing in Minneapolis is part of a dangerous pattern</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Machine: When Putin Warned Bush About Dangers of Regime Change</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/time-machine-when-putin-warned-bush</link>
      <description>Irony abounds in newly unearthed telephone call on eve of US invasion of Iraq that records Putin warning Bush about violating UN charter and &amp;#8220;international law.&amp;#8221;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Russian and Chinese Air Power Threats</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/insights-papers/evolution-russian-and-chinese-air-power-threats</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compared to 2020, Russian and, particularly, Chinese capabilities pose greater threats to Western air power than in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s Nuclear Latency May Be Washington’s Least Bad Option</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/south-korea-us-submarine-nuclear-latency-uranium-enrichment/</link>
      <description>With U.S. extended deterrence under strain, managing Seoul’s nuclear hedging may be safer than trying to stop it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Seize or Not to Seize Greenland</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/us-annex-greenland-military-trump-rubio-denmark-nato/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration issues mixed messaging on whether it will use U.S. military force to annex Greenland.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Army narrows field for its flight-school outsourcing contract, Congress says: not so fast</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/army-narrows-field-its-flight-school-outsourcing-contract-congress-says-not-so-fast/410528/</link>
      <description>Bell, Lockheed Martin, and M1 got the service’s thumbs-up just as lawmakers put brakes on the effort.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s Military Won’t Surrender Its Privileges Easily</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/venezuela-military-army-strikes-politics/</link>
      <description>Problems with the armed forces pre-date Maduro and even Chávez.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India-Bangladesh Tensions Reach a Fever Pitch</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/india-bangladesh-tensions-cricket-hasina-modi-elections/</link>
      <description>Cricket drama underscores the depth of the crisis, but Dhaka’s upcoming election offers a shot at a reset.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s astoundingly messy debts are about to get messier</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/07/venezuelas-astoundingly-messy-debts-are-about-to-get-messier</link>
      <description>Oil majors, hedge funds, Chinese lenders—all have a stake</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Violence in Northern Afghanistan Pits Locals Against Gold Mining Operators and the Taliban</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/violence-in-northern-afghanistan-pits-locals-against-gold-mining-operators-and-the-taliban/</link>
      <description>At least four were killed in a recent outbreak of violence between locals and a gold mining company allegedly backed by the Taliban.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Strike: The US Munition That Hit a Residential Building in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/07/inside-the-strike-the-us-munition-that-hit-a-residential-building-in-venezuela/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Bellingcat investigation has identified remnants of an AGM-88 series missile inside a three-storey apartment complex that was hit in Catia La Mar during the US military raid on Venezuela on Jan. 3, 2026 that reportedly killed at least one civilian.  According to the Venezuelan independent media outlet, El Pitazo, Rosa Gonzalez, 79, was killed [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/07/inside-the-strike-the-us-munition-that-hit-a-residential-building-in-venezuela/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Inside the Strike: The US Munition That Hit a Residential Building in Venezuela&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bellingcat.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;bellingcat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will South Sudan Get Dragged Into Sudan’s Civil War?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/south-sudan-sudanese-armed-forces-conflict-rsf-oil/</link>
      <description>Tensions rise after the Sudanese military captures South Sudanese nationals in battle.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada’s armed forces are now planning for threats from America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/07/canadas-armed-forces-are-now-planning-for-threats-from-america</link>
      <description>They started rebuilding in 2025, before Donald Trump’s most recent bid for hemispheric dominance</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canada’s armed forces are planning for threats from America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/07/canadas-armed-forces-are-planning-for-threats-from-america</link>
      <description>They started rebuilding in 2025, before Donald Trump’s most recent bid for hemispheric dominance</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “ChatGPT moment” has arrived for manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/interactive/business/2026/01/07/the-chatgpt-moment-has-arrived-for-manufacturing</link>
      <description>Artificial intelligence promises to transform how and where things are made</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democrats Scathing, Republicans Exultant Over Maduro Capture</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/democrats-republicans-congress-response-trump-venezuela-maduro-war-powers/</link>
      <description>The polarized response to the Venezuela military operation shows how deeply divided Congress is on Trump’s foreign policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where should predators hang out if there are no watering holes?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/07/where-should-predators-hang-out-if-there-are-no-watering-holes</link>
      <description>Salt licks are a good option</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real flying saucers</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/07/real-flying-saucers</link>
      <description>The latest satellites are flat and circular</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A way to expand Earth’s arable land</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/07/a-way-to-expand-earths-arable-land</link>
      <description>Make the semi-desert bloom by enridging it</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran’s Supreme Leader Should Listen to the People</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/iran-listen-to-the-people</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT OPINION —&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The Iranian people are saying they want new leadership. And it’s not too hard to understand why so many merchants, university students and young people in Iran are on the streets calling for political &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/irans-protests-expose-deeper-fragility-as-leaders-struggle-to-contain-crisis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;change&lt;/a&gt; and an end to the current Islamic Republic rule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the merchants in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/iran-security-forces-clash-with-protesters-at-grand-bazaar-at-least-36-killed-in-demonstrations&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tehran’s Grand Bazar&lt;/a&gt; that initially closed their shops because they couldn’t make a living with soaring inflation and the collapse of the national currency, the rial. Merchants in over 32 cities quickly followed suit, with university students and the public joining in protests calling for change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not new for Iran. In 2009, the government ensured that incumbent Mahmood Ahmadinejad was reelected president, despite the popular opposition leader, Mir-Hossein Mousavi, having widespread support from the public, promising hope and change. The government’s heavy hand in ensuring their man was reelected, regardless of what the public wanted and voted for, understandably angered the public, resulting in Iran’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2009/jun/13/iran-mahmoud-ahmadinejad-riots-tehran-election&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Green Movement&lt;/a&gt;.” Protesters, who adopted green as the symbol of hope and change, claimed the election was rigged. When they demanded greater democracy, the rule of law, and an end to authoritarian practices, the government responded violently. Peaceful protesters were beaten, with thousands arrested and dozens killed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September 2022, Jina Mahsa Amini, a 22-year-old Kurdish Iranian was arrested for improperly wearing her head scarf (hijab). She died in police custody, with eyewitnesses saying she was beaten and died because of police brutality. The death of Amini resulted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/tehrans-protest-problem-may-run-deeper-than-it-thinks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nationwide protests&lt;/a&gt;, with Iran Human Rights reporting that at least 476 people were killed by security forces. Amnesty International reported that the Iranian police and security forces fired into groups with live ammunition and killed protesters by beating them with batons. Amini’s death gave rise to the global movement of: Women, Life, Liberty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since then, Iran has conducted a war against its own people, with widespread arrests of anyone protesting widespread government corruption and human rights abuses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today’s protests were sparked by Iran’s severe economic crisis and water shortages, but also by Iran’s humiliating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/israel-iran-proxies&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;defeat&lt;/a&gt; by Israel in its 12-day war of June 2025 and the subsequent U.S. bombing of Iran’s nuclear facilities in Natanz, Fordow, and Isfahan. This was after the people were told that Israel would never dare to attack Iran. But they did, with impunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hundreds of millions of dollars spent on Iran’s nuclear program, building thousands of spinning sophisticated centrifuges, enriching uranium at 60% purity, concealed in deeply buried underground facilities -- and related scientific work— certainly contributed to Iran’s economic collapse. The resultant global &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/defiance-meets-desperation-as-iran-faces-fresh-un-sanctions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sanctions&lt;/a&gt; imposed on Iran also contributed to the crumbling of Iran’s economy. Indeed, Iran’s long history of pursuing nuclear weapons and then claiming they ceased such a pursuit, although continuing to enrich uranium while denying IAEA access to suspect nuclear facilities ensured that the global community viewed Iran with deep suspicion and was supportive of the biting sanctions imposed on Iran. Iran’s nuclear pursuits and the resultant sanctions led to Iran’s failed economy. And it was the people who suffered when the rial lost its value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian acknowledged the legitimacy of the protesters’ complaints, while announcing the appointment of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/iran-currency-inflation-central-bank-governor-protests-ccc43409cfceed3096db8cf63cc0ce53&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new central bank chief&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reportedly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp37w9xnxxwo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;36 people&lt;/a&gt; have been killed during the demonstrations, with hundreds arrested and thousands on the street saying they want change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamnei, in an address on Saturday, blamed foreign interference and said that “rioters must be put in their place.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump had warned Iran that if Iran “violently kills peaceful protesters” the U.S. “will come to their rescue.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What these and previous demonstrations tell us is that the people have suffered enough. They’ve taken to the street because they want change, hope and a leadership that cares for the people. The protesters carry signs saying, “the mullahs must leave Iran.” It’s clear: the government has mismanaged Iran’s economy; has made Iran a pariah nation. The Iranian theocracy, led by supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, apparently no longer has the support of the Iranian people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Is a democratic secular Iran possible?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The author is a former associate director of national intelligence. All statements of fact, opinion or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the U.S. government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying U.S. government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This column by Cipher Brief Expert Ambassador Joseph DeTrani was first published in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2026/jan/6/democracy-possible-iran/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Washington Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcapacity Is China’s Biggest AI Advantage</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-overcapacity-may-help-it-win-global-ai-race-by-angela-huyue-zhang-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The global AI race will be won not by the power of models and chips, but by how effectively systems can be deployed and improved across the economy. China’s chronic excess capacity, long seen as its greatest weakness, has reduced costs and accelerated adoption, providing the country's AI sector with a decisive edge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Has a Strategy for Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/trump-venezuela-democracy-oil-transition/</link>
      <description>It is designed to avoid repeating the mistakes of Iraq and Afghanistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump chases down Venezuela’s shadow fleet</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/07/donald-trump-chases-down-venezuelas-shadow-fleet</link>
      <description>America seizes two of its oil tankers, including one flying a Russian flag</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Looming Population Bust</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/population-aging-declining-fertility-ticking-time-bomb-by-beata-javorcik-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Across much of the world, fertility rates are falling and populations are aging faster than economies can adapt, putting pressure on labor markets, pension systems, and public finances. The challenge is made more difficult to address by growing resistance from older voters and risk-averse leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China’s Exploitative Labor System Gives It a Strategic Edge</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-chinas-exploitative-labor-system-gives-it-a-strategic-edge/</link>
      <description>China’s decisive source of global competitive advantage lies in its weak labor protections. And it’s driving a race to the bottom for labor rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Trump plans oil seizure; US forces seize tanker; Greenland seizure floated; Experts pan Maduro seizure; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-07-2026/410509/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Mongolia’s New, Old Capital at Kharkhorum</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/building-mongolias-new-old-capital-at-kharkhorum/</link>
      <description>Mongolia wants to resurrect the ancient capital of the Mongol Empire as a modern-day urban hub.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hollowing Out of East Asian Industry</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-competition-from-china-are-hollowing-out-east-asian-industry-by-keun-lee-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China’s changing economic structure, together with high and unpredictable US tariffs, has placed Japan and South Korea under intensifying pressure. Only by deepening engagement with each other, and with other reliable partners, can these countries safeguard the industries on which their economies depend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Polk’s Warning for Donald Trump</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/venezuela-trump-history-mexican-american-war-polk/</link>
      <description>The Mexican-American War offers sobering reminders of the current U.S. intervention in Venezuela.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s Military Procurement Is a Warning for Europe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/russia-ukraine-putin-europe-drones-missiles/</link>
      <description>Putin’s order books reveal plans for conflict well beyond Ukraine</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicolás Maduro is unlikely to beat his rap</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/07/nicolas-maduro-is-unlikely-to-beat-his-rap</link>
      <description>He has credible legal defences but diplomacy may be his best shot</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine now has the fortress belt it wishes it had in 2022</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/07/ukraine-now-has-the-fortress-belt-it-wishes-it-had-in-2022</link>
      <description>But American-led peace proposals threaten to hand it to Russia</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of China’s One-Child Policy, Ten Years Later</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinese-one-child-policy-highlighted-fatal-governance-flaw-by-yi-fuxian-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The logic behind China’s family-planning policies was always suspect, as were the data that convinced officials to keep them in place long after it should have been clear that they had failed. The history of the 35-year one-child policy highlights a fatal flaw in Chinese governance, for which the country is paying a steep price.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Expands Visa Bond List to Include Bangladesh, Tonga, and Kyrgyzstan, Among Other Asian Countries</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/us-expands-visa-bond-list-to-include-bangladesh-tonga-and-kyrgyzstan-among-other-asian-countries/</link>
      <description>While the pilot program largely targets countries in Africa, the latest expansion includes countries in Central Asia, South Asia, and the Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America at 250</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/interactive/america-at-250</link>
      <description>From the Declaration of Independence to the rise of Donald Trump, we assess America’s complicated relationship with its founding ideals</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our polling with YouGov shows what MAGA-land thinks about Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/01/07/our-polling-with-yougov-shows-what-maga-land-thinks-about-venezuela</link>
      <description>Comparing polls before and after the capture of Nicolás Maduro reveals a sharp turn in Donald Trump’s base</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The US Raid on Venezuela: The View From Beijing</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-us-raid-on-venezuela-the-view-from-beijing/</link>
      <description>The U.S. capture of Maduro is likely to bolster, rather than undermine, deterrence across the Taiwan Strait.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyeing Local Elections, PPP Leader Makes Half-hearted Apology Over Martial Law</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/eyeing-local-elections-ppp-leader-makes-half-hearted-apology-over-martial-law/</link>
      <description>The leader of the People Power Party, who repeatedly defended Yoon Suk-yeol, delivered his apologies to the public. However, he did not admit the illegitimacy of martial law.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is it better to rent or buy?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/07/is-it-better-to-rent-or-buy</link>
      <description>Much depends on long-term interest rates</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The radical honesty of Donald Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/07/the-radical-honesty-of-donald-trump</link>
      <description>Why the world will miss hypocrisy in American foreign policy</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Pandemic Financing for Middle-Income Countries</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/multilateral-development-banks-must-commit-to-at-risk-funding-next-pandemic-by-masyita-crystallin-and-rachel-glennerster-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the COVID-19 pandemic, middle-income countries struggled to invest in vaccines and other medical countermeasures. To avoid repeating the same mistake, policymakers from these countries must demand that multilateral development banks make at-risk financing available as soon as the next outbreak occurs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Backs Pakistan’s Regional Ambitions as ‘All-Weather’ Ties Deepen</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/china-backs-pakistans-regional-ambitions-as-all-weather-ties-deepen/</link>
      <description>Beijing does not seem worried about Islamabad’s warming ties with the US at this stage.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Tactics Could Unravel U.S. Strategy in Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/trump-southeast-asia-asean-china-strategy-geopolitics/</link>
      <description>The region is no stranger to dealmaking, but Washington’s selfish ends are self-damaging.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Southeast Asia Spoke Out Against Maduro’s Capture</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/07/southeast-asia-maduro-capture-response/</link>
      <description>The region’s rhetorical commitment reflects a wariness of great-power interference.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Save the Fight for Women’s Rights</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/world/how-save-fight-womens-rights</link>
      <description>The backlash against democracy calls for new strategies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Transactional Trap</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/transactional-trap</link>
      <description>How foreign policy dealmaking can sow violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wider Implications of US Action in Venezuela: RUSI Experts React</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/wider-implications-us-action-venezuela-rusi-experts-react</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our experts comment on the US attacks on Venezuela and arrest of &lt;span&gt;President Nicolás Maduro.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White House floats military action to take Greenland</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/white-house-floats-military-action-take-greenland/410503/</link>
      <description>White House press secretary Karoline Leavitt calls acquiring the Danish territory an &quot;important foreign policy goal.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Says it Will “Run” Venezuela. What Will That Mean?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-run-venezuela</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/pro-government-supporters-attend-a-rally-a-day-after-the-capture-of-nicolas-maduro-by-us-forces-on-january-4-2026-in-caracas-v.jpg?id=62668354&amp;amp;width=1200&amp;amp;height=600&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C85%2C0%2C86&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE – &lt;/strong&gt;As audacious and complex as it was for the U.S. to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-maduro-2026&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;extract Nicolas Maduro from Venezuela&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – and to do so without a single U.S. casualty – the challenges ahead may be even harder. “We’re gonna run it,” President Donald Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/loud-noises-heard-venezuela-capital-southern-area-without-electricity-2026-01-03/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Saturday, referring to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-was-a-surprise-what-could-be-next&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;post-Maduro Venezuela&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The president gave few details and no specific time frame, saying only that the U.S. would “run the country” until a “safe, proper and judicious transition” could be arranged. U.S. oil companies would return to Venezuela, investing “billions and billions” of dollars to reboot the oil sector and the country’s economy. American “boots on the ground” might be deployed in the interim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a remarkable series of statements from a president who has criticized past American nation-building projects, and it raised questions about how exactly the Trump Administration would “run” a country beset by profound challenges. Venezuela, a country twice the size of Iraq, has endured decades of authoritarian rule, corruption, drug-related violence, and economic pain. And for the moment at least, the country’s leader still pledges allegiance to Maduro. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miguel Tinker Salas, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venezuela&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Venezuelan&lt;/a&gt; historian, Professor Emeritus at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomona_College&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pomona College&lt;/a&gt; and Fellow at the Quincy Institute, said that when Trump spoke those words – “we’re gonna run it” – he was stunned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Initially, my jaw dropped,” Salas told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “Even at the height of U.S. influence in Venezuela, in the 1950s, 60s and 70s, they never said they wanted to run the country. And I don't think the Trump administration comprehends the complexity that they're dealing with for a country as diverse and as big as Venezuela.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even those who cheered the U.S. military operation warned of the difficulties that lie ahead. Former National Security Adviser John Bolton, who pronounced himself “delighted” by Maduro’s ouster, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7e7HABk-Ji0&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;told&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; NewsNation the mission was “maybe step one of a much longer process. Maduro is gone but the regime is still in place.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Maduro’s fall is good for Venezuela and the United States,” Richard Fontaine, CEO of the Center for a New American Security, &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/RHFontaine/status/2007514907143467380&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;posted&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on X. “It was a brilliant military operation and the world should be better off because of it. Whether it WILL in fact be better off depends on what happens next. One of the lessons of other regime-change operations is not to topple a government without a plan for what comes next. What comes next in Venezuela seems as vague as the plan for running postwar Gaza under a ‘Board of Peace’.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Venezuelans who might lead&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a news conference following Maduro’s capture, Trump said that Delcy Rodriguez, the regime’s vice president, would lead Venezuela as long as she “does what we want.” And he suggested the U.S. would enforce that arrangement at the barrel of a gun. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re not afraid of boots on the ground,” Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/loud-noises-heard-venezuela-capital-southern-area-without-electricity-2026-01-03/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said,&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; adding that the U.S. might deploy “a second wave” of forces if Venezuelan officials or troops don’t go along with Washington’s wishes. The U.S. naval presence near Venezuela remains in place – the largest such deployment in the region since the 1962 Cuban missile crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day later, Secretary of State Marco Rubio &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/04/us/politics/rubio-military-quarantine-venezuela-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;painted&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a slightly different picture of the U.S. role. “It’s not running — it’s running policy, the policy with regards to this,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Rubio and Trump were clear about the overall approach: in essence, &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do what we say, and things will be fine. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re going to make decisions based on their actions and their deeds in the days and weeks to come,” Rubio&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/04/us/politics/rubio-military-quarantine-venezuela-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; told&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “We think they’re going to have some unique and historic opportunities to do a great service for the country, and we hope that they’ll accept that opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not clear that Rodriguez, the former Vice President, will be a pliant ally. She was sworn in Monday as interim president, after almost immediately accusing the U.S. of invading her country on Saturday. She &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/03/world/americas/delcy-rodriguez-maduro-only-president.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;called&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the operation “a barbarity,” and in an address to the nation said that Maduro was still Venezuela’s head of state. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There is only one president in this country, and his name is Nicolás Maduro Moros,” Rodriguez &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/03/world/americas/delcy-rodriguez-maduro-only-president.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, with other senior officials at her side. Venezuela, she said, would never agree to being a U.S. &quot;colony.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day later she &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/venezuela-acting-president-seeks-us-govt-collaboration-2026-01-05/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;struck&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a less defiant note, calling on the U.S. to work with her government on an “agenda of cooperation oriented towards shared development.” She added that “we prioritize moving towards balanced and respectful international relations between the United States and Venezuela.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not at all clear that’s what Trump has in mind; he insisted that Rodriguez would comply with his wishes – one way or another. &quot;She had a long conversation with Marco [Rubio], and she said, 'We'll do whatever you need,'” Trump said. “I think she was quite gracious, but she really doesn't have a choice.” On Sunday he upped the ante, &lt;a href=&quot;http://v&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;telling&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that if Rodriguez “doesn’t do what’s right, she is going to pay a very big price, probably bigger than Maduro.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts said Rodriguez will have to navigate an almost impossible political tightrope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“She claims to represent a socialist party opposed to U.S. intervention and to U.S. meddling in her internal affairs – so how does she rationalize this to her base?” Salas said. “This is a very difficult, challenging position for her to be in – to on the one hand promise social change reforms, a continuation of Maduro, and at the same time, now become compliant in providing oil to the United States.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond Rodriguez, who serves as both Vice President and minister for oil, other Maduro regime leaders remain in place, including the military chief General Vladimir Padrino Lopez and Interior Minister Diosdado Cabello. They have denounced Maduro’s abduction as well – Padrino &lt;a href=&quot;https://mazo4f.com/en/padrino-lopez-the-countrys-military-forces-are-united-and-cohesive-in-the-face-of-imperial-aggression&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;vowed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to resist “the most criminal military aggression” and ordered a mobilization of Venezuelan forces on land, sea, and air. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts have warned of splits within the army – between hardliners who may refuse to support anyone who bows to Trump’s demands, and others who will stand with Rodriguez no matter what. Such divides could lead to violence and – if Trump is true to his word – a deployment of U.S. “boots on the ground.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael Shifter, a former president of the Inter-American Dialogue, said that while Rodriguez might be able to deliver on Trump’s demands to open up the oil sector, other critical tasks will prove more challenging. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It will be exceedingly difficult if not impossible for her to tame the entrenched corruption and widespread criminality in the country while leaving the machinery of Chavista governance intact,” Shifter told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, using a term for policies begun by Maduro’s predecessor Hugo Chavez. “The risks that chaos, violence and instability will ensue are high, and under that scenario the U.S. would have no choice but to send in troops to stabilize the situation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Control of the military is essential for control of Venezuela, particularly in this unstable moment,” Salas said. “And so far, the commanding general of the military, Padrino, has shown no disposition to break with the PSUV [Maduro’s party].”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Absent in the Trump plans for now is any role for the Venezuelan opposition. The main opposition leader, Maria Corina Machado, who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize last month, issued a statement urging that her political ally, Edmundo Gonzalez, be recognized as Venezuela’s president. Gonzalez was widely seen as the rightful winner of the 2024 presidential vote. “Today we are prepared to enforce our mandate and take power,” Machado &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/04/world/americas/trump-venezuela-leader-rodriguez-machado.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in his news conference after Maduro’s capture, Trump never mentioned Gonzalez, and threw cold water on the prospects of a role for Machado. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I think it'd be very tough for her to be the leader,&quot; Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/04/us/politics/rubio-military-quarantine-venezuela-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;She doesn't have the support or the respect within the country. She's a very nice woman, but she doesn't have the respect.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those remarks left Machado in the odd position of having won her goal of Maduro’s exit, while failing to win the backing of Washington. Salas said Venezuelans he had spoken with “were disillusioned about the fact that Trump essentially threw her under the bus.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked Saturday which American officials would “run” Venezuela, Trump nodded to Rubio, Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth, and General Dan Caine, the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, who flanked the president during his news conference. “The people that are standing right behind me, we’re going to be running it,” Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/04/us/politics/rubio-military-quarantine-venezuela-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That drew a rebuke from Elliott Abrams, a Senior Fellow for the Council on Foreign Relations and longtime hawk in terms of U.S. policy in Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Venezuelans wanted Maduro out and voted against him,” Abrams &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.cfr.org/click/43359392.4336/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuY2ZyLm9yZy9leHBlcnQtYnJpZWYvYXNzZXNzaW5nLXZlbmV6dWVsYXMtZnV0dXJlLWFmdGVyLW5pY29sYXMtbWFkdXJvcy1ib2xkLWNhcHR1cmU_dXRtX3NvdXJjZT1kYWlseWJyaWVmJnV0bV9jb250ZW50PTIwMjYwMTA1/5deac970fc942d4a17cc4f78Bd4ae29de&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;wrote&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the organization’s website. “They did not vote for U.S. rule, and pursuing that path will create instability—exactly what Trump does not want.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The oil factor &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the months-long runup to Maduro’s capture, as the U.S. deployed naval forces to the Caribbean and attacked alleged drug traffickers from the air, the Trump administration justified its actions by invoking the drug trade and the illegitimacy of Maduro’s rule. Oil was rarely mentioned. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, as U.S. officials explain their post-Maduro plans, oil is front and center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, Trump accused Venezuela of seizing U.S. oil assets in the country, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/04/us/politics/rubio-military-quarantine-venezuela-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; U.S. companies would return to operate Venezuela’s state-controlled oil reserves, “spend billions of dollars” and “start making money for the country.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. oil companies have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/backgrounder/venezuela-crisis&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;long history&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Venezuela, dating to the early 20th century, when they came at the government’s invitation to explore and develop oil reserves. Gulf, Shell, and Standard Oil were among the early arrivals, in what proved to be a symbiotic relationship: the companies earned billions of dollars, and Venezuela grew rich; by the mid-1970s, oil revenues had helped make it the wealthiest nation, per capita, in Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1976, Venezuela nationalized its oil industry, creating a state-owned company, Petroleos de Venezuela (PDVSA), that continued to partner with foreign companies. More than two decades later, President Hugo Chavez &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/business/chavez-drives-exxon-and-conocophillips-from-venezuela-idUSN26378950/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;renegotiated&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contracts with foreign oil companies to boost Venezuela’s share of the profits, a move that prompted ExxonMobil and ConocoPhillips to leave the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Venezuela’s oil sector and its broader economy suffered the consequences – a deteriorating oil infrastructure, and U.S. sanctions on Venezuela and the PDVSA. Today, Venezuela &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_Venezuelan_oil_industry&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;produces&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; fewer than one million barrels of oil a day, down from roughly 3.5 million in 1997, and more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://v&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;90 percent&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of Venezuelans live in poverty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Venezuela has been a problem both for the United States and for the Venezuelan people for over 20 years,” Paul Kolbe, a former Director of The Intelligence Project at Harvard University’s Belfer Center, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “For the Chavez years and then the Maduro years, they've driven a country that was once one of the wealthiest in the world, and certainly the wealthiest in South America…into the ground through corruption, poor leadership, poor decisions, and oppression of the people.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only one U.S. oil company – Chevron – has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/17/world/americas/trump-venezuela-chevron-oil.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;remained&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Venezuela, operating under joint ventures with the PDVSA. Rubio’s and Trump’s remarks suggest that the U.S. intends to force Rodriguez, the interim leader, to offer favorable conditions to other American companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But experts aren’t sure the others will return. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ali Moshiri, who oversaw Chevron’s operations in Venezuela until 2017, said the big oil firms won’t go back until they clear signs of change. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Not many companies are going to rush to go into an environment where there’s not stability,” Moshiri &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/05/business/energy-environment/venezuela-oil-us-chevron.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;told&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;He also said that while Chevron and smaller operators could boost the country’s oil output slightly in the short term, a more robust expansion would take years, given the political situation, the state of the country’s oil infrastructure, and the time needed to reestablish operations in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salas echoed the point. “Exporting oil from Venezuela is a challenge,” he told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; “The infrastructure has collapsed. The oil itself that has to be pumped out of the ground is heavy crude, which requires a lot of technology, and billions of dollars of investment. So I'm not convinced that American companies are going to be running in.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A long history of regime change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Maduro mission came exactly 36 years after the surrender of another Latin American dictator – Panama’s Manuel &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manuel_Noriega&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Noriega&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – to face drug charges in the U.S. That operation had its detractors, but in the history of U.S. regime-change missions, it probably counts as a relative success story. The list of other cases is long – and while each episode had its own specific history, there have been few good outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To take three very different examples: The 2003 decapitation of the Saddam Hussein regime in Iraq – which involved a huge force of “boots on the ground” – was celebrated initially by President George W. Bush in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/uncategorized/20-year-retrospective-reflecting-on-the-mission-accomplished-speech-and-its-aftermath/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;“Mission Accomplished”&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; speech, only to unravel in a fierce domestic insurgency that lasted for years, cost more than 4,000 American lives, and led – indirectly – to the rise of the Islamic State. The Kennedy administration backed a coup against South Vietnamese President Ngo Dinh Diem in 1963; Diem was later murdered, unrest followed, and in his memoirs, President Lyndon Johnson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1971/10/17/archives/memoir-terms-kennedy-role-in-diem-coup-a-blunder-book-terms-diem.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;blamed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the coup for the escalation of the Vietnam War. In Iran, the nationalization of the oil industry was at the heart of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1953_Iranian_coup_d%27%C3%A9tat&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;coup&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; orchestrated by the U.S. and Britain in 1953 to overthrow Prime Minister Mohammed Mossadegh. That led to the return to power of Shah Mohammad Reza Pahlavi – and ultimately to the revolution that brought an Islamic theocracy to power in Tehran in 1979.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I immediately am reminded of Iraq, where the military operation was well done and we removed Saddam Hussein pretty quickly in 2003, but then what came after was not great,” Glenn Corn, a former CIA Senior Executive, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “So I hope we've learned that lesson and we're not going to repeat the mistakes we made there.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salas noted that one lesson of the Iraq War involved the perils of driving out the remnants of an ousted regime. “The lesson learned in Iraq was when they attempted to expunge the Ba’ath Party, they realized that they had utter chaos because there was no one there to run the government, no one with experience,” he said. “You had the nation fracture into particular sections, regions, strongmen, military individuals, and others. If that happened in Venezuela, it would be chaotic. The country's very big, very diverse. It has oil regions, it has urban areas, it has an industrial base. So you could imagine that happening on a national scale.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To some, the Maduro operation was reminiscent of an earlier era of American “gunboat diplomacy,” when the U.S. military was deployed regularly to seize territory and resources. The &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;New York Times’ &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;David Sanger noted that Trump installed a portrait of William McKinley in the White House – and it was President McKinley who presided over the U.S. seizures of the Philippines, Guam and Puerto Rico. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The U.S. operation, in seeking to assert control over a vast Latin American nation, has little precedent in recent decades,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/03/us/politics/trump-venezuela-oil-risks.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sanger wrote&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “recalling the imperial U.S. military efforts of the 19th and early 20th centuries in Mexico, Nicaragua and other countries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What comes next&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the uncertainties of the moment, experts said the next phase in Venezuela will hinge on answers to several core questions: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does the Trump administration have an arrangement with Rodriguez and other Maduro regime officials to do the White House’s bidding? If not, how will the U.S. respond if they fail to oblige? Does the U.S. have a plan to remove those leaders? What might trigger that “second wave” Trump referred to, and the deployment of U.S. forces to the country? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What milestones must be met for the end of the interim period? Would elections follow – and would the U.S. organize or oversee those? What will the major U.S. oil companies do? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Uncertainties abound in Venezuela about what comes next,” Shifter said.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;“For now, a framework of coerced cooperation between the Venezuelan regime, now led by Delcy Rodriguez, and the Trump administration, seems to be in effect. But it is far from clear whether that model is viable, much less sustainable.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fontaine said that “the default could well be to work with a compliant President Delcy and most of the existing government. It would be a head of state change more than regime change.” But he added that such an arrangement would do little to satisfy the opposition – the same people who have cheered the news of Maduro’s capture. “Many would-be supporters of this move hoped for the restoration of democracy in Venezuela, not just a different approach on drugs and oil.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also noted that Trump was hardly the first president to decry nation-building projects, only to wind up taking them on. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“For 25 years, every U.S. president has opposed nation-building abroad and then gotten involved in it,” Fontaine said. “Trump, with the commitment to run Venezuela, appears to be the latest. The welcome fall of Maduro is not the end, or the beginning of the end, but the end of the beginning.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Americans Really Think About Trump’s Venezuela Gambit</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/trump-venezuela-maduro-public-opinion-poll/</link>
      <description>New polling offers a revealing look into shifting U.S. public opinion.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, observers watch for cyber, disinformation campaigns in wake of Venezuela raid</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/analysts-watch-heightened-cyber-disinformation-campaigns-following-venezuela-raid/410497/</link>
      <description>Disinformation operations have been spotted, but there are no signs the efforts are being coordinated by a foreign government, one observer said.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annexing Greenland Would Be a Strategic Catastrophe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/greenland-annex-trump-denmark-strategic-catastrophe/</link>
      <description>Any attempt by the United States to claim the island would quickly spiral out of control.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Venezuela Attack Means for China</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/venezuela-china-maduro-capture-trump-attack-oil-taiwan/</link>
      <description>Beijing’s response will test its “all-weather” partnership with Caracas.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATO Leaders Push Back Against Trump’s Greenland Threats</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/trump-annex-greenland-nato-frederiksen-denmark/</link>
      <description>Seven alliance members warn against U.S. imperialism.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 21:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela presents a big headache for big oil</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/06/venezuela-presents-a-big-headache-for-big-oil</link>
      <description>It has been decades since the industry relished foreign-policy entanglements</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 20:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maduro's Trial: What to Look For</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/maduros-trial-what-to-look-for</link>
      <description>The 1990 prosecution of Panama's Manuel Noriega offers a roadmap filled with dicey witnesses and get-out-of-jail cards</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 20:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China and the US Can Make AI Safer for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-china-and-the-us-can-make-ai-safer-for-everyone/</link>
      <description>Trump and Xi have agreed in principle to AI talks. A “smart” security agenda would cut shared risk, not U.S. leverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump Is Channeling George W. Bush</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/trump-venezuela-maduro-bush-iraq-saddam-military-war-victory/</link>
      <description>Iraq showed that removing a dictator isn’t the same thing as overcoming a dictatorship.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Reason China and Russia Won’t Try a Maduro-Style Raid</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/venezuela-maduro-us-operation-china-russia-ukraine-taiwan/</link>
      <description>U.S. rivals aren’t deterred by norms so much as by the limits of their own militaries.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rash of Baltic cable-cutting raises fears of sabotage</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/06/a-rash-of-baltic-cable-cutting-raises-fears-of-sabotage</link>
      <description>But Russian grey-zone attacks may not be the only reason for outages</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Africa newsletter: Life and death in an illegal gold mine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/06/analysing-africa-newsletter-life-and-death-in-an-illegal-gold-mine</link>
      <description>Liam Taylor, a contributor in Africa, reflects on his time at a site of gold—and tragedy</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:52:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Taliban’s ‘Successful’ 2025 Was Anything But</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-talibans-successful-2025-was-anything-but/</link>
      <description>Last year was actually one of increased isolation, regional tensions, and strategic failure.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump still has no clear plan for Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/06/donald-trump-still-has-no-clear-plan-for-venezuela</link>
      <description>Some Republicans fret about a quagmire, and the president’s contempt for democracy</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s missing manufacturing renaissance</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/06/americas-missing-manufacturing-renaissance</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s tariffs have hurt the factories they were meant to protect</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Venezuela Attack May Give China Cover on Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/china-taiwan-maduro-venezuela-sovereignty-norms/</link>
      <description>Beijing will welcome the chance for its own regional hegemony.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I've Tracked Terrorist Networks for Decades. I've Never Seen Anything Like 764.</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/764-terrorism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;In 2021, a fifteen-year-old in a small Texas town started something from his bedroom. He’d dropped out of school. He spent his days online, deep into violence and gore. He found others like him and built a network. He named it after his ZIP code: &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/modern-day-terrorism-online-extremist-network-764-threatening/story?id=127528502&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;764&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within two years, it had spread to every continent. Members – a lot of them teenagers – were finding kids as young as nine on Minecraft and Roblox. They’d befriend them, earn their trust, then trap them. They forced children to hurt themselves on camera. To hurt animals. To do things I’m not going to describe here. That kid from Texas is serving eighty years now. But 764 didn’t stop. It splintered and kept growing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://abc3340.com/news/nation-world/fbi-intensifies-crackdown-on-international-764-child-exploitation-network-crimes-kash-patel-children-federal-authorities&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FBI&lt;/a&gt; currently has over 300 active cases in the U.S. – investigations running in every single field office across the country. They’re looking at more than 350 people tied to the network. Worldwide, authorities believe there are thousands of victims. Arrests connected to groups like 764 jumped nearly 500% in 2025 compared to 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FBI ranks 764 as a “tier one” threat. That’s the same level as ISIS. Last year, Canada became the first country to officially call 764 a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/764-youth-extremist-group-9.7010571&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;terrorist organization&lt;/a&gt;. Not a crime ring. Not predators. Terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran the State Department’s programs against violent extremism. I’ve studied how terrorist groups find and recruit people for most of my career. Canada got this one right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who’s Reading this? More than 500K of the most influential national security experts in the world. Need &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;full access&lt;/a&gt; to what the Experts are reading?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Canada Did&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calling something a terrorist organization isn’t just a label. It changes what governments can do. In Canada, the designation means that anyone who helps 764 – with money, with recruitment, with anything – is now committing a crime. Banks have to freeze assets. Immigration can block people at the border. Law enforcement gets access to tools they can’t use for regular crimes. It also sends a message. When a country puts a group on the same list as Hezbollah and the Islamic State, it tells allies, tech companies, and the public: this is serious. Pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canada’s intelligence service says nearly one in ten of their terrorism investigations now involves a minor. Think about that. We’re not talking about kids as victims – we’re talking about kids as suspects in terrorism cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How They Find Kids&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;764 doesn’t stumble onto victims. &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/rare-public-comments-career-doj-officials-offer-chilling/story?id=128526657#:~:text=Epstein%20files%20so%20far%20don,years%20old%2C%20according%20to%20authorities.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;They go looking&lt;/a&gt; for specific kinds of kids. Depressed kids. Lonely ones. Kids who get picked on at school. Kids who cut themselves or post about wanting to disappear. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/jul/31/far-right-extremists-games-platforms-radicalise-teenagers-report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;They hunt for these signs in Discord servers, on Roblox, in Minecraft&lt;/a&gt; – places your kid probably hangs out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When they find someone, they’re patient. They don’t ask for anything. They just show up. They say “I get it” and “you’re not crazy” and “I’ve been there.” If you’re a thirteen-year-old who feels invisible, having someone actually listen? That hits different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weeks go by. Maybe months. They share darker stuff. Normalize it. Then they ask for a photo – something the kid wouldn’t want anyone to see. Once they have that, everything changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Send more or we show everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most blackmail is about money. Not 764. They want content. They make kids film themselves getting hurt. Humiliated. Some get pushed toward suicide attempts—on camera, while the network watches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One mother told investigators her daughter carved a screen name into her arm with a razor blade. When she finished, the guy on the other end told her he loved her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her daughter said it back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victims Become Recruiters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s what turns 764 from a bunch of predators into an actual network. Members earn status by producing “content.” The worse the content, the higher they climb. They keep files on their victims – records of what they made them do—and trade them like trophies. Kids who started as victims become perpetrators because that’s how you move up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Connecticut, a former honor roll student got caught up in 764. She ended up making bomb threats against her own school – threats phoned in by someone overseas who she thought was her friend. When police searched her devices, they found abuse images, photos of self-harm, and pictures of her paying tribute to the network. Her mom told &lt;em&gt;ABC News&lt;/em&gt;, that “It was very difficult to process, because we didn’t raise her to engage in that kind of activity.” That’s the thing. Nobody raises their kid for this. These children get found, groomed, trapped, and turned. One researcher put it simply, “The most horrendous part is it’s minors doing this to minors.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This Is Terrorism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know – it sounds like the worst kind of predator ring. So why call it terrorism? Because it works exactly like the terrorist networks I’ve tracked for years. Find someone in pain. Give them a worldview that makes sense of that pain. Then get them to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/interactive/2024/764-predator-discord-telegram/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;764 finds broken kids and tells them the world deserves to burn&lt;/a&gt;. That cruelty is honesty. That hurting people is power. The ideology underneath is simple: chaos for its own sake. No political demands. No territory. Just destruction as the point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then they turn victims into recruiters – kids climb the ranks by trapping other kids. The ones who got groomed become the groomers. And it doesn’t stay online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last July, a 764 member in Minnesota stabbed a woman twenty times. In Germany, authorities arrested someone connected to the network on over 120 charges — including murder. In Finland, police are investigating whether two teen suicides are linked to 764. The network shares guides on how to plan real-world attacks. This isn’t abuse that sometimes leads to terrorism. It’s a terrorism pipeline that uses child abuse as its on-ramp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the U.S. Hasn’t Moved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Canada calls this terrorism. Why haven’t we? Our laws weren’t built for this. We’ve got tools to go after foreign terrorist groups. We’ve got tools to prosecute child predators. But 764 started in Texas, spread everywhere, and mixes exploitation with extremism in ways that confuse the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right now, we’re going after these guys one at a time for the abuse. That puts individuals in prison. But it treats 764 like random criminals instead of a network with a shared playbook and a body count that keeps growing. The FBI calls it “one of the most disturbing things we’re seeing.” The Attorney General calls it “one of the most heinous online child exploitation enterprises we have ever encountered.” Meanwhile, kids keep getting trapped. The network keeps growing. And we keep treating each case like it exists in a vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canada made a call. We should make the same one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cipher Brief Expert Dexter Ingram also publishes on Substack &lt;a href=&quot;https://dexteringram.substack.com/p/ive-tracked-terrorist-networks-for?utm_campaign=post-expanded-share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&amp;amp;triedRedirect=true&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Code Name: Citizen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/dec/23/pope-leos-world-day-peace-opportunity-put-words-action/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Does Not Lack Capital - It Lacks Scale</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-technological-innovation-suffers-from-lack-of-market-scale-and-incentives-by-antonin-bergeaud-et-al-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even the best startups cannot thrive sustainably in an environment where each country protects its national champions, and where administrative barriers prevent the emergence of truly European ones. If Europe wants to be a technological power, it must finally implement a genuine single market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Post-Maduro moves; Europe unites over Greenland; Marines’ ‘hidden crisis’; Jan. 6, remembered; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-06-2026/410476/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Airpower Can’t Run Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/06/venezuela-maduro-airpower-trump/</link>
      <description>Any attempt to govern the nation’s future will need collaborators on the ground.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Venezuela Herald a No-Rules International Order?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-venezuela-intervention-and-the-international-order-by-carla-norrlof-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US intervention in Venezuela raises many questions, not just about its legality, but about the international order that the United States has long anchored. Although that order will not suddenly collapse, it will now be costlier and more difficult to sustain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Venezuelan regime is rapidly consolidating its grip on power</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/06/the-venezuelan-regime-is-rapidly-consolidating-its-grip-on-power</link>
      <description>The democratic opposition is left out in the cold</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sure, Turkmen Can Get Visas to Visit the US Again. It May Cost $15,000.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/sure-turkmen-can-get-visas-to-visit-the-us-again-it-may-cost-15000/</link>
      <description>The visa bond pilot program mandates that otherwise eligible applicants for business or tourism visas from select countries, now including Turkmenistan, will have to post a bond of up to $15,000 in order to enter the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela’s Key Takeaways for the World</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuelas-key-takeaways</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/05-january-2026-venezuela-caracas-detail-of-a-statue-on-the-subject-of-oil-in-caracas-venezuela.jpg?id=62672565&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C104%2C0%2C104&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIPHER BRIEF EXPERT INTERVIEW – &lt;/strong&gt;While the U.S. operation to detain Venezuelan president Nicolas Maduro took just hours to execute, a full assessment of its global impact will take weeks or months to fully understand in part, because of the complicated dynamic connecting the country’s assets, allies and oil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Venezuela is what I would call one of those hyphenated accounts,” says Norm Roule, a global energy expert who also served as former National Intelligence Manager for Iran at ODNI. “Venezuela in and of itself is important, but it's also Venezuela/oil, Venezuela/Russia, Venezuela/China, Venezuela/Cuba. There are a lot of different accounts and issues that must be taken into consideration.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela’s partners depend on it for various strategic reasons: &lt;strong&gt;Cuba&lt;/strong&gt; for economic support, &lt;strong&gt;Iran&lt;/strong&gt; for political alignment in Latin America, and &lt;strong&gt;China&lt;/strong&gt; for a notable share of its oil imports. The United States, meanwhile, is signaling a major shift in how it intends to assert influence in the Western Hemisphere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cipher Brief Executive Editor Brad Christian talked with Roule, a leading global consultant on Middle East and Energy issues, about what is likely to happen next as the U.S. signals a major shift in how it intends to assert influence in the Western Hemisphere. Their conversation has been lightly edited for length and clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;expert-block-container expert-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-item&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Norman T. Roule&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.rbl.ms/56514528/origin.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;expert-description&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;expert-name&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts/norman-t-roule&quot;&gt;Norman T. Roule&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;expert-original-about&quot;&gt;
          Norman Roule is a geopolitical and energy consultant who served for 34 years in the Central Intelligence Agency, managing numerous programs relating to Iran and the Middle East. He also served as the National Intelligence Manager for Iran (NIM-I)\n at ODNI, where he was responsible for all aspects of national intelligence policy related to Iran.
    	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE INTERVIEW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: The Trump administration recently released an updated &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/2025-National-Security-Strategy.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;national security strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; that weighed heavily on the Western hemisphere. Are we seeing perhaps the first kind of inclination that this is going to actually be something to pay close attention to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Absolutely. And I think the national security strategy is something that every one of the Cipher Brief's readers and listeners should pull out today. Look at it again, because I can assure you that policymakers around the world - in both our partner and adversary countries - are certainly doing so. If you look at events in Venezuela and read that national security strategy, a number of themes come forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. will be the dominant power in the Western hemisphere. In Venezuela, we saw a display of massive U.S. power and skill in the form of our military intelligence and technology. This is very similar to the display that the world witnessed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts-assess-strikes-response-and-what-comes-next&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Iran last June&lt;/a&gt;. So, this is coming very, very close to two sets of actions. And I think this is meant to be seen also, as the president alluded to in his press conference, as a visible reset of what he described as a previous erosion of U.S. military power in his predecessor's administration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is also showing that the U.S. is now capable of executing what was described by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff as an extraordinarily large and complicated military and intelligence operation, without being leaked. This did not require foreign partners. And it also did not require the disruption of regional commercial air operations. If you listen to what the chairman talked about, this involved 150 aircraft from multiple locations descending upon another country. And other than closing the airspace for a short period of time, commercial air traffic was not disrupted. But you're seeing some other things that are also notable. The U.S. will undertake regime change when it perceives that the existing regime threatens core U.S. national security interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This also represents another U.S. blow against a Chinese partner in the Western hemisphere following the Trump administration's actions in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hks.harvard.edu/faculty-research/policy-topics/international-relations-security/why-panama-canal-president-trumps&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Panama&lt;/a&gt;. The operation also took place on the anniversary of the killing of Iranian Quds Force leader General &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/soleimani-and-the-true-measure-of-deterrence&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Qassem Soleimani&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 as well as the surrender of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/january-3/noriega-surrenders-to-u-s&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Manuel Noriega&lt;/a&gt; in 1990.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are both examples of the long arm of the U.S. government. And certainly, the United States may have thought that the selection of this date would dampen any commemorations by the Iranian government for Soleimani's death in Tehran. Which would have been difficult enough given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/irans-protests-expose-deeper-fragility-as-leaders-struggle-to-contain-crisis&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;ongoing demonstrations&lt;/a&gt; in Tehran. But the ripples from this Venezuela operation will be global. And I think the national security strategy puts some meat on the bone with this operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: Just looking at the intelligence that was needed to pull off an operations like this for a moment, what do you think this says about U.S. intelligence and what would have gone into that for this particular operation?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Well, it tells you a couple of things. It tells you that first, the intelligence was exquisite and up to date. But it also tells you that the intelligence was integrated into the military operation with an intimacy, with care, so that our military personnel were able to move with extraordinary speed to get to the location as quickly as humanly possible. We've seen this in the past with the operation against Osama bin Laden. This is just another example of the close integration between the U.S. intelligence communication and our amazing and extraordinary special forces personnel. I can't speak highly enough of those extraordinary and humble operators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This also shows you the breadth of that intelligence community. The intelligence agencies that were cited included, the National Security Agency (NSA), the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), and the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA). So, you're getting a sense of some very broad intelligence capabilities which were brought to bear and then integrated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The president, I believe, also mentioned that a house had been built in advance. I mean, you're just watching some incredible intelligence capability that was brought to bear by people on the ground over many months. It shows courage, it shows tenacity, it shows you the resources that were pulled together. And it also shows an ability to compartment this information and to prevent a leak. The U.S. government is doing what it's supposed to do. And in a world where we're often complaining about government, the American people and our partners should be gratified that our tax dollars are being well spent. And that the U.S. intelligence community and the military are performing superbly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: There's a lot of connective tissue between Venezuela and the rest of the world when you consider the oil industry, including China. As an energy expert, can you share what’s top of mind for you on the broader impact on the oil and energy markets?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe the best way to answer that is to just explain a little bit about the Venezuelan oil system. First, the operation did not occur near Venezuelan oil production. Upstream oil operations are not located near Caracas, although exports and storage are highly sensitive to obviously, as you correctly put it, a U.S. maritime enforcement of a U.S. embargo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of Venezuela's oil production, about two thirds, is derived from what is known as the Orinoco belt. And oil production from this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-31/venezuela-oil-output-slows-25-in-orinoco-belt-under-us-pressure&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Orinoco belt&lt;/a&gt; had fallen to about 498,000 barrels by the end of December, which is about a 25% drop from just a couple of weeks earlier. And it's been shutting down because they're running out of storage space because Venezuela can't export oil because of the blockade. So, they're trying to put the oil anywhere they can. They've put it in their own storage, they've put it in ships that are docked. They're putting it in almost in teacups at this point because they are running out of space to store the oil that they're producing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let's talk about the oil that is produced in Venezuela. They produce it from tar sands. It's extra heavy. It's a heavy type of crude oil and there are relatively few refineries that can process this grade of oil. It's difficult to extract. It's expensive to extract. Chinese refineries in 2025 tended to get a majority of Venezuelan exports. That amount ranged from 75 to 90% depending upon the amount. But even here, the Chinese tended to put much of that oil in their own storage. And China and Russia tend to be the two big players in Venezuela. For China, it is transactional. Chinese buyers look at it as a way to purchase cheap oil that they again put in storage. It's about 4% of China's exports and China again, has used a shadow fleet of intermediaries to purchase this oil. If China were to lose access to this, it's a problem. But because much of this has gone into storage and there are other suppliers out there in Saudi Arabia and other places, they could make this up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia's a different story. Russia is an enabler of the Venezuelan oil industry. Because Venezuela's oil is so tar heavy, in essence, they need to import &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/science/naphtha&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;naphtha&lt;/a&gt; from Russia and this dilutes the ore and eco output and makes it blendable and then shippable. So, Russia sends in naphtha, it blends the stuff down and then stuff can then be exported. What would happen if suddenly Venezuela is opened up? Well, a couple of things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, because the oil market is relatively well supplied, people would look at it and ask, ‘where are the investment opportunities?’ If you look at the places where the world has changed suddenly and investment opportunities occurred, production didn't dramatically change. Let's take Iraq and Libya for example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Iraq, it took about a dozen years to get back to the level of pre-Saddam. And at that point, China was a major player. The U.S. is now returning to Iraq. In Libya, we're now a number of years after the fall of Gaddafi, and they are still about 25% below production levels under Gaddafi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And again, the U.S. is returning. Much of it does depend upon the security of the country and the stability of the country. So, the president's comments about running Venezuela the right way really does strike at the heart of what happens in the oil industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: Devil’s Advocate here: how does it compete with Texas’ output? What does the U.S. do with that oil? Is it going to be sold to China?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The president and the Secretary of State have talked about stolen oil. What does this refer to? Is there a U.S. case there? I'll leave it to others to talk about the amounts and so forth but when this is talked about, this refers to a 2007 Venezuela expropriation of what I believe was then Conoco Phillips or ExxonMobil investments. That Venezuela did indeed expropriate. So, there is indeed a legal case of Venezuela nationalization of U.S. assets for which the U.S. was not compensated. If Venezuela's government did change and if U.S. oil companies were to go in, could the oil industry be dramatically changed? Yes, but it would depend upon security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe my final comment would be that Chevron has been heavily invested there, and they have maintained a very mature and stable outlook for the country. If you hear Chevron’s CEO speak about Chevron's investments, they've been very levelheaded and unflappable about national security events. So, I think you're going to see them stay there as well. And I think when you listen to the president's comments about how the U.S. would run Venezuela, he seemed fairly confident that the U.S. oil industry would play a role there. Which makes one think that there have been some sort of discussions in this regard playing out in some way in the background.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief: At the most recent &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tcbconference.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cipher Brief Threat Conference&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, there was a lot of discussion around the idea of global conflict and some people believe that we are at the precipice of World War III. Certainly everyone agrees that global disruption is at fairly unprecedented levels. What is your thinking on this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roule:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; We are in a different world, but we're in a world of permanent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-can-the-u-s-better-manage-the-gray-zone&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;gray zone conflict&lt;/a&gt;. But gray zone is defined and very, very differently. Gray zone was once defined by Iranian militias and it was defined by drone attacks or cyberattacks that were non-attributed. But we now have drone attacks or drone flights in Europe that come from God knows where, but they're Russian. We have Chinese routine harassment for more than a decade in the South China Sea. We have routine theft of intellectual property by China and North Korea, which in and of itself is a type of attack against our economy. But it's not necessarily a traditional gray zone attack. Because the people who are often involved in gray zone operations only see a certain number of colors on the palate. But the theft of intellectual property is just another form of attack.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're in that kind of a world and the people who are running the countries, they don't need to launch a war per se. They need to launch a series of short, sharp conflicts. Or short, sharp attacks. Now they said these could lead to a war if people believe we don't care about certain areas. And I do think there is the issue of what could happen in Taiwan in 2026. That should be a worry for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump Administration Could Finally Roll Back China’s Advances in Latin America</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-trump-administration-could-finally-roll-back-chinas-advances-in-latin-america/</link>
      <description>Beijing has torn through the Monroe Doctrine. Post-Maduro Venezuela will be an important test case for the U.S. strategy to change that.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latin America fears what comes next after the Venezuela raid</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/06/latin-america-fears-what-comes-next-after-the-venezuela-raid</link>
      <description>The tactical success of his operation in Caracas appears to have whetted Donald Trump’s appetite for intervention</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Coast Guard Presence Near Senkaku/Diaoyu Islands Reaches Record High in 2025</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/china-coast-guard-presence-near-senkaku-diaoyu-islands-reaches-record-high-in-2025/</link>
      <description>Japan’s Coast Guard is on high alert as China seeks to irreversibly alter the status quo.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Xi Jinping’s New Year Speech Signals to India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/what-xi-jinpings-new-year-speech-signals-to-india/</link>
      <description>As China’s technological and military power continues to grow, the central issue is whether Beijing can accommodate a stable coexistence with India as an autonomous Asian power.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India Avoids Ruffling Trump’s Feathers Over Military Strikes on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/india-avoids-ruffling-trumps-feathers-over-military-strikes-on-venezuela/</link>
      <description>Its carefully worded statement does not condemn the military action. Indeed, it makes no mention of the U.S. at all.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Economic Transformation Will Be Local</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-economic-transformation-must-be-locally-led-by-gordon-hanson-et-al-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it is generating good jobs, navigating the climate transition, stimulating innovation, or building economic resilience, structural transformation is now the name of the game worldwide. While the ends may differ, the means are the same: effective state action, led by subnational governments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bangladesh-India Rift Has Spread to the Cricket Pitch</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-bangladesh-india-rift-has-spread-to-the-cricket-pitch/</link>
      <description>Mustafizur’s removal from the IPL is a yorker to Bangladesh-India relations and regional stability. So much for cricket diplomacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ocean Has Finally Entered the Global Climate Debate</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ocean-moved-to-the-mainstream-of-climate-governance-at-cop30-by-kilaparti-ramakrishna-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world has started to recognize that the climate’s fate depends on what happens to the ocean. At COP30, ocean-based solutions attracted significant attention and investment, but much more must be done to establish the governance structures required for safeguarding this critical planetary system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Risk in Venezuela—To What End?</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/high-risk-venezuela-what-end</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“I knew the possible danger. It was a very dangerous operation. It was amazing that we had a few injured, but all are in good shape right now, but I knew there was great danger. You got off a helicopter. The helicopters were being shot out. They got on the ground amazing talent and tremendous patriotism, bravery. The bravery was incredible…They got off the helicopter and the bullets were flying all over the place. As you know, one of the helicopters got hit pretty badly, but that we got everything back. Got everything back and nobody killed,” meaning Americans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was President Donald Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/program/white-house-event/president-trump-speaks-with-reporters-aboard-air-force-one/671169&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;speaking Sunday&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aboard Air Force One on the way back from Florida about what he observed watching the early Saturday morning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-maduro-2026&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;U.S. raid in Caracas&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that captured Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro and his wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While events in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/venezuela-was-a-surprise-what-could-be-next&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Venezuela&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are still unfolding and I will discuss some below, I use that quote because it illustrates that deaths of American service members is one thing I believe is high in Trump’s mind as he has in recent months undertaken a series of worldwide military actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump almost regularly points out that no Americans have been killed in the four months the U.S. has been blowing up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/caribbean-double-tap-counternarcotics-strike&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;alleged narco-trafficking boats&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. No Americans were lost in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/experts-assess-strikes-response-and-what-comes-next&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;bombing of Iran nuclear facilities&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And despite Trump’s threat that he could put U.S. boots-on-the-ground if needed to “run” Venezuela, there is no immediate indication he has plans to do that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it appears Trump’s plan is to “run” Venezuela using what remains of the corrupt Maduro military/police hierarchy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2026/01/05/trump-demands-venezuela-leader-00711728&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;as long as they do what Trump wants&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. To me it recalls Trump as a builder working with questionable union leaders and construction firms to get jobs done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just why has President Trump spent time and money, first to negotiate with Maduro to get him to leave, and finally to dramatically oust the Venezuelan President from office?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I divert for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday, the original beginning of this column was, “Most fentanyl and methamphetamine trafficking into the U.S. occurs through official ports of entry along the southwest border, according to DEA (Drug Enforcement Agency).”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was a quote from a Government Accountability Office (GAO) report entitled, &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;“&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-26-107918&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illicit Synthetic Drugs: Trafficking Methods, Money Laundering Practices, and Coordination Efforts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,” &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;that was sent to Congress and released publicly December 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GAO’s report, including the finding cited above, focuses attention on fentanyl primarily coming into the U.S. through land ports of entry while the Trump administration made its anti-fentanyl focus on attacking narco-trafficking swift-boats initially from Venezuela, claiming they were headed for the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More recently, the attacks, and killing of those aboard, have been those in the eastern Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/31/us/politics/trump-boat-strikes-coast-guard-drug-operations.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; published a story by Carol Rosenberg that discussed what happens when U.S. Coast Guard cutters intercept narco-trafficking boats, seize drugs and capture those aboard – but not kill 115 on 35 speedboats as the U.S. military did last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Putting together the December GAO report and the &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;story raised some serious questions about the rationality of the Trump administration’s so-called anti-drug program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Up to that time, interception of drug-carrying boats and interrogation of the crews gave valuable information on drug routes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, as &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; noted, “Attorney General Pam Bondi directed [U.S.] prosecutors in February to mostly stop bringing charges against low-level offenders in favor of bigger investigations.” According to &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, “For the most part, people captured by the Coast Guard in the same smuggling routes the U.S. military is bombing are being repatriated -- either directly, before reaching the United States, or through deportation after briefly being questioned near U.S. ports.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; noted that many earlier captured crew members were “poor, undereducated farmers or fishermen [who] would reach cooperation agreements that offered details of their engagement at the bottom rung of the drug smuggling business in exchange for possible leniency.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; quoted Tampa-lawyer Stephen M. Crawford, who in the past had been assigned to represent defendants captured by the Coast Guard, who said the killing of crew members without prosecution amounted to very dangerous “political theater.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I could say the same today for what I consider today’s ill-thought-out Trump actions in Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What national security news are you missing today? Get full access to your own national security daily brief by upgrading to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscriber+Member&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; status.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As many others have pointed out, returning democracy to the Venezuelan people was not uppermost in Trump’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, in announcing the raid, Trump told reporters he had not been in contact with Venezuelan Opposition leader and Nobel Peace Prize laureate María Corina Machado. He then went on to say, &quot;I think it'd be very tough for her to be the leader. &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/7343295/venezuela-machado-trump-nobel-peace-prize/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;She doesn't have the support or the respect within the country&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. She's a very nice woman but she doesn't have the respect.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I believe Trump meant was that the Maduro power structure – the Venezuelan Army, Bolivarian National Police and urban paramilitary networks known as &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;colectivos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; -- remain active and it is they that don’t “respect” Machado.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are also probably the reason there are no U.S. boots-on-the-ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, Trump seems to believe that by keeping major U.S. military forces near Venezuela, he can threaten additional military attacks to keep the ex-Maduro crowd in line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Trump put it Sunday on Air Force One, “Venezuela thus far has been very nice, but it helps to have a force like we have. You know, we were ready for a second wave. We were all set to go, but we don't think we're going to need it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently it is Venezuela’s oil which is primarily on Trump’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with other matters, Trump seems to be living in the past as illustrated when he told reporters over the weekend, “We [the U.S.] had a lot of oil there [in Venezuela]. As you know they threw our companies out, and we want it back.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nationalization was the culmination of a decades-long effort by Venezuelan administrations of both the right and the left to bring under government control an industry that an earlier leader had largely given away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;American oil companies, including Exxon and Mobil, which merged in 1999, and Gulf Oil, which became Chevron in 1984, were hit hardest. The Dutch giant Shell was also affected. The companies, which had accounted for more than 70 percent of crude oil production in Venezuela, lost roughly $5 billion in assets but were compensated just $1 billion each, according to news stories from that period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, Trump said, “The oil companies are ready to go. They're going to go in, they're going to rebuild the infrastructure. You know, we built it to start off with many years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They took it away. You can't do that. They can't do that with me. They did it with other presidents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to several sources, major oil companies &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2026/01/05/business/venezuela-trump-oil-chevron&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;are not eager&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to spend the years and money at the present time to revive the Venezuelan oil industry, but as with much about the Venezuelan situation, there’s little yet that is predictable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One potentially dangerous outcome, looming already, is how Trump reads what he so far considers his military success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday he made &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/International/live-updates/venezuela-live-updates-trump-give-details-after-us?id=127792811&amp;amp;entryId=128901259&amp;amp;userab=abc_web_player-460*variant_b_abc_dmp-1901%2Cotv_web_player-461*variant_b_otv_dmp-1903%2Cotv_web_content_rec-445*variant_c_trending-1851%2Chp_banner-426*variant_a_control-1777&amp;amp;userab=abc_web_player-460*variant_b_abc_dmp-1901%2Cotv_web_player-461*variant_b_otv_dmp-1903%2Cotv_web_content_rec-445*variant_a_control-1849%2Chp_banner-426*variant_a_control-1777&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;open threats&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to both Colombia and Cuba.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He called Colombian President Gustavo Petro “a sick man who likes making cocaine and selling it to the United States. And he's not going to be doing it very long, let me tell you?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And as for Cuba, Trump said, “Cuba always survived because of Venezuela. Now, they won't have that money coming in. They won't have the income coming in.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He then went on to point out, “You know, a lot of Cubans were killed yesterday. You know that. A lot of Cubans were killed…There was a lot of death on the other side.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then Trump quickly added, as I have pointed out before, “No death on our side.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who's reading this? 500K+ dedicated national security professionals. Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Japan Be the World’s Next AI Leader?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/will-japan-supportive-regulatory-environment-give-rise-to-ai-leaders-by-hiroshi-mikitani-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Japan has so far taken an “innovation-first” approach to AI governance, avoiding stringent rules or penalties that could stifle adoption or experimentation. Firms must make the most of this supportive environment to build the tools that can help offset the economic effects of population aging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a Strong Baht Bad for Thailand’s Economy?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/is-a-strong-baht-bad-for-thailands-economy/</link>
      <description>Despite the country's stagnant economy, the baht gained nearly 9 percent against the dollar over the course of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
