<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>A long-awaited trade truce between America and India</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/02/a-long-awaited-trade-truce-between-america-and-india</link>
      <description>Will it last?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S.-China Economic Cold War Is No Longer Silent</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-china-economic-cold-war</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION —&lt;/strong&gt; For decades&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the United States (U.S.) operated under a fatal delusion that free trade with China would liberalize its politics and that the global market was a neutral playing field. We were profoundly wrong. In 2000&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the U.S. controlled 37% of global semiconductor fabrication. Today&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; we control less than 12%&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; while China is on track for 40% by 2030. While we played by the rules of Adam Smith&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; Beijing played by the rules of Sun Tzu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are now in the midst of a silent asymmetric economic war. China does not have a private sector in the American sense. Under its strategy of Civil Military Fusion&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; every ByteDance algorithm and every ton of refined lithium is a dual use asset of the Chinese Communist Party. Meanwhile&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the U.S. encouraged the atrophy of its industrial base by prioritizing short term profits from outsourcing to China instead of securing our own economic and national security future. The West created this irrational strategic vulnerability where Beijing now controls 80% of refined rare earth supplies and more than 60% of the magnets in actuation systems for the F35.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recognizing that economic security is national security&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the Trump administration has installed a genuine war cabinet for economic conflict. This includes the Treasury and Commerce Secretaries&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; but the pivot is most visible at the Department of War. There the Deputy Secretary, is a battle&lt;u&gt;-&lt;/u&gt; tested private equity leader who left his firm in order to bring his skills to fight and has operationalized a new offensive strategy to link private sector dynamism with state imperatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tip of this spear is the newly chartered Economic Defense Unit or EDU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Directly overseen by the Deputy Secretary of War and run by another private equity industry specialist in industrial consolidation, the EDU is not another regulator. It functions as an internal merchant bank designed to bypass the Pentagon’s notoriously slow procurement cycles. The EDU has replaced compliance&lt;u&gt;-&lt;/u&gt; based bureaucracy with commercial first financing. Its mandate is to generate investable demand signals using the government balance sheet to de-risk private capital investment in the defense industrial base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of vague promises&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the EDU now utilizes Advance Market Commitments. These are binding contracts to purchase critical technologies such as solid rocket motors or autonomous drones before the factories are even built. This transforms government contracts into bankable assets that companies can use to secure private loans. Furthermore&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the EDU has restructured acquisition management&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; replacing narrow Program Executive Officers with Portfolio Acquisition Executives who are authorized to move capital rapidly across capability sets much like a private equity managing partner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Complementing this is the transformed Office of Strategic Capital or OSC. Once merely an advisory body&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the OSC has been re codified by the FY2026 NDAA into a direct capital allocator. It is aggressively bridging the valley of death not just for software but for heavy manufacturing. By offering direct loans and guarantees specifically for equipment finance&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the OSC ensures that American companies can afford the high capital machinery needed to onshore production of semiconductors and batteries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This architecture represents a total departure from the status quo. We are moving from a system that audits costs to a system that finances outcomes. The Army parallel initiative to grant Direct Commissions to Silicon Valley engineers further reinforces this culture shift – destroying the wall between the Pentagon and Palo Alto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The message to the American private sector is clear. The era of neutrality is over. There is no free market left to win if China ends up owning the building blocks of every major industry. Wall Street and Silicon Valley must partner with the USG not out of charity&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; but out of necessity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The administration has built the financial and policy architecture for economic sovereignty. American capital now faces the simplest decision in its history, which is to deploy here and own the 21st century&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; or deploy elsewhere and become its tenant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump, Modi Reach Long-Awaited U.S.-India Trade Deal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/us-india-trade-deal-trump-modi-tariffs-russia-oil-european-union/</link>
      <description>New Delhi has vowed to stop purchasing Russian oil in exchange for reduced U.S. tariffs.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What We Know About the India-U.S. Trade Deal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/us-india-trade-deal-trump-modi-oil-russia-venezuela/</link>
      <description>Trump announced the deal in a social media post on Monday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Trade Deals With Russia Won’t Bring Peace</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/why-trade-deals-with-russia-wont-bring-peace/</link>
      <description>“Here we are once again, thinking that business can transform political relationships,” said one formerly Moscow-based risk analyst.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 20:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Transatlantic Energy Relationship Is Stronger Than Ever</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/us-europe-transatlantic-energy-relationship-greece-lng/</link>
      <description>And here’s how to make U.S.-European energy ties even more resilient.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 20:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI is not the only threat menacing big tech</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/02/ai-is-not-the-only-threat-menacing-big-tech</link>
      <description>Are Meta and Google ads really recession-proof?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An election that hopes to bring democracy back to Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/02/an-election-that-hopes-to-bring-democracy-back-to-bangladesh</link>
      <description>But voters are having to pick between Islamists and a tainted party from the past</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right to die spreads in America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/02/the-right-to-die-spreads-in-america</link>
      <description>States that are home to a third of Americans could soon allow it</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s opacity brings Pekingology back into vogue</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/02/chinas-opacity-brings-pekingology-back-into-vogue</link>
      <description>What, for example, is behind Xi Jinping’s sweeping military purge?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the hopeless effort to quash cocaine by force</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/02/inside-the-hopeless-effort-to-quash-cocaine-by-force</link>
      <description>Commando raids in the Colombian jungle are little better than whack-a-mole</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A social network for AI agents is full of introspection—and threats</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/02/a-social-network-for-ai-agents-is-full-of-introspection-and-threats</link>
      <description>How worried should you be about Moltbook?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Europe do nuclear deterrence without America?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/02/can-europe-do-nuclear-deterrence-without-america</link>
      <description>Britain and France are deepening their co-operation</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Tariff-Era Dollar, Your Problem</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-widening-gap-between-financial-role-and-trade-effects-of-dollar-by-qiyuan-xu-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The greenback’s effective depreciation on the trade side and its continued stability on the financial side will likely not last forever, at which point the US economy could be forced into a painful rebalancing. But until that day arrives, non-US economies should not assume that a weaker dollar will deliver the usual relief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Why Xi keeps gutting his own army</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/02/the-war-room-newsletter-why-xi-keeps-gutting-his-own-army</link>
      <description>Shashank Joshi, our defence editor, explores what it means for China’s military readiness</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: CBP’s wartime rhetoric; Agents’ high crime rate; Russian drone kills miners; Israeli strikes kill 32 in Gaza; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-02-2026/411123/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Drug Policies in Asia Make a Turn Toward Human Rights in 2026?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/will-drug-policies-in-asia-make-a-turn-toward-human-rights-in-2026/</link>
      <description>Looking back at the past decade, positive measures were significantly outweighed by the brutal violence exacted by drug policies in the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Trump’s Tariffs on Latin America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-tariffs-uneven-effect-on-latin-america-make-case-for-trade-diversification-by-eugenia-andreasen-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Latin American and Caribbean region has weathered the increase in US import tariffs relatively well, although certain countries and sectors have been more affected than others. But the more fraught global trade environment has underscored the need to deepen ties with regional and extra-regional partners.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia’s H200 Chips Re-enter China – But Beijing Isn’t Giving up on Huawei</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/nvidias-h200-chips-re-enter-china-but-beijing-isnt-giving-up-on-huawei/</link>
      <description>Even with controlled access to H200 chips, China will continue to incentivize the growth of domestic chipmakers.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenland’s Worth a Fight and Russia’s Trying to Start One</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/greenlands-worth-a-fight-and-russias-trying-to-start-one</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;The “quickest way for Russia to penetrate our naval defenses is steaming from the Arctic to the North Atlantic.” The Greenland-Iceland-United Kingdom (GIUK) Gap is the last place allied forces “have any hope of detecting a Russian sub before it’s in the vast Atlantic barreling toward New York.” These insightful comments were spoken not by President Donald Trump but by &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/__0Qubv3Dn8?si=bkhDFuCxgHg63TXE&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fictional President Grace Penn&lt;/a&gt; in Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;The Diplomat&lt;/em&gt;. By contrast Trump’s rhetoric and attempts to gain leverage on Denmark have been appalling and unhelpful. But Trump and “President Penn” are both right about one thing — although the Arctic island is remote, Greenland’s location makes it fundamental to U.S. and NATO naval intelligence and missile defense missions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia knows this as well and is using the Trump-inspired kerfuffle to &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/russia-watches-us-european-tensions-greenland-glee-gloating-129427398&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;drive a disinformation narrative&lt;/a&gt; intended to further weaken Euro-Atlantic relations. Kremlin-aligned sources have been circulating social media posts suggesting that Western aid to Ukraine has weakened European countries and that weaponry committed to Kyiv may be redistributed to Greenland. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsguardrealitycheck.com/p/russian-fakes-make-the-most-of-europes#:~:text=Actually%3A%20The,Kremlin%20bot%20activity.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;deepfake&lt;/a&gt; of a Danish newscaster stating that Denmark plans to recall all F-16s given to Ukraine to be redeployed to Greenland was circulated by Russian influence accounts and received over 45.3K &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghostarchive.org/archive/e7tU3&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;views&lt;/a&gt; on X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsguardrealitycheck.com/p/russian-fakes-make-the-most-of-europes#:~:text=Another%20video%20imitated,sent%20via%20email.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;, which received over 254.3K &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghostarchive.org/archive/UBxYr&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;views&lt;/a&gt; on X, imitated the Institute for the Study of War and claimed that Europeans siding with Ukraine in 2022 is costing them Greenland now and that NATO will be destroyed soon, thereby forcing Europeans to align with Moscow. This Russian &lt;a href=&quot;https://subscriber.politicopro.com/newsletter/2026/01/trumps-greenland-play-is-fueling-russian-disinfo-campaigns-00581185#:~:text=FUEL%20ON%20THE,Russia%2DUkraine%20war.%E2%80%9D&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tactic&lt;/a&gt; of riffing off legitimate think tanks and news channels to validate Russian &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdd.org/analysis/2024/09/26/how-u-s-adversaries-undermine-the-perception-of-election-integrity/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lies&lt;/a&gt; is essential to making their false pro-Kremlin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdd.org/analysis/2024/10/29/foreign-malign-election-meddling-persists-but-struggles-to-gain-traction/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;narratives&lt;/a&gt; appear more credible and increase the likelihood of their posts spreading across social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moscow is trying to use the divide between the United States and Europe to sow confusion, degrade support for Ukraine, and rupture NATO. What Putin forgets is that disagreements between allies are common and constructively overcoming them builds stronger relationships. The strategic importance of Greenland demands the alliance work through its disagreement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are significant reasons why Russia is trying so hard to split NATO over Greenland. Nuuk holds significant naval intelligence value. Moscow’s Northern Fleet and nuclear submarine HQ are on the Kola Peninsula, located near the Russia-Finland border. For Russian (RU) forces to reach the North and Baltic Seas, and beyond into the North Atlantic Ocean, RU submarines must transit through the GIUK Gap; making the two stretches of water critical for monitoring RU subsea activity, just as “President Penn” demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the growing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationaldefensemagazine.org/articles/2025/7/16/just-in-china-russia-arctic-allyship-appears-to-grow-but-distrust-presents-roadblocks-report-says&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;partnership&lt;/a&gt; between Beijing and Moscow in the Arctic and China’s increasing interest in the region over the past decade should raise red flags for NATO. In 2018, China released their first Arctic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/BRIE/2018/620231/EPRS_BRI(2018)620231_EN.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;white paper&lt;/a&gt;, in which they called themselves a “near-Arctic state” and detailed a desire to establish a “polar silk road.” Since then, China and Russia have performed numerous joint air and naval patrols in Arctic waters. Coordination between U.S. adversaries in the High North places an even higher value on NATO Arctic maritime intelligence capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greenland is also strategically important for missile defense operations. Nuuk is a prime location for American early warning systems to track intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs) with trajectories that arch over the High North. The Pentagon currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://simpleflying.com/us-air-force-base-greenland-strategic-role/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;operates&lt;/a&gt; a variety of early warning radars and communications systems at Pituffik Space Base in Greenland. These radars work in tandem with systems in Alaska and Canada to provide essential early warning capabilities for U.S. missile defense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ICBMs launched by Moscow can reach the United States in approximately 40 &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2026/01/20/us-news/greenland-critical-for-us-to-fend-off-icmbs-from-russia-and-beyond-experts/#:~:text=%E2%80%9CMost%20Americans%20are,in%20the%20US&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;minutes&lt;/a&gt;, offering the Pentagon’s command and control centers, and the president himself, extremely limited time to detect, decide, and respond. This mission set will expand as Russia develops long-range conventional hypersonic missiles that will also use a High North flight route.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prioritizing and expanding U.S. military radar and communication systems in Greenland will certainly be part of the “underlayer” elements of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euronews.com/next/2026/01/19/what-is-donald-trumps-proposed-golden-dome-missile-defence-system-and-how-would-it-work#:~:text=US%20President%20Donald,or%20from%20space.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Golden Dome&lt;/a&gt; missile defense effort, allowing for Russian missiles of all varieties to be detected earlier and provide U.S. and Canadian warfighters additional reaction &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2026/01/20/us-news/greenland-critical-for-us-to-fend-off-icmbs-from-russia-and-beyond-experts/#:~:text=Doran%20explained%20that%20positioning%20Golden%20Dome%20interceptors%20in%20Greenland%20would%20give%20the%20US%20a%20bigger%20cushion%2C%20or%20margin%20of%20error%2C%20for%20detecting%20and%20shooting%20down%20an%20incoming%20nuke.%C2%A0&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;time&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia will always be a malevolent actor and adversary in the High North, and the Kremlin will utilize any advantage and division among Arctic allies to sow disinformation, destabilize alliance efforts, and advance its own interests. Although the political particularities of Nuuk lie in the hands of Greenland, Denmark, and the United States, the geostrategic and deterrence value of the island is shared among all NATO allies; and should be a factor that unifies and strengthens the alliance, not something that divides Western partners and advances adversarial interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rear Admiral Mark Montgomery (U.S. Navy, ret.) is the Senior Director of the Center on Cyber and Technology Innovation and Senior Fellow at the Foundation for Defense of Democracies (FDD), where Emmerson Overell is a project coordinator.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Export Controls Backfire: The China Innovation Paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/export-controls-backfire-the-china-innovation-paradox</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/this-aerial-photograph-taken-on-january-14-2026-shows-the-building-housing-the-headquarters-of-chinese-ai-startup-deepseek-in-h.jpg?id=63688027&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C53%2C0%2C54&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export Controls Backfire: The China Innovation Paradox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;When the Biden administration rolled out its semiconductor export restrictions in October 2022, the logic seemed airtight: cut off Beijing’s access to advanced AI chips, and you’d put the brakes on China’s tech ambitions. Three years on, that bet looks a lot shakier than anyone in Washington expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of paralyzing China’s AI sector, these controls have promoted domestic self-reliance. With no choice but to develop indigenous workarounds and architectural innovations, Chinese businesses are&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/chinas-progress-semiconductors-and-implications-us-national-security&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;rapidly&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; decoupling AI progress from sheer hardware volume. U.S. policies have undoubtedly bought time, but they have also ushered in a parallel innovation ecosystem totally independent of Western influence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the Trump administration is trying a different tack. By allowing conditional chip&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-08/nvidia-set-to-win-us-approval-to-export-h200-ai-chips-to-china&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;exports&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to approved Chinese customers, complete with revenue-sharing arrangements, the White House appears to be hedging its bets. The strategy banks on maintaining some leverage through controlled access rather than outright denial. Yet critics caution this could backfire spectacularly: American companies might be financing the very Chinese AI capabilities designed to render them&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/expert-brief/consequences-exporting-nvidias-h200-chips-china&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;obsolete&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both strategies, it seems, lead to uncomfortable places.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The DeepSeek Shock and Algorithmic Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, DeepSeek’s&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;new&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;R1 model sent tremors through Silicon Valley and Washington. The Chinese startup demonstrated AI reasoning capabilities closely mirroring those of OpenAI’s ChatGPT o1, without access to cutting-edge chips restricted by U.S. export controls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Algorithmic efficiency is a useful technique that enables developers to achieve reasonable performance compared to frontier models through inference-time optimization—essentially adapting the achievements of others for your own purposes,” Martijn Rasser, Vice President of Tech Leadership at the Special Competitive Studies Project, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “DeepSeek’s engineering is genuinely impressive, and this ‘fast follower’ strategy is very attractive for price-sensitive, commoditized AI applications.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By optimizing inter-chip memory bandwidth on less sophisticated H800 chips, DeepSeek&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/01/27/1109346/deepseek-r1-ai-model-china-breakthrough/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;achieved&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; competitive performance through algorithmic efficiency rather than brute force. According to the MIT Technology Review, Chinese startups are responding to export restrictions by prioritizing efficiency, resource pooling, and collaboration, thereby gaining an edge over competitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The breakthrough, however, should not be overinterpreted, Rasser warns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Algorithmic efficiency and raw compute aren’t substitutes at the frontier — you need both,” he says. “Training next-generation foundation models, achieving breakthroughs in areas like protein folding or materials science, and developing the most advanced autonomous systems all require massive compute that efficiency gains alone cannot replicate.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other analysts see the dynamic playing out along different timelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“AI progress is shaped by two concurrent trends: pushing the capability frontier requires ever-greater computing power, yet over time, reaching any given capability level requires less and less computing power,” James Sanders, Research Associate at the Center for a New American Security, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While American AI companies continue advancing along the compute-intensive frontier, Chinese firms constrained by chip shortages focus instead on the lower-cost, lower-capability portion of the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If the U.S. continues to maintain its computational dominance, China will likely continue to play a role as a fast follower, rather than leader, in AI capabilities,” Sanders explains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smuggling Networks and Systematic Circumvention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from inventiveness under constraints, Chinese companies have also shown remarkable versatility by smuggling goods through shell companies and elaborate smuggling operations. The procurement of chips for Huawei’s Ascend 910 AI processor is one of the most dramatic examples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Congressional&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.commerce.senate.gov/2024/11/combating-threats-from-china-s-semiconductor-industry&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;testimony&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Huawei used shell companies to deceive Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company into manufacturing approximately 2 million computer chiplets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, a smuggling ring operating under the company name “Luxuriate Your Life” reportedly purchased $390 million worth of&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/us-prosecutors-charge-chinese-national-with-illegally-exporting-ai-chips-2024-10-25/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;servers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from Dell and Supermicro containing banned Nvidia graphics processing units, then smuggled them into Malaysia for ultimate delivery to Chinese customers. Hundreds of controlled chips have subsequently been sold in Shenzhen markets as vendors trade restricted AI technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dramatic scale of smuggling operations thus raises fundamental questions about enforceability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“No export control regime is 100% leakproof,” Rasser acknowledges. “But the goal should be making evasion costly, risky, and limited in scale rather than expecting perfect enforcement.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He contends that the most effective approach is drawing a clear line: semiconductors exceeding certain performance thresholds should not be sold to end users in countries of concern at all, regardless of stated end use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sanders takes a more optimistic view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“America has the ability to reduce AI chip smuggling to negligible levels if it wanted to. It only requires the political will to do so,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology that verifies a chip’s location could reduce smuggling to negligible levels, Sanders argues, noting that Nvidia has reportedly built such a capability and several congressional bills have proposed mandating location verification for exports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Even with the level of smuggling we see today, export controls on advanced AI chips are still effective,” Sanders insists. “They impose a large differential cost on China’s AI development and make it much harder for these chips to be obtained and used by adversaries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Self-Sufficiency Acceleration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most significantly for long-term strategic competition, export controls have supercharged China’s decades-long quest for semiconductor self-sufficiency. At a February 2025&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/deepseek-moment-chinas-ai-ambitions&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;meeting&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; between Chinese Communist Party Chairman Xi Jinping and technology executives, Huawei founder Ren Zhengfei reported that his previous concerns about domestic advanced semiconductor production had eased due to recent breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A CSIS analysis underscores that Ren stated he is leading a network of more than 2,000 Chinese companies working collectively to ensure that China achieves self-sufficiency of more than 70 percent across the entire semiconductor value chain by 2028.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rasser is skeptical of the ambitious timeline.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This timeline is not credible for leading-edge semiconductors,” Rasser observes. “If he means trailing-edge components and packaging, 2028 might be achievable. But if he means the advanced logic chips that power AI training and high-performance computing, it isn’t.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese firms still can't build the ultra-precise manufacturing equipment needed to produce chips at the most advanced nodes, he points out. But that hasn't stopped Beijing from doubling down. Overall chip investment dipped slightly in early 2025, yet spending on semiconductor&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductors.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/SIA_Government-Incentives-and-US-Competitiveness-in-Semiconductor-Manufacturing_Jul-2023.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;equipment&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; jumped more than 53 percent, a clear signal that China is dead serious about building out a complete domestic supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government has channeled well over $150 billion into semiconductor&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductors.org/strengthening-the-global-semiconductor-supply-chain-in-an-uncertain-era/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;development&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from 2014 through 2030, according to Semiconductor Industry Association analysis — an investment equivalent to the U.S. CHIPS Act virtually every year since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bifurcation Dilemma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unintended consequence of U.S. export controls may be accelerating the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iss.europa.eu/content/tech-war-escalation-deeper-look-us-chip-export-controls&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;bifurcation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of global technology ecosystems into incompatible, competing supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consequently, we are faced with a strategic paradox: Does a China that relies on Western chips but is constrained by American controls pose a lower long-term risk than one that operates in a technologically autonomous fashion beyond American eyesight?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A technologically autonomous China certainly poses a greater risk of strategic surprise,” Rasser concedes. “But the alternative framing — that we could maintain Chinese dependency on Western technology indefinitely—isn’t realistic. It ignores history, Chinese strategy, decades of mercantilist industrial policy, and the inherent difficulty of controlling technology diffusion over long time horizons.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The better frame, he suggests, is that export controls buy time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The question is what we do with that time,” Rasser continues. “Years of constrained Chinese progress are years during which the United States and allies can extend their own technological lead, build more resilient supply chains, strengthen alliances with key semiconductor nations, and shape the trajectory of AI governance.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sanders echoes this assessment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“China is determined to develop a fully domestic AI chip industry, and will likely eventually be able to do so,” he notes. “The real question is whether we equip China to compete with American AI leadership today.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fundamental constraint on Chinese domestic AI chip production, Sanders points out, isn’t the lack of logic chips but access to advanced manufacturing&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnas.org/publications/reports/securing-semiconductor-supply-chains&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;equipment&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Strengthening and fully enforcing current export restrictions on semiconductor manufacturing equipment is the most important step in preventing China from developing an AI chip industry that could outcompete America’s,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet the competitive landscape extends beyond manufacturing capacity alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Supply Chain War&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leland Miller, co-founder and CEO of China Beige Book, who serves on the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission, however, sees the entire framework shifting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The trade war is dead,” he tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “This is a supply chain war. Beijing wants to weaponize supply chains for leverage. Tariffs are background noise now.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miller notes that China has advantages in data, talent, energy, and scale. Their weakness remains computing — advanced chips and lithography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That’s why H100s matter so much,” he says, referring to Nvidia’s high-end processors. On open-source AI platforms like&lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/spaces/open-llm-leaderboard/open_llm_leaderboard&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;Hugging Face&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Chinese dominance is already evident. “Seventeen of the top 20 models are Chinese,” Mike Kuiken, Vice Chair of the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission, tells &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “Software plus enough hardware can close gaps. That’s why this moment is dangerous.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration’s December 2025&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/us-allows-conditional-export-nvidia-h200-chips-china-2025-12-15/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;decision&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to allow conditional exports of Nvidia H200 chips to approved Chinese customers in exchange for a 25 percent revenue stake represents recognition that absolute denial may be neither achievable nor desirable. Yet Beijing has reportedly discouraged state-linked firms from adopting these chips, while Chinese companies like Huawei and Alibaba continue to advance domestic AI alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controls have bought time — China’s AI development has slowed, and the U.S. still holds the edge in cutting-edge tech. The more complex question is whether Washington can consolidate that lead before Beijing circumvents the restrictions entirely, potentially causing an even bigger crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The goal isn’t perpetual dependency, it’s ensuring that when China does achieve greater autonomy, the strategic balance still favors us,” Rasser concludes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Middle-Power Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/middle-power-dilemma-interests-rarely-align-especially-in-short-term-by-eswar-prasad-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney's call for the rest of the world to join forces in managing a new era of economic and geopolitical turmoil will certainly resonate with national leaders worldwide. But the path to unity among middle powers is fraught, because interests within such a broad grouping rarely align.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s New Viral App Asks: Are You Dead?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/chinas-new-viral-app-asks-are-you-dead/</link>
      <description>Demumu’s success reveals a complex reality of solo living and changing social ties.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of China's Strategic Soft Power and its Global Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-rise-of-china-s-strategic-soft-power-and-its-global-impact</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; The United States is currently mired in a cycle of aggressive trade renegotiations and a transactional foreign policy that has alienated its most critical allies. By perceiving partners as free riders on American defense investments, Washington is increasingly defaulting to raw financial and military coercion, or hard power. While cultural attraction remains a core Western strength, this shift toward transactionalism is allowing the global power balance to tilt decisively in China’s favor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China has successfully evolved from the world’s manufacturing engine into an innovation powerhouse, with massive investments in research and development now yielding strategic dividends. The old adage, &quot;USA innovates, China replicates, Europe regulates,&quot; is being rendered obsolete as Beijing takes the lead in high-tech research, dominates renewable energy supply chains, and weaponizes its monopoly on rare earth materials. This is not just a technological shift; it is the foundation of a new form of systemic influence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soft power, the ability to influence through attraction rather than coercion, is now a primary battleground for Beijing. In its 2010-2015 5-Year Plan, China explicitly identified cultural products like computer animation, books, and social media as strategic priorities, and is expected to spend over $10Bn per year. Today, that strategy is manifest in TikTok, where international audiences are fed a curated diet of technological wonders and friendly diplomacy, while the domestic version (Douyin) remains strictly regulated. This curated reality leverages Western influencers paid to travel to China to marvel at bullet trains and flying cars, effectively masking the tightening grip of government control and persistent domestic poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The silver screen has become a frontier for this historical revisionism. The evolution of Oriental Dreamworks illustrates the point: after the original Kung Fu Panda sparked national soul-searching in China over why a Western studio told their story better, Beijing forced a co-production model. This ensured that subsequent global hits, like The Abominable, which sparked international backlash for including the nine-dash line, served as vehicles for Chinese territorial and cultural narratives. Similarly, the success of The Three-Body Problem on platforms like Netflix signals a shift from passive consumption to the strategic export of techno-optimism, reshaping how the West perceives China’s past and future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lately one of China’s most potent soft power assets, however, is its strategic silence. In a world defined by shock events, from the 2025 Indo-Pakistani conflict to the Venezuelan raids to arguing over Greenland, Beijing projects a calculated lack of surprise. While United States foreign policy is viewed as an erratic series of active disruptions, China markets itself as a pillar of stability. By refusing the role of global savior, Beijing avoids the inevitable backlash of interventions while presenting its intentions, most notably regarding Taiwan, as historic certainties rather than chaotic ruptures. This perceived predictability is the velvet glove that makes its authoritarian consistency look like a safe harbor for global markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The change in soft power execution (or lack thereof), both by the United States and China, has yielded quantifiable results. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2025/07/15/views-of-the-us-have-worsened-while-opinions-of-china-have-improved-in-many-surveyed-countries/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2025 Pew Research Center survey &lt;/a&gt;of 28,000 adults shows the favorability gap between Washington and Beijing closing fast. Even inner circle partners are decoupling: in &lt;strong&gt;Australia&lt;/strong&gt;, importance placed on economic ties with China (53%) has eclipsed the U.S. (42%) for the first time. In &lt;strong&gt;Canada&lt;/strong&gt;, reeling from American rhetoric regarding annexation and the Greenland crisis, favorability for the United States plummeted from 87% to 67%. &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Brazil &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;Argentina &lt;/strong&gt;all view the United States as their highest threat, while the &lt;strong&gt;United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Netherlands&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Germany &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;Sweden &lt;/strong&gt;think of the United States as their second highest threat, only surpassed by &lt;strong&gt;Russia&lt;/strong&gt;. When the world’s most stable democracies begin to view the United States as a greater threat to their sovereignty than China, the global architecture of power has already moved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This erosion between the United States and its NATO allies is precipitating a tangible financial and geopolitical divorce. As European pension funds signal a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rog0QA0s3WI&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pivot toward non-American assets and gold&lt;/a&gt; to hedge against United States volatility, Washington has resorted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/news/trump-warns-retaliation-europe-sells-141827096.html?guccounter=1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hard-power retaliation&lt;/a&gt;, to counter rising interest costs on its own federal debt, but risks further alienating allies. This shift is giving rise to a Western middle-power bloc, where leaders from Canada to the U.K. are bypassing United States hegemony to secure autonomous ties with Beijing, most recently shown in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cm24k6kk1rko&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Canadian trade deal with China&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/uk-approves-china-plan-its-largest-embassy-europe-despite-espionage-fears-2026-01-20/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;London approving a new embassy&lt;/a&gt; before their prime minister is set to visit China next month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Domestic Crisis of American Soft Power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States faces a disadvantage in this competition that is as much internal as it is external. While cultural attraction remains a Western strength, America is stuck in a cycle of political division and a pervasive internal culture war. This domestic fragmentation has direct geopolitical consequences, creating a soft power deficit by eroding internal stability and the reliability that allies previously took for granted. When a superpower’s domestic policy is defined by institutional distrust and crippling polarization, its foreign policy becomes erratic, swinging violently between administrations and leaving partners to wonder if today’s agreement will survive tomorrow’s election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this climate, Washington is increasingly defaulting to financial and military coercion, hard power, to maintain influence. By viewing alliances through a purely transactional lens, the United States signals that its leadership is no longer based on shared values, but on momentary leverage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Authoritarian Impact of the Chinese Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conversely, China’s authoritarian system provides a strategic soft power advantage by ensuring internal dissent never detracts from international ambitions. While the United States is distracted by internal quibbling over social issues, Beijing’s centralized control allows it to project a facade of unwavering stability and consistency. The CCP’s absolute control over society prevents political in-fighting from slowing its global expansion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This marketed reliability is a powerful tool. To many developing nations, the Chinese model, which prioritizes state security and economic growth over the perceived chaos of liberal democracy, looks increasingly attractive. China is expertly using this image to mask the reality of structural debt traps and economic coercion they have expertly laid in the Global South, particularly in Africa and Central Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, this is also China’s greatest weakness. Democratic values, such as a free press, labor rights, data and public privacy and private ownership are values where the West, and America in particular, still is attractive and acts as a magnet. While China might be a partner, they might not be a role model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Collision Course with an Existential Vacuum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Transatlantic alliance is now on a collision course with an existential power vacuum. If the West fails to move past aggressive theater and nurture shared security architectures, it will cede the century to a model that demands compliance in exchange for short-term financial benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For any nation flirting with realignment toward China, the warning is stark: China offers immediate liquidity, but demands a level of sovereign collateral that eventually leaves the partner more vulnerable than it was before the investment began, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/chinas-economic-coercion-lessons-lithuania&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lithuania’s experience&lt;/a&gt; with economic sanctions has shown. Old alliances between America and Europe should not be so quickly forgotten. All indications are that Chinese soft power, backed by an undistracted authoritarian state, could eventually be followed by hard power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soft power should not be discarded so quickly. There is strength in a shared Western cultural heritage that attracts nations precisely because it avoids totalitarianism. However, if America cannot find a way to resolve its internal dissent and project a unified front, it risks losing the very American Example that once served as its greatest global asset, and part of its allies with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Compromise Olympics</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/winter-olympics-climate-milan-cortina-compromise/</link>
      <description>How Milan Cortina became the Winter Games nobody wanted to fight about.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why South America’s Right Won’t Align With Trump on China</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/trump-south-america-latin-china-venezuela-brazil-argentina-mexico-right-maga-china/</link>
      <description>Even the most MAGA of the region’s leaders can’t abandon their motor of economic development.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record Trade Surplus Masks China’s Underlying Economic Weakness</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/record-trade-surplus-masks-chinas-underlying-economic-weakness/</link>
      <description>China’s world-leading export surplus delivered headline growth in 2025, but slowing domestic demand, falling prices and doubts over data credibility point to an economy losing momentum beneath the surface.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Misinformation Kills</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/kennedy-anti-vaccine-policies-causing-preventable-disease-and-death-by-peter-singer-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disregard for scientific evidence by opponents of vaccination, led by US Secretary of Health and Human Services Robert F. Kennedy Jr., is producing exactly the harms experts predicted: disease outbreaks, preventable deaths, and the reversal of decades of progress in public health. The consequences could become truly catastrophic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSTO Sends Weapons to Tajikistan to Secure Afghan Border</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/csto-sends-weapons-to-tajikistan-to-secure-afghan-border/</link>
      <description>The decision to arm Tajikistan's border troops comes after months of cross-border attacks, but the CSTO's track record gives little reason for confidence.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Justice Looks Like for Rohingya Women</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-justice-looks-like-for-rohingya-women/</link>
      <description>For Rohingya women, the question is not whether violence can be legally defined or classified, but whether such naming alters the material conditions of their lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A United Front to Tame Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democracies-must-stand-together-against-trump-might-makes-right-worldview-by-chris-patten-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s foreign policy rests on contempt for longstanding allies and a belief that force alone matters in international affairs. The path forward, as Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney argued in Davos, lies in midsize democracies banding together to preserve what remains of the postwar order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Israel Courts the Far Right in Europe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/israel-courts-far-right-europe-netanyahu/</link>
      <description>The parties include some with a history of antisemitism.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Has Killed American Deterrence</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-national-defense-strategy-lacks-credible-commitment-by-stephen-holmes-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deterrence fails not only when threats to act or retaliate lack credibility, but when the absence of credibility tempts adversaries into recklessness. A leader like Donald Trump, who cannot commit and is disloyal to even his closest allies, is not merely ineffective; he is dangerous because he tempts adversaries to act recklessly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving the Australia-India Maritime Partnership Forward Through Coast Guard Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/moving-the-australia-india-maritime-partnership-forward-through-coast-guard-cooperation/</link>
      <description>Institutionalizing engagements across their coast guard agencies can help strengthen the maritime security architecture of the Indo-Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rueben Dass on the Nexus Between Emerging Technologies and Terrorism in India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/rueben-dass-on-the-nexus-between-emerging-technologies-and-terrorism-in-india/</link>
      <description>Commercial availability and ease of access to drone systems – particularly commercial-off-the-shelf drones – could increase their prominence in terror plots in India.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracks in India’s ‘Hindu Unity’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/cracks-in-indias-hindu-unity/</link>
      <description>Tension between traditional spiritual authority and political Hindutva is growing. Religious leaders feel that the government is not sincere about the Hindu cause.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What It Took for George H.W. Bush to Invoke the Insurrection Act</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/02/insurrection-act-george-bush-la-riots/</link>
      <description>The president’s decision to send troops to Los Angeles received broad national, bipartisan support.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peace Through Leverage in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/peace-through-leverage-gaza</link>
      <description>How to limit Hamas’s influence and ensure Israel’s compliance.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi the Destroyer</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/xi-destroyer</link>
      <description>The latest military purge signals China’s leader is entering a new era.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unable or Unwilling?: Indonesia’s Failed Natural Disaster Response</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/unable-or-unwilling-indonesias-failed-natural-disaster-response/</link>
      <description>The human and environmental impact of the recent floods in Sumatra is the result of years of ecological destruction and failures in disaster governance.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People’s Party Extends Lead in Polls Ahead of Thai General Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/peoples-party-extends-lead-in-polls-ahead-of-thai-general-election/</link>
      <description>The progressive party remains in pole position, but it remains to be seen whether it can win enough seats to form Thailand's next government.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia Stops Blocking Grok Chatbot After Assurances From Parent Company</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesia-stops-blocking-grok-chatbot-after-assurances-from-parent-company/</link>
      <description>Southeast Asian states' efforts to restrict the service may offer signs of how the region plans to regulate AI services going forward.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Dependencies Undermine UK National Security</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/tech-dependencies-undermine-uk-national-security</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the UK focuses on hybrid threats, is it being undermined by dependencies on US providers? Can the UK have a national security agenda in isolation?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Thai Political Parties Can – and Cannot – Say About Military Reform</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-thai-political-parties-can-and-cannot-say-about-military-reform/</link>
      <description>Ahead of next week's election, the major parties' platforms reflect different conceptions of military reform as well as a growing convergence on key aspects of reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Cheap Oil Strategy Is Becoming a Geopolitical Liability</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/chinas-cheap-oil-strategy-is-becoming-a-geopolitical-liability/</link>
      <description>Beijing’s reliance on discounted crude from Russia, Iran, and Venezuela is colliding with political reality, and the strains are starting to show.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
