<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Initial Sentinel ICBM expected by early 2030, Air Force says</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/02/initial-sentinel-icbm-expected-early-2030-air-force-says/411483/</link>
      <description>Officials say a new Pentagon-controlled manager role helped accelerate the Sentinel timeline.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 23:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Myth of ‘996’ Work Culture</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/17/china-work-culture-996-myth-labor-business/</link>
      <description>In most Chinese workplaces, the stereotype is far from the reality.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A U.S.-India Trade Deal Can’t Restore Lost Trust</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/17/us-india-trade-deal-lost-trust-trump/</link>
      <description>Trump’s approach has done damage to bilateral ties that won’t so easily be repaired.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hectic Day for U.S. Negotiators</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/17/us-negotiations-geneva-iran-nuclear-deal-russia-ukraine-war/</link>
      <description>Washington is trying to tackle Iran’s nuclear ambitions and the Russia-Ukraine war at the same time.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s envoys failed to reassure Europe</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/17/donald-trumps-envoys-failed-to-reassure-europe</link>
      <description>A gathering of world leaders in Munich shows how trust has collapsed</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Gulf’s most powerful countries are at odds</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/17/why-the-gulfs-most-powerful-countries-are-at-odds</link>
      <description>A feud between Saudi Arabia and the UAE will have far-reaching consequences</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How big is the prize of reopening Russia?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/17/how-big-is-the-prize-of-reopening-russia</link>
      <description>The Kremlin is promising $12trn-worth of deals to Donald Trump’s administration</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will investing in Russia really bring America a $12trn bonanza?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/17/will-investing-in-russia-really-bring-america-a-12trn-bonanza</link>
      <description>The Kremlin is making big promises to Donald Trump’s administration</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Playing Good Cop/Bad Cop With Europe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/17/trump-europe-munich-vance-rubio-good-bad-cop/</link>
      <description>The United States is conducting diplomacy by way of the &quot;Law and Order&quot; television show.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 20:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The financialisation of AI is just beginning</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/17/the-financialisation-of-ai-is-just-beginning</link>
      <description>Get ready for a new wave of securities, hedges and collateral</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beware China’s shrinking car market</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/17/beware-chinas-shrinking-car-market</link>
      <description>The resulting flood of exports will be good news for consumers. Less so for the world’s carmakers</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off the Charts newsletter: Coping with outliers</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2026/02/17/off-the-charts-newsletter-coping-with-outliers</link>
      <description>Sarah Leo, our visual data journalist, explains how to deal with unruly data points</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope and Disappointment in India</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/can-india-live-up-to-its-enormous-potential-by-kaushik-basu-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India’s promise is undeniable, yet political dysfunction and empty rhetoric continue to undermine its long-term prospects. The absence of reliable statistics, lagging innovation, and worsening air quality all point to institutional decay that only sustained, coordinated national action can reverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Second carrier to Mideast; Hormuz closure; AI fallout at DOD; El Paso drone weapon; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-17-2026/411461/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Financing the Global South’s Infrastructure Boom</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/financing-global-south-infrastructure-boom-by-rakesh-mohan-and-divya-srinivasan-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Across the Global South, one of the biggest challenges is not just to build more infrastructure, but to build it right. Without institutional capacity and financial depth, the increasingly popular public-private-partnership model can backfire, creating a vicious spiral of debt, delays, and disillusionment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s Royalist Right Turn</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-did-conservative-royalists-win-thailand-election-by-thitinan-pongsudhirak-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a rock-solid parliamentary majority, as well as the backing of the military and judiciary, the royalist-conservative Bhumjaithai Party is poised to spend its full four-year term governing in the service of establishment interests. But that does not mean it will all be smooth sailing ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The flaws in India’s AI plans</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/17/the-flaws-in-indias-ai-plans</link>
      <description>Despite hosting a global summit, it is a bystander in the race to develop frontier models</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Interpretation: Who Governs the Korean DMZ?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-politics-of-interpretation-who-governs-the-korean-dmz/</link>
      <description>The legal disagreement over who controls DMZ access – South Korea’s government or the U.N. Command – has evolved into a full-fledged institutional and political confrontation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redrawing the Map of American Prosperity</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-us-states-can-bring-economic-opportunity-to-neglected-american-regions-by-joseph-parilla-1-and-rohan-sandhu-1-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a country as large and diverse as the United States, expanding economic opportunity cannot and should not depend on volatile federal policies. A framework of directed improvisation that aligns federal and state priorities with local capacities offers a promising way to promote broad-based development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Needs to Get Creative on Hong Kong</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/america-needs-to-get-creative-on-hong-kong/</link>
      <description>American leaders are rightly condemning Jimmy Lai’s sentence. But when it comes to concrete policy responses, Washington’s cupboard is increasingly bare.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan’s Protracted Fight Over the Defense Budget</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/taiwans-protracted-fight-over-the-defense-budget/</link>
      <description>Defense spending in Taiwan continues to be politically contentious, particularly as the U.S. seeks to pressure the opposition KMT over the issue.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Uzbekistan, ‘Farmers Have No Freedom’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/in-uzbekistan-farmers-have-no-freedom/</link>
      <description>A new report exposes abuse and exploitation of cotton and wheat farmers in Uzbekistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conflicting Policies, Confused Investors, and the Weak Dollar</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-populism-weakening-the-us-dollar-by-sebnem-kalemli-ozcan-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States’&amp;nbsp;unique economic advantages –&amp;nbsp;deep financial markets, a strong institutional framework, and the world's dominant reserve currency – should not be mistaken for invincibility. In fact, markets are already pricing US policy uncertainty the same way they price that of countries that do not have a reserve currency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defending the Homeland: Pentagon Shifts Strategy on Drone Threats</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/defending-the-homeland-pentagon-shifts-strategy-on-drone-threats</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;“This memorandum consolidates approximately ten separate outdated memoranda that were inadequate to address the current, complex unmanned aircraft system (UAS) threat environment. The new guidance affects a culture shift by empowering commanders to unambiguously apply their authority to mitigate threat UAS. Our message is clear, Department of War (DoW) airspace is off limits, and our commanders on the ground have the discretion to defend our airspace against all manner of UAS threats…Expanding the Defensive Perimeter : Grants commanders the authority to extend defensive actions beyond the physical ‘fence line’ of an installation; allows for the adequate protection of covered facilities, fixed assets, and mobile assets; placing trust in the commander and maximizing their flexibility to defend facilities and assets.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s a quote from last Tuesday’s Defense Department (DoD) press release, &lt;em&gt;Fact Sheet: C-UAS [counter unmanned aircraft systems] Policy in the U.S. Homeland&lt;/em&gt;. It was issued just hours before the Federal Aviation Agency (FAA) temporarily closed airspace within an 11-mile radius of El Paso International Airport, but after Customs and Border Protection (CBP) personnel on the day before [Monday, February 9] used a classified Pentagon laser system on nearby Fort Bliss Air Base, to shoot down what they thought were drug cartel UAS systems [drones], but turned out to be metallic party balloons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth last month had approved lending the 20-kilowatt directed-energy LOCUST [laser] weapon to CBP for use on the Fort Bliss installation, whose fence line is on the Mexican border.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CBP test was not coordinated with the FAA and the resultant uproar, which subsequently involved the White House and Congress, marks only the beginning of what I believe will be a series of similar episodes related to homeland protection against suspect UAS drone systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An interesting sidelight to last week’s events: The Senate Armed Services Committee was scheduled to have a meeting last Thursday morning with two Pentagon drone experts, Owen O. West, DoD&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Senior Advisor for Drone Dominance, and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Travis Metz, Drone Dominance Program Manager. It was called off at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What national security news are you missing today? Get full access to your own national security daily brief by upgrading to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; status.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drones are becoming smarter, more autonomous and more widespread, and as their uses grow the lines get blurry between legitimate and illegitimate, secure and not secure, particularly in metropolitan areas. There are strict FAA rules that govern drones over 55 pounds or any flown for non-recreational purposes. There are even some FAA requirements for outdoor flying of smaller drones for personal pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back on June 6, 2025, President Trump issued an Executive Order (EO) called Restoring American Airspace Sovereignty that dealt primarily with UAS. It said of them, “criminals,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;terrorists, and hostile foreign actors have intensified their weaponization of these technologies, creating new and serious threats to our homeland. Drug cartels use UAS to smuggle fentanyl across our borders, deliver contraband into prisons, surveil law enforcement, and otherwise endanger the public. Mass gatherings are vulnerable to disruptions and threats by unauthorized UAS flights. Critical infrastructure, including military bases, is subject to frequent — and often unidentified — UAS incursions. Immediate action is needed to ensure American sovereignty over its skies and that its airspace remains safe and secure.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump’s June 2025 EO also said that the United States must have a secure and strong domestic UAS industrial base and that relying on UAS produced in foreign countries as well as foreign-made UAS critical components pose unacceptable national security risks to the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one response, the June EO called for, “The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense; the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the FAA; the Secretary of Homeland Security; the Director of OMB; and the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, shall promptly take all appropriate steps…with regard to the creation of the National Training Center for Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems (Center), and, upon establishment of the Center, focus initial training provided by the Center on development of Federal and SLTT [State, Local, Tribal, and Territorial] capabilities to secure major upcoming national and international sporting events held in the United States, such as the FIFA World Cup 2026 and the 2028 Summer Olympics.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By December 2025, the FBI had established the National Counter-UAS Training Center (NCUTC) at Redstone Arsenal in Huntsville Alabama where the Bureau already had cybersecurity, intelligence, and forensic training. Ever since, the NCUTC has been training officers from state, local, tribal, and territorial agencies on how to detect drones using radar, radio frequency sensors, and related technologies. More important, they are trained how to identify whether a drone is authorized or hostile, assess threats, and coordinate responses across various agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During training, the FBI emphasizes that offensive actions against drones only occur when legally authorized, but the rules are complex. The FAA website, to assist law enforcement personnel responding to drone incidents, has created a three-part video series that covers the basics of drone regulations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An additional response to the Trump June 2025 EO was Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth’s establishment in August 2025 of Joint Interagency Task Force 401 (JIATF 401) to replace the Pentagon’s then existing Joint C-sUAS Office. Operating under the Secretary of the Army, Hegseth’s order said, “JIATF 401 will be a joint activity and established as a jointly manned organization. The Military Services will support JIATF 401 with timely joint manning…This&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;new task force is empowered with broader authorities, funding flexibility, and rapid acquisition capabilities. Its mission is to strengthen U.S. airspace sovereignty, protect personnel and facilities, and outpace adversaries’ growing drone threats. With joint manning, interagency collaboration, and streamlined governance, JIATF 401 is designed to deliver innovative, mission-ready solutions at speed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an example of cooperation, last Thursday, Army Brig. Gen. Matt Ross, JIATF 401 Director, visited the FBI's NCUTC in Huntsville yesterday. He met with Mike Torphy, FBI acting assistant section chief for UAS and counter-UAS, and discussed security preparations for this summer's soccer FIFA World Cup activities. Ross and Torphy also met with expert instructors who are teaching a specialized course for local law enforcement in each of the soccer tournament's eleven host cities across the nation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the more unusual steps underway in the drone security field was announced by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) last December 21. It referred to “a [White House] National Security Determination regarding the unacceptable risks posed by UAS and UAS critical components that are produced in foreign countries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It added that, “U.S. cybersecurity and critical infrastructure guidance has repeatedly highlighted how foreign manufactured UAS can be used to harvest sensitive data, used to enable remote unauthorized access, or disabled at will via software updates.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, the FCC has updated its so-called Covered List, which identifies foreign-made communications equipment and services that pose unacceptable risks to U.S. national security, and thus cannot be imported for sale or use in the U.S. The action, taken by the FCC last December 22, prohibited the future imports of both foreign-made UAS and UAS components, but does not affect any previously-purchased drone, nor does it prevent retailers from continuing to sell, import, or market foreign drone models or parts approved earlier in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found one of the best descriptions of the drone security dilemma was in a sales brochure entitled &lt;em&gt;Countering UAV Threats&lt;/em&gt;, produced by BAE Systems, a leading defense contractor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BAE brochure said, “Detecting small and inexpensive UAVs remains one of the most persistent operational challenges facing today’s militaries. These platforms possess small radar cross-sections, produce minimal acoustic and thermal signatures, and often operate at low altitudes within ground clutter. Many are capable of autonomous flight with little or no radio frequency (RF) emission, making traditional detection methods unreliable. Urban and vegetated terrain further complicate detection, as buildings and foliage create blind spots and signal reflections that mask UAV movement. Adverse weather, restricted lines of sight and interference from birds or civilian activity introduce additional uncertainty.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then brochre went on, “A connected challenge is distinguishing between hostile and civilian UAVs. Attribution and intent are major challenges, as it is often unclear who controls a UAV and for what purpose it is being used, particularly in grey-zone or proxy scenarios. The compressed decision timelines of UAV operations further complicate matters, as engagements frequently occur in seconds, leaving little room for deliberation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Needless to add, last week the Air Force Life Cycle Management Center, Eglin Air Force Base, Florida awarded BAE a cost-plus-fixed-fee $145 million contract for the development, manufacturing, and delivery of Counter Unmanned Aerial Systems weapon systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with everything else, the drone problem is worth keeping an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who's reading this? 500K+ dedicated national security professionals. Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Cuba's Infrastructure Crisis Is Opening the Door to Foreign Intelligence Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-cuba-s-infrastructure-crisis-is-opening-the-door-to-foreign-intelligence-networks</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/topshot-view-of-the-nico-lopez-oil-refinery-in-havana-cuba-on-february-12-2026-russia-is-expected-to-supply-cuba-with-oil.jpg?id=64944872&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C56%2C0%2C57&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;On February 13, nighttime light emissions across major Cuban cities had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2026-cuba-oil-supply-power-grid-blackout/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dropped&lt;/a&gt; as much as 50 percent compared to historical averages — the latest chapter in a crisis that has seen the island's grid collapse multiple times over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As desperate citizens in half the country waited in the dark, something else was accelerating along the island's few electrified corridors. Chinese technicians continued installing telecommunications equipment, Russian engineers maintained radar stations, and intelligence operatives from both nations embedded themselves deeper into Cuba's crumbling infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just 90 miles from Florida, Cuba's energy crisis has metastasized from an economic catastrophe into a national security vulnerability. Although Havana struggles to maintain the lights, Beijing and Moscow have come to Cuba's aid not as charitable donors but as strategic opportunists seeking to expand their intelligence-collection capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The State Department &lt;a href=&quot;https://cu.usembassy.gov/alert-increased-nationwide-power-outages-to-include-havana/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; just one day after the latest outage that &quot;scheduled power cuts occur daily, and unscheduled outages persist throughout Cuba.&quot; The island's thermoelectric plants, many dating back decades, now operate at barely &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/cuba-energy-crisis&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt; percent of their capacity. In February, five of eight Turkish-leased floating power &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.med-or.org/en/news/cuba-guarda-alla-cina-per-risolvere-la-crisi-energetica&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plants&lt;/a&gt; departed Cuban ports after Havana failed to meet payment obligations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The crisis has intensified dramatically as Cuba's oil lifelines have been severed. Following the U.S. seizure of control over Venezuelan oil operations in early January, Mexico had become Cuba's primary supplier, shipping nearly 20,000 barrels per day through September 2025. Yet, under mounting pressure from the Trump administration, which threatened tariffs on any country supplying Cuba with oil, Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum announced in late January that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2026/01/28/nx-s1-5691086/mexico-oil-shipments-cuba&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shipments&lt;/a&gt; had been at least temporarily halted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The figure had already plummeted to about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/mexico-cuba-trump-oil-tariff-9.7069046&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;7,000&lt;/a&gt; barrels per day, leaving Cuba essentially without oil imports for the first time in years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The breakdown has created an opening that America's strategic competitors are exploiting with alarming sophistication. From this vantage point, intelligence services can monitor U.S. military installations across the Southeast, track Space Force &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/chinas-intelligence-footprint-cuba-new-evidence-and-implications-us-security&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;launches&lt;/a&gt; from Cape Canaveral, intercept communications from Southern Command headquarters in Florida, and observe naval movements throughout the Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Beijing and Moscow, Cuba's desperation has become an important windfall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beijing's Digital Footprint Expands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China's presence in Cuba has grown exponentially, particularly in telecommunications and digital infrastructure. In testimony before Congress last May, national security analysts confirmed that satellite imagery identifies at least four Chinese-linked signals intelligence &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/beijings-air-space-and-maritime-surveillance-cuba-growing-threat-homeland&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facilities&lt;/a&gt; across Cuba — Bejucal, Wajay, and Calabazar near Havana, plus a newly constructed site at El Salao near Santiago de Cuba.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Cuba's proximity to the homeland continues to make the island an attractive intelligence platform for U.S. adversaries,&quot; Connor Pfeiffer, senior director of government relations at Foundation for the Defense of Democracies Action, tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. &quot;Within 400 miles of Havana sit the headquarters of the U.S. combatant commands for Latin America and the Middle East, U.S. Special Operations Command, and air bases that regularly host advanced U.S. fighter aircraft.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need a daily dose of reality on national and global security issues? Subscriber to The Cipher Brief’s Nightcap newsletter, delivering expert insights on today’s events – right to your inbox. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscribe&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for free today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Cuban telecommunications companies struggle with outdated Soviet-era equipment and chronic power failures, Chinese firms, particularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csis.org/analysis/chinas-intelligence-footprint-cuba-new-evidence-and-implications-us-security&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Huawei&lt;/a&gt; and ZTE, have positioned themselves as the only viable solution. These companies aren't simply selling hardware; they're installing the very networks through which Cuba's limited internet traffic flows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Because of this proximity, intelligence outposts in Cuba provide signals intelligence and other capabilities that are invaluable to Beijing and Moscow,&quot; Pfeiffer explains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The El Salao site features a circularly disposed antenna array, a configuration highly effective at determining the origin and direction of incoming high-frequency signals. These installations can track signals up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalsecurity.org/intell/library/news/2024/intell-240702-voa01.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;9,300&lt;/a&gt; miles, providing Beijing with unprecedented visibility into U.S. military communications and operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, MacDill Air Force Base in Tampa, home to U.S. Central Command and Special Operations Command, sits less than 300 miles from Cuban shores. Naval Station Mayport in Jacksonville, Naval Air Station Key West, and dozens of other sensitive military installations across Florida, Georgia, and Alabama all operate within easy range. The advantage over satellite surveillance is stark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;By contrast to what can be obtained from overhead satellite images and other collection from satellites in low earth orbit whose time passing overhead can be anticipated, the ELINT facilities in Cuba are a constant presence with line of sight to key U.S. facilities,&quot; Evan Ellis, research professor of Latin American Studies at the U.S. Army War College Strategic Studies Institute, tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure crisis has made Cuba more dependent on Chinese technical expertise. In February 2025, Chinese Ambassador Hua Xin and Cuban President Miguel Díaz-Canel announced China would construct 55 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.med-or.org/en/news/cuba-guarda-alla-cina-per-risolvere-la-crisi-energetica&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solar&lt;/a&gt; plants by the end of 2025, with an additional 37 planned by 2028. If completed, the network would add over 2,000 megawatts of capacity. However, this dependency gives Chinese intelligence services unprecedented access to Cuban government communications, military installations, and infrastructure systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;During the present U.S. military operations in the Caribbean, and in a future U.S. conflict in the Indopacific involving U.S. deployment from bases on the Atlantic seaboard and transit through the Caribbean, the Chinese electronic intelligence gathering facilities in Cuba are well positioned to capture not only things like radio transmissions, but the emissions from U.S. facilities, and the signatures of U.S. ships and other forces,&quot; Ellis underscores.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In simpler terms: China's Cuban listening posts can intercept not just what U.S. forces communicate, but the electronic fingerprints of their equipment, from radar emissions to communications arrays and ship propulsion systems. By using these signatures, adversaries can identify specific vessels and aircraft, track their movements, and potentially develop countermeasures to defeat U.S. military technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moscow's Renewed Military Presence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia's intelligence footprint in Cuba never entirely disappeared after the Cold War, yet Moscow's activities have intensified dramatically. In March 2025, Russia and Cuba signed a military &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.kremlin.ru/acts/news/78222&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cooperation&lt;/a&gt; agreement that Russian lawmakers ratified in October. Ukrainian intelligence estimates that between 6,000 and 7,000 Cubans are currently fighting as mercenaries in Russia's war against Ukraine — the second-largest foreign contingent after North Korea's approximately &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defensenews.com/global/europe/2025/10/30/ukraine-closes-havana-embassy-over-cuban-fighter-pipeline-for-russia/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;12,000&lt;/a&gt; troops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than operating out of a single massive facility like the Soviet-era Lourdes complex, Russian intelligence has embedded personnel and equipment within ostensibly civilian infrastructure projects. Russian engineers arrive whenever Cuba's power grid requires emergency maintenance, bringing more than just technical skills. When radar systems at Cuban air defense installations fail, Russian specialists provide upgrades with built-in collection capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia has also leveraged Cuba's energy crisis to deepen military cooperation through increasingly frequent naval port calls in Havana; visits that allow Russian intelligence personnel to rotate in and out without scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not everyone in the intelligence community shares the alarm. Critics argue the threat is being overblown by voices eager to justify increased defense spending or maintain hardline Cuba policies that have failed for six decades. Some policy experts argue the infrastructure crisis actually presents an opportunity. If Washington eased sanctions and provided assistance to Cuba's energy sector, Havana would have less incentive to accommodate Chinese and Russian intelligence requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet Ellis rejects the notion that Cuba could credibly reduce its ties to Beijing and Moscow in exchange for U.S. economic relief.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Although U.S. economic coercion, taking advantage of Diaz-Canel's currently desperate economic state, could facilitate a deal in which Cuba promises to reduce its Cuban or Russian presence, Cuba will promise to comply to the degree that it can without truly breaking those ties to China and Russia, which for it are both ideological allies and partners in its survival,&quot; he continues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regime's dependency, Ellis stresses, runs too deep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Not until there is a sincerely democratic pro-US regime in Cuba will the U.S. be truly secure from the type of extra-hemispheric threats that Cuba, like Venezuela, can host in the Caribbean,&quot; he asserts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The desperation-dependence cycle gives Beijing and Moscow leverage that extends beyond traditional espionage. Cuban officials are not in a position to demand transparency when Chinese technicians install new telecommunications equipment. Moreover, when Russian engineers service radar installations in Havana, the government lacks leverage to refuse requests for expanded intelligence cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Without Venezuelan oil aid, the Cuban regime faces acute energy shortages and reduced inflows of much-needed foreign currency,&quot; Pfeiffer says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration's successful pressure on Mexico to halt oil shipments represents a calculated gamble—one that leverages Mexico's vulnerability during upcoming trade agreement negotiations. The complete severance could accelerate the regime's collapse—or drive it even more desperately into Chinese and Russian arms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic Vulnerabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intelligence implications extend far beyond passive eavesdropping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The data that could be collected could allow the Chinese to capture particular intelligence transmitted in an imperfectly secure or decipherable fashion, but also just from the signatures, have an idea regarding the composition and state of activity of U.S. forces, their location, and signatures that could allow them to more effectively locate and defeat U.S. systems in combat,&quot; Ellis points out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The worst-case scenarios involve cyber weapons pre-positioned in critical infrastructure, electronic warfare systems that could interfere with U.S. military communications during a crisis, or intelligence networks that could support hostile operations on America’s doorstep. The geographic proximity compounds every vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet not everyone views American intervention as the solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leon Valencia, a former ELN rebel commander and director of the Bogota-based think tank Fundación Paz y Reconciliación, offers a Colombian perspective that reflects broader Latin American sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We do see Cuba more as a victim,&quot; Valencia tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. &quot;Throughout several peace negotiations, Cuba has been a very important part. For example, the peace agreements with the FARC rebels, signed back in 2016, were negotiated in Cuba. Cuba has always kept its doors open towards us. We are thankful to Cuba, but we wouldn't get involved in military actions; there would be a protest.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet Valencia and other regional analysts increasingly believe change in Cuba may be inevitable. Enrique Serrano, a Colombian political analyst specializing in Latin American authoritarianism, sees the current crisis as potentially terminal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It's very unlikely that the government in Cuba might survive this year,&quot; Serrano tells &lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;. &quot;I think finally we can change, and especially because Venezuela failed too, and even I think Nicaragua will fail to. Those authoritarian governments like Venezuela, Nicaragua and Cuba, what they try to do in real life is to gain time. They will disappear earlier or later.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington's Dilemma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The expansion of Chinese and Russian intelligence capabilities in Cuba presents Washington with a challenge that defies easy solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Pfeiffer, &quot;continued U.S. pressure will make it difficult for China or Russia to assist the Cuban regime in getting out of this crisis of their own making.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure crisis complicates any potential diplomatic opening. A government desperate to keep the lights on may prove more willing to accommodate Chinese and Russian intelligence requirements than it would under less dire circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intelligence collection capabilities that Beijing and Moscow are establishing in Cuba will persist long after the current blackouts end. Once installed, telecommunications infrastructure operates for years or decades. Every blackout pushes Havana closer to Beijing, every grid failure necessitates Moscow's help; each represents an incremental expansion of foreign intelligence capabilities on American soil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The opportunities stemming from Cuba's military and political alignment with the PRC, longstanding working relationship with its military and other personnel, geographical proximity, and other benefits, both before and during war, are hard to overstate,&quot; Ellis adds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marco Rubio’s Sugar-Coated MAGA</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rubio-munich-speech-changes-nothing-by-carl-bildt-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While US Vice President JD Vance used his remarks to the Munich Security Conference last year to hector and insult European leaders, Secretary of State Marco Rubio seemed more eager to flatter. And yet, America’s top diplomat merely confirmed that the transatlantic divide has become massive –&amp;nbsp;and is still widening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Is a peace deal possible?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/17/the-war-room-newsletter-is-a-peace-deal-possible</link>
      <description>Oliver Carroll, our foreign correspondent, analyses the prospects—and pitfalls—of ending the war in Ukraine</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Apex Court Declares Menstrual Health and Hygiene a Fundamental Right</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indias-apex-court-declares-menstrual-health-and-hygiene-a-fundamental-right/</link>
      <description>The ruling mainstreams menstrual health. But India needs to normalize sex education too. Otherwise, menstruation will be treated as a “dirty issue” shrouded in silence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s New Arms Rules Will Hit Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/17/trump-weapons-arms-exports-defense-southeast-asia-china-alliances-military/</link>
      <description>An “America First” export strategy complicates efforts to obtain U.S.-made weapons.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dream Palace of the West</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/dream-palace-west</link>
      <description>A Response to “The West’s Last Chance”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Next War</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/russia/europes-next-war-charap-haukkala</link>
      <description>The rising risk of NATO-Russia conflict.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine and the New Way of War</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/ukraine/ukraine-and-new-way-war-lissner-warden</link>
      <description>Learning the right lessons for the conflicts of the future.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia After America</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/asia-after-america-cooper</link>
      <description>How U.S. strategy failed—and ceded the advantage to China.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women’s Rights Are Democratic Rights</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/womens-rights-are-democratic-rights-hillary-clinton</link>
      <description>The global authoritarian backlash to gender equality.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Globalist Delusion</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/globalist-delusion-nadia-schadlow</link>
      <description>Why America must build a new operating system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Multipolar Delusion</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/multipolar-delusion-mohan</link>
      <description>And the unilateral temptation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Age of Kleptocracy</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/age-kleptocracy-cooley-nexon</link>
      <description>Geopolitical power, private gain.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion of Readiness</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/illusion-readiness</link>
      <description>Will Washington Repeat Moscow’s Mistakes?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What America Must Learn From Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/what-america-must-learn-ukraine</link>
      <description>Will Washington Repeat Moscow’s Mistakes?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s Monarchy is Caught in a ‘Visibility Trap’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/thailands-monarchy-is-caught-in-a-visibility-trap/</link>
      <description>The social media age has stripped the House of Chakri of its once-formidable royal aura. The only route to preservation is reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam Gives Greenlight to Starlink Satellite Internet Service</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/vietnam-gives-greenlight-to-starlink-satellite-internet-service/</link>
      <description>The approval will allow Starlink's local subsidiary to provide satellite internet access to up to 600,000 user terminals.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia Readies 1,000 Soldiers for Potential Deployment to Gaza in April</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesia-readies-1000-soldiers-for-potential-deployment-to-gaza-in-april/</link>
      <description>Jakarta's contribution to the U.N. Security Council-mandated International Stabilization Force (ISF) has stirred controversy at home.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Gathering Storm</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/gathering-storm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the threat of conflict with Russia, and as with the Great Wars of the 20th Century, Europe is finding a new resolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Robin Hood state is coming for the rich</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/16/the-robin-hood-state-is-coming-for-the-rich</link>
      <description>Tax systems are more progressive than you think</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 20:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Long Can Kyrgyzstan’s Economic Boom Keep Booming?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-long-can-kyrgyzstans-economic-boom-keep-booming/</link>
      <description>Sanctions scrutiny and overheating risks are threatening one of the few winners from the Russia-Ukraine war.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
