<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Air Force revives a deployment concept used for the GWOT—with a few twists</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/air-force-revives-deployment-concept-used-gwot-few-twists/410922/</link>
      <description>Air Expeditionary Wing 2.0 is the latest move away from Biden-era attempts to orient the force toward China.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 03:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On a Knife’s Edge—Again—With Iran</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/on-a-knifes-edgeagainwith-iran</link>
      <description>Trump's &quot;madman&quot; movement of U.S. forces into position for an Iran strike could force Tehran into existential choices of surrender or a regional war&amp;#8212;or both</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Europe Resist American Coercion?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/trump-europe-resist-american-coercion/</link>
      <description>Options range from targeted tariffs to selling off U.S. debt—but they’re risky.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Territory Still a Deal-Breaker in Russia-Ukraine Peace Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/ukraine-russia-united-states-war-negotiations-putin-trump-zelensky-abu-dhabi-davos/</link>
      <description>Trilateral discussions among Russia, Ukraine, and the United States show little sign of compromise from Moscow.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Soviet Lessons for Trump’s Greenland Gambit</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/trump-greenland-davos-history-soviet-invasion-czechoslovakia-1968/</link>
      <description>A 1968 invasion of Czechoslovakia offers a key to understanding how Trump’s adventurism plays out.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story: The true danger posed by Donald Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/01/23/cover-story-the-true-danger-posed-by-donald-trump</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Israel-Iran Detente Won’t Last</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/iran-israel-netanyahu-war-detente-nuclear-program-missiles/</link>
      <description>The next round could be bigger and uglier than last year’s 12-day war.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/foreign-policy-news-quiz-trump-europe-tariff-threat-world-economic-forum-china-demographics/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Jan. 17: Trump threatens Europe, the World Economic Forum begins, and China’s demographic slide continues.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain’s New Spy Chief Has a New Mission</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/mi6-sis-blaise-metreweli-intelligence-espionage-britain-russia/</link>
      <description>Blaise Metreweli is revamping the legendary MI6 for an era of conflict in Europe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Chinese Vibe Shift</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/china-lying-flat-work-meritocracy-young/</link>
      <description>A country once obsessed with success is taking things slower.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Collapse That Created Today’s Russia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/book-review-dark-side-of-the-earth-mikhail-zygar-soviet-collapse/</link>
      <description>From the ashes of communism emerged a corrupt, nihilistic, and warmongering elite.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space Force probably needs twice as many guardians, vice chief says</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/01/space-force-probably-needs-twice-many-guardians-vice-chief-says/410910/</link>
      <description>The service’s budget and constellation have doubled since its founding, Gen. Shawn Bratton noted.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loosening the Gordian Knot of Global Terrorism: Why Legitimacy Must Anchor a Counterterrorism Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/loosening-the-gordian-knot-of-global-terrorism-why-legitimacy-must-anchor-a-counterterrorism-strategy</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—&lt;/strong&gt; The global terrorism landscape in 2026 — the 25&lt;sup&gt;th &lt;/sup&gt;anniversary year of the 9/11 terrorism attacks — is more uncertain, hybridized, and combustible than at any point since 9/11. Framing a sound U.S. counterterrorism strategy — especially in the second year of a Trump administration — will require more than isolated strikes against &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/25/us/politics/trump-isis-nigeria-strike.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ISIS in Nigeria&lt;/a&gt;, punitive counterterrorism operations in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/12/19/g-s1-103194/u-s-launches-strikes-syria&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Syria&lt;/a&gt;, or a tougher rhetorical posture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Trump administration counterterrorism strategy will require legitimacy: the domestic, international, and legal credibility that leverages a wide-range of counterterrorism tools, while engendering international counterterrorism cooperation. Without legitimacy, even tactically successful counterterrorism operations risk becoming illusory, politicized, and ultimately self-defeating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The terrorist threat landscape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extremist violence no longer conforms to clean ideological lines. Terrorist objectives and drivers are muddled in ways that are hard to understand — but evolving. There’s little &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hstoday.us/featured/wray-lone-actors-purity-of-radical-ideology-giving-way-to-weird-hodgepodge-of-beliefs-behind-attacks/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ideological purity&lt;/a&gt; with those radicalizing in today’s extremist milieu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, state-directed intelligence officers increasingly behave like terrorists. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/15/world/europe/uk-mi6-russia-chaos.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Russian intelligence-linked&lt;/a&gt; sabotage plots blur the line between terrorism and hybrid warfare. Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps officers provide hands-on training to Lebanese Hizballah commanders. Addressing these kinds of risks requires legitimacy, too, especially among allies whose intelligence cooperation, legal authorities, and public support are indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowhere is this threat picture more tenuous than in the Middle East. Hamas’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/R47828#:~:text=Summary,the%20Gaza%20Strip%20into%20Israel.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;October 7, 2023&lt;/a&gt;, attacks triggered a profound rebalancing of power in the region. Yet, Syria remains unfinished business. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/playing-the-role-of-good-shepherd-in-a-post-assad-syria&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Power vacuums&lt;/a&gt; there invite foreign jihadists, threaten Israel's border communities, and create future opportunities for Iranian influence to rebound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A modest but persistent U.S. presence in Syria with a friendly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/syria-to-join-coalition-against-islamic-state-as-countrys-president-visits-trump-ed16328c&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ahmed al-Sharaa&lt;/a&gt;-led government remains a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/column_article/trump-administrations-counterterrorism-policy-should-begin-at-golan-heights&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;strategic hedge&lt;/a&gt; against an Islamic State resurgence, and is a strong signal of U.S. commitment that helps sustain partner confidence. The U.S. counterterrorism presence and alignment with al-Sharaa is not without its risks, though: in December, three Americans were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/14/world/middleeast/syria-us-soldiers-killed.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;killed&lt;/a&gt; by a lone ISIS gunman in central Syria. The country is, and will continue to be, plagued by sectarianism and terrorism, which means that restoring control over a deeply fractured Syria remains fraught. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taken together, the current transnational terrorism threat landscape is volatile and difficult to predict, a challenge compounded by resource constraints. In such an environment, legitimacy becomes a force multiplier. A belief that America is a ‘force for good’, credible messaging, and confidence that U.S. government action is perceived as just, can go a long way. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not an abstract concern. Terrorism today thrives in contested information environments, polarized societies, and fragile states. In short, transnational jihadist networks now coexist with domestic violent extremists, and online &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/world/islamic-states-caliphate-is-gone-its-influence-lives-on-7aed6cec&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;radicalization ecosystems&lt;/a&gt; that blur the line between terrorism, insurgency, and hybrid warfare. Terrorist propaganda continues to resonate with individuals in the West, especially younger generations who radicalize online. In this environment, legitimacy is no longer a secondary benefit of sound strategy—it is a core guiding principle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Trump administration's counterterrorism approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are looking for more clarity on the trajectory of Trump 2.0 counterterrorism efforts. It’s still, premature to consider a strategy that has yet to be formally articulated, as many in the counterterrorism community eagerly await its release. History offers a useful reminder. The first Trump administration did not publish its &lt;a href=&quot;https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/NSCT.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Strategy for Counterterrorism&lt;/a&gt; until its second year. When it appeared in 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2018/10/trump-counterterrorism-strategy/572170/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;critics&lt;/a&gt; and supporters alike acknowledged that it reflected professional judgment rather than ideological excess. That document recognized terrorism’s evolution and called for strengthening counterterrorism partnerships within the U.S. government, but abroad as well, with a range of longstanding allies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What gave that strategy durability was its legitimacy. Authorities were grounded in law, threat assessments were evidence-based, policies were stress-tested for faulty assumptions, and foreign partnerships were treated as strategic assets rather than transactional relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Biden administration publicly released a set of redacted rules secretly issued by President Trump in 2017 for counterterrorism operations — such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/01/us/politics/trump-drone-strike-rules.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“direct action”&lt;/a&gt; strikes and special operations raids outside conventional war zones — those &lt;a href=&quot;https://int.nyt.com/data/documenttools/trump-psp-drone-strike-rules-foia/52f4a4baf5fc54c5/full.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; explicitly acknowledged the power of legitimacy. Counterterrorism succeeds when allies trust the U.S., and the American public believes force is used proportionately and lawfully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That legacy of trust matters now more than ever, given signals that a second Trump administration could overcorrect on its counterterrorism priorities by redirecting and focusing resources on far-left extremist groups such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/us-news/justice-department-charges-four-in-alleged-new-years-eve-bomb-plot-37d38bb3&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turtle Island Liberation Front (TILF)&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/12/18/justice-department-fbi-first-amendment-antifa/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Antifa&lt;/a&gt;, while downplaying far-right extremism—or being distracted from the more dangerous terrorism threats from ISIS and other violent jihadists. As the world recently witnessed during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/isis-syria-bondi-beach-attacks-christmas-11239979&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;holidays&lt;/a&gt;, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/31/world/australia/bondi-beach-attack-vigil-new-year-sydney.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bondi Beach&lt;/a&gt; to Syria, ISIS remains a threat. Far-Left terrorism in the U.S. is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/09/charlie-kirk-left-wing-terrorism/684323/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on the rise&lt;/a&gt;, but far-right terrorism accounts for greater lethality than did the left. And still, after 25 years, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesoufancenter.org/intelbrief-2025-december-19/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ISIS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctc.westpoint.edu/the-global-state-of-al-qaida-24-years-after-9-11/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;al-Qa’ida&lt;/a&gt; that remain the most persistent and enduring transnational terrorism threat against U.S interests. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Trump National Security Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s concerning that the recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/2025-National-Security-Strategy.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Security Strategy&lt;/a&gt; (NSS) only tepidly addresses &lt;a href=&quot;https://mwi.westpoint.edu/what-happened-to-transnational-terrorism/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transnational terrorism&lt;/a&gt;, but notably links terrorism with cross-border threats and hemispheric cooperation against things like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/inside-trump-s-second-term-national-security-strategy?utm_source=chatgpt.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“narco-terrorists,”&lt;/a&gt; blurring the traditional separation between transnational organized crime and terrorism. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, the Trump administration’s emphasis on drug cartels is justifiable, if it does &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;detract from broader counterterrorism objectives, such as the ISIS or hybridizing terrorist threats that continue to emerge. Commentators claim, however, that the Trump administration is already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/12/22/terrorism-antifa-cartels-islamic-state-trump/?pwapi_token=eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJyZWFzb24iOiJnaWZ0IiwibmJmIjoxNzY2NDY2MDAwLCJpc3MiOiJzdWJzY3JpcHRpb25zIiwiZXhwIjoxNzY3ODQ4Mzk5LCJpYXQiOjE3NjY0NjYwMDAsImp0aSI6IjBmZjlhNzVjLTY2ZTMtNGE5Ni1iYTE1LTVhMWI2ZjJhY2Y4ZiIsInVybCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vd3d3Lndhc2hpbmd0b25wb3N0LmNvbS9vcGluaW9ucy8yMDI1LzEyLzIyL3RlcnJvcmlzbS1hbnRpZmEtY2FydGVscy1pc2xhbWljLXN0YXRlLXRydW1wLyJ9.G3CUd5dUcejxMk6jlx5otj5FfSyAg8z_r0x4xmdUGvk&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;losing sight&lt;/a&gt; of the ISIS and al-Qa’ida threats, though settling that debate here is quixotic at best — only time will tell. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides jihadi threats, the U.S. does not need the unintended consequences and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/new-atlanticist/us-intervention-against-mexican-cartels-carries-major-risks-heres-how-to-mitigate-them/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;risks&lt;/a&gt; of triggering a cycle of cartel retaliation – or &lt;a href=&quot;https://icct.nl/publication/counter-terrorism-implications-second-trump-presidency&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;provoking greater far-left violence&lt;/a&gt; – down-the-line in the U.S. homeland. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contrastingly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/NSS-Final-12-18-2017-0905.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2017 National Security Strategy&lt;/a&gt; saw radical Islamist terrorism as one of the priority transnational threats that could undermine U.S. security and stability. The strategy highlighted groups such as ISIS and al-Qa’ida as continuing dangers, stressing that terrorists had taken control of parts of the Middle East and remained a threat globally. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Addressing transnational terrorism during the first Trump administration required discipline and steadiness amid predictable frictions at the National Security Council (NSC) among policymakers who wanted a more rapid shift toward other priorities, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/opinion/national-security/595674-how-the-us-can-balance-counterterrorism-and-the-great-power/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;great power competition.&lt;/a&gt; Still, terrorist labeling and designations, strategic messaging, and resource allocation for counterterrorism were grounded in evidence rather than politics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, overhyping some threats while minimizing others undermines legitimacy, invites backlash, and weakens the very moral authority needed to operationalize a cogent, thoughtful national security strategy. It also erodes trust between the government and the public and leads citizens to second-guess whether they are being told the truth or being led astray. The 2017 NSS carried weight precisely because it was grounded in intelligence, not politics. Moreover, the NSS helped frame the counterterrorism strategy that followed and proved highly effective in keeping Americans safe. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drawing lessons from the 2018 National Strategy for Counterterrorism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3466967&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2018 National Strategy for Counterterrorism (NSCT)&lt;/a&gt; remains a useful foundation for the second Trump administration—not because the world is unchanged, but because it embraced balance. The strategy emphasized foreign partnerships, non-military tools, and targeted direct action when necessary. It recognized a central legitimacy principle: the United States cannot and should not fight every terrorist everywhere with American troops when capable counterterrorism partners can do so in their own backyards, with local consent, and a more granular understanding of the grievances that motivate these terrorist groups and their supporters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And still, U.S. counterterrorism pressure through direct action remains a necessary tool to disrupt terrorism planning. It seems that the second Trump Administration is following the playbook of the first Trump administration in terms of aggressive counterterrorism kinetic strikes in places like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/01/us/politics/trump-airstrikes-isis-somalia.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Somalia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/15/us/politics/us-attack-houthis.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yemen,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/14/middleeast/iraq-syria-isis-killed-intl-hnk/index.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Iraq&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/01/us/politics/counterterrorism-drone-strikes.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rescinded Biden-era limits on counterterrorism drone strikes&lt;/a&gt;, allowing the kind of flexible operational framework used for counterterrorism throughout the President’s first term. Thus far, in the aggressive counter-narcotic campaign in international waters off Venezuela, the standoff U.S. strikes resemble &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/12/18/stephen-miller-boat-strikes-mexico-venezuela-execute-order/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;counterterrorism operations&lt;/a&gt; in Yemen and Somalia during the first Trump administration. Operationally, direct action remains an indispensable counterterrorism tool for disrupting terror groups overseas, and more U.S. direct action will likely be necessary in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/world/africa/africa-terrorism-trump-ivory-coast.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;West Africa and the Sahel&lt;/a&gt; to keep jihadist groups operating there off balance, forcing them to devote more time and resources to operational security. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But pressure without legitimacy is counterproductive. What works against jihadist networks does not necessarily translate cleanly to drug cartels or transnational criminal gangs. So, policymakers must be circumspect that expanding the scope of counterterrorism authorities and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justsecurity.org/107770/cartels-foreign-terrorism-designation/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;terrorist designations&lt;/a&gt; to canvas drug cartels, risks the unintended consequences of triggering destabilizing cycles of violence in the future, and straining more traditional counterterrorism resources. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming full circle, in light of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/03/us/politics/trump-capture-maduro-venezuela.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U.S. capture of Nicolás Maduro&lt;/a&gt; for narcoterrorism-related offenses, the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/03/opinion/venezuela-attack-trump-us.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;legitimacy&lt;/a&gt; will be fiercely debated in the days and weeks ahead. If the Trump National Security Strategy is the roadmap for focusing on narcoterrorism in the Western Hemisphere, then the need for publishing a clarifying and rational U.S. counterterrorism strategy for the rest of the world takes on even greater sense of urgency. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pushing a boulder uphill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drawing on past counterterrorism lessons to find a comprehensive strategy—from the Bush administration’s wartime footing, through 8 years of Obama counterterrorism work, to President Trump’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/pdf/26557430.pdf?refreqid=fastly-default%3A1faeef863e0ec72ac7818cd224ce47cf&amp;amp;ab_segments=&amp;amp;initiator=&amp;amp;acceptTC=1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;war on terror&quot;&lt;/a&gt; — is a Sisyphean task. But, in the wake of over two decades of relentless overseas counterterrorism work, a few ideas have come into sharper focus:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After more than two decades of counterterrorism, loosening the Gordian knot of modern terrorism requires balance, far greater clarity, and consistent, predictable national leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Above all, counterterrorism strategy requires legitimacy. Without it, counterterrorism becomes reactive and politicized. With it, a Trump 2.0 counterterrorism strategy can still be firm, flexible, and credible in a far more dangerous world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Buried by Baghdad’s Construction Boom</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/politics-history-baghdad-rebuilding-architecture-ottoman-british-empire-saddam/</link>
      <description>The politics of rebuilding in a city of memories.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Poet Finds New Life in America’s Borderlands</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/a-poet-finds-new-life-in-americas-borderlands/</link>
      <description>Saretta Morgan’s poems speak the language of the Southwest’s deserts.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 202: The known perils of regime change</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2026/01/defense-one-radio-ep-202-documented-dangers-regime-change/410883/</link>
      <description>A scholar of civil wars warns against repeating the past mistakes from U.S. military interventions abroad.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is ahead in the race for Japan’s next parliament</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/interactive/2026-japan-election</link>
      <description>Prime Minister Takaichi Sanae has gambled on an early election</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Has Abandoned the World</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-withdrawal-from-international-organizations-is-harmful-not-popular-by-gordon-brown-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s decision to withdraw the United States from 66 international organizations is ostensibly aimed at cutting waste, but the inclusion of agencies supporting girls and women underscores the move’s arbitrariness and vindictiveness. It will have dire consequences for people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong’s New LegCo Faces Test Over Same-Sex Partnership Recognition</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/hong-kongs-new-legco-faces-test-over-same-sex-partnership-recognition/</link>
      <description>At stake is not only the rights of sexual minorities, but also whether Hong Kong's court rulings have any teeth.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Drone War in Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-drone-war-in-ukraine/</link>
      <description>China’s dominance of global drone supply chains has become strategically indispensable to both Russia and Ukraine, revealing a new form of power rooted in civilian technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran at the Breaking Point: How Afghanistan and Iraq Still Inform U.S. Strategy</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/iran-at-the-breaking-point-how-afghanistan-and-iraq-still-inform-u-s-strategy</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE — &lt;/strong&gt;Iran is experiencing its most consequential period of internal &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/Business/wireStory/toll-irans-protest-crackdown-reaches-5002-dead-trump-129476717&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;unrest&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in years. Nationwide demonstrations driven by economic collapse, social grievance, and political frustration have been met with force, mass arrests, and near-total information control. The scale and coordination of the response suggest a regime that feels threatened but not unmoored, confident in its ability to absorb pressure while preventing fragmentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This moment has reignited debate in Washington about escalation, leverage, and the possibility—explicit or implicit—of regime collapse. That debate is familiar. The United States has confronted similar moments before, most notably in Afghanistan and Iraq, where early assumptions about pressure, legitimacy, and endurance proved wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is not an argument for restraint or intervention. It is a warning drawn from experience: without understanding how competition unfolds below the level of open conflict - the gray zone - pressure alone does not produce favorable outcomes. Iran today sits at the center of a problem the United States has repeatedly misunderstood - not the use of force, but what comes before and after it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Afghanistan and Iraq: Where Strategy Slipped&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Afghanistan, the United States removed the Taliban from power quickly. In Iraq, Saddam Hussein’s regime collapsed even faster. In both cases, the decisive phase of the conflict ended early. What followed was the harder contest—one defined less by firepower and more by local power structures, informal authority, and external interference operating quietly and persistently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Afghanistan, as I witnessed firsthand, regional actors adapted faster than Washington. Iran, Pakistan, Russia, and later China treated the conflict as a long game. They invested in relationships, cultivated influence, and positioned themselves for the post-U.S. environment years before the withdrawal. The result was not an immediate defeat on the battlefield, but a strategic hollowing-out of the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iraq followed a similar trajectory. Iranian-aligned militias embedded themselves within neighborhoods, religious institutions, and political parties. Over time, they became inseparable from the state itself. U.S. military dominance did not prevent this. In fact, it often obscured it, until the architecture of influence was already in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lesson from both cases is straightforward: control of territory is temporary; control of networks endures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iran Is Not Afghanistan or Iraq — But the Pattern Rhymes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran today is often discussed as if pressure will produce rapid political change. That assumption ignores how power is organized inside the Islamic Republic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran’s security model is deliberately social. The Basij is not simply a paramilitary &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/6238623/iran-basij-militia-meaning-mahsa-amini/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;force&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; it is embedded across society—universities, workplaces, neighborhoods, religious institutions. Its purpose is not only repression, but surveillance, mobilization, and ideological reinforcement. This structure was built to survive unrest, sanctions, and isolation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Externally, Iran has exported the same logic. In Iraq, allied militias function simultaneously as armed actors, political movements, and social providers. In Afghanistan, Iran preserved influence across regime changes, maintaining access to key actors even after the fall of the Republic. These are not improvisations; they are the product of decades of learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is worth remembering that Iran was not a spectator during the U.S. presence in Afghanistan and Iraq. It observed American methods up close—what worked, what failed, and where patience outperformed power. Tehran adapted accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Escalation Without Preparation Backfires&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moments of internal unrest often create pressure for external action. Yet Afghanistan and Iraq show that collapse—real or perceived—creates its own risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removing a regime does not dismantle informal power structures. It often accelerates their consolidation. Networks that survive pressure are the ones that define what comes next. Iran’s internal system is designed precisely for this kind of stress: decentralized, redundant, and socially embedded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is also a strategic paradox at play. External pressure can validate internal narratives of siege and foreign threat, strengthening coercive institutions rather than weakening them. Information controls, security mobilization, and proxy signaling are not reactions; they are rehearsed responses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is why simplistic comparisons—whether to Eastern Europe, Latin America, or past protest movements, are misleading. Iran’s political &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/iran-crumbling-revolutionary-facade-protests&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;ecosystem&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is closer to the environments the United States faced in Kabul and Baghdad than many in Washington are willing to admit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who’s Reading this? More than 500K of the most influential national security experts in the world. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Need &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;full access&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; to what the Experts are reading?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of this suggests that Iran is immune to pressure or that its current trajectory is stable. Economic distress, generational change, and legitimacy erosion are real. But history cautions against assuming that pressure equals control or that unrest equals opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more relevant question for U.S. policymakers is not whether Iran is vulnerable, but whether the United States is prepared to operate effectively in the space that follows vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That preparation requires understanding how authority is distributed beneath formal institutions, recognizing how coercive and social systems reinforce one another, and anticipating how regional actors adapt during periods of instability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are the same lessons Afghanistan and Iraq offered lessons learned too late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran’s current unrest has reopened a familiar debate in Washington about pressure, leverage, and escalation. But Afghanistan and Iraq should have settled that debate long ago. The United States did not lose those conflicts because it lacked military power; it lost because it underestimated how authority, loyalty, and influence actually function inside contested societies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran is not a blank slate, nor is it a fragile state waiting to collapse under external strain. It is a system built to absorb pressure, manage unrest, and outlast moments of crisis. Any approach that treats unrest as an opportunity without first understanding what follows it risks repeating the same strategic error the United States has already made—twice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The choice facing U.S. policymakers is therefore not whether to act, but how to act without misunderstanding the terrain. Escalation without preparation does not produce control; it produces consequences that others are better positioned to manage. If Washington has truly learned from Afghanistan and Iraq, it will recognize that the most dangerous moment is not the collapse of order, but the false confidence that comes before it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;History will not judge the United States on whether it applied pressure. It will judge whether it understood what that pressure would unleash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Editor@thecipherbrief.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Must Close Its Climate Disclosure Gap</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/taiwan-must-close-its-climate-disclosure-gap/</link>
      <description>While Taiwan took an early stance on climate action in East Asia, it is now lagging in its response to green finance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get power naps right</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/01/23/how-to-get-power-naps-right</link>
      <description>It’s all in the timing</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI Could Restore Trust in Democratic Governance</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-ai-could-restore-trust-democratic-governance-by-sami-mahroum-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The key to success for high-trust technocracies like Singapore and the United Arab Emirates is that they have figured out how to deliver visible policy results while remaining responsive to ever-evolving public concerns. Now, new AI tools help low-trust democracies do the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Trump’s ‘Board of Peace’; Russian hybrid warfare; More Ukraine talks; Combat fitness, reimagined; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-23-2026/410893/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Apparent Calm With a Long Shadow: Revisiting Central Asia’s Illiberal Peace</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/an-apparent-calm-with-a-long-shadow-revisiting-central-asias-illiberal-peace/</link>
      <description>Central Asia’s illiberal peace has endured through inter- and intrastate conflict, but its ability to survive environmental crisis remains untested.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Pakistan Ready to Reform Its Lethal Blasphemy Laws?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/is-pakistan-ready-to-reform-its-lethal-blasphemy-laws/</link>
      <description>The blasphemy law – and its death sentence – is ripe for abuse and extortion. Is Pakistan’s government finally going to make a change?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As ICE becomes more violent, state and local officials struggle to fight back</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/ice-becomes-more-violent-some-state-and-local-officials-are-trying-fight-back/410869/</link>
      <description>They seek limits and accountability for the deadly immigration crackdown that the White House calls vital to national security.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Balance-of-Power Theory Strikes Again</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/trump-threats-europe-greenland-balance-power/</link>
      <description>Nobody should be surprised at how the world is reacting to Donald Trump’s threats.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lee Jae-myung’s Vision for Peace Faces a Hardened ‘New Cold War’ Reality</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/lee-jae-myungs-vision-for-peace-faces-a-hardened-new-cold-war-reality/</link>
      <description>In light of North Korea’s strengthened ties with Russia and its continuous nuclear buildup, Lee should seek a Plan B to construct peace on the Korean Peninsula.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Disintegration of NATO Would Not Be in China’s Interests</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-disintegration-of-nato-would-not-be-in-chinas-interests/</link>
      <description>China views NATO as a remnant of the Cold War that should have been disbanded. But in its current form, the group actually works to China’s advantage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s Foreign Ministry in Transition: Pragmatic Diplomacy in Practice</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/south-koreas-foreign-ministry-in-transition-pragmatic-diplomacy-in-practice/</link>
      <description>Under Lee, South Korea’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs is navigating a pivotal phase of reform grounded in pragmatic, efficiency-driven diplomacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time Has Come to Shutter the World Economic Forum</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/davos-world-economic-forum-serves-no-beneficial-purpose-by-katharina-pistor-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a place where political and business leaders can enjoy one another’s company, the World Economic Forum's annual Davos gathering has been an incubator for standards that have shaped the global economy. But the Davos order is now crumbling, and if regular attendees had bothered to consult ordinary people, they might understand why.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade After Trump: How India and EU Are Rewiring Global Commerce</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/trade-after-trump-how-india-and-eu-are-rewiring-global-commerce/</link>
      <description>The implications of the India-EU FTA extend beyond Brussels and New Delhi.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Latin America Has Been Demure in Davos</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/latin-america-davos-carney-global-order-us-trump-economy/</link>
      <description>U.S. aggression is nothing new for the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Pakistan Conquered the US – While India Lost Trump</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-pakistan-conquered-the-us-while-india-lost-trump/</link>
      <description>How did India lose its standing in Washington? And how did Pakistan gain ground so quickly?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Trump Should Accept Putin’s New START Offer</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/23/us-russia-trump-putin-nuclear-arms-control-treaty-new-start-extension/</link>
      <description>Extending the nuclear treaty is not about trust—it’s about pragmatism.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Democracy After Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/american-democracy-after-maga-trumpism-by-mordecai-kurz-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;America's current dysfunction - as exemplified by Trumpism and the decline of democracy - stems from the massive rise of private power and the deep inequalities it has produced. As the root causes of everything that has gone wrong since the 1980s, these are where any project of national rejuvenation must begin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nepal’s Post-uprising Elections Take Shape</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/nepals-post-uprising-elections-take-shape/</link>
      <description>Thousands of people from across 68 political parties have thrown their hats in the electoral ring for the March 5 elections.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IP Enforcement in Asia: Economic and Geopolitical Implications</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/ip-enforcement-in-asia-economic-and-geopolitical-implications/</link>
      <description>Is the war of intellectual property rights chipping away at countries’ industrial innovation in Asia?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of Female Suicide Bombers Spreads Across Baloch Militant Groups</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/use-of-female-suicide-bombers-spreads-across-baloch-militant-groups/</link>
      <description>The BLF is the third group, after the BLA-Jeeyand and BLA-Azad to deploy women in suicide missions.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Perfect Storm for Taiwan in 2026?</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/perfect-storm-taiwan-2026</link>
      <description>How a convergence of factors could tempt Beijing to act.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Only Way to Disarm Hamas</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/palestinian-territories/only-way-disarm-hamas</link>
      <description>How private security contractors can help stabilize Gaza.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libya’s Lessons for Venezuela: Reform the Economy Before It Is Too Late</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/libyas-lessons-venezuela-reform-economy-it-too-late</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Venezuela needs fundamental change to its economic structures to prevent the abduction of Nicolas Maduro from eventually leading to increased corruption and systemic violence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 11: How Russian Sabotage Is Financed and How to Disrupt It</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/suspicious-transaction-report/episode-11-how-russian-sabotage-financed-and-how-disrupt-it</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Financing is a critical yet overlooked element of Russian sabotage in Europe, shaping how operations unfold and where they can be disrupted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording: Greenland: The New Battleground in US-Europe Relations</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/members-event-recordings/recording-greenland-new-battleground-us-europe-relations</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A briefing and question and answer session with a panel of RUSI experts, exploring the implications of President Trump’s threats to annex Greenland, part of NATO ally Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan’s Secret Gold Rush Risks Poisoning Its Waters</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/afghanistans-secret-gold-rush-risks-poisoning-its-waters/</link>
      <description>The largely hidden gold rush in Badakhshan poses considerable risks to Afghans, and others living downstream in Central Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and the Future of Education</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-future-of-education-by-pinelopi-koujianou-goldberg-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The central challenge for educators in the age of AI is to prepare students to operate effectively in the face of uncertainty. The answer is not to train them for specific tasks that may soon become obsolete, but to make them as adaptable and intellectually independent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Deliberate Pivot to the Pacific: Why History Matters</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/japans-deliberate-pivot-to-the-pacific-why-history-matters/</link>
      <description>Driven by lessons from World War II and China’s expanding presence, Japan’s strategic orientation is pivoting eastward into the Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian State Proposes Law Against ‘Honor Killing’ As Crimes Continue</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/indian-state-proposes-law-against-honor-killing-as-crimes-continue/</link>
      <description>Choosing a life partner beyond one’s caste or religion can prove deadly in India, as rising numbers of &quot;honor crimes&quot; show.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
