<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 14: Russian Oligarch Sanctions: Frozen Assets, Due Process and What Happens Next</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/suspicious-transaction-report/episode-14-russian-oligarch-sanctions-frozen-assets-due-process-and-what-happens-next</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following Russia’s full-scale invasion, Western governments issued a slew of sanctions against oligarchs. But to what end? What’s been achieved, and what happens next?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump and Iran at a Potential World-Changing Crossroads</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/trump-and-iran-at-a-potential-world</link>
      <description>U.S., British lies about Iraq WMD haunt Trump claims on Iran&amp;#8217;s nuclear, missiles programs</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump directs government to ‘immediately cease’ using Anthropic technology</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/trump-directs-government-immediately-cease-using-anthropic-technology/411776/</link>
      <description>Ban follows AI firm’s refusal to enable mass surveillance, autonomous weapons.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 23:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purpose-Built or Perilous: Congress Faces a Critical FBI Headquarters Decision</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/purpose-built-or-perilous-congress-faces-a-critical-fbi-headquarters-decision</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/washington-dc-united-states-february-20-federal-bureau-of-investigation-headquarters-logo-is-seen-in-washington-dc-united-s.jpg?id=65098297&amp;amp;width=980&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION –&lt;/strong&gt; Congress is weighing a decision with critical National Security implications for generations to come: where to locate the next FBI headquarters? The current headquarters, the Hoover Building, is long past its sell-by date, and there is general agreement it needs to be replaced. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new headquarters, wherever it is located, must deal with a fundamental threat. It will inevitably be a high-priority target for terrorists, spies, and cyber criminals. That means the single most important consideration must be the safety of the men and women who work there; secondarily, the security of highly sensitive investigative and national security data held inside; lastly, the security of adjacencies - both human and physical. That kind of security requires more than a strong building. It requires a safe location to meet current and evolving threats. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the frontrunner for the new headquarters fails those crucial considerations. We can do better--much better--than refurbishing the Ronald Reagan Building and International Trade Center. The vulnerabilities have been known for over two decades. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The April 19, 1995 bombing of the Murrah Federal Office Building in Oklahoma City prompted new security measures for federal office buildings. Independent security consultants warned that the Reagan Building’s sprawling 11-Acre complex, mixed-use design, convention space, vast underground parking garage left it vulnerable to terrorist attacks. The September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks confirmed that the FBI needed a new headquarters complex - one that satisfied Interagency Security Committee (ISC) Level V protocols - the highest security standards for nonmilitary federal facilities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A retrofit of the 30-year-old Reagan Building will fail to meet the physical and cybersecurity requirements of Level V. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Reagan Building is a quasi-public building in the heart of downtown Washington, DC, designed as a center for international events and public use. Its architecture is antithetical to Level V due to features such as a one-acre glass atrium roof, famed sky lights, and open access to surrounding buildings and Metro. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The urban density of the Reagan Building surroundings creates permanent vulnerabilities that will never satisfy Level V Security. The Reagan Building is in the DC core, which exacerbates security risks to itself and adjacent federal and civilian activity: the District’s Wilson Building, Department of Commerce, Willard Hotel, Freedom Plaza, 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Street artery and in closer proximity to the White House. No amount of retrofitting will change these physical adjacencies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearby high-rise buildings provide clear vantage points for hostile actors. The required standoff distances from blast threats can never be met. Nor can the Reagan Building adequately be shielded from line-of-sight surveillance, infrared detection, or electronic signal collection. And, the one acre of glass in the atrium skylight provides an easy drone threat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pedestrian tunnel under 14th Street, a popular food court, Metro access, and public garage connectivity undermine perimeter control, as well. Additionally, the Reagan Building cannot provide the square footage for the redundant power infrastructure mandated for a national security headquarters, including a separate utility plant and multiple independent grid connections. Moving FBI here shows a grave disregard for the safety and security of federal personnel, citizens, and national intelligence. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Real Tab: GSA’s FY 2026 prospectus estimates roughly $1.4 billion for design, construction, and FBI fit-out, but omit the costs of: temporary housing during construction, maintaining Level V-compliant interim facilities, and the likelihood of future leased space if full consolidation proves impossible within the fixed footprint of the Reagan Building. Outdated estimates and assumptions do not reflect the complexity of Level V security or the rapid evolution of cyber and surveillance threats. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Time to Act is Now: Congress needs to remove the Reagan Building from consideration and insist on a purpose-built solution. The FBI needs a campus-style headquarters with adequate standoff distance, full perimeter control, redundant power and communications, and infrastructure flexible to adapt to evolving threats. Over 23 years ago, a bipartisan report was issued, using the attacks on the Murrah Building and World Trade Center as background, as well as GAO, DOJ/OIG, and Independent Security reports with similar conclusions. But nothing has happened. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our first article appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Hill, &lt;/em&gt;Frank Keating, Oklahoma Governor at time of the Murrah Building Bombing, responded to us with, “The Murrah tragedy was a wake-up call. Now, thirty years later it doesn’t look like any lessons were learned.” A former Ambassador shared, “The State Department's post Benghazi worldwide building requirements are very unfriendly to retrofitting buildings for occupation by State personnel whether or not a SCIF is involved. The Bureau will be the target like the Marines in Beirut.”&lt;/p&gt;If lawmakers want to ensure the FBI remains the world’s premier law enforcement and counterterrorism organization, they should demand a headquarters that is purposefully built from a national security perspective, not a retrofit of a building never intended to be a secured facility. Let’s, finally, do this right&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 21:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan Says It’s in ‘Open War’ With Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/pakistan-afghanistan-taliban-clashes-open-war/</link>
      <description>Islamabad bombed major Afghan cities, accusing Kabul of harboring the Pakistani Taliban.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/news-quiz-icc-rodrigo-duterte-russia-ukraine-war-mexico-china-japan-olympics/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Feb. 27: The ICC begins hearings against Rodrigo Duterte, the Russia-Ukraine war marks a grim anniversary, and China continues its feud with Japan.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a Warner Bros-Paramount colossus would look like</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/27/what-a-warner-bros-paramount-colossus-would-look-like</link>
      <description>Hollywood’s new giant will be indebted and unwieldy</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Third Neighbor: Mongolia-US Ties in an Era of Great Power Competition</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/beyond-the-third-neighbor-mongolia-us-ties-in-an-era-of-great-power-competition/</link>
      <description>U.S. Ambassador Richard R. Buangan talks to The Diplomat about the future of the partnership.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Is Running Short of Donkey for Dinner</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/china-donkey-meat-brazil-food-markets-trade/</link>
      <description>The shortage of a popular regional specialty is shaking global meat markets.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Year’s Oscar Documentaries Are Tough to Watch</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/oscar-documentary-nominees-2026/</link>
      <description>From a Russian schoolteacher to an Iranian feminist, the choices reflect our troubled times.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>During Lula’s Visit, South Korea and Brazil Agree to Revive Mercosur Trade Talks</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/during-lulas-visit-south-korea-and-brazil-agree-to-revive-mercosur-trade-talks/</link>
      <description>Amid intensifying China-U.S. rivalry and global trade volatility, middle powers such as South Korea and Brazil are diversifying their supply chains through minilateralism.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s Lost Generation</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/ukraines-lost-generation/</link>
      <description>Students and teachers are struggling to keep education alive in underground schools.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why No One Is Pushing Back on Trump’s Iran Threats</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/why-no-one-is-pushing-back-on-trumps-iran-threats/</link>
      <description>A quarter century of “forever wars” has inured Democrats and even Europeans to U.S. aggression.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:13:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does “open war” between Pakistan and Afghanistan amount to?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/27/what-does-open-war-between-pakistan-and-afghanistan-amount-to</link>
      <description>The bombing of military sites in Kabul and Kandahar marks a sharp escalation in tensions</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Counting Comes at a Cost</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/caste-con-census-book-review-anand-teltumbde-india-reservations/</link>
      <description>In India, a new caste census risks making prejudice permanent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Takeaways From North Korea’s 9th Party Congress</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/6-takeaways-from-north-koreas-9th-party-congress/</link>
      <description>The biggest takeaway: there were no groundbreaking changes, whether in foreign policy or domestic politics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will magnesium supplements help you relax?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/27/will-magnesium-supplements-help-you-relax</link>
      <description>Not everyone will feel the benefits</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Got My Career in Foreign Policy: Alan Cullison</title>
      <link>https://www.cfr.org/articles/how-i-got-my-career-in-foreign-policy-alan-cullison</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The AI Sovereignty Paradox at Home and Abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.cfr.org/articles/the-ai-sovereignty-paradox-at-home-and-abroad</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Transition in Iran</title>
      <link>https://www.cfr.org/reports/leadership-transition-in-iran</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Ukraine’s Future: Adapting to New Realities After Four Years of War</title>
      <link>https://www.cfr.org/articles/securing-ukraines-future-adapting-to-new-realities-after-four-years-of-war</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Should Take the U.S. Military’s Warning on Iran Seriously</title>
      <link>https://www.cfr.org/articles/trump-should-take-the-u-s-militarys-warning-on-iran-seriously</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sen. Wyden to block confirmation for NSA director, citing lack of experience</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/02/wyden-block-confirmation-nsa-director-citing-lack-experience/411762/</link>
      <description>The Oregon senator took issue with Lt. Gen. Joshua Rudd’s responses to questions regarding civil liberties and oversight against unlawful surveillance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s Digital Empire Has a Trust Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.cfr.org/articles/americas-digital-empire-has-a-trust-problem</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Anthropic says no to DOD; Afghanistan-Pakistan war; Ukraine tactics update; US laser downs DHS drone; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-27-2026/411756/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Do ceasefires actually work?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2026/02/27/the-war-room-newsletter-do-ceasefires-actually-work</link>
      <description>Richard Cockett, a senior editor, considers whether one is possible in Ukraine</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 204: “Until the Last Gun Is Silent” by Matthew Delmont</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2026/02/defense-one-radio-ep-204-until-last-gun-silent-matthew-delmont/411654/</link>
      <description>A historian explores patriotism, U.S. foreign policy, and the anti-war movement during the Vietnam era.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Olympic Gold Medalists Show the Mixed Results of China’s Efforts to Bring Back Diaspora Talent</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/2-olympic-gold-medalists-show-the-mixed-results-of-chinas-efforts-to-bring-back-diaspora-talent/</link>
      <description>China’s push to attract ethnic Chinese talent from the U.S., in particular, is up against hard limits – but anti-Chinese sentiment in the United States may work to Beijing’s advantage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Indonesia Just Lock Itself Into an Energy Future It Can’t Afford?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/did-indonesia-just-lock-itself-into-an-energy-future-it-cant-afford/</link>
      <description>Indonesians cannot afford to buy U.S. oil and gas because they can’t afford to keep paying for their own destruction.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>British Lessons About American Decline</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/british-lessons-as-american-decline-accelerates-under-trump-by-harold-james-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than indulging in anti-immigration culture wars and tarring Britain as a case study in &quot;civilizational erasure,&quot; Donald Trump and his followers’ would do well to examine how Britain struggled with the loss of its own global preeminence. No other country’s recent past better represents America’s possible future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan and the Politics of ‘Murder of the Century’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/taiwan-and-the-politics-of-murder-of-the-century/</link>
      <description>A new film attempts to rewrite one of the most infamous murders of Taiwan’s martial era in a way that aligns with China’s interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Delhi Undermining India’s Primary Healthcare Missions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/new-delhi-undermining-indias-primary-healthcare-missions/</link>
      <description>Instead of a thrust on key areas such as women and children’s health, the government has chosen to expand tertiary healthcare.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merz in China: Germany Between De-Risking and Strategic Partnership</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/merz-in-china-germany-between-de-risking-and-strategic-partnership/</link>
      <description>Merz’s trip should not be viewed as a strategic pivot, but as a focused attempt to rebalance an increasingly uneven economic relationship.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil’s almighty Supreme Court must win back public trust</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/27/brazils-almighty-supreme-court-must-win-back-public-trust</link>
      <description>Recent scandals have tarnished the image of one of Brazil’s most important democratic institutions</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Should Australia Do About Its ‘ISIS Brides’?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-should-australia-do-about-its-isis-brides/</link>
      <description>Ultimately, the dilemma facing the Australian government about these women and their children stems from an uncomfortable truth: citizenship is a concept that sits above good and bad behavior.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Japan’s Regional Banks: Demographics, Mergers, and a Tight Market</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-future-of-japans-regional-banks-demographics-mergers-and-a-tight-market/</link>
      <description>Regional banks helped fund Japan’s post-war economy. But can they survive a dwindling population?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Shaky Bargains</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-tactics-cannot-produce-lasting-settlements-in-ukraine-or-iran-by-ana-palacio-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Positional bargaining might work for real-estate transactions, but it is woefully ill-suited to complex diplomatic challenges. Negotiations like those over the Ukraine war and Iran’s nuclear ambitions should aim not to settle the terms of a one-off exchange, but to build a framework that can shape and manage future developments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China’s New Embassy in London Actually a Security Risk?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-chinas-new-embassy-in-london-actually-a-security-risk/</link>
      <description>The reality depends on how the site fits into wider influence operations, the consolidation of diplomatic outposts, and renewed U.K. engagement with China amid shifting global alliances.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan at a Critical Minerals Crossroads: Tungsten and Middle Power Resource Sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/kazakhstan-at-a-critical-minerals-crossroads-tungsten-and-middle-power-resource-sovereignty/</link>
      <description>Kazakhstan finds itself at the intersection of two structural trends: the militarization of the global economy and the technological rivalry between the United States and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War With Iran Would Be Illegal and Stupid. Democrats Should Care.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/democratic-party-shaheen-coons-sullivan-trump-war-iran-state-of-the-union/</link>
      <description>Now is the time for Democratic leaders to stand firm against the risk of a catastrophic conflict.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheinbaum Breaks From AMLO on Security</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/mencho-killing-mexico-jalisco-cartel-sheinbaum-amlo-security/</link>
      <description>The killing of “El Mencho” shows that Mexico’s president has ditched her predecessor’s softer approach to cartels.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Health Financing Needs a Reset</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-health-aid-needs-broader-financial-base-by-bertrand-badre-and-johanna-benesty-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With major donor countries slashing their foreign-aid budgets, the financial foundations of global health have come under strain, revealing structural weaknesses long masked by steady public funding. The solution lies in building a more resilient system that combines grants, concessional loans, and private capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 6G Race Will Define the Next Digital Order</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/6g-race-standards-will-shape-ai-and-future-digital-order-by-bjorn-fagersten-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next generation of mobile technology will determine who controls the critical infrastructure on which modern economies, security systems, and democratic governance depend. The stakes in the race to shape the sector's technical standards could not be higher, for developed and developing countries alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muhammad Deepak: A Symbol of Defiance Against Hindutva’s Hate Politics</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/muhammad-deepak-a-symbol-of-defiance-against-hindutvas-hate-politics/</link>
      <description>When a mob of Hindutva goons descended on a Muslim shopkeeper, a young gym owner stepped forward to defend him.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and the End of Time</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/how-ai-is-splintering-labor-by-sami-mahroum-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For more than two centuries, time has been capitalism’s organizing principle, structuring wages, contracts, and collective action. But AI has made human time functionally abundant, undermining that foundation and fracturing labor into three incompatible regimes no single legal system can reconcile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Age of Resource Competition Needs Transparency</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-resource-competition-demands-transparency-democratic-accountability-by-helen-clark-and-ellen-johnson-sirleaf-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As countries scramble to secure the minerals needed for clean energy, digital technologies, AI, and defense industries, the new era of resource competition implies both great promise and grave peril. Transparency is essential to ensure that producer countries are not left poorer, more divided, and more indebted than before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Decoupling From U.S. Tech</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/europe-technology-digital-sovereignty-eu-decoupling-us/</link>
      <description>The European Union is serious about technological sovereignty, but it’s aware that it won’t be easy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Balochistan the Region’s New Drug Cultivation and Trafficking Hub?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-balochistan-the-regions-new-drug-cultivation-and-trafficking-hub/</link>
      <description>The Taliban regime’s ban on poppy cultivation in Afghanistan has led to this illicit crop being cultivated in neighboring Balochistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helpless in Bangladesh: Rohingya Women and the Failures of Protection</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/helpless-in-bangladesh-rohingya-women-and-the-failures-of-protection/</link>
      <description>Refugees in Bangladesh are vulnerable to kidnappings and forced recruitment, alongside restrictive movement regimes, and denial of access to education and livelihoods.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Cambodia’s PM Really Lying About His Ignorance of Scamming ‘Kingpin’ Chen Zhi?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-cambodias-pm-really-lying-about-his-ignorance-of-scamming-kingpin-chen-zhi/</link>
      <description>If not, it raises serious questions about the government's ability to detect, let along eradicate, organized crime within its own borders.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tehran Has Discovered Moscow Is a Fair-Weather Friend</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/27/iran-russia-threats-strategic-alignment/</link>
      <description>Iran’s Look East doctrine resulted in a strategic partnership but not a strategic commitment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump Effect in Israel</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/trump-effect-israel</link>
      <description>How his popularity among Jewish Israelis can boost the prospects for peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Is Winning by Waiting</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/china-winning-waiting</link>
      <description>How Beijing turns predictability into power.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What It Will Take to Change the Regime in Iran</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/iran/what-it-will-take-change-regime-iran</link>
      <description>The U.S. military must go big—and then let Iranians do the rest.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sticking Power or Plaster? The UK Armed Forces Bill 2026 and Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/sticking-power-or-plaster-uk-armed-forces-bill-2026-and-preparedness</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Armed Forces Bill 2026 will improve flexibility for the armed services, but how does it affect the UK's material preparedness for war?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Rakhine War Affects Bangladesh’s Economy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-the-rakhine-war-affects-bangladeshs-economy/</link>
      <description>In addition to disrupting the official trade flow, the war in Myanmar has led to a spike in smuggling, black markets, and other economic crimes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escapes from Islamic State Camps in Syria: Implications for Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/escapes-from-islamic-state-camps-in-syria-implications-for-southeast-asia/</link>
      <description>The region may be far away, but the emptying of camps housing foreign Islamic State fighters and their families could have local repercussions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
