<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>HII CEO touts productivity gains—but says new contracts are needed to sustain progress</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/hii-ceo-touts-productivity-gains-says-new-contracts-are-needed-sustain-progress/411243/</link>
      <description>Shipyard exec says deals to build attack and ballistic-missile subs must be inked by mid-year.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon leaders should have more control over services’ tech budgets, GAO suggests</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/02/pentagon-leaders-should-have-more-control-over-services-tech-budgets-gao-suggests/411242/</link>
      <description>Unsurprisingly, “The Departments of Army, Air Force, and Navy disagreed.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 12: Controlling Crypto in UK Politics: Is a Ban What’s Really Needed?</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/podcasts/suspicious-transaction-report/episode-12-controlling-crypto-uk-politics-ban-whats-really-needed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the UK brings forward new electoral legislation, what should the government do about crypto donations, and does it really understand the risks?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three firms move ahead in Army’s future-of-flight-training helicopter training takeover</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/three-firms-move-ahead-armys-future-flight-training-helicopter-training-takeover/411241/</link>
      <description>Despite Congressional concerns, the Army is sprinting to Phase III of its “Flight School Next” initiative.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 23:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. and Iran Agree on Holding Talks but Not Much Else</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/us-iran-talks-oman-russia-new-start-syria/</link>
      <description>The two sides remain at odds over what will be discussed in Oman.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Death of New START</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/new-start-treaty-nuclear-weapons-control-russia-us-trump-putin/</link>
      <description>The world’s two largest nuclear superpowers no longer have limits on their arsenals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S.-Russia New START Nuclear Arms Control Treaty Expires</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/new-start-treaty-nuclear-weapons-control-russia-us/</link>
      <description>The world’s two largest nuclear superpowers no longer have limits on their arsenals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cricket Crisis With Olympic Consequences</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/india-pakistan-bangladesh-cricket-world-cup-olympics/</link>
      <description>By mishandling the T20 World Cup, India is ruining its 2036 Olympic dream.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Is Trying to Bully the World Over Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/trump-climate-shipping-environment/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration has sabotaged a key maritime treaty.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a Deal Between Trump and Cuba Might Look Like</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/deal-trump-cuba-oil-tourism-blockade/</link>
      <description>The regime in Havana may concede on key issues but won’t give up power.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greek PM: “I haven’t given up on the trans-Atlantic relationship.”</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/greek-pm-mitsotakis-trump-trans-atlantic-relationship/</link>
      <description>Kyriakos Mitsotakis on Trump, NATO, and how Athens thinks about strategic autonomy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managed Deprivation in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/gaza-trump-board-of-peace-humanitarian-hamas-israel/</link>
      <description>Until humanitarian conditions improve, Trump’s Board of Peace doesn’t deserve the benefit of the doubt.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Secrets to Sensors: Why Open Source Data Must Drive Modern Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/from-secrets-to-sensors-why-open-source-data-must-drive-modern-intelligence</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE BLUF / COLUMN — &lt;/strong&gt;The Department of Defense is on a tear to revamp technology for warfighters. Secretary Hegseth signed an AI strategy on 9 January and prior to that he called for an Enterprise Command and Control Program Office that would provide a real time battlespace picture for military commanders, something that has been talked about for years but never completed. The urgency is clear. The intelligence community must play a large part in this Department of Defense technology transformation if it wants to remain relevant to the warfighter and decision makers. Key for the intelligence community will be to fundamentally rethink its relationship with open source data. To be most useful for the decision makers and operators, the intelligence community must rebuild itself on the backbone of open source data and commercial technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only is data important but because of the volume and complexity of that data, so is the technology that can sift through the data. Public domain data must be the first place to gather trends and threat warnings that feed the many watch centers across the department of defense and intelligence community which will be the basis of the enterprise command and control picture. Much of the technology already exists for sifting through the data; fusing it into one picture will be a feat. The intelligence community, however, must make cultural changes first to accept the importance of the technology and public data, and secondly to acquire the technology and data on a timely basis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need for Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intelligence community has struggled with adopting the reality that to remain relevant, it must embrace publicly and commercially available data into its threat and warning process and use the powerful technologies that the commercial world is developing to sift through that data. There has been much work in this area across the intelligence community and some of it has been groundbreaking but the work has not been comprehensive, integrated, or fast. There are boutique enterprises that attempt to develop their own high-tech way forward but when it comes to scaling such technology across the intelligence community or within the Defense Intelligence Enterprise, the hurdles are huge. Each intelligence agency claims its own security issues and erects fences against cross intelligence technology modernization. Even organizations like the Defense Innovation Unit or IN-Q-TEL focus on discreet requirements, not the wholesale cultural change needed to bring in the latest commercial technology that can support warning and security. As the largest part of the intelligence community, the Defense Intelligence Enterprise needs to lead the way in developing a high tech, open source, data rich environment for its customer base. Military commanders need a real-time, complete, and high-quality battlespace picture to quickly make informed decisions, take direct actions, and assess the high volume of potential targets and threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The capabilities that are available to do this are endless. For example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning Against Biological Events&lt;/strong&gt;: Technical sensors and human sensors worldwide record biological events and provide data on disease upticks and hazardous environments. Environmental &amp; Biosensors are global and are critical tools for detecting, quantifying, and interpreting dynamic changes in environmental or biological systems. There are multiple crowd sourced disease outbreak platforms. Biosensors, local reporting, and crowdsourcing technologies monitor everything from air and water quality to metabolic and cellular activity in real time. Technology can combine these complex platforms and sensors to read the data and provide intelligence analysts a real time global map of trends ad anomalies, that once fused with other intelligence could lead to early detection of a pandemic, an industrial or environmental bio event, or development of a WMD. Such a real time platform, based on open source data would also support military and clandestine operations by providing information to the operator about the environment they will encounter. Such maps are currently available either through a subscription or to the public but not one that fuses all this data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humans and Sensors&lt;/strong&gt;: Multiple commercial enterprises are employing social media&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BLOCKINT&lt;/strong&gt;: Blockchain intelligence (BLOCKINT) is mission-critical to modern defense and counterintelligence operations, supporting analysis and targeting on such issues as terrorism financing, disinformation campaigns, and espionage. BLOCKINT can be an important tool to detect adversary threats and to perpetrate grey zone activity against adversaries. BLOCKINT enables proactive disruption —not just retrospective analysis — allowing agencies to deny, degrade, and disrupt threat actors before funds are fully laundered or operationalized. BLOCKINT provides national security analysts and officials with unique data on how a threat actor is using virtual assets for revenue generation. It also provides a high-level overview of a country's cryptocurrency usage, which could provide valuable insights into the nation’s overall economic health and strategy. The importance of blockchain analysis was underscored in 2024 when the US Senate Committee on Armed Services recommended that the Department of Defense (DOD) explore blockchain technology to potentially revolutionize national security. In the committee’s 2025 National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA), they instructed the Secretary of Defense to investigate and test potential blockchain applications for DoD. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Department of Defense has made clear, commercial solutions for trend analysis, finding anomalies, and providing data for decision makers are abundant. The intelligence community already has some of these abilities. What is missing is the fusion of this data into one picture. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting with Cultural Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to provide the intelligence needed for an increasingly complex world, we need to fundamentally change the practice of intelligence to accept the importance of publicly available and commercially available data. Additionally, the intelligence cycle needs to change. The intelligence cycle needs to start with open source information and data. This means that the intelligence community also needs to incorporate the technology and the algorithms that will allow today’s intelligence professionals see trends, anomalies, and threats in that data. This data then should be fused with intelligence collected by the traditional intelligence disciplines to provide decisionmakers and operators with the information they need to perform their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further, to demonstrate the importance of harnessing the publicly and commercially available data, the intelligence community must develop an open source center that brings in the myriad open source/PAI/CAI and data sifting technologies that industry currently is building. The high tech center would be the first step for intelligence analysts of all types in building threat and warning analysis and targeting. This center would be a place where the US and its allies could share data and techniques to build a global warning picture. It would be the intelligence community’s beginning of the Enterprise Command and Control picture or the Common Intelligence Picture. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will need creativity and leadership to move forward with this generational change in how the intelligence community does business. If this major shake up does not begin soon, the US will lose its edge and remarkable, intelligence driven operations like Absolute Resolve will become amazing stories of American glory that we recount to our grandchildren. The change can happen now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Shocked Canada Out of Complacency on Defense. Will It Last?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/trump-canada-defense-spending-nato-norad-carney-arctic/</link>
      <description>Ottawa has announced ambitious military spending plans, including in the sparsely protected Arctic.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Hot New Critical Minerals Club</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/trump-china-rare-earth-critical-mineral-trade-bloc/</link>
      <description>The U.S. administration is seeking to form a trade bloc with countries that it has otherwise scorned.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: New START expires; Restoring a mil-to-mil tie; US, Iran to talk; CENTCOM hits ISIS; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-05-2026/411216/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Iran Gamble</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-iran-gamble-geopolitical-military-energy-economic-risks-by-ian-bremmer-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although it is still possible that US President Donald Trump could accept a limited nuclear deal with Iran that allows him to declare victory, the more likely scenario is that he will try to repeat his recent success in Venezuela. There is just one problem: Iran is not Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Kyrgyzstan, US Special Envoy Gor Brushes Aside Visa Restrictions, Promotes Business</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/in-kyrgyzstan-us-special-envoy-gor-brushes-aside-visa-restrictions-promotes-business/</link>
      <description>U.S. policy toward Central Asia has narrowed to the economic realm.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Failure of the Will</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-show-shock-with-no-spectacle-does-not-expand-the-base-by-j-p-singh-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump’s shock-and-awe approach to politics has often been compared to authoritarian and fascist leaders who have consolidated power through grand political spectacles. But these accounts conflate shock with genuine spectacle, which Trump is incapable of producing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can One Nation Turn Its Polling Hype Into Seats in Parliament?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/can-one-nation-turn-its-polling-hype-into-seats-in-parliament/</link>
      <description>History suggests it will struggle, as the far-right party's internal dynamics pose its biggest obstacle.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Inbound Tourism Is Booming, But Japanese Are Less Interested in Going Abroad</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/japans-inbound-tourism-is-booming-but-japanese-are-less-interested-in-going-abroad/</link>
      <description>Japan’s government is cutting passport fees in a bid to incentivize overseas travel, which has yet to recover from the pandemic.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh’s 2026 Election Is a Litmus Test for Global Democratic Revival</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/bangladeshs-2026-election-is-a-litmus-test-for-global-democratic-revival/</link>
      <description>If successful, Bangladesh could inspire beleaguered democrats across Asia and beyond. If not, it risks validating the resilience of hybrid regimes that mimic elections while stifling competition.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China and the US Want Africa’s Critical Minerals. Will African Countries Actually Benefit?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/china-and-the-us-want-africas-critical-minerals-will-african-countries-actually-benefit/</link>
      <description>Amid the great power competition, do either the U.S. or Chinese strategies advance Africa’s own vision for developing the continent’s mining sector?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Strengthening the Logic of Authoritarianism and Nationalism in Turkey</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/trump-erdogan-turkey-ozel-imamoglu-democracy/</link>
      <description>In an illiberal world, the Turkish opposition can no longer convince voters that democracy alone is a source of strength.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The outsized influence of America’s admiral in Asia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/05/the-outsized-influence-of-americas-admiral-in-asia</link>
      <description>Can Sam Paparo keep US strategy on an even keel?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newborn parties are scrambling Japanese politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/05/newborn-parties-are-scrambling-japanese-politics</link>
      <description>Though small, they have large megaphones</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weekly cartoon</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/05/the-weekly-cartoon</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/05/politics</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/05/business</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeffrey Epstein’s ghost is haunting the grand old men of capitalism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/05/jeffrey-epsteins-ghost-is-haunting-the-grand-old-men-of-capitalism</link>
      <description>The taint of the disgraced financier will endure</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When management mantras help—and when they hurt</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/05/when-management-mantras-help-and-when-they-hurt</link>
      <description>Don’t bring me problems, bring me solutions. Except in some circumstances</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The elusive Czech at the centre of European business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/05/the-elusive-czech-at-the-centre-of-european-business</link>
      <description>Daniel Kretinsky still believes in the old continent—but fears its lack of pragmatism</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adults are propping up the toy industry</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/05/adults-are-propping-up-the-toy-industry</link>
      <description>In praise of lifelong joy</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Panama Canal is a hinge point in Donald Trump’s new order</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/05/the-panama-canal-is-a-hinge-point-in-donald-trumps-new-order</link>
      <description>A recent Panamanian supreme-court ruling shows how the “Donroe doctrine” really works</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After years of despair, Haiti has a sliver of hope</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/02/05/after-years-of-despair-haiti-has-a-sliver-of-hope</link>
      <description>The UN and America are mounting a new effort to drag the country out of the abyss</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How democracies are using autocratic tools to muzzle journalism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/02/05/how-democracies-are-using-autocratic-tools-to-muzzle-journalism</link>
      <description>As scrutiny of government withers, corruption thrives</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new Bangladesh is only half built</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/05/the-new-bangladesh-is-only-half-built</link>
      <description>Whoever wins the coming election has a lot to do</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to think about new risks of nuclear proliferation</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/05/how-to-think-about-new-risks-of-nuclear-proliferation</link>
      <description>In a might-makes-right world, many countries may conclude that only nukes can keep them safe</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress defended American science. Its work is not over</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/05/congress-defended-american-science-its-work-is-not-over</link>
      <description>It can do more to resist Donald Trump’s assault</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As global press freedom dwindles, corrupt politicians rejoice</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/05/as-global-press-freedom-dwindles-corrupt-politicians-rejoice</link>
      <description>Less scrutiny, more booty</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The outsize influence of America’s admiral in Asia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/05/the-outsize-influence-of-americas-admiral-in-asia</link>
      <description>Can Sam Paparo keep US strategy on an even keel?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why more foreigners are seeking health care in China</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/05/why-more-foreigners-are-seeking-health-care-in-china</link>
      <description>The growth of medical tourism is making locals uneasy</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s graduates face a whole new set of gruelling tests</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/02/05/chinas-graduates-face-a-whole-new-set-of-gruelling-tests</link>
      <description>They prefer certainty to good pay</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voting rights and wrongs in America</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/05/voting-rights-and-wrongs-in-america</link>
      <description>Squabbles over the Voting Rights Act could boost black turnout</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal prosecutors in Minnesota are cracking down on dissent</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/05/federal-prosecutors-in-minnesota-are-cracking-down-on-dissent</link>
      <description>But the pursuit of serious criminals has slackened off</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the brains who explain Trumpism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/05/meet-the-brains-who-explain-trumpism</link>
      <description>The Californian think-tank that applies intellectual gloss to MAGA</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How “remigration” is penetrating Europe’s political mainstream</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/05/how-remigration-is-penetrating-europes-political-mainstream</link>
      <description>A meme from the far-right fringe could spell legal trouble for Germany’s AfD</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How neighbouring populists fall out</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/05/how-neighbouring-populists-fall-out</link>
      <description>The nationalist leaders of Hungary and Slovakia are bitterly divided by history</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe proposes a magical fix for its half-finished single market</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/02/05/europe-proposes-a-magical-fix-for-its-half-finished-single-market</link>
      <description>The “28th corporate regime” is meant to be the one to rule them all</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethiopia inches ever closer to war</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/05/ethiopia-inches-ever-closer-to-war</link>
      <description>The latest flare-up in Tigray shows the risk of a regional conflagration</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hundreds die in a mine collapse in Congo</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/05/hundreds-die-in-a-mine-collapse-in-congo</link>
      <description>The government blames rebels, but such accidents are sadly common</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American aid to Africa comes with more strings attached</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/05/american-aid-to-africa-comes-with-more-strings-attached</link>
      <description>A new crop of health deals is unlikely to meet the needs of recipient countries</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two countries have changed their position about war with Iran</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/05/two-countries-have-changed-their-position-about-war-with-iran</link>
      <description>Further regional conflict could bring chaos—and opportunities</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The reopened Rafah crossing in Gaza brings pitiful gains</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/05/the-reopened-rafah-crossing-in-gaza-brings-pitiful-gains</link>
      <description>Gaza’s putative technocrats are still languishing in Cairo</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Strategic Autonomy for a Capital Lifeline?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indias-strategic-autonomy-for-a-capital-lifeline/</link>
      <description>With the February 2 U.S.-India tariff deal announcement, New Delhi has apparently traded its energy security for capital reassurance.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Cannot Avoid an AI Reckoning</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europes-ai-reckoning-calls-for-domestic-compute-fabs-model-development-by-sona-muzikarova-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given the risks it faces from all sides, Europe must move past its focus on regulatory excellence. Unless it makes rapid strides toward building the physical and financial infrastructure that a domestic European AI industry will need, such preoccupations will prove to be more of a liability than an asset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Yang Sung Ho’s Dismissal Reveals About Kim Jong Un’s New Accountability</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-yang-sung-hos-dismissal-reveals-about-kim-jong-uns-new-accountability/</link>
      <description>The public humiliation of Vice Premier Yang Sung Ho is part of a longer pattern: Kim has been escalating his accountability rhetoric for years.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Super Bowl of Prediction Markets</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/prediction-markets-market-design-to-unlock-full-potential-by-scott-duke-kominers-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As prediction markets have exploded onto the scene in recent years, allowing bets to be placed on a wide range of event-driven outcomes, many have asked whether it is optimal to have markets in everything. But the real question is how best to ensure that these powerful tools are transparent and auditable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Oil Deal for Trump Can Mean a Nuclear Deal for Iran</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/05/iran-trump-oman-nuclear-talks-oil-venezuela-deal/</link>
      <description>Venezuela offers a potential diplomatic model for Washington and Tehran.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s Stature Grows as Trump Invites It to Participate in Iran-US Nuclear Talks</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/pakistans-stature-grows-as-trump-invites-it-to-participate-in-iran-us-nuclear-talks/</link>
      <description>Previously, Pakistan has quietly facilitated backchannel contacts between the U.S. and Iran. Its inclusion now in nuclear talks between the two is unprecedented.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan-Philippines Security Cooperation in the Indo-Pacific Region</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/japan-philippines-security-cooperation-in-the-indo-pacific-region/</link>
      <description>A steady course in troubled waters.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea Waits for Major Concessions From Trump</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/north-korea-waits-for-major-concessions-from-trump/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brother Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/what-thomas-mann-can-teach-us-about-how-to-resist-trump-style-authoritarianism-by-grzegorz-kwiatkowski-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump has demonstrated how quickly democratic politics can be overtaken by intimidation and cruelty. As Thomas Mann argued in the early 20th century, authoritarians gain power because they activate dispositions that already exist within democratic societies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A booming gig economy is formalising India’s labour force</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/05/a-booming-gig-economy-is-formalising-indias-labour-force</link>
      <description>Good news for delivery drivers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The age of a volatile, falling dollar has dawned</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/05/the-age-of-a-volatile-falling-dollar-has-dawned</link>
      <description>Those holding American assets will have to get used to it</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The age of a treacherous, falling dollar</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/02/05/the-age-of-a-treacherous-falling-dollar</link>
      <description>Those holding American assets will have to get used to it</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong is getting its financial mojo back</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/05/hong-kong-is-getting-its-financial-mojo-back</link>
      <description>The hub is attracting more deals. And more Beijing-style politics</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untangling the ideas of Donald Trump’s Fed nominee</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/05/untangling-the-ideas-of-donald-trumps-fed-nominee</link>
      <description>What is Warshonomics?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the dollar may have much further to fall</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/02/05/why-the-dollar-may-have-much-further-to-fall</link>
      <description>It is hard to be a safe haven when trouble starts at home</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timing Africa’s Debt Restructuring</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ethiopia-shows-how-debt-restructuring-delays-allow-crises-to-escalate-by-vera-songwe-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025, sovereign-debt sustainability was largely a matter of luck. In 2026, governments and creditors must embrace a new framework for action on debt –&amp;nbsp;one that identifies and addresses hidden debt issues before they spiral out of control, and delivers restructuring agreements fast enough to offer genuine relief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Will Succeed Xi Jinping?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/who-will-succeed-xi-jinping/</link>
      <description>It is a season of personnel changes in China.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fears of a nuclear arms race rise as New START expires</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/fears-nuclear-arms-race-rise-new-start-expires/411210/</link>
      <description>Fading U.S. leadership has countries from Poland to South Korea thinking about nuclear-weapons programs of their own.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Limits of Russian Power</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/russia/limits-russian-power</link>
      <description>Why Putin isn’t thriving in Trump’s anarchic world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strength Over Peace</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/strength-over-peace</link>
      <description>Venezuela, Iran, and the dicey politics of military intervention.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam Planning For ‘Second US Invasion,’ Leaked Government Document Claims</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/vietnam-planning-for-second-us-invasion-leaked-government-document-claims/</link>
      <description>A leaked planning document published by Project88 emphasizes that Hanoi deeply distrusts the official U.S. proclamations that it respects Vietnam’s political system.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Congressional Committee Says Marcos Impeachment Efforts Lack Substance</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/philippine-congressional-committee-says-marcos-impeachment-efforts-lack-substance/</link>
      <description>The two complaints sought the president's removal for a range of offenses, including alleged drug use and involvement in high-level corruption.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Powers Shaping Global Conflict From the Shadows</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-powers-shaping-global-conflict-from-the-shadows/</link>
      <description>In Myanmar, Cambodia, and beyond, technology has enabled illicit economies to become enmeshed with the systems that underpin legitimate trade and finance.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uganda: Idi Amin 2.0 Loading</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/uganda-idi-amin-20-loading</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Uganda’s leadership is drifting into another authoritarian spiral.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New START Expiry: Implications for Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/new-start-expiry-implications-europe</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The expiry of New START could further undermine the credibility of US extended deterrence and complicate European and US efforts to strengthen conventional deterrence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Targeting Web: Bridging the Gap between Aspiration and Battlefield Reality</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/rusi-defence-systems/digital-targeting-web-bridging-gap-between-aspiration-and-battlefield-reality</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Britain’s Digital Targeting Web moves from concept to reality, learning lessons from past and current conflicts will be crucial to the success of the Army’s digitalised Land Targeting Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military Proxy Party Declared Lopsided Victor in ‘Sham’ Myanmar Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/military-proxy-party-declared-lopsided-victor-in-sham-myanmar-election/</link>
      <description>The Union Solidarity and Development Party (USDP) won 739 of the 1,025 seats up for grabs in national and provincial assemblies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elon Musk is betting his business empire on AI</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/02/04/elon-musk-is-betting-his-business-empire-on-ai</link>
      <description>The fates of xAI, SpaceX and Tesla are increasingly intertwined</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 22:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As It Ages, Southeast Asia Needs a 4-Day Workweek</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/as-it-ages-southeast-asia-needs-a-4-day-workweek/</link>
      <description>Cutting working hours may offer a paradoxical solution to the region's coming demographic crunch.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defense Business Brief: The case for more ground stations | Drone dominance | SDA’s reality check?</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/02/defense-business-brief-case-more-ground-stations-drone-dominance-sdas-reality-check/411211/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
