<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligence I.G. on Hot Seat in Roiling Whistleblower Case</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/intelligence-ig-on-hot-seat-in-roiling</link>
      <description>Christopher Fox implicated in ominous allegations of a Tulsi Gabbard coverup</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S.-Iran Talks Make Little Headway</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/us-iran-indirect-nuclear-talks-oman-trump-military/</link>
      <description>The top U.S. military commander in the Middle East joined the negotiations for the first time.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S.-Iran Indirect Nuclear Talks Fail to Make Significant Progress</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/us-iran-indirect-nuclear-talks-oman-trump-military-force-araghchi/</link>
      <description>The top U.S. military commander in the Middle East joined the negotiations for the first time.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story newsletter: The dangerous dollar</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2026/02/06/cover-story-newsletter-the-dangerous-dollar</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/news-quiz-us-india-trade-deal-nuclear-treaty-expires-philippines-impeachment/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Jan. 31: The U.S. and India sign a trade deal, a nuclear treaty expires, and the Philippines’ VP is in hot water.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Army moves to link a full division with its next-gen C2 prototype</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2026/02/army-moves-link-full-division-its-next-gen-c2-prototype/411259/</link>
      <description>Ivy Sting 4 tested out logistics, tracking soldiers’ vitals and overcoming jammers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the British Empire Chose Canada Over Guadeloupe</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/british-empire-france-americas-history/</link>
      <description>London won the spoils of war from France—and lost the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Enormous Business of the Super Bowl</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/super-bowl-lx-economics-commercials-seahawks-patriots/</link>
      <description>How the economics of football shape American culture.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Melania’ Is a Lousy Film but Forever Part of U.S. History</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/melania-amazon-documentary-review-trump/</link>
      <description>It’s less “Triumph of the Will,” more Jackie Kennedy’s landmark TV special.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America may be reaching peak Spanish</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/06/america-may-be-reaching-peak-spanish</link>
      <description>Bad Bunny’s Super Bowl show may mark a ceiling for the language he performs in</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Pair of Inventive Novels on Migration</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/international-fiction-new-releases-review-kenan-orhan-renovation-patmeena-sabit-good-people/</link>
      <description>Plus, more international fiction releases in February.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawsuits over transgender medicine for minors could be huge</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/02/06/lawsuits-over-transgender-medicine-for-minors-could-be-huge</link>
      <description>One detransitioner was awarded $2m. As America’s guidelines change, more will follow</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s Parliament Mounts Rare Bipartisan Effort to Avert US Tariffs</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/south-koreas-parliament-mounts-rare-bipartisan-effort-to-avert-us-tariffs/</link>
      <description>Both President Lee Jae-myung and the National Assembly want to send a clear message to Trump that they are working to expedite implementation of the trade deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Path to Universal Prosperity by 2100</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/realistic-growth-plan-for-universal-prosperity-by-next-century-by-marc-canal-noguer-et-al-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past century, economic growth has delivered higher incomes and longer lives, while empowering millions of people. Looking to the future, a world where everyone can live securely and with options – as opposed to just subsisting – is within reach, but will require emerging economies to continue expanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh’s Left Returns to the Ballot. Can It Escape Political Irrelevance?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/bangladeshs-left-returns-to-the-ballot-can-it-escape-political-irrelevance/</link>
      <description>Many Bangladeshis are deeply disillusioned with the current political landscape. But are they willing to embrace communists and socialists as the alternative?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does being induced lead to a medicalised birth?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2026/02/06/does-being-induced-lead-to-a-medicalised-birth</link>
      <description>It might actually prevent it</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuela Reformed Its Oil Law. Now What?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/venezuela-oil-law-reform-production-pdvsa-trump/</link>
      <description>Caracas is trying desperately to boost investment in its oil patch, but it may be disappointed.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the leader of Japan’s hard-right populist movement</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/02/06/meet-the-leader-of-japans-hard-right-populist-movement</link>
      <description>Kamiya Sohei’s party has mobilised disaffected voters</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Warsh’s Dangerous Monetary Nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/kevin-warsh-plan-to-shrink-fed-balance-sheet-is-misguided-by-lucrezia-reichlin-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next US Federal Reserve chair seems to think that the large size of the central bank’s balance sheet reflects a discretionary policy choice which can and should be reversed. In reality, however, the Fed's balance sheet has become part of the financial system’s core infrastructure, and shrinking it would carry serious risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: Cost of the DC Guard mission; Shipyard reports production rise; US dronemakers in Asia; Carrier clears builder’s trials; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/02/the-d-brief-february-06-2026/411251/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Driving China’s Mega Medog Hydropower Project?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/whats-driving-chinas-mega-medog-hydropower-project/</link>
      <description>Energy security, frontier development, technological ambition, and geopolitical calculation are increasingly intertwined in China’s infrastructure strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Surging Nationalism Could Shape Thailand’s Election</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/thailand-election-cambodia-border-crisis-military-monarchy/</link>
      <description>The recent border crisis with Cambodia has reignited pro-military sentiment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceasing Imports of Russian Crude: India Pays the Piper</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/ceasing-imports-of-russian-crude-india-pays-the-piper/</link>
      <description>If you want to be in the dance, you have to pay the piper. In the modern global economy, the piper is Donald Trump’s America.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Should Reject US-Style Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-should-not-emulate-us-style-competitiveness-by-sandeep-vaheesan-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;European leaders seem increasingly convinced that, to succeed in the 21st century, they must reshape Europe's economy in America’s image. But the American brand of &quot;competitiveness&quot; contributes to major imbalances and far-reaching harm, which the European Union can avoid by embracing effective competition policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media and Sinophobia: South Korea’s New Political Frontier</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/social-media-and-sinophobia-south-koreas-new-political-frontier/</link>
      <description>What makes the current wave of Sinophobia in South Korea different is not just its intensity, but the infrastructure through which it circulates.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian MP Luvsanjamts Ganzorig on How to Tackle Air Pollution, Corruption, and More</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/mongolian-mp-luvsanjamts-ganzorig-on-how-to-tackle-air-pollution-corruption-and-more/</link>
      <description>“To achieve meaningful reductions in air pollution, we need participation not only from the state, but also from local governments, the private sector, civil society organizations, and citizens themselves.”</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Critical Minerals Resilience Didn’t Start in 2010 – or 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/japans-critical-minerals-resilience-didnt-start-in-2010-or-2026/</link>
      <description>Japan's deep-sea rare earth breakthrough in January 2026 was not a rapid response. It was the latest turn of a ratchet that has been clicking forward for decades.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Other Nazi Olympics</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/olympics-winter-germany-hitler-history/</link>
      <description>Ninety years ago, Nazi Germany hosted both the Summer and Winter Olympics—but the latter has unjustly gone forgotten.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Japan Ready for Internal Displacement Sparked by a Taiwan War?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-japan-ready-for-internal-displacement-sparked-by-a-taiwan-war/</link>
      <description>Part two of a two-part series exploring Japan’s civil protection planning for its southwestern islands.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Democracy Govern Capitalism - or Be Consumed by It?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-corporate-tax-convention-democracy-vs-trumpian-caesarism-by-joseph-e-stiglitz-and-jayati-ghosh-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following aggressive lobbying by the Trump administration, more than 145 countries agreed to give big US multinationals a free pass under the global corporate minimum tax rules that were agreed in 2021. But if democracy is to prevail over oligarchy, policymakers must tax extreme wealth appropriately – and they must do it fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China Really Changing Its Approach to the Yellow Sea?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/is-china-really-changing-its-approach-to-the-yellow-sea/</link>
      <description>Beijing moved one of its maritime platforms in waters disputed by China and South Korea, but other Chinese assets remain.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh’s Election Is Critical to the Future of Press Freedom and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/bangladeshs-election-is-critical-to-the-future-of-press-freedom-and-democracy/</link>
      <description>A free press forms the foundation of all robust, democratic systems and serves as a critical bulwark against rising authoritarianism.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi Jinping Tightens Grip as China’s Military Purge Deepens</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/xi-jinping-tightens-grip-as-chinas-military-purge-deepens</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;In China, the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) “commands the gun”, and Chinese President Xi Jinping controls the one million members of the CCP. In October 2022, Mr. Xi was elected to an unprecedented third term as Secretary General of the CCP and President of the People’s Republic of China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Xi succeeded Hu Jintao as Secretary General in November 2012 and immediately proceeded to expel Politburo member Bo Xilai from the CCP and Zhou Yongkang in 2014, responsible for China’s security services and one of nine-members of the powerful Standing Committee of the Politburo. This was the beginning of Mr. Xi’s anti-corruption campaign – and the removal of political rivals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The anti-corruption campaign continues, with over 115 senior officials investigated in 2025 and reportedly over 60 punished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what got the public’s attention was the removal of defense ministers Wei Feng he and Li Shangfu in October 2023 and June 2024. Then in 2025 the removal of General He Wei Dong, Vice Chairman of the nine-member Central Military Commission (CMC), for “serious violations of Party discipline” and Admiral Miao Hua, Director of the CMC’s Political Work Department.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also removed from the CCP in October 2025 were eight additional senior military officials, to include Lin Xiangyang, former commander of the Eastern Theatre Command responsible for Taiwan; Wang Houbin, former commander of the Rocket Force, responsible for China’s nuclear and missile programs and Wang Chunning, former commander of the People’s Armed Police.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the 1970s and 80s, both General He Weidong and Admiral Miao Hua were assigned to the 31 Group Army in Fujian Province, responsible for any potential military operations against Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And now, in January 2026, Mr. Xi continued with his purge of the military, with the removal of General Zhang Youxia, senior Vice Chairman of the CMC and China’s most senior general and General Liu Zhenli, Chief of CMC’s Joint Staff Department responsible for planning and operations. Both generals are accused of committing severe violations of party discipline and state laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;General Zhang is also a member of the Politburo and a close associate of Mr. Xi. Their fathers fought together in the Chinese civil war with Mao Zedong’s forces that eventually prevailed in 1949. For Mr. Xi to purge a fellow “princeling” – descendants of revolutionary elders – must have shocked senior officials in Beijing wondering when does this hollowing-out of seniors in the military stop, and if they’re next.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;General Zhang. as vice chairman of the CMC, had direct responsibility for military strategies concerning Taiwan. He was responsible for planning for potential conflict with Taiwan. General Zhang was an outspoken proponent of forceful unification, saying the military would “show no mercy” if Taiwan declared independence. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late December 2025, China’s military conducted large-scale drills around Taiwan – “Justice Mission 2025.” This was the sixth major exercise since 2022, simulating a full blockade of Taiwan, with naval vessels and aircraft testing joint operational capabilities; deploying warships, bombers, and fighter jets to encircle Taiwan. The exercise was designed to test China’s ability to seal off Taiwan’s major ports, while simulating strikes on land and sea targets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These “gray zone” tactics were meant to intimidate the public and exhaust Taiwan’s defense resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is quite possible that Mr. Xi removed generals Zhang Youxia, He Wei Dong and Liu Zhenli, all members of the 7-member CMC designed for rapid decision-making and China’s highest military command, with Mr. Xi as its chairman, due to disagreements over Taiwan. All these generals, and general Lin Xiangyang, former commander of the Eastern Theatre Command responsible for Taiwan, were responsible for military operations against Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Xi demands loyalty from all CCP and military colleagues. It’s possible that Mr. Xi’s military colleagues were pushing for a kinetic move against Taiwan in 2027, a date that Mr. Xi said China would have the military capability to kinetically move against Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It appears to me that Mr. Xi was not prepared for a kinetic move against Taiwan, despite what his military generals were strongly advocating. And when Mr. Xi got push back from his generals, he removed them. In China, the CCP controls the gun, and Mr. Xi controls the CCP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The author is the former Associate Director of National Intelligence. All statements of fact, opinion or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the U.S. government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying U.S government authentication of information or endorsement of the author’s views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This column by Cipher Brief Expert Ambassador Joseph DeTrani was first published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2026/jan/20/russia-targeting-ukrainian-civilians/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Washington Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How American Technology Helps China Persecute Its Christians</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-american-technology-helps-china-persecute-its-christians/</link>
      <description>Technologies evolved from U.S. hardware and software are used to surveil and arrest China’s people, especially minorities and those with religious beliefs.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pay Attention to the Prioritizers</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/prioritizers-primacy-restraint-trump-hegseth-venezuela-greenland/</link>
      <description>The Republican foreign-policy establishment is developing a robust middle way between primacy and restraint.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Past Choices Made Sumatra Flood-prone</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/how-past-choices-made-sumatra-flood-prone/</link>
      <description>Decades of damaging forest governance decisions degraded landscapes, turning heavy rain into catastrophe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Trump’s Latest Tariff Threat Against South Korea</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/understanding-trumps-latest-tariff-threat-against-south-korea/</link>
      <description>Looking for a hidden motive misses the point: Trump is extremely direct about expressing his displeasure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake Mental Hospitals Highlight China’s Elder Care Challenge</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/fake-mental-hospitals-highlight-chinas-elder-care-challenge/</link>
      <description>A scandal in which scores of seniors were sucked into an insurance scam shows how the current system is failing vulnerable people.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Costa Rica Elects a Trump Ally</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/costa-rica-election-hernandez-chaves-crime-economy/</link>
      <description>Why the country chose a tough-on-crime candidate for president.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is China Really Doing in Greenland? Fact-Checking Trump’s Arctic Claims</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/what-is-china-really-doing-in-greenland-fact-checking-trumps-arctic-claims/</link>
      <description>Trump’s obsession with Greenland could actually create the result he is so afraid of: increasing China's Arctic presence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe Is Getting Ready to Pivot to Putin</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/europe-russia-putin-trump-pivot-detente/</link>
      <description>In the face of U.S. bullying, European leaders are considering reaching out to Russia’s president.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy Dies in Broad Daylight</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-democracy-media-takeover-by-those-avoiding-accountability-by-carla-norrlof-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In America today, journalism still exists, but the chain that once ran from reporting to shared reality to institutional response has begun to break apart. The consequence is a democracy where truth no longer matters, because facts can be published, verified, and still fail to trigger a response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bond Markets Are Now Battlefields</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/02/06/finance-trump-europe-us-treasurys-greenland/</link>
      <description>The world is returning to an era of weaponized finance.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Defense Budget Jumps 15 Percent</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indias-defense-budget-jumps-15-percent/</link>
      <description>Defense officials say that the inflated spending reflects a new focus on military modernization triggered by Operation Sindoor.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things to Watch in Bangladesh’s Upcoming Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/things-to-watch-in-bangladeshs-upcoming-election/</link>
      <description>Violence remains one of the most serious concerns in the run-up to and during the polls.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Destroying the Far-Right Brand</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-authoritarianism-will-make-liberal-democracy-look-better-harm-far-right-by-maciej-kisilowski-and-anna-wojciuk-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With its unparalleled global visibility, the United States offers an unavoidable case study of radical right-wing governance in action. Just as Brexit ultimately strengthened support for the European Union, MAGA-era America may serve as a cautionary example, weakening the appeal of authoritarianism in other democracies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plebiscite or Refounding? The Constitutional Limits of the Referendum in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/plebiscite-or-refounding-the-constitutional-limits-of-the-referendum-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>By passing this referendum, Bangladesh is likely to set another precedent for disregarding the Constitution in times of crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkmen Gas: A Missing Piece in Europe’s Long-Term Energy Security Puzzle</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/turkmen-gas-a-missing-piece-in-europes-long-term-energy-security-puzzle/</link>
      <description>Europe has a problem. Turkmenistan may be part of the solution.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Financial Gulf Stream Is Nearing a Tipping Point</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/financial-arrangement-that-powered-global-growth-is-unraveling-by-giancarlo-corsetti-2026-02</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the global economy rested on a financial arrangement that allowed the United States to borrow cheaply and absorb much of the world’s surplus output. But that system is beginning to come undone amid escalating geopolitical tensions and growing doubts about US policy stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Plastic Pollution Crisis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/the-plastic-pollution-crisis/</link>
      <description>The evidence is now overwhelming, current levels of plastic production and consumption are unsustainable.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 06:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand Prepares to Vote in High-stakes General Election</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/thailand-prepares-to-vote-in-high-stakes-general-election/</link>
      <description>No party is expected to win the 251-seat majority needed to rule alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Next Hegemon</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/germany/europes-next-hegemon-liana-fix</link>
      <description>The perils of German power.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Risks of the Saudi-UAE Feud</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/real-risks-saudi-uae-feud</link>
      <description>Regional rivalry will raise tensions far beyond the Gulf.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Government Removes Embargo on Arms Sales to Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/us-government-removes-embargo-on-arms-sales-to-cambodia/</link>
      <description>The Department of Commerce's ruling is the latest sign of the positive momentum in relations between Phnom Penh and Washington.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok, Nudification and Addressing Online Harms to Women and Girls</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/networks/shoc/informer/grok-nudification-and-addressing-online-harms-women-and-girls</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;With the new UK law on banning non-consensual intimate images coming into force today. Giles Herdale offers a timely assessment of the need to ensure that the central role of policing is not marginalised within national efforts to address online violence and harms affecting women and girls.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Eighty Billion Dollar Wake-Up Call</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/02/indonesias-eighty-billion-dollar-wake-up-call/</link>
      <description>The country's recent stock crash was a clear warning that the world will no longer invest in a market dominated by a handful of powerful families.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After pushing thousands of federal tech workers to leave last year, the administration is trying to replace them</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2026/02/agencies-lost-around-20000-tech-workers-last-year-and-now-trump-admin-hiring/411274/</link>
      <description>The Defense Department and other agencies are hiring.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How regional powers are thinking about a war in Iran</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/02/05/how-regional-powers-are-thinking-about-a-war-in-iran</link>
      <description>Further conflict could bring chaos—and opportunities</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
