<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Last 48 Hours, Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the movement challenging—and disrupting—ICE</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2026/01/29/inside-the-movement-challenging-and-disrupting-ice</link>
      <description>A non-violent network of activists is forming across America</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Level Beijing Purge Salted with Spy Allegation</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/high-level-beijing-purge-salted-with</link>
      <description>Xi Jinping&amp;#8217;s ouster of topmost general stirs fears of Taiwan grab</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just how debased is the dollar?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/28/just-how-debased-is-the-dollar</link>
      <description>Not nearly as much as it could be</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rubio Faces Tough Questions From Democrats on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/rubio-senate-hearing-venezuela-trump-cuba-rand-paul/</link>
      <description>Senators attacked the Trump administration’s justification for Maduro’s capture.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US military used new 'non-kinetic' cell to guide cyber ops during Maduro capture</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2026/01/us-developed-non-kinetic-cell-ahead-venezuela-mission-push-cyber-operations/411034/</link>
      <description>The unit is part of a broader push to better integrate cyber, EW, and other non-destructive effects into missions, leaders told lawmakers on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi Jinping is immensely powerful. Why can’t he stamp out corruption?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/28/xi-jinping-is-immensely-powerful-why-cant-he-stamp-out-corruption</link>
      <description>His purge of the top brass is part of a wider campaign</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigration agents have become Donald Trump’s personal posse</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2026/01/28/immigration-agents-have-become-donald-trumps-personal-posse</link>
      <description>That is a liability for America and, increasingly, for him</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley wades into a trade spat with South Korea</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2026/01/28/silicon-valley-wades-into-a-trade-spat-with-south-korea</link>
      <description>Coupang’s data breach is turning into a diplomatic row</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. ICE Actions Spark International Concern</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/ice-shootings-us-minneapolis-immigration-trump-italy-winter-olympics-world-cup-ecuador/</link>
      <description>Foreign countries appear worried that the United States’ immigration crackdown could have spillover effects.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:08:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is America about to attack Iran?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/28/is-america-about-to-attack-iran</link>
      <description>Donald Trump says he is willing to negotiate. He might be bluffing</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2026 National Defense Strategy:  No Surprises but Plenty of Mandate</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-2026-national-defense-strategy-no-surprises</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;—&lt;/strong&gt; The 2026 National Defense Strategy (NDS) follows closely the 2025 National Security Strategy, as it should. It also falls in line with the Department of Defense’s narrative and the actions they have taken regarding priorities. The NDS has four lines of effort:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defending the U.S. Homeland&lt;/strong&gt; - Homeland defense is the top priority, with the Western Hemisphere elevated above other regions. This includes border security, open lines of transportation (Panama Canal and Greenland), counter-narcotics operations, and countering adversary influence. This is not a surprise.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deterring China in the Indo-Pacific&lt;/strong&gt; - The approach focuses on deterrence through military strength rather than confrontation, aiming to prevent Chinese dominance while avoiding conflict. The strategy emphasizes expanded military-to-military communication with Beijing to reduce conflict risks. It still cites China’s predatory behaviors and makes clear that China is the second highest priority. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increasing Burden-Sharing with Allies&lt;/strong&gt; - The document argues that allies must significantly increase defense spending, pointing to a new global benchmark of 5% of GDP for defense-related expenditures. It also calls on allies to keep watch against threats in their part of the world so that the US can focus on the Western Hemisphere.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revitalizing the U.S. Defense Industrial Base&lt;/strong&gt; - Described as a once-in-a-century effort essential for military readiness, providing strength to deter the US from getting embroiled in a war, and, if needed, the ability to produce weapons at scale during crises. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notable Omissions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The strategy makes no specific mention of or guarantee to Taiwan, unlike the 2022 Biden era strategy which explicitly supported Taiwan's self-defense. It also omits climate change as a security threat, which the Biden administration had identified.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Perhaps, the most concerning issue is that the NDS does not mention Ukraine. It would have been easy to call out Ukraine’s successes against Russia as the example for how the strategy forecasts the behaviors it seeks from our allies. It also characterizes Russia as a persistent but manageable threat, in effect relegating Russia at the end of the day as inconsequential to the US. This underestimates Moscow’s ability to cause havoc beyond Ukraine. It also is much like waving the red flag at the bull. Moscow will not like being considered a minor player on the world stage. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is Cognitive Warfare Still a Thing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the Defense Industrial Base is called out as important as is the need for weapons systems and platforms, there is nothing in the document about increasing activities in the cognitive warfare area. This is an area where the US needs to step up. There are statements throughout the NDS where one can read into the need for cognitive warfare. The NDS talks about providing options in the spaces prior to war and being ready if the US must go to war. These statements support increasing intelligence support and non-kinetic options for decision makers. Specifically, the NDS says:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;…&lt;em&gt;this Strategy will ensure that we see things and the choices we need to make clearly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;For decisionmakers to “see things” and understand the landscape and to provide them options or choices they will need a strong intelligence community that can collect the information needed to provide warning and articulate the threats we are facing. This same community will then be able to analyze the adversaries’ responses to choices that we make and help inform decisionmakers on what path might work best.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;….&lt;em&gt;including by leading efforts to deter or defend against other, lesser threats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, to deter adversaries, not only does the adversary have to fear your kinetic response but also what you can do behind the scene. Additionally, cognitive warfare can prep the battle space, even if we do not ultimately resort to a battle space. Influence operations could play a huge role in deterrence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;·      ….&lt;em&gt;partner with ….other federal departments and agencies to reinvigorate and mobilize our great nation’s unrivaled creativity and ingenuity, re-spark our innovative spirit….&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This statement seems to be here to support calls for increased irregular warfare activities. Creativity and ingenuity are the hallmark for cognitive warfare and the Department can best support activities within the cognitive warfare or irregular warfare space by partnering with other federal departments and agencies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is nothing surprising in the NDS and that is a good thing. If the NDS had not closely matched the National Security Strategy or the direction we have witnessed the Department headed in the last year, something would have been off. What the NDS does do is provide the military and the Defense Intelligence Enterprise with a strategic framework for priorities. The National Intelligence Strategy should follow next. While the regional priorities in a National Intelligence Strategy should not be surprising, it will be illuminating to see the strategic direction that the Director of National Intelligence sets for how the intelligence community should move forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NDS priorities mean that there will be some adjustments to resources. Reporting indicates that there may soon be changes to the unified command plan whereby US SOUTHCOM and NORTHCOM will be combined into an America’s Command. There will also need to be an adjustment to resources, both money and people to be able to fulfill the NDS mandate. Such a change will take time to build. Expertise does not come overnight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Department will need to make major changes in acquisition and contracting to be able to develop the capabilities the NDS has called out and in the time frame it demands. It is clear that the Department is moving in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are repercussions for our partners and our adversaries. More will be expected of our partners but again, the administration has been clear on that issue and when pressed, our partners have shown that they can step up. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Finally, the NDS is clear that the US is not looking for a fight. However, it is also clear that if our adversaries move in that direction, we will be prepared to push back. We need to make sure that we are and put more focus on cognitive warfare to help us be prepared but also to keep us out of a kinetic fight!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Editor@thecipherbrief.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/a&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Counter a Decentralized Islamic State</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/islamic-state-counterterrorism-strategy/</link>
      <description>A franchising model has led to “inspired” rather than “directed” attacks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haters on the right and left are wrong about London</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2026/01/28/haters-on-the-right-and-left-are-wrong-about-london</link>
      <description>It’s a hub, not a hellhole. Labour should give it more love</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Northrop CEO: deal to accelerate B-21 production could arrive in months</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2026/01/northrop-grumman-ceo-deal-accelerate-b-21-production-could-arrive-months/411021/</link>
      <description>Last year’s government shutdown delayed negotiations between the company and service. Another is looming.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Other India-EU Deal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/india-eu-security-defense-partnership/</link>
      <description>The trade pact may be getting all the attention, but the pair also inked a landmark defense agreement.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Multibillion-Dollar Aid Deals Face Growing Pushback</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/pushback-africa-trump-us-health-aid-deals-nigeria-kenya/</link>
      <description>African governments are increasingly putting the brakes on Washington-led health plans.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Stunning Military Purge – and What It Means For Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/chinas-stunning-military-purge-and-what-it-means-for-taiwan</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/zhang-youxia-first-ranked-vice-chairman-of-the-cmc-attends-the-opening-ceremony-of-the-chinese-people-s-political-consultative.jpg?id=63513488&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C53%2C0%2C54&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEEP DIVE – &lt;/strong&gt;President Xi Jinping’s latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8d0l0g8yz5o&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;purge&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of generals has eviscerated China’s military leadership, drawn comparisons to crackdowns carried out by Chairman &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hoover.org/research/lin-biao-incident-and-peoples-liberation-army-purges&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mao Zedong&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a half century ago, and raised questions about China’s military plans for a takeover of Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xi moved in the past week against China’s most senior military official, General Zhang Youxai, and General Liu Zhenli, who heads the Joint Staff Department, which oversees operations, intelligence and training. Zhang and Liu were members of the Central Military Commission, or CMC, China’s most important military body – and Xi’s campaign has now claimed all but two of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.institutmontaigne.org/en/expressions/purge-zhang-youxia-reading-chinas-army-party-relations-through-tea-leaves&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;CMC’s six leaders&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (one of whom is Xi himself). Xi’s earlier purges have ended the careers of dozens of lower-ranking generals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The PLA’s core command has been mutilated by these purges,” Dr. Zi Yang, an expert on China’s military at the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies (RSIS), told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. As for the CMC, he said that “this organization…that is supposed to oversee quality military advice is more or less gutted. Who’s giving Xi advice on running an organization of two million military personnel?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine an American president firing all but one member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, along with several other high-ranking generals, while simultaneously preparing for a major military contingency, and you have some sense of what’s happening in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dennis Wilder, who served as a senior CIA official and a top White House adviser on China, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/24/what-xi-jinpings-purge-of-chinas-most-senior-general-reveals&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;called&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the moves against Generals Zhang and Liu the “most stunning developments in Chinese politics” since Xi’s rise to power – and said the purges would almost certainly affect any moves against Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If Xi had plans for 2027, I think they’re delayed,” Wilder told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, referring to Xi’s directive that the military be prepared by 2027 to take taiwan by force. “I don't know for how long but they have to be delayed at this point. There's no way that they're ready to take on a major military confrontation in these circumstances.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gen. Zhang was widely considered Xi’s most trusted military aide. Former U.S. National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan, who attended a &lt;a href=&quot;https://china.usembassy-china.org.cn/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-vice-chairman-of-the-central-military-commission-zhang-youxia-of-the-prc/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;meeting&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with Zhang in 2024, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;that he “spoke in an unvarnished way that was typical of a military guy, but also reflective of someone who didn’t feel like he had to be cautious.” Now Gen. Zhang is the latest and most consequential casualty of Xi’s widening purge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s fair to say this is a seismic event,” Sullivan said. For Xi to “take out somebody who he had such a long history with is striking, and raises a lot of questions.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anatomy of a crackdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On January 24th the Defense Ministry announced that Generals Zhang and Liu had been placed under investigation for “suspected serious discipline and law violations”. An &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/3AYwV&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;editorial&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in China’s&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Liberation Army Daily&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; said the two men had “trampled on” Xi’s authority and “severely undermined the party’s absolute leadership over the military.” Their actions, the paper said, had caused “massive damage” to the military’s political strength and combat readiness. &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/world/china/chinas-top-general-accused-of-giving-nuclear-secrets-to-u-s-b8f59dae?gaa_at=eafs&amp;amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqc7eOBnepRsB3zOUMzXCx-OIWjKhBsH3_Gr7HKG4aus02Idlr9tAzQvrwK2yTE%3D&amp;amp;gaa_ts=697a4482&amp;amp;gaa_sig=bVwB7qjAHpuqirsR5vAE5eiaDRiWmrJVcOs2VP5fsIr03VTCkr9mVOZsGF7lzs7H-F8D4SeM0dY36_kB-eLNsQ%3D%3D&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;reported&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that General Zhang has been accused of leaking nuclear secrets to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts had assumed that Gen. Zhang would avoid the purges, given his rare combination of attributes: a decades-long close relationship with Xi; and a decorated record during the 1979 border war with Vietnam. Few current commanders in China have experienced combat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Zhang matters, both as a combat-tested veteran – which is a very rare commodity within the PLA – but also because he truly understands war.” Shanshan Mei, a China defense expert at RAND and former advisor to the U.S. Air Force on China, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “He truly understands tactics and morale and real combat issues.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since taking power in 2012, Xi Jinping has prioritized a revamping of the military, which was widely seen as beset by corruption and outmoded thinking. He &lt;a href=&quot;http://v&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;fired&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; dozens of generals and began an overhaul of the People’s Liberation Army (PLA), which was ultimately led by Gen. Zhang. Xi’s purging of the CMC leadership &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/china/2026/01/24/what-xi-jinpings-purge-of-chinas-most-senior-general-reveals&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;began in 2023&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and culminated in last week’s moves against Zhang and Liu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, Dr. Zi – the RSIS expert – wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamestown.org/five-key-factors-behind-irregular-leadership-changes-in-the-peoples-liberation-army/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;article&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the purges and argued that Zhang Youxia’s removal would likely trigger a crisis within the People’s Liberation Army (PLA). Now, Zi says, that moment has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It's going to have trickle-down effects for sure to the operational level,” Zi told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;“All of Zhang’s associates are going to be put under suspicion. All of Zhang’s underlings are going to feel the pressure as well.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it means for Taiwan – and beyond&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;that the latest ousters will likely have several immediate effects: a drop in PLA morale; less high-level risk-taking and innovation; a disruption in decision-making – involving everything from procurement to high-tech modernization to actual priorities and battle plans; and an almost-certain delay in any military operations against Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ambassador Joseph DeTrani, a former CIA director of East Asia operations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/inside-xi-jinpings-military-purge-loyalty-power-and-taiwan&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;wrote an article&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;in October in which he warned that the high-level upheaval within the PLA might impact decisions involving Taiwan. Now he says that delays are inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got to say this is not going to happen [by 2027],” Amb. DeTrani told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. “And if it is, you have got to wonder, what sort of planning and what sort of leadership would go in? I just don't see how President Xi Jinping could feel even remotely confident that China’s military would be prepared, or is prepared, to use kinetic means to take over Taiwan.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zi said that the purging of the two top generals “has clearly damaged the PLA’s operational capacity,” and he, too, doubted that the military could move against Taiwan until the internal turbulence passes and a new leadership is put in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Any war in the Taiwan Strait is going to be an extremely complex large-scale military operation,” Zi said. “It will require the mobilization of China’s resources in all realms and mobilization of basically all military services and forces. You need people who are capable and talented in positions to plan and lead these operations.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wilder said that while China’s basic military readiness is not in question – “pilots know how to fly their planes…(and) naval and infantry commanders know how to lead their units,” he said – the latest purges will compromise the oversight and execution of any major operations in the near term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think this changes the readiness of PLA forces,” he said. “It’s really about the command structure. I think execution is a problem, because your command structure has been so disrupted.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That “command structure” has been housed within the CMC, whose only remaining uniformed officer is Gen. Zhang Shengmin, who Zi described as a “political commissar with next to no operational command experience.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;“He’s not a combat veteran,” Wilder said of Zhang Shengmin. “You have to find a general in charge, if you're going to go forward with a plan. Who’s your operational commander?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond Taiwan, Wilder said the purges risk a broader “paralysis” within the military’s top echelons. “You don't know what's safe anymore, and whether you might be investigated,” he said. “Officers will want to keep their heads down. They won’t want to propose anything. They will simply wait for instructions.” That, he added, will render the military leadership “dysfunctional for a while. It becomes incapable of serious decision-making.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts said decision-making wasn’t a problem for Gen. Zhang Youxia, who was seen as a straight-shooting advisor who wouldn’t hesitate to give Xi a less-than-rosy assessment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Zhang could give Xi Jinping critical advice and know that Xi would listen,” RAND’s Mei said. “A key question now is: Who is going to give Xi Jinping the Zhang Youxai-style, informed and combat-tested advice, if Xi decides to make any big moves militarily? Who’s going to give him the honest opinion?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amb. DeTrani said that morale at lower ranks will be challenged as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It's got to affect the troops,” DeTrani said. “What is the message that Xi Jinping is sending to the troops – that his leaders are all either corrupt or involved in other nefarious activities? It's got to be very demoralizing for the core of the People's Liberation Army.” He said frontline soldiers may go so far as to question their own commitments. “I've been taking orders from these people and told to potentially give up my life to serve the country – and these people are feeding off the trough? They're corrupt and we're hearing that from our supreme leader? How could they expect us to sacrifice so much if they're not invested the same way as we are?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who will take their place?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the near term, all eyes will be on the generals Xi taps to fill the vacancies – and how soon he does so. Wilder said that one of his “best contacts” inside China told him in the wake of the moves against Zhang and Liu that “There’s more coming. There are going to be other generals that go.” Any further bloodletting would suggest an extended period without a fully reconstituted top brass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whenever Xi chooses to fill the top-tier positions, he will presumably be looking for loyalists who also bring experience and expertise. But experts said that the trickle-down effect of the purges means that many candidates may be tainted by association to the ousted generals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In China, when you take down one person, everything about that person is wrong,” Mei said. “Who is going to replace Zhang? We keep looking one level down, to the theater commanders and political commissars. But many of these people were Zhang Youxian proteges. You take him out, it doesn’t mean that you will have a big collection of qualified, loyal military leaders ready to take over.” She added that among China’s ten theater commanders, “at least 4 or 5 are Zhang Youxian’s people.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several experts referenced Mao’s 1950s “Red” versus “Expert” ideological formula, in which fealty to the Communist Party (i.e., “Red”) was prized above technical skills. The ideal citizens were &quot;Red and Expert&quot; – people who brought both elements to their work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The real question is, can he find the loyalists he needs in those jobs?” Wilder said. “Does he have a slate of candidates? I would presume he cannot leave these positions open for too long.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“My gut feeling tells me that Xi is valuing loyalty over professionalism,” Zi said. “A military professional may tell you things that you don’t want to hear. If he cannot find someone who is both ‘Red’ and ‘expert,’ he is going to choose someone who is loyal.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zi and others added that whoever lands in these positions will have to tread carefully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They will have to be extremely cautious about their behavior, their words, they must carry themselves in a more subservient way,” Zi said. “Maybe even total obedience to Xi’s will and Xi’s mind. Because you don't want to put yourself in the same position as Zhang. And they won’t have anything like his capital.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside China, watching with interest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials in Taiwan &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/china/taiwan-monitoring-abnormal-china-military-leadership-changes-after-top-general-2026-01-26/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;said&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this week that they were closely monitoring what they called “abnormal shifts” within China’s senior military leadership. That said, Defense Minister Wellington Koo projected a nothing-has-changed approach, saying Taipei would not relax its guard, and noting that China’s war games have continued and Beijing has not changed its position vis-a-vis Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mei, Zi and Wilder all raised a concern about another regional flashpoint: The South China Sea. In their view, Xi may seek to quiet domestic concerns about the PLA – and send the rest of the world a message – by initiating a smaller-scale conflict involving those disputed waters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I would worry about the South China Sea, because Xi might want to prove that he’s still strong,” Wilder said. “So what do you do? You pick on a small guy. I’d worry about the Philippines. I think we’re going to have to watch for muscle-flexing of some sort.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zi voiced the same concern, suggesting Xi might seek a “rally-the-flag” operation in the South China Sea – a “small conflict that might be viewed as easy pickings.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for the U.S., the chaos in China’s military leadership offers at least one benefit: the gift of time, as Washington and its Asian allies consider the range of contingencies involving Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You've got a wonderful opportunity,” Wilder said. “Number one, you have time that you didn't have before. We have all these Indo-Pacom plans, we're trying to get AI in the field, drone swarms into the field. It gives us a longer timeline for working with the Japanese, the Philippines, the Australians. That's the good news.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals. Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor@thecipherbrief.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; for publication consideration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Year In: How the China-Cook Islands Partnership Agreement Is Shaping Up</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/1-year-in-how-the-china-cook-islands-partnership-agreement-is-shaping-up/</link>
      <description>While much remains uncertain, developments over the past year offer a clearer sense of what lies ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Getting His Weaker Dollar After All</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/us-dollar-index-value-usd-trump-tariffs-economic-policy-currency/</link>
      <description>That may not be a good thing.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Expert Urges Uzbekistan to Release Tajimuratov Amid Continued Torture Allegations</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/un-expert-urges-uzbekistan-to-release-tajimuratov-amid-continued-torture-allegations/</link>
      <description>The Karakalpak lawyer was sentenced in 2023 to 16 years in prison; ever since there have been consist reports of his mistreatment and torture.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our allies passed your test, Mr. President. Would we?</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2026/01/our-allies-passed-your-test-mr-president-would-we/411011/</link>
      <description>A former U.S. infantryman responds to Trump’s amnesiac take on Afghanistan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near the front line, Russians are growing tired of war</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/28/near-the-front-line-russians-are-growing-tired-of-war</link>
      <description>A report from Belgorod, where not all residents see Ukrainians as enemies</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: CBP report belies ‘terrorist’ charges; Rubio threatens Venezuelan leaders; ‘Unsustainable’ national-security strategy?; EU, India near trade deal; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2026/01/the-d-brief-january-28-2026/411010/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the first time in 54 years there are no pandas in Japan</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2026/01/28/for-the-first-time-in-54-years-there-are-no-pandas-in-japan</link>
      <description>It is a sign of worsening relations with China</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fall of Rojava</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/rojava-turkey-syria-kurds-erdogan-sharaa/</link>
      <description>After defeat, Kurdish aspirations for autonomy remain.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, the International Community Isn’t Dead Yet</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/international-community-dead-trump-carney/</link>
      <description>The “rules-based international order” may prove stronger than Trump—or anyone else—realizes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Military Dimension of the China-US AI Race</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/the-military-dimension-of-the-china-us-ai-race/</link>
      <description>Insights from Dan Tadross.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Congress Keep Trump From Compromising With China at Taiwan’s Expense?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/will-congress-keep-trump-from-compromising-with-china-at-taiwans-expense/</link>
      <description>Even as Trump demonstrates unprecedented power, bipartisan congressional efforts to counter China and support Taiwan.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American or Chinese Exceptionalism?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-threatens-american-exceptionalism-could-worsen-us-china-conflict-by-stephen-s-roach-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both US and Chinese leaders are guilty of personalizing the conflict-prone Sino-American relationship. Continuing down this path – particularly if Donald Trump’s degradation of American leadership becomes a permanent shift, rather than an aberration – raises the important question of which country is truly exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington’s Silence in Asia Is a Gift to Beijing</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/trump-china-japan-taiwan-threats/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration has done little as China threatens U.S. allies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracks in the ‘Ironclad’ South Korea-US Alliance</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/cracks-in-the-ironclad-south-korea-us-alliance/</link>
      <description>U.S. and South Korean leaders dost protest too much, methinks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look Northward, Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/pakistan-afghanistan-tajikistan-central-asia-dorah-torkham/</link>
      <description>A major border feud with Afghanistan should force Islamabad to reevaluate its latent ties with Central Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyzstan Files EAEU Lawsuit Against Russia Over Migrant Medical Care</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/kyrgyzstan-files-eaeu-lawsuit-against-russia-over-migrant-medical-care/</link>
      <description>Bishkek has reportedly taken Moscow to the EAEU court over Russia's failure to provide social protection – medical insurance – to the families of Kyrgyz migrant workers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Greenland Matters</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-greenland-matters-by-michael-froman-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The announcement of a skeletal agreement between US President Donald Trump and NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte was good news, even if it turns out to be a fig leaf for a failed land grab. The brouhaha over Trump’s rhetoric was obscuring what is a genuinely serious geostrategic concern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Anti-Corruption Work Is Set to Get Even More Intense</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/chinas-anti-corruption-work-is-set-to-get-even-more-intense/</link>
      <description>Reading the tea leaves after the CCDI’s Fifth Plenum.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel’s Emergence as an Energy Power Could Become a Liability</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/israel-egypt-gas-deal-strategic-benefits-but-only-a-temporary-solution-by-avri-schechter-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although Israel’s recent deal to supply natural gas to Egypt offers many strategic and economic benefits, it also carries serious risks. Without careful planning, future Israeli governments may find themselves forced to choose between honoring export obligations and safeguarding domestic energy security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran Escalates Protest Crackdown but Says Open to U.S. Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/iran-protests-currency-economy-us-military-intervention-trump/</link>
      <description>“We are not looking for war, but we are prepared for war,” Iran’s foreign minister warned.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Know When You’re an Empire</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-greenland-line-between-hegemony-and-empire-by-carla-norrlof-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite Donald Trump's varying threats against Greenland, the United States has not yet crossed the line into empire, because Greenlandic and Danish consent still matters. Instead, it remains a hegemon that can pressure and persuade without displacing local authority.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:37:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why PTI’s Election Grievance Struggles to Spark Nationwide Action</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-ptis-election-grievance-struggles-to-spark-nationwide-action/</link>
      <description>Public response to PTI’s calls for protests is low, as Pakistanis, battered by inflation and economic woes, have little appetite for upheaval.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Rearmament Paradox</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/28/europe-nato-rearmament-paradox-france-italy-poland-baltics/</link>
      <description>The European countries most able to fill Washington’s military role are those that most want to stay at its side.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Young People Are Choosing Protest</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/gen-z-protests-driven-by-longstanding-institutional-failures-by-rose-ngugi-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Across much of the world, Gen Z-led protests have become proxies for broader discontent, fueled by deep and persistent governance failures rather than isolated events. These are not episodic flare-ups, but rather expressions of widespread frustration with the yawning gap between policy commitments and implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Hinduism Rose and Fell in Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/why-hinduism-rose-and-fell-in-southeast-asia/</link>
      <description>Hinduism gained ground in the region in the early centuries of the Common Era because it provided elites with a fully-fleshed metaphysical package along with literacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Economic Statecraft Is Working</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/chinas-economic-statecraft-working</link>
      <description>Why Beijing can succeed even with an imperfect strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Industrial Strategy Great Again</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/making-industrial-strategy-great-again</link>
      <description>It has worked for America before, but Trump’s approach is all wrong.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Better Greenland Deal</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/better-greenland-deal</link>
      <description>How to turn Trump's tantrum into a win for everyone.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka’s Problem Isn’t Military Boots on the Street</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/sri-lankas-problem-isnt-military-boots-on-the-street/</link>
      <description>It’s the state’s inability to create civilian capacity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Southeast Asia: The Economic Outlook for 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/southeast-asia-the-economic-outlook-for-2026/</link>
      <description>Marcus Tantau from Templeton Research sees maritime Southeast Asia faring well, but predicts mixed fortunes for the mainland nations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Economic Pain Won’t Stop Russia’s War</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/why-economic-pain-wont-stop-russias-war</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Russia, wartime brought on a change of values.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old Ships, Modern Menace: How to Tackle the World’s Shadow Fleets</title>
      <link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/old-ships-modern-menace-how-tackle-worlds-shadow-fleets</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shadow fleets sit at the centre of maritime hybrid warfare, economic security and environmental risk. Despite this growing recognition, the West lacks the coherence to confront it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China’s Embassy in the Philippines Wages Public Opinion Warfare on Facebook</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2026/01/how-chinas-embassy-in-the-philippines-wages-public-opinion-warfare-on-facebook/</link>
      <description>A deep dive into China’s changing propaganda narratives on the South China Sea.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
