<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>USAF adds third contender for initial robot-wingman buy; picks 9 for next phase</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/12/usaf-adds-third-contender-initial-robot-wingman-buy-picks-9-next-phase/410375/</link>
      <description>More than a year after Anduril and General Atomics got R&amp;amp;D contracts, Northrop wins entry with a self-financed CCA.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Year of Patience</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/23/china-year-review-2025-trade-trump-ai-military-purge/</link>
      <description>The trends that defined Beijing’s 2025, from the trade war with Trump to challenges on the home front.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Baltic is becoming a battleground between NATO and Russia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/23/the-baltic-is-becoming-a-battleground-between-nato-and-russia</link>
      <description>Poland, Sweden and others are buying subs to protect pipelines</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The D Brief: New ‘battleship’ announced; Nigeria, under US surveillance; China’s ICBMs; Boat-strike Qs; And a bit more.</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/12/the-d-brief-december-23-2025/410367/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now you can train for the next drone war on simulated Ukrainian front lines</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/12/now-you-can-train-next-drone-war-simulated-ukrainian-front-lines/410368/</link>
      <description>A public version of the simulator used by thousands of Ukrainian drone pilots offers a terrifying glimpse into modern warfare.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The twists and turns of Trump’s 2025 war on unions</title>
      <link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/12/twists-and-turns-trumps-2025-war-unions/410369/</link>
      <description>A look at how the Trump administration has sought to undermine collective bargaining at the Defense Department and across the federal government.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killing of Tajik Boy in Moscow Sparks Debate About Motive</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/killing-of-tajik-boy-in-moscow-sparks-debate-about-motive/</link>
      <description>After a 10-year-old Tajik boy was killed at a Moscow-area school last Tuesday, Dushanbe has spoken out, calling the attack an act of ethnic hatred, but have left bilateral relations unchanged.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Trump Has an Affordability Problem</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-affordability-problem-assigning-blame-by-michael-r-strain-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although Americans are rightly worried about inflation and the affordability of basic goods and services, much of the commentary on the issue has offered more heat than light. How much blame does the president deserve, and what could he do to stave off electoral disaster in November 2026?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is Perhaps Ukraine’s Most Dangerous Time</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/perhaps-ukraines-most-dangerous-time</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERT PERSPECTIVE —&lt;/strong&gt; Each of my eight trips to Ukraine since retiring from the CIA in the summer of 2023 has been filled with unique challenges. Each time I’ve witnessed first-hand the sacrifices the Ukrainians are making on a daily basis to fight for their country’s independence. And while each trip has been physically exhausting, each one has also been highly inspiring because the Ukrainians are fighting to protect many of the traditional American values that I grew up believing in, including the right to self-determination, liberty and national sovereignty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But my latest visit to Ukraine was by far the most difficult. Not just because the Russians are significantly increasing their air attacks on Ukrainian towns and cities or because Ukraine is once again going through a very cold winter while facing significant power shortages caused by Moscow’s attacks against energy infrastructure targets. But mainly because for the first time, I heard Ukrainians questioning my country’s commitment to helping them defend their country. Because I heard Ukrainian interlocutors conclude that the U.S. was not a reliable partner and because Ukrainians who are fighting to protect their country, questioned whether the U.S. was willing to abandon support for their cause in order to secure potential business deals with Russian dictator Vladimir Putin and his regime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remembering all the Americans I had served with over the years, especially those who made the ultimate sacrifice defending liberty and the honor of our country, it is extremely painful to consider the possibility that my country might choose to placate someone like Putin and, in doing so, turn its back on those who have suffered from Putin’s aggression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After more than 10 years of being at war, the Ukrainians are clearly fatigued. Russia's constant attacks against civilian targets are taking a toll. Families throughout the country are living without regular access to electricity and are subjected to daily mass Russian drone and missile attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine's own internal corruption challenges, including the &quot;Operation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/28/world/europe/zelensky-yermak-resigns-ukraine-corruption-scandal.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Midas&lt;/a&gt;&quot; investigation, which resulted in the resignation of President Zelensky’s longtime advisor and head of the Presidential Office, Andriy Yermak, have raised questions among many Ukrainians about Zelensky and his Administration. The scandal also opened the door for many of the opponents of continued support to Ukraine to claim that Ukraine is a corrupt country led by corrupt leaders. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, these critics forget that the Midas investigation is actually evidence of Ukraine’s efforts to deal with corruption and a development that highlights Kyiv’s determination to create a more transparent government based on “rule of law” principles. And there is no comparison between Ukraine’s efforts to deal with corruption, and Russia’s lack of transparency and complete rejection of “rule of law” governance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukrainian fears about being abandoned by Washington are linked to the perception that the U.S. is going to end its support for Kyiv. Fears that are amplified by the recent leaking of the &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-peace-deal&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;28 Point Plan&lt;/a&gt;&quot; that was initially presented to Kyiv by the U.S. as part of Washington’s efforts to bring the war to an end and revelations that the bulk of the plan was written by the Kremlin and then delivered to the U.S. Special Envoy for the Middle East and Russia Steve Witkoff by Russian Sovereign Wealth Fund head Kiril Dmitriyev.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These leaks bore many of the hallmarks of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/russia-narratives-ukraine&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Russian disinformation campaign&lt;/a&gt;, and whether or not the Kremlin leaked this information, there is little doubt that Moscow is using the leaks to undermine the U.S. internationally; to drive a wedge between the U.S. and its allies in Europe; to undermine the morale of the Ukrainian population; and to deceive international and domestic audiences into believing Russian President Vladimir Putin is trying to find a peaceful resolution to the war that he started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moscow has worked relentlessly to create the impression in Washington, Brussels and Kyiv - that the Ukrainian Armed Forces are on the verge of collapse, and it is only a matter of time before Putin achieves his military objectives. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ukrainians, on the other hand, are trying to counter this narrative and demonstrate that the Russians continue to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/en/international/article/2025/12/12/russia-s-phantom-advances-in-ukraine_6748441_4.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;minimal battlefield gains&lt;/a&gt; while paying a tremendous price in terms of personnel and resources. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While people are tired, few appear ready to surrender or give up. Many equate surrender to betrayal of the memories of those Ukrainians who have died since 2014 fighting to defend the country from Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Putin’s effort to control the narrative on Ukraine is partially linked to his desire to cover up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putin-strategic-failure-ukraine&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;how bad his own hand is&lt;/a&gt; at present. Putin does not want the West to focus on how the Russian military continues to struggle to take small amounts of territory, while suffering high casualty rates. He does not want others to focus on Russia’s own struggles with growing financial, economic and social problems that threaten the long-term stability of his regime and the future of Russia itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the Kremlin has shifted its limited financial resources to the Military-Industrial complex, resulting in cutbacks to social spending and bringing an end to support of critical civilian infrastructure projects. While this policy has resulted in an increase in defense production, it is bankrupting the country and in recent months even Russia’s defense industry has had to implement spending cutbacks. Many factories and production sites across Russia are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russias-industrial-titans-furlough-workers-its-war-economy-stalls-2025-10-09/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unable to pay workers&lt;/a&gt; and have been forced to reduce their work week to three or four days per week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The money that Putin was once able to use to incentivize Russians to join the military and fight Ukraine is drying up, forcing him to once again consider mobilization plans, which will no doubt be highly unpopular with many Russians, especially with the “elites” living in the country’s main population centers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The war has also drained off workers, resulting in significant labor shortages. Putin’s war is threatening to plunge Russia into the chaotic and painful social and economic conditions that the country faced in the early and mid-1990s. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before leaving on my latest trip to Ukraine, I was asked to speak at an event in Washington D.C. focused on the future of U.S.-European relations. During that event, one attendee told me that recent polling in the U.S. showed that - since President Trump’s January 2025 inauguration - support for Ukraine among Republicans had risen significantly. This claim was supported by a report published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/12/majority-americans-favor-more-support-ukraine-ukrainian-victory/409925/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Defense One&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; based on polling conducted by the Ronald Reagan Institute and a previous report published by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalaffairs.org/research/public-opinion-survey/dramatic-rise-republican-support-ukraine&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chicago Institute on Global Affairs&lt;/a&gt;. These signs are heartening. In a system where the population’s interests should be considered by elected leaders, this means that the United States Government should be continuing its support for Ukraine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The growing public support for Ukraine should give Ukrainians some hope that the U.S. is not going to abandon them. But it is hard for the Ukrainians to hear that message when it is often drowned out by much more negative news about alleged backroom deals made between Putin’s couriers and individuals close to President Trump and the very real possibility that those couriers are using their access to actively pursue a whisper campaign to influence the President and his policy decisions. That, combined with targeted leaks and distortions of facts to exaggerate the perception that Washington now prefers Moscow to Ukraine and the Europeans is painting a Russian-preferred narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What national security news are you missing today? Get full access to your own national security daily brief by upgrading to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscriber+Member&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; status.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is correct when President Trump says that he inherited a terrible situation in Ukraine. I also agree that as the elected leader of the most powerful country in the world, President Trump has a responsibility to try to end the bloody and senseless conflict. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The President deserves credit for trying, although I do not agree with his periodic claims that the Ukrainians, or their President, are guilty of starting the war - or that Kyiv does not want to end the war. Vladimir Putin is guilty of starting the conflict and despite all of President Trump’s efforts and the Ukrainians willingness to try to find a compromise, Putin has &lt;a href=&quot;https://kyivindependent.com/putin-opens-annual-presser-with-maximalist-demands/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;continued to make maximalist demands&lt;/a&gt; and drag out the conflict in hopes of stealing more of Ukraine’s territory and feeding Russia’s defense industrial complex, which is now the sole functioning part of Russia’s struggling economy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It appeared President Trump recognized this reality in October, when he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/trump-putin-summit-cancelled-after-moscow-sent-memo-washington-ft-reports-2025-10-31/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;canceled&lt;/a&gt; plans to meet with Putin in Budapest and levied &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/do-oil-sanctions-still-work&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;new sanctions&lt;/a&gt; on the Russian Energy sector. Unfortunately, the President allowed Putin to manipulate the U.S. team into thinking Putin was ready to negotiate in November, opening the door to a lot of Russian disinformation and information warfare designed to undermine the U.S., Ukraine and its allies - but not designed to bring the war to an end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I have seen the level of political infighting within Ukraine increase. During a discussion with one Ukrainian General in September of 2024, the General opined that historically, Ukraine had never lost a war to Russia but had lost many wars to itself. He warned that internal political struggles in the country allowed the Russians to identify and exploit the political ambitions of some leaders and use these ambitions to divide the country and undermine national unity. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine is again facing the threat of serious internal divisions that the Kremlin will manipulate and use to achieve its military and political objectives. It appears likely that the Ukrainian government will hold elections in 2026, and the U.S. and the West should be ready to help Kyiv protect those elections from Russian interference. There is also little doubt that Russia itself will not hold fair elections in 2026 or as long as Putin remains in power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an American, I pray that our elected leaders will not repeat the mistakes made by British Prime Minister Neville Chamberlain when trying to deal with Adolf Hitler. The appeasement of Hitler by forcing allies to cede territories to the Nazi regime in Berlin did not lead to “Peace in our Time”. It led to a much greater and more horrific World War that could have been stopped if the English and French had taken decisive action against Hitler at that time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To “Make America Great Again”, Americans need to stand up for what is right. Right - is not appeasing Putin. Justice is not allowing Putin to get away with stealing large portions of Ukraine’s territory and then benefit from killing more than a million Ukrainian and Russian citizens in a war that was designed to protect Putin’s personal power and re-establish an empire that has collapsed twice in the last 150 years. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an American, I pray that we find our way through this very confusing and troubled period, hold the aggressor, Putin, accountable for his crimes, and successfully bring this war to an end while protecting Ukraine’s sovereignty and America’s reputation in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;All statements of fact, opinion, or analysis expressed are those of the author and do not reflect the official positions or views of the US Government. Nothing in the contents should be construed as asserting or implying US Government authentication of information or endorsement of the author's views.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Fed Became a Lender of Immediate Resort</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-mission-creep-undermines-its-legitimacy-by-amit-seru-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With each crisis over the past 15 years, the Federal Reserve has expanded the scope and scale of its interventions. This gradual mission creep has blurred the line between routine liquidity support and support for insolvent institutions, undermining the very purpose of central-bank independence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does anyone still want to help the Uyghurs?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/23/does-anyone-still-want-to-help-the-uyghurs</link>
      <description>Chinese pressure and migration backlashes may result in many being sent back to China</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rogue Hegemons Are Sabotaging the Global Economy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-tariffs-and-chinese-mercantilism-upending-global-trading-system-by-arvind-subramanian-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than providing global public goods, the United States and China are inflicting global economic costs –&amp;nbsp;in mutually reinforcing ways. Donald Trump's tariffs have exacerbated Chinese mercantilism, and Chinese exports are provoking developing countries to engage in protectionism of their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s Labor Model and Its Strategic Consequences</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/south-koreas-labor-model-and-its-strategic-consequences/</link>
      <description>A persistent labor-time gap reflects deeper features of Korea’s economic model rather than cultural habits alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Quiet Stake in Post-Assad Syria</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinas-quiet-stake-in-post-assad-syria/</link>
      <description>China’s approach to post-Assad Syria is defined less by opportunity than by caution.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Navy’s Combat Aviation Capability Takes Wing</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indian-navys-combat-aviation-capability-takes-wing/</link>
      <description>The MH-60R Romeo is widely regarded as the world’s premier all-weather, day and night-capable helicopter, designed for maritime operations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Australia Need Additional Hate Speech Laws?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/does-australia-need-additional-hate-speech-laws/</link>
      <description>Or does Australia need to recommit to the ideals of liberalism?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA is eating itself</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/23/maga-is-eating-itself</link>
      <description>Fighting among conservative influencers reveals broader rifts within the Republican Party</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Military’s Newest Enemy: Fentanyl</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/the-u-s-militarys-newest-enemy-fentanyl</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/media-library/photo-by-matt-mcclain-the-washington-post-via-getty-images.jpg?id=62624280&amp;amp;width=980&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;“There's no doubt that America's adversaries are trafficking fentanyl into the United States in part because they want to kill Americans. If this were a war, that would be one of the worst wars. I believe they killed over the last five or six years, per year, 200-to-300,000 people. You hear about a 100,000, which is a lot of people, but the number is much higher than that. That's been proven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was President Trump in the Oval Office on December 15, explaining why he was signing an Executive Order (EO) designating “illicit fentanyl and its core precursor chemicals as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/12/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-designates-fentanyl-as-a-weapon-of-mass-destruction/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Weapons of Mass Destruction&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (WMD).”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice Trump’s use of the word “war,” and the vast exaggeration of numbers of fentanyl drug deaths in the U.S. -- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-25-107667&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;actually 48,000 in 2024&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Also, does anyone really think that the cartels are pushing fentanyl into this country “to kill Americans?” Or is the real reason they are doing it is to make money – as is the case with most drug dealers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am focusing on this rather odd EO because to me it is another sign that President Trump is bringing the U.S. military into yet another essentially domestic American problem, drug use. I also see it as the Trump administration regularizing employment of the U.S. military to be a normal response to control civil issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, President Trump has employed some 9,000 active and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/national-guard-posse-comitatus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;National Guard service members&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the U.S. southern border to block what he termed an invasion of illegal immigrants. He has also federalized National Guard troops in U.S. cities like Washington, D.C. claiming they were needed to combat crime, and required hundreds of Marines and originally 4,000 California National Guard personnel in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/los-angeles-protests-national-guard&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to put down protests against immigration raids.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was even a military atmosphere in the Oval Office on December 15, because the President used that same meeting to make the first awards of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.war.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4360811/trump-awards-soldiers-marines-border-defense-medal/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mexican Border Defense Medal&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to 13 Army and Marine service members who provided military support to the Department of Homeland Security and U.S. Customs and Border Protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Oval Office meeting, Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth explained that the newly-issued medal exactly replicated the 1918 Mexican Border Defense Medal, but that one went to U.S. troops who patrolled the border during 1916-1917, when fear was of a German-inspired invasion by the paramilitary forces of Francisco &quot;Pancho&quot; Villa as part of the Mexican Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While President Trump said that “to kill Americans” was a purpose of trafficking fentanyl, the EO itself said there was a more complex goal. The EO said, “The production and sale of fentanyl by Foreign Terrorist Organizations and cartels fund these entities’ operations — which include assassinations, terrorist acts, and insurgencies around the world — and allow these entities to erode our domestic security and the well-being of our Nation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, this EO seeks to link up with one of President Trump’s first EOs, signed on January 20, that designated unspecified cartels as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/designating-cartels-and-other-organizations-as-foreign-terrorist-organizations-and-specially-designated-global-terrorists/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Foreign Terrorists Organizations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to make them subject to laws Congress passed in the wake of the September 11, 2001, attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new December 15 EO goes on to say, “The two cartels that are predominantly responsible for the distribution of fentanyl in the United States engage in armed conflict over territory and to protect their operations, resulting in large-scale violence and death that go beyond the immediate threat of fentanyl itself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inexplicably, the EO does not name those two cartels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dea.gov/sites/default/files/2025-07/2025NationalDrugThreatAssessment.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;2025 National Drug Threat Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; makes it clear who they are by saying, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/mexican-drug-cartels&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;The Sinaloa and Jalisco New Generation Cartels&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in particular, control clandestine [fentanyl] production sites in Mexico, smuggling routes into the United States, and distribution hubs in key U.S. cities.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then both the new EO and &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;2025 National Drug Threat Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; carry the exact same following sentence: “Further, the potential for fentanyl to be weaponized for concentrated, large-scale terror attacks by organized adversaries is a serious threat to the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out that back in the 1990s, a number of countries investigated using fentanyl as part of an incapacitating agent, including the U.S. Defense Department. The U.S. dropped the idea because of a margin of safety issue – the difference between a dosage that would incapacitate and one that would kill a person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However the Russians did create a fentanyl-based incapacitating agent and used it in October 2002, when 40 Chechen terrorists seized Moscow’s Dubrovka Theater and held some 800 people hostage. Russians finally released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nonproliferation.org/the-moscow-theater-hostage-crisis-incapacitants-and-chemical-warfare/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;fentanyl-based gas&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to incapacitate those in the theater and it killed some 130 of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fentanyl is an FDA-approved synthetic opioid used medically as a pain reliever and anesthetic. It is close to 100 times stronger than morphine. Two milligrams of fentanyl -- equivalent to 10-to-15 grains of table salt – can be lethal. Unlike other illegal drugs such as cocaine, wholesale traffickers distribute fentanyl by the kilogram, equal to 2.2 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DEA has found wide U.S. usage of illicit, manufactured, counterfeit fentanyl pills ranging from .02 to 5.1 milligrams, the latter more than twice the lethal dose depending on a person’s body size, tolerance and past usage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fentanyl illegal drug use has been a major problem in the U.S. since 2021 when overdose deaths reached &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/cdc-estimates-more-than-107000-americans-died-of-drug-overdoses-in-2021-setting-staggering-record#:~:text=Dr.,made%20treatment%20harder%20to%20get.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;71,000&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But as shown above overdose fentanyl deaths are on the way down. President Trump even recognized fentanyl use had gone down saying in the Oval Office on December 15, “We've also achieved a 50% drop in the amount of fentanyl coming across the border and China is working with us very closely and bringing down the number and the amount of fentanyl that's being shipped…We've got it down to a much lower number.” But Trump added, “Not satisfactory, but it will be satisfactory soon.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term “weapon of mass destruction” has specific legal definitions, typically tied to nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological weapons that are &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to cause large-scale death or bodily harm. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the Trump WMD EO, implementation calls for Defense Secretary Hegseth and Attorney General Pam Bondi to determine if the U.S. military is needed to enforce 10 U.S.C. 282, a post-9/11, 2002 counterterrorism law covering emergency situations involving weapons of mass destruction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If they agree the military is needed, under 10 U.S.C. 282 Hegseth and Bondi are to “jointly prescribe regulations concerning the types of assistance that may be provided,” and “describe the actions that Department of Defense personnel may take in circumstances incident to the provision of assistance.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are provisions in 10 U.S.C. 282 prohibiting the military from authority to arrest individuals, directly participate in searches or seizures of evidence related law violations or collection of intelligence for law enforcement – but those provisions also can also be waived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, under the Trump EO, Hegseth is to consult with Secretary of Homeland Security Kristi Noem to “update all directives regarding the Armed Forces’ response to chemical incidents in the homeland to include the threat of illicit fentanyl.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I go into all these details because I believe something other than fentanyl is involved here. Others are questioning the December 15 EO, such as Andrew McCarthy in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/2025/12/trump-has-no-authority-to-categorize-fentanyl-as-a-weapon-of-mass-destruction/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on December 20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;McCarthy wrote, “President Trump may despise ‘forever wars,’ but he sure seems to like pretend wars. The point of the fentanyl ‘designation’ is to shore up his case for using military force against drug traffickers — although its relevance to high seas around Venezuela is hard to fathom since fentanyl is neither produced nor imported from there. At any rate, fentanyl, a dangerous drug but one with legitimate medical uses, is a narcotic, not a weapon of mass destruction akin to a chemical or biological bomb.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href=&quot;http://military.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Military.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; pointed out, “The [December 15] Executive Order does not spell out a specific military mission, and Pentagon officials have not yet stated whether the armed forces will take on a direct role under the new designation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the EO creates yet another new, domestic area for military operations within the homeland, and what emerges needs to be watched.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Geopolitical Words We Learned in 2025</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/23/new-words-geopolitical-taco-drone-wall-multipolarization-narcoterrorism-asylum-fatigue/</link>
      <description>When it’s TACO time, no one wants to be a persistent objector.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why fewer Americans are giving than before</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/23/why-fewer-americans-are-giving-than-before</link>
      <description>The decline of philanthropy is not about Donald Trump</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What It Means Now that Fentanyl is Designated a “WMD”</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/fentanyl-weapon-of-mass-destruction</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;“There's no doubt that America's adversaries are trafficking fentanyl into the United States in part because they want to kill Americans. If this were a war, that would be one of the worst wars. I believe they killed over the last five or six years, per year, 200-to-300,000 people. You hear about a 100,000, which is a lot of people, but the number is much higher than that. That's been proven.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was President Trump in the Oval Office on December 15, explaining why he was signing an Executive Order (EO) designating “illicit fentanyl and its core precursor chemicals as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/12/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-designates-fentanyl-as-a-weapon-of-mass-destruction/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Weapons of Mass Destruction&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (WMD).”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice Trump’s use of the word “war,” and the vast exaggeration of numbers of fentanyl drug deaths in the U.S. -- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-25-107667&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;actually 48,000 in 2024&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Also, does anyone really think that the cartels are pushing fentanyl into this country “to kill Americans?” Or is the real reason they are doing it is to make money – as is the case with most drug dealers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am focusing on this rather odd EO because to me it is another sign that President Trump is bringing the U.S. military into yet another essentially domestic American problem, drug use. I also see it as the Trump administration regularizing employment of the U.S. military to be a normal response to control civil issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember, President Trump has employed some 9,000 active and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/national-guard-posse-comitatus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;National Guard service members&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the U.S. southern border to block what he termed an invasion of illegal immigrants. He has also federalized National Guard troops in U.S. cities like Washington, D.C. claiming they were needed to combat crime, and required hundreds of Marines and originally 4,000 California National Guard personnel in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/los-angeles-protests-national-guard&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to put down protests against immigration raids.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was even a military atmosphere in the Oval Office on December 15, because the President used that same meeting to make the first awards of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.war.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4360811/trump-awards-soldiers-marines-border-defense-medal/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mexican Border Defense Medal&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to 13 Army and Marine service members who provided military support to the Department of Homeland Security and U.S. Customs and Border Protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Oval Office meeting, Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth explained that the newly-issued medal exactly replicated the 1918 Mexican Border Defense Medal, but that one went to U.S. troops who patrolled the border during 1916-1917, when fear was of a German-inspired invasion by the paramilitary forces of Francisco &quot;Pancho&quot; Villa as part of the Mexican Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While President Trump said that “to kill Americans” was a purpose of trafficking fentanyl, the EO itself said there was a more complex goal. The EO said, “The production and sale of fentanyl by Foreign Terrorist Organizations and cartels fund these entities’ operations — which include assassinations, terrorist acts, and insurgencies around the world — and allow these entities to erode our domestic security and the well-being of our Nation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, this EO seeks to link up with one of President Trump’s first EOs, signed on January 20, that designated unspecified cartels as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/designating-cartels-and-other-organizations-as-foreign-terrorist-organizations-and-specially-designated-global-terrorists/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Foreign Terrorists Organizations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to make them subject to laws Congress passed in the wake of the September 11, 2001, attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new December 15 EO goes on to say, “The two cartels that are predominantly responsible for the distribution of fentanyl in the United States engage in armed conflict over territory and to protect their operations, resulting in large-scale violence and death that go beyond the immediate threat of fentanyl itself.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inexplicably, the EO does not name those two cartels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dea.gov/sites/default/files/2025-07/2025NationalDrugThreatAssessment.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;2025 National Drug Threat Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; makes it clear who they are by saying, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/mexican-drug-cartels&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;The Sinaloa and Jalisco New Generation Cartels&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in particular, control clandestine [fentanyl] production sites in Mexico, smuggling routes into the United States, and distribution hubs in key U.S. cities.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then both the new EO and &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;2025 National Drug Threat Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; carry the exact same following sentence: “Further, the potential for fentanyl to be weaponized for concentrated, large-scale terror attacks by organized adversaries is a serious threat to the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out that back in the 1990s, a number of countries investigated using fentanyl as part of an incapacitating agent, including the U.S. Defense Department. The U.S. dropped the idea because of a margin of safety issue – the difference between a dosage that would incapacitate and one that would kill a person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However the Russians did create a fentanyl-based incapacitating agent and used it in October 2002, when 40 Chechen terrorists seized Moscow’s Dubrovka Theater and held some 800 people hostage. Russians finally released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nonproliferation.org/the-moscow-theater-hostage-crisis-incapacitants-and-chemical-warfare/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;fentanyl-based gas&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to incapacitate those in the theater and it killed some 130 of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fentanyl is an FDA-approved synthetic opioid used medically as a pain reliever and anesthetic. It is close to 100 times stronger than morphine. Two milligrams of fentanyl -- equivalent to 10-to-15 grains of table salt – can be lethal. Unlike other illegal drugs such as cocaine, wholesale traffickers distribute fentanyl by the kilogram, equal to 2.2 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DEA has found wide U.S. usage of illicit, manufactured, counterfeit fentanyl pills ranging from .02 to 5.1 milligrams, the latter more than twice the lethal dose depending on a person’s body size, tolerance and past usage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fentanyl illegal drug use has been a major problem in the U.S. since 2021 when overdose deaths reached &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/cdc-estimates-more-than-107000-americans-died-of-drug-overdoses-in-2021-setting-staggering-record#:~:text=Dr.,made%20treatment%20harder%20to%20get.&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;71,000&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But as shown above overdose fentanyl deaths are on the way down. President Trump even recognized fentanyl use had gone down saying in the Oval Office on December 15, “We've also achieved a 50% drop in the amount of fentanyl coming across the border and China is working with us very closely and bringing down the number and the amount of fentanyl that's being shipped…We've got it down to a much lower number.” But Trump added, “Not satisfactory, but it will be satisfactory soon.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term “weapon of mass destruction” has specific legal definitions, typically tied to nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological weapons that are &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to cause large-scale death or bodily harm. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the Trump WMD EO, implementation calls for Defense Secretary Hegseth and Attorney General Pam Bondi to determine if the U.S. military is needed to enforce 10 U.S.C. 282, a post-9/11, 2002 counterterrorism law covering emergency situations involving weapons of mass destruction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If they agree the military is needed, under 10 U.S.C. 282 Hegseth and Bondi are to “jointly prescribe regulations concerning the types of assistance that may be provided,” and “describe the actions that Department of Defense personnel may take in circumstances incident to the provision of assistance.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are provisions in 10 U.S.C. 282 prohibiting the military from authority to arrest individuals, directly participate in searches or seizures of evidence related law violations or collection of intelligence for law enforcement – but those provisions also can also be waived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, under the Trump EO, Hegseth is to consult with Secretary of Homeland Security Kristi Noem to “update all directives regarding the Armed Forces’ response to chemical incidents in the homeland to include the threat of illicit fentanyl.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I go into all these details because I believe something other than fentanyl is involved here. Others are questioning the December 15 EO, such as Andrew McCarthy in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/2025/12/trump-has-no-authority-to-categorize-fentanyl-as-a-weapon-of-mass-destruction/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on December 20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;McCarthy wrote, “President Trump may despise ‘forever wars,’ but he sure seems to like pretend wars. The point of the fentanyl ‘designation’ is to shore up his case for using military force against drug traffickers — although its relevance to high seas around Venezuela is hard to fathom since fentanyl is neither produced nor imported from there. At any rate, fentanyl, a dangerous drug but one with legitimate medical uses, is a narcotic, not a weapon of mass destruction akin to a chemical or biological bomb.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href=&quot;http://military.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Military.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; pointed out, “The [December 15] Executive Order does not spell out a specific military mission, and Pentagon officials have not yet stated whether the armed forces will take on a direct role under the new designation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the EO creates yet another new, domestic area for military operations within the homeland, and what emerges needs to be watched.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Impose a Loser’s Peace on Ukraine Is a Dead End</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-losers-peace-dead-end</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;The fate of territory in eastern Ukraine remains the “most difficult” sticking point in the ongoing peace talks, President Volodymyr Zelensky&lt;a href=&quot;https://kyivindependent.com/alternatives-to-us-support-are-uncertain-zelensky-says-strength-to-end-war-exists-with-trump-names-most-difficult-issues-in-negotiations/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;acknowledged&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend as U.S. negotiators held separate meetings with Ukrainian and Russian officials. In pursuit of peace, the Trump administration is pushing Ukraine to bend to maximalist Kremlin demands that Russia has failed to impose militarily, while promising Kyiv “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/12/15/us-ukraine-security-guarantees/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;platinum standard&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” security guarantees to sweeten the deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach is unlikely to succeed — and may prove harmful. The administration would be wise to focus instead on pressing Russia to soften its terms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Putin Demands Victory He Hasn’t Earned&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of his conditions for peace, Vladimir Putin&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgexgwr1wrro&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;insists&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that Ukrainian troops withdraw from the roughly 23 percent of the eastern Donetsk region they still control. He vows that if Kyiv refuses, his military will take that territory anyways. Putin seems convinced that Russia eventually can grind down Ukraine’s undermanned forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some U.S. officials have&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/11/19/trump-ukraine-peace-plan-russia-donbas&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;echoed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; those&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/us-army-secretary-warned-ukraine-imminent-defeat-pushing-initial-peace-rcna245704&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;arguments&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, apparently believing that pressuring Kyiv into concessions offers the surest path to peace. As President Donald Trump recently&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/12/09/donald-trump-full-interview-transcript-00681693&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;put it&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Russia is “much bigger” than Ukraine, and “at some point, size will win.” Ukraine is “losing,” Trump contended, so it must “accept” Russian demands. An initial U.S.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/79eefaf8-2fc1-47ac-9653-24cf6a0239f5&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;peace plan&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; released in November, drafted with Russian input, called for Ukraine to cede the remainder of Donetsk, which would become a “demilitarized buffer zone,” which Washington is now pitching as a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/746f1c06-6dbb-4ae2-86a4-916acbfdecf2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;free economic zone&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, it’s anything but certain that Russian forces can conquer the rest of Donetsk. They would need to seize a so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/ec490909-80e5-48ff-a518-8185a6a5d2c7&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;fortress belt&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” of cities and towns, just one of which — Pokrovsk — has taken Russia over a year to capture despite advantages in manpower and materiel. Despite&lt;a href=&quot;https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/07/23/ukraine-war-drone-air-battle-russia-technology-tactics/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;improvements&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in drone warfare, Russia has remained unable to achieve a major breakthrough. That’s partly due to degraded force quality, which is unlikely to recover while large-scale hostilities continue. Russia can continue inching forward so long as it can recruit enough men to throw into the “meatgrinder.” Since 2023, Moscow has maintained a surprisingly strong recruitment rate thanks to ever-larger financial incentives. But that can’t last forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Ukrainian forces are weary and short on infantry, they are not on the verge of breaking. Ukraine continues to put up a stout defense, relying chiefly on Ukrainian-made drones to inflict disproportionate casualties. The decline in American aid has hurt. But even a complete cutoff probably wouldn’t trigger a collapse, though it would mean more Ukrainian lives lost and infrastructure destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, Putin is demanding that Ukraine accept defeat despite the inconvenient fact that Russia hasn’t defeated Ukraine on the battlefield and is unlikely to do so. As long as that remains the case, lopsided peace plans will be a dead end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not a “Zelensky problem.” Recent&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/vast-majority-ukrainians-reject-major-peace-concessions-poll-finds-2025-12-15/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;polling&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; indicates that the Ukrainian people still overwhelmingly reject ceding more territory, seen as synonymous with capitulation. Many in the Ukrainian military are understandably loathe to cede defensible terrain for which Ukrainians have bled for nearly four years. No Ukrainian leader will agree to a deal that would mean political suicide. Even if Zelensky did try to capitulate, it could ignite domestic political&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2025/12/03/8010090/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;instability&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and undermine morale, which Russia would seek to exploit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beware Empty Promises&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In part to convince Kyiv to swallow territorial concessions, the Trump administration has been surprisingly forward-leaning on security guarantees for Ukraine. Although Washington has made clear it won’t allow Ukraine to join NATO, U.S. officials touted an “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/12/15/us-ukraine-security-guarantees/#:~:text=really%20strong%20guarantees%2C-,Article%205%2Dlike,-%2C%E2%80%9D%20said%20one%20U&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article 5-like&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” commitment during recent talks in Berlin. This has enthused Ukrainian and European officials, who are rightly concerned Russia will violate any peace agreement it signs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The White House, though, should take care not to make empty promises. Ukraine must not be left with another 1994 Budapest Memorandum, which gave Kyiv hollow security assurances in exchange for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/nuclear-proliferation-crisis&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;relinquishing nuclear weapons&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; inherited from the Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the administration has released few details regarding the specific commitments it made in Berlin, press&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/16/world/europe/ukraine-security-guarantees-talks.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;reports&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; indicate elements of the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-18/ukraine-security-plan-offers-robust-protections-officials-say&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;plan&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are sensible. The Ukrainian Armed Forces would be permitted to maintain a peacetime strength of 800,000 troops and would receive Western training and equipment, defying Moscow’s demand for Ukrainian demilitarization. A U.S.-led international monitoring and verification mechanism would ensure compliance with a ceasefire, and a deconfliction mechanism would work to prevent escalation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/11/21/ukraine-security-guarantee-nato-article-5-trump&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;earlier media leaks&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2025/12/15/leaders-statement-on-ukraine/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;European statement&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; released following the Berlin talks, suggest Washington may also be offering a non-committal promise to respond with measures up to and including “armed force” if Russia re-invaded Ukraine. The Trump team says it will grant Kyiv’s request to seek Senate approval to make this pledge legally binding. Even so, the threat of U.S. military intervention lacks credibility. Both Trump and his Democratic predecessors have eschewed direct conflict with Russia over Ukraine. That’s unlikely to change under a future president, especially since Washington is trying to focus on deterring China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the White House is betting its bluff won’t be called, it should think again. However the current war ends, it’s unlikely to resolve Russia’s decades-long struggle to dominate Ukraine and reshape the European security order. Moscow will be racing to reconstitute its army, drawing on lessons learned in Ukraine and expanded defense-industrial capacity. Another Russian invasion is a distinct possibility. And if America’s “Article 5-like” guarantee is revealed to be hollow, it could undermine the credibility of the actual Article 5, weakening NATO deterrence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As another part of the security guarantee package, the Trump administration apparently has agreed to support a British- and French-led multinational force in Ukraine. After hostilities cease, countries from the so-called “Coalition of the Willing” would&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-coalition-of-the-willing-headquarters-as-leaders-step-up-support-for-ukraines-immediate-flight&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;help&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; police Ukraine’s skies, clear naval mines, and regenerate the Ukrainian army. This would include deployments of Europe troops to Ukraine (though far from the front lines) — an idea which Moscow vehemently opposes. Other than ruling out putting American boots on the ground, the administration hasn’t publicly specified how it would support this force (likely&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/66ec25a0-4af8-467f-9fbe-cf42de890a7e&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;involving&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance and possibly other so-called “strategic enablers”). Nor has Washington publicly agreed to provide an air-power “backstop” if that force were attacked. If a ceasefire looks shaky and no U.S. backstop is committed, European countries will be more reluctant to put troops in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that tying the force’s deployment to a ceasefire incentivizes Russia to prolong the war. Putin invaded Ukraine precisely to reverse its Westward drift, and Moscow insists that any peace settlement must bar Western troops from the country — a demand that earlier&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/79eefaf8-2fc1-47ac-9653-24cf6a0239f5&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;drafts&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the&lt;a href=&quot;https://zn.ua/ukr/amp/WORLD/novij-mirnij-plan-trampa-do-choho-primushujut-ukrajinu-analiz-chotirokh-dokumentiv.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;U.S. peace plan&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sought to satisfy. As British scholar Jack Watling has&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/ukraine/ukraines-hardest-winter&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;argued&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Europe could obviate the Russian veto commencing with air policing and training in western Ukraine now, before the war ends. Yet European capitals remain unwilling to do so, wary of escalation with Russia. That same fear undermines the force’s deterrent value in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscriber+Members&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; get exclusive access to expert-driven briefings on the top national security issues we face today. Gain access to save your virtual seat now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Path to Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than gunning for a quick but lopsided deal, Washington should patiently focus on shifting the Kremlin’s calculus. Moscow has&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/us-envoy-kellogg-says-ukraine-peace-deal-is-really-close-2025-12-07/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;made clear&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that its ambitions go well beyond Donetsk. In essence, Putin seeks a settlement that locks Ukraine within Russia’s sphere of influence. Given the maximalist nature of Putin’s demands, peace will remain impossible unless Moscow reduces its expectations considerably. Ukraine will also have to make concessions, including on its NATO aspirations. But Russia is the primary obstacle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perversely, pressuring Ukraine to cede more territory could put a deal farther from reach. By attempting to strong-arm Kyiv, echoing Kremlin arguments about the inevitability of Russian advances, and reducing military aid for Ukraine, Washington risks hardening Putin’s intransigence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The consequences could also extend beyond Ukraine. Since the Second World War, the United States has led the free world in opposing the acquisition of territory by military means. Discarding that now could shake allied trust in America while emboldening adversaries such as China. President Trump is right to push for peace in Ukraine, but the medicine must not be worse than the disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So long as Putin is overconfident in his military prospects and feels no sense of urgency to end the war, he is unlikely to make the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/putin-sets-trap-for-u-s-negotiators&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;necessary compromises&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Russian autocrat must be made to realize that more war will bring nothing but pain. The European Union just took an important step by&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/ukraine-welcomes-90-billion-euro-eu-loan-despite-lack-deal-russian-assets-2025-12-19/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;pledging&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 90 billion euros to shore up Kyiv’s state budget through 2027. The United States should do its part, too. Washington could bolster Ukraine’s bargaining position by surging military assistance, much of which could be financed by Europe. This effort should include support for Kyiv’s air defense and long-range strike capabilities, helping Ukraine &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-winter-coming&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;endure the winter&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and impose greater costs on Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Washington should&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdd.org/analysis/2025/11/25/to-build-leverage-for-peace-enforce-oil-sanctions-on-russia/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;stringently enforce&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and build on its recent sanctions targeting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/do-oil-sanctions-still-work&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Russia’s top oil companies&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Treasury Department should target unsanctioned Russian oil suppliers as well as other entities, vessels, and infrastructure that help bring that oil to market. Western countries could further ramp up the pressure by&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/eu-g7-weigh-ban-maritime-services-russian-oil-exports-end-price-cap-2025-12-05/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;replacing&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the Biden-era price cap on Russian oil flows with a full ban on providing shipping or financial services for those exports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Kyiv’s Western partners should encourage the Ukrainian military to fight smarter. Ukraine must stop wasting precious manpower&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2025/12/10/8011187/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;clinging&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to semi-encircled towns or counterattacking to reclaim insignificant positions. This penchant stems in part from concerns that admitting to battlefield setbacks would discourage U.S. support and fuel calls for territorial concessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ukrainians aren’t going to give Russia more than it can take by force of arms. Rather than trying to do Putin’s dirty work for him, Washington should put its energies into convincing Moscow to accept realistic terms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Movies That Made Us Think This Year</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/23/movie-film-2025-top-reviews/</link>
      <description>Our most insightful film reviews of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X’s Location Feature Exposes a Real Problem, but Does Not Fix It</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/x-location-feature-disinformation</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;A new location transparency feature on X is&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj38m11218xo&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;revealing foreign influence&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on American discourse just as federal agencies designed to deal with such threats are being dismantled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techbuzz.ai/articles/x-rolls-out-profile-transparency-feature-to-combat-bots&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;November&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, X began listing&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.x.com/en/managing-your-account/how-to-change-country-settings&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;account locations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the “About this account” section of people’s (or bots’) profiles. X also can list the platform through which users access the social media site, such as the web app or a region-specific app store.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With these new transparency features, X exposed that major&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/x-new-location-transparency-feature-questions-origins-maga-accounts-rcna245487&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;MAGA influencers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are likely operating from Eastern Europe, Africa, and Southeast Asia. And while anti-Trump profiles posing as Americans on X haven’t made headlines, the authors found one&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghostarchive.org/archive/2SkDY&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;listing itself in Charlotte, NC&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that X indicates&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghostarchive.org/archive/pHymu&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;connected via the Nigeria App Store&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One factor driving foreign accounts to masquerade as domestic political commentators could be commercial gain. Heated political debate, abundant in the United States, drives engagement, which can be monetized. Account owners posing as Americans may also be funded or operated by America’s adversaries who seek to shape votes, increase social divisions, or achieve other strategic goals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem of foreign adversaries pretending to be American is not new. During the cold war, Soviet KGB agents even&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/1984/08/07/us-ties-klan-olympic-hate-mail-to-kgb/80918fe8-fcf0-46cf-bb58-726ee46d8ce9/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;posed as KKK members&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and sent hate mail to Olympic athletes before the 1984 summer Olympics. What is different now is the scale and speed of influence operations. The internet makes it dramatically easier for foreign adversaries to pose as Americans and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/disinformation-human-algorithim&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;infiltrate domestic discourse&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The past decade provides countless examples of Russia, China, and Iran &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/us-intelligence-russia-china-and-iran-in-election-propaganda-blitz&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;targeting Americans&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with online influence operations. In 2022, a Chinese operation masqueraded as&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/threat-intelligence/dragonbridge-targets-rare-earths-mining-companies&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;environmental activists in Texas&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to stoke protests against rare earth processing plants. Iran posed as the Proud Boys to send voters&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/archives/opa/pr/two-iranian-nationals-charged-cyber-enabled-disinformation-and-threat-campaign-designed&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;threatening emails&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; before the 2020 elections. In 2014, Russia spread a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/why-are-russian-trolls-spreading-online-hoaxes-in-the-u-s&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;hoax about a chemical plant explosion&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in Louisiana. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;X’s new country of origin feature is a step in the right direction for combatting these operations. Using it, a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/live/cd6xyjj0gnjt?post=asset%3A2ba54356-2607-4b9e-947e-3bdb84143475&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;BBC&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; investigation revealed that multiple accounts advocating for Scottish independence connect to the platform via the Iran Android App. On first blush, this makes little sense. But Iran has a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clemson.edu/centers-institutes/watt/hub/images/hiding-under-the-kilt1.pdf#page=16&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;documented history&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of promoting Scottish independence through covert online influence operations and a track record of sowing discord wherever it can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosing origin alone paints an incomplete picture. Identifying an account’s location does not always tell you who directs or funds the account. For example, Russia has previously&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2020/mar/13/facebook-uncovers-russian-led-troll-network-based-in-west-africa&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;outsourced its attempts&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to influence Americans to operators in Ghana and Nigeria. America’s adversaries continue to leverage proxies in their operations, as seen in a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.memeticwarfare.io/p/guest-post-lagos-doesnt-believe-in&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;recently exposed&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Nigerian YouTube network aggressively spreading&lt;a href=&quot;https://incidentdatabase.ai/cite/1195/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;pro-Kremlin narratives&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, malign actors will likely still be able to spoof their location on X. Virtual private networks (VPNs) mask a user’s real IP address, and while X appears to flag suspected VPN use, the platform may have a harder time detecting&lt;a href=&quot;https://nordvpn.com/blog/residential-proxies/?srsltid=AfmBOoqYyOJ6-Ap93DSv0iEhTJdt-PUDau9QTjpKRuJsWMO0dv9l7JeT&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;residential proxies&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which route traffic through a home IP address. Sophisticated operators and privacy enthusiasts will likely find additional ways to spoof their location. For example, TikTok tracks user locations but there are&lt;a href=&quot;https://nordvpn.com/blog/how-to-change-location-on-tiktok/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;easy-to-find guides&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on how to change one’s apparent location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The additional data points provided by X’s transparency feature, therefore, do not provide a shortcut to attributing a nation-state or other malign actor behind an influence operation. Proper attribution still requires thorough investigation, supported by both regional and technical expertise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief brings expert-level context to national and global security stories. It’s never been more important to understand what’s happening in the world. Upgrade your access to exclusive content by &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;becoming a subscriber&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media platforms, private companies, and non-profits play a significant role in combatting online influence operations. Platforms have access to internal data — such as emails used to create an account and other technical indicators — that allow them to have a fuller picture about who is behind an account. Non-profits across the United States, Europe, Australia, and other aligned countries have also successfully exposed many influence operations in the past purely through open-source intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government, however, plays a unique role in countering influence operations. Only governments have the authority to issue subpoenas, access sensitive sources, and impose consequences through sanctions and indictments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Washington, however, has significantly reduced its capabilities to combat foreign malign influence. Over the past year, it has dismantled the FBI's Foreign Influence Task Force, shut down the State Department’s Global Engagement Center, and&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justsecurity.org/119653/wjh-dismantling-foreign-malign-influence-center/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt;effectively dismantled&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the Foreign Malign Influence Center at the Office of the Director of National Intelligence. These changes make it unclear who — if anyone — within the U.S. government oversees countering influence operations undermining American interests at home and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;X’s new transparency feature reveals yet again that America’s adversaries are waging near-constant warfare against Americans on the devices and platforms that profoundly shape our beliefs and behaviors. Now the U.S. government must rebuild its capacity to address it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A War Story Fit for Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.spytalk.co/p/a-war-story-fit-for-christmas</link>
      <description>'Midnight Flyboys' is a riveting tribute to the pilots who ferried secret agents into Nazi-occupied Europe</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Model to Keep Multilateralism Alive</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/gavi-model-can-sustain-multilateral-cooperation-by-jose-manuel-barroso-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the world becomes more multipolar, geopolitical tensions are hampering efforts to devise common solutions to shared problems, and developments within many countries are threatening the institutions on which multilateralism depends. Mission-driven, public-private partnerships like Gavi may offer the only way forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Türkiye Interested in South Asia?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-is-turkiye-interested-in-south-asia/</link>
      <description>Although Türkiye is geographically distant from South Asia, it has a history of involvement in the region because of religion and geopolitics.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Immigration Policy and the Normalization of Military Rule in Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/us-immigration-policy-and-the-normalization-of-military-rule-in-myanmar/</link>
      <description>The Department of Homeland Security's claim that there has been “notable progress in governance and stability&quot; in Myanmar borders on military propaganda.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza’s New Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/gazas-new-normal</link>
      <description>Persistent limited conflict is more likely than peace.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Germany Afford to Be Europe’s Protector?</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/germany/can-germany-afford-be-europes-protector</link>
      <description>A stronger military requires a stronger economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pacific Money Blog: 2025 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-pacific-money-blog-2025-year-in-review/</link>
      <description>From new state investment funds to U.S. tariffs, it has been a busy year for Southeast Asia's economies.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James Chin on the Shifting Political Sands in Malaysia’s Sabah State</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/james-chin-on-the-shifting-political-sands-in-malaysias-sabah-state/</link>
      <description>Last month’s state election delivered a “a vote for Sabah nationalism” and a major defeat for peninsula-based parties.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s Military Prepares to Enact Its Election Plan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/myanmars-military-prepares-to-enact-its-election-plan/</link>
      <description>The junta’s polls, which will be held in three phases starting on December 28, are intended to strengthen military rule by erecting a façade of civilian government.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Really Happened to Flight MH370?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/what-really-happened-to-flight-mh370/</link>
      <description>The lack of information about the aircraft's disappearance in 2014 has led to the emergence of a range of theories, from the plausible to the wildly speculative.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysian Court Rejects Former PM Najib’s House Arrest Bid</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/malaysian-court-rejects-former-pm-najibs-house-arrest-bid/</link>
      <description>The court ruled that while a royal order existed stating that the 72-year-old could serve his prison sentence at home, it was invalid and therefore not legally enforceable.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
