<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Daily Feed (Updated 9 AM BD) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Building U.S. Drone Dominance Brick by Brick</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/drones-brick-by-brick</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION — &lt;/strong&gt;One of the things I loved about LEGO as a child was the ability to mix and match an endless amount of parts to create unique builds. Children (and some adults) gather around a bin of parts to create something new. Imagine being asked: “Build 10 houses in 30 minutes.” Everyone would come up with unique designs using various parts. Now, imagine a constraint: “You may only use red, 2x4, 2x2, and 1x2 bricks, white windows and doors, and it all has to fit on a green 32x32 baseplate.” Quickly, the limited supply causes a frantic scramble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This scenario mirrors the recent call by the Department of War to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.army.mil/article/289322/war_department_asks_industry_to_make_more_than_300k_drones_quickly_cheaply&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;field 300,000 drones&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; over two years. The conflict in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/inside-ukraine-s-innovation-under-fire&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ukraine&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; exposed the U.S.'s lack of preparedness to equip forces with Purpose Built Attritable Systems (PBAS) at the scale of its peer competitors. Further, manufacturers are restricted by the requirement for critical components to be NDAA / BlueUAS compliant and, as of December 22nd, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DA-25-1086A1.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;even &lt;u&gt;more restrictions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which demand non-critical components be U.S.-manufactured. The defense industrial base is struggling to meet unprecedented demand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;embed-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;While numerous startups and giants have stepped up, the U.S. supply chain cannot sustain the required pace. Existing suppliers’ manufacturing capabilities are quickly surpassed as companies scramble to design, build, and market the requested systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;sUAS are fundamentally basic, consisting of a flight controller (FC), electronic speed controller (ESC), motors, propellers, camera, radio/video transmitters, receivers, and a frame. The main problem is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/ukraine-drones-russia-china&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;availability of parts&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and, more critically, sub-components needed to make them. Manufacturers are all reaching into the same scarce “bin,” forcing suppliers to seek materials with increased vigor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Motors, for instance, require neodymium and copper. The majority of motor production occurs outside of the U.S., where technology is mature, labor costs are lower, and the supply chain exists. However, the sUAS industry accounts for less than 8% of neodymium consumption in the U.S. Returning to the LEGO analogy, if a child asks for more 1x1 red bricks to make houses, LEGO, which (in this scenario) makes over 90% of its money on other parts, has little incentive to retool for large-scale 1x1 brick production.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, most FC and ESC boards are produced in Taiwan. While this was permissible under the original NDAA and BlueUAS frameworks, the new requirement for U.S. production necessitates standing up domestic manufacturing, likely to ensure production continues in the event that trade with Taiwan is disrupted. However, standing up U.S. companies, sourcing materials, hiring labor, and developing technology all create significant costs that are passed to the consumer. Since PBAS systems must remain &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;attritable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (affordable enough to be lost in combat), a higher cost per unit will force warfighters to be more judicious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What national security news are you missing today? Get full access to your own national security daily brief by upgrading to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscriber+Member&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; status.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the intense demand and additional domestic constraints, how can the U.S. remain competitive? There are a few ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incentivize existing global manufacturers to stand up U.S.-based manufacturing. &lt;/strong&gt;Companies with existing technology, design, manufacturing, and supply chains should be incentivized to establish domestic production of like products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encourage raw material companies to invest upstream.&lt;/strong&gt; Critical material mining companies (e.g., for lithium and neodymium) currently lack incentive to ensure stable, consistent supply to manufacturers. Encouraging investment upstream offers supply chain guarantees for domestic manufacturing and additional revenue for investors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish a “strategic reserve” of raw materials.&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. maintains strategic oil and gas reserves. For future conflicts, a strategic reserve of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/for-the-trump-administration-policy-often-involves-a-hunt-for-minerals&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;critical sUAS materials&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is vital given the global stranglehold countries like China have on the market to enable rapid manufacturing scale-up even if trade is disrupted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase throughput of BlueUAS and NDAA compliant components from outside the U.S. &lt;/strong&gt;Maintaining U.S. connectivity to the global sUAS marketplace is important. While the restrictions are righteous, isolating U.S. production strains the raw material supply chain, causes allies to follow suit, and increases the overall cost per unit, reducing attritability. The U.S. should use the BlueUAS framework, with increased throughput, to identify compliant vendors across a wide section of allies and trade partners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expedite current NDAA compliant components manufactured overseas through BlueUAS processes.&lt;/strong&gt; As manufacturing shifts to the U.S., the U.S. could provide ‘provisional’ BlueUAS certifications with limited durations to cover companies during the transition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyberinitiativesgroup.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cyber Initiatives Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Sunday newsletter, delivering expert-level insights on the cyber and tech stories of the day – directly to your inbox. Sign up for the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecipherbrief.us10.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=9775ab595d580738d839f9d01&amp;amp;id=9307211312&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CIG newsletter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without a temporary easement or an adequate transitional period, the U.S. drone market is likely to shift abruptly. Many companies cannot afford to stand up U.S. production, or the cost of compliance would render their price points untenable. This situation would likely result in defense giants acquiring the IP/technology from smaller companies at a steep discount, leveraging their supply networks, lobbying, and significant capital advantage to continue development and manufacturing under their umbrella, returning the U.S. defense ecosystem to its former exclusive state, prior to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/defense-acquisition-arsenal-freedom&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;recent tranche of reforms&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. is at a critical inflection point in its quest for American Drone Dominance. The foundation it establishes will define its final strength and resilience. Care must be taken to avoid supply chain degradation, continue providing affordable solutions for the warfighter, and remain flexible and responsive in future crises. Incentivizing domestic production without isolation will ensure the U.S. has all the pieces it needs to build successfully, brick by brick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief is committed to publishing a range of perspectives on national security issues submitted by deeply experienced national security professionals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opinions expressed are those of the author and do not represent the views or opinions of The Cipher Brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who's reading this?  500K+ dedicated national security professionals. Have a perspective to share based on your experience in the national security field? Send it to Editor@thecipherbrief.com for publication consideration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; because national security is everyone’s business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 21:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Trained Eye Sees Strategic Patterns in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.thecipherbrief.com/a-trained-eye-sees-strategic-patterns-in-venezuela</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPINION&lt;/strong&gt; -- Venezuela presents a long-standing challenge tied to narcotics trafficking and transnational criminal networks. For years, the country has functioned as a major transit hub for illicit drug flows, money laundering, and organized crime, with direct consequences for U.S. domestic security and for stability across the Western Hemisphere. These realities alone justify sustained U.S. attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But criminal activity does not explain Venezuela’s full strategic significance. What distinguishes Venezuela today is not only the scale of illicit activity, but the conditions surrounding it: political isolation, economic dependence, weakened institutions, and contested legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These conditions are familiar. These are precisely the environments external adversarial powers exploit in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/how-can-the-u-s-better-manage-the-gray-zone&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;gray zone&lt;/a&gt; to embed influence and preserve leverage without crossing the threshold of open conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In such settings, influence is not imposed abruptly. It is embedded gradually, normalized through routine engagement, and retained for use when pressure mounts. That method, rather than any single triggering event - is what places Venezuela squarely within the scope of longer-term U.S. strategic concern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assessing Venezuela this way does not require assumptions about covert orchestration or crisis direction by outside states. It requires recognizing a recurring competitive approach that has played out repeatedly in fragile and isolated systems: establish access early, avoid responsibility for governance, and preserve optionality as conditions deteriorate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cipher Brief applies expert-level context to national and global security stories. Grant yourself full-access to Cipher Brief expert insights, analysis and private briefings in the new year by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/subscriber-plus&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;becoming a Subscriber+Member&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;horizontal-rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Pattern Observed Across Multiple Theaters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecipherbrief.com/welcome-to-the-gray-zone-and-the-future-of-great-power-competition&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cipher Brief&lt;/em&gt; analysis&lt;/a&gt; has highlighted that strategic competition increasingly unfolds below the threshold of armed conflict. In states facing internal stress or external isolation, influence is rarely asserted through overt coercion. Instead, it is accumulated through sustained presence, access to institutions, and normalization of engagement — creating leverage that can be exercised selectively during moments of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pattern is not theoretical. It is consistent across actors and regions, even where tactics differ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China: Economic and Technical Presence as Strategic Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s approach relies on economic and technical engagement as strategic infrastructure. Commercial projects, administrative systems, and digital platforms provide access long before crises emerge. Over time, this presence enables intelligence collection, political influence, and situational awareness without requiring overt security commitments or visible military footprints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The value of this approach lies in patience. By embedding early and remaining engaged through periods of instability, China preserves optionality when political alignments shift or governance weakens. Influence accumulated quietly can later be activated to protect strategic equities, shape outcomes, or constrain competitors’ freedom of maneuver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This model avoids ownership. It does not require Beijing to stabilize fragile states or assume responsibility for their internal failures. Access is sufficient. Optionality is the objective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russia: Security Engagement and Access Without Ownership&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia applies a more security-centric variant of the same logic. Moscow’s engagement with sanctioned governments or non-recognized actors has repeatedly prioritized intelligence access, operational insight, and regional buffers rather than political alignment or long-term stabilization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By maintaining relationships across formal and informal power structures, Russia ensures continued relevance during periods of transition or escalation. This posture allows Moscow to influence events without absorbing the costs associated with governance, reconstruction, or economic support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here again, the emphasis is not control but access. Engagement is calibrated to preserve leverage while avoiding entanglement — a model designed to expand or contract as circumstances dictate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iran: Network Persistence and Crisis Adaptability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iran’s approach centers on the durability of networks rather than institutions. Elite cultivation, security penetration, and proxy relationships are established early and maintained quietly. When political systems weaken or collapse, these networks remain intact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The advantage is resilience. Preexisting relationships allow rapid recalibration during crises without the need to rebuild influence under pressure. This approach is particularly effective in environments where authority is fragmented and legitimacy contested.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Across cases, Iran’s method demonstrates how influence survives regime change when it is rooted in people, systems, and incentives rather than formal state structures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Analytic Distinction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Across these approaches, a central distinction applies: Presence and enablement do not equal operational control. But sustained presence creates optionality — the ability to act, influence, or constrain outcomes when conditions shift. That optionality, accumulated quietly over time, is what allows external powers to convert instability into strategic advantage without triggering direct confrontation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venezuela as a Permissive Strategic Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela now exhibits many of the conditions that have enabled this form of competition elsewhere. Politically, it remains isolated and internally polarized, with contested legitimacy and eroded institutions. Economically, it is dependent on external partners and vulnerable to leverage through finance, energy, and technology. Strategically, it occupies a sensitive position - proximate to the United States, central to regional migration flows, and endowed with significant energy resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open-source reporting has documented sustained external engagement consistent with these vulnerabilities. Chinese firms maintain long-term financial and energy exposure, while Chinese technology has been linked to state administrative and digital systems. Russia has pursued military cooperation and security ties with the Maduro government over several years. Iran has expanded defense-related cooperation, including activities now cited in U.S. sanctions actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of this establishes direct operational control over events in Venezuela. That distinction matters. Modern competition does not depend on command-and-control relationships. It depends on positioning — ensuring access, protecting equities, and shaping the environment so that options exist when pressure mounts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, Venezuela is not an abrupt escalation point. It is the maturation of a permissive environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. National Interests at Stake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viewed through this lens, the U.S. interests implicated extend beyond narcotics enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security and Intelligence Access: Adversarial access or technical presence in the Western Hemisphere creates intelligence and counterintelligence risks. Proximity amplifies the strategic consequences, particularly during crises when early warning and situational awareness are decisive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional Stability: Venezuela’s instability already fuels migration flows, strains neighboring states, and sustains criminal economies. External actors that selectively stabilize the regime — without addressing governance or legitimacy - risk prolonging instability while insulating it from internal pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Energy and Economic Leverage: Venezuela’s energy sector remains strategically significant. External involvement that secures preferential access or shields operations from pressure can distort markets and complicate sanctions, reducing U.S. leverage over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alliances and Credibility: Regional partners watch not only U.S. actions, but their durability. Episodic pressure without strategic continuity reinforces perceptions that U.S. engagement is temporary, a perception that competitors routinely exploit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Risk of Tactical Action Without Strategic Effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Military or law-enforcement action can disrupt illicit networks and impose immediate costs. But disruption alone rarely dismantles the access structures external powers cultivate over years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When political or economic stress intensifies, those structures often remain intact, allowing competitors to protect their equities and adapt quickly. Pressure that is not paired with a longer-term access-denial strategy risks plateauing or incentivizing deeper external involvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Venezuela, criminal disruption addresses symptoms. It does not, by itself, degrade the political, economic, and intelligence ecosystems that enable adversarial positioning. Without sustained follow-through, tactical success can coexist with strategic stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrative, Legitimacy, and the Competitive Space&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Competition below the threshold of war is also a contest over legitimacy. External powers rarely challenge U.S. actions on operational grounds alone. Instead, they exploit ambiguity, sovereignty narratives, and perceptions of disproportion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These narratives gain traction when objectives appear narrow, temporary, or disconnected from a broader political strategy. Countering them does not require rhetorical escalation. It requires clarity, about purpose, duration, and the outcomes the United States seeks to prevent or enable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic Implications Going Forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela should be assessed as part of a broader competitive environment in which external actors exploit fragility, isolation, and economic dependence to secure enduring access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experience from other regions points to several implications:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Denying durable access matters more than disrupting individual activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time favors persistent presence over episodic pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clarity of purpose constrains adversarial narratives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional confidence and allied coordination reduce competitive space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this environment, success is measured not only by disruption, but by whether competitors are prevented from converting instability into lasting advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela reinforces a familiar reality: in an era of competition below the threshold of war, strategic outcomes are shaped less by single actions than by whether access, influence, and legitimacy are denied over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you Subscribed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SV_DhOZPmrM&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief’s Digital Channel&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube? There is no better place to get clear perspectives from deeply experienced national security experts. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more expert-driven national security insights, perspective and analysis in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecipherbrief.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Cipher Brief&lt;/a&gt; because National Security is Everyone’s Business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 20:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of the Beginning in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/venezuela/end-beginning-venezuela-maduro-trump</link>
      <description>The real challenges and risks for U.S. policy are still to come.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burundi is running out of space</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2026/01/04/burundi-is-running-out-of-space</link>
      <description>The African Great Lakes are becoming one of the most crowded places in the world</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Has no Real Plan for Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2026/01/04/venezuela-maduro-trump-machado/</link>
      <description>The U.S. president is snubbing the democratic opposition.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s power grid is struggling under Russia’s blitz</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2026/01/04/ukraines-power-grid-is-struggling-under-russias-blitz</link>
      <description>Putin is trying ever harder to freeze Kyiv into submission</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s great Venezuelan oil gamble</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2026/01/04/donald-trumps-great-venezuelan-oil-gamble</link>
      <description>The country has the world’s largest petroleum reserves. Getting them out of the ground will be tortuous</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trump Doctrine in Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-venezuela-intervention-reflects-trump-national-security-strategy-by-richard-haass-2026-01</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US military operation to arrest Nicolás Maduro underscores President Donald Trump’s view of the Western Hemisphere as a region where US interests take precedence. Russia and China will welcome this as a sign that Trump shares their vision of a world divided into spheres of influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There are many risks to Donald Trump’s plans to run Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/04/there-are-many-risks-to-donald-trumps-plans-to-run-venezuela</link>
      <description>The regime that was led by Nicolás Maduro may well prove tricky to control</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The many risks to Donald Trump’s plans to “run” Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2026/01/04/the-many-risks-to-donald-trumps-plans-to-run-venezuela</link>
      <description>The regime that was led by Nicolás Maduro may well prove tricky to control</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
