<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins)</title>
    <link>https://evilgodfahim.github.io/</link>
    <description>Master Feed (Updated every 30 mins) generated by script</description>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Parliament Dissolves to Head Off No-Confidence Vote</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/thailand-dissolves-parliament-anutin-cambodia-clashes-snap-elections/</link>
      <description>Triggering snap elections raises the specter of more political turmoil amid deadly clashes with Cambodia.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Make of China’s Trade Surplus</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/china-trade-surplus-economics-trump-policy/</link>
      <description>The imbalance raises questions about the global economy and Trump administration policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will California try to block Hollywood’s next megadeal?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/12/will-california-try-to-block-hollywoods-next-megadeal</link>
      <description>States are beefing up their antitrust enforcement</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/news-quiz-west-africa-coup-thailand-cambodia-conflict-lithuania-emergency-trump-semiconductors/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Dec. 6: A West African coup fails, violence flares on the Thailand-Cambodia border, and Lithuania declares a state of emergency.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happens to China’s Surplus Men?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/china-gender-dating-demographic-population-documentary/</link>
      <description>The one-child policy’s gender imbalance has spawned desperate bachelors, dubious gurus, and a rising manosphere.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nvidia Chip Deal Is a National Security Disaster Waiting to Happen</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/nvidia-chips-national-security-trump-united-states-china-ai/</link>
      <description>Trump’s latest proposal would cede the United States’ AI advantage.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soccer Still Has Some Explaining to Do</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/franklin-foer-how-soccer-explains-the-world-globalization-capitalism-fifa-world-cup/</link>
      <description>Re-read today, Franklin Foer’s 2004 classic inadvertently suggests where globalization went wrong.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Two Asylum-Seekers</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/souleymanes-story-film-review-france-migration-politics/</link>
      <description>“Souleymane’s Story” interrogates the fictions we tell ourselves about what makes an acceptable migrant.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Framework for Financing Global Security</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/defense-spending-crowding-out-development-aid-other-priorities-by-nilima-gulrajani-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather than improving global security, surging military expenditure threatens to deepen geopolitical instability, destroy ecosystems, fuel arms races, raise conflict risks, and crowd out public investment in other priorities, not least development aid. It doesn't have to be this way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Immigration Crackdown Isn't Working</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-immigration-crackdown-is-no-model-to-emulate-by-jorge-g-castaneda-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some right-wing political leaders view Donald Trump’s immigration crackdown as a model to emulate. But a closer look at the numbers confirms that, while denouncing foreigners can be politically fruitful, attempting to get rid of them is both economically costly and demonstrably futile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia Sees the Former Soviet Union as a ‘Fiefdom,’ Moldova’s Foreign Minister Says</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/russia-putin-ukraine-moldova-foreign-minister-popsoi-interview/</link>
      <description>The foreign minister also said if anyone can bring peace to the region, it’s U.S. President Donald Trump.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story: newsletter Can anyone stop Europe’s populist right?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/12/cover-story-newsletter-can-anyone-stop-europes-populist-right</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are some types of sugar healthier than others?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/12/are-some-types-of-sugar-healthier-than-others</link>
      <description>We weigh up the options</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Diplomats Take Trump to Court Over Mass Firings</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/us-diplomats-state-department-firings-rif-trump-court-injunction-union/</link>
      <description>The U.S. Foreign Service officers union seeks an injunction to prevent nearly 250 terminations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany Loves to Hate Friedrich Merz</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/friedrich-merz-germany-chancellor-economy-ukraine-trump-america/</link>
      <description>Germany’s chancellor is doing far better than everyone seems to think.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benin’s Failed Coup and the Future of African Democracy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/benin-coup-plot-future-of-democracy-in-africa-by-kingsley-moghalu-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent explosion of coups and coup plots in West Africa, most recently in Benin, suggests that the region's performative approach to Western-style democracy is running out of steam. While democracy itself is not dead, the continent most likely is heading toward more varied forms of political organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should China Be Reassured by Trump’s National Security Strategy?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/should-china-be-reassured-by-trumps-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <description>The NSS is likely to offer China short-term relief – but cause for long-term concern.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the EU’s Blacklisting of Russia Make a Difference?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-blacklisting-russia-money-laundering-financing-terrorism-is-effective-but-painful-by-miles-kellerman-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The European Commission has finally added Russia to its list of “high-risk” third countries with strategic deficiencies in their anti-money laundering and counter-terrorist financing controls. This blunt measure will close certain loopholes while also imposing collateral damage on innocent Russians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Electric Buses Are Thriving in Europe – Despite Security and Forced Labor Concerns</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinese-electric-buses-are-thriving-in-europe-despite-security-and-forced-labor-concerns/</link>
      <description>Chinese electric bus manufacturers are using their membership in the U.N. Global Compact to deflect scrutiny from European regulators.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan’s 27th Amendment Upends Its Nuclear Command</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/pakistan-constitution-amendment-nuclear-weapons-military-policy/</link>
      <description>A constitutional reform throws restraint, deterrence, and regional stability into question.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Chinese Analysts Interpret Trump’s 2025 National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-chinese-analysts-interpret-trumps-2025-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <description>Far from celebrating an American retreat, Beijing’s strategists are reading the NSS as a blueprint for leaner – and potentially more dangerous – U.S. primacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Nepal’s September Uprising Transform the Ballot?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/will-nepals-september-uprising-transform-the-ballot/</link>
      <description>The elections set for March 2026 will test whether the political energy unleashed by the youth uprising can truly break free from transactional politics.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump Is Unaffordable</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/affordability-crisis-frustrating-us-voters-ahead-of-2026-elections-by-desmond-lachman-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is every reason to think that US President Donald Trump will not have solved his affordability problem by the time voters head to the polls for next year's midterm elections. After all, his entire economic agenda seems designed to make things worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France and Mauritius: Strengthening Ties in the Indian Ocean</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/france-and-mauritius-strengthening-ties-in-the-indian-ocean/</link>
      <description>With major powers like China and India asserting their ambitions in the Indian Ocean, France relies on partnerships with like-minded countries, including Mauritius, to maintain its influence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omar García Harfuch, Mexico’s “Batman” with big political ambitions</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/12/omar-garcia-harfuch-mexicos-batman-with-big-political-ambitions</link>
      <description>The country’s best security minister in years must contend with drug cartels, Donald Trump and assassins’ bullets</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUKUS After AUSMIN: Why Canberra Must Read Washington Clearly</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/aukus-after-ausmin-why-canberra-must-read-washington-clearly/</link>
      <description>Washington’s political message remains supportive, but its strategic priorities no longer clearly align with the long-term demands of the partnership.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Japan’s First Woman Prime Minister Finally Tackle Violence Against Women?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/will-japans-first-woman-prime-minister-finally-tackle-violence-against-women/</link>
      <description>How Takaichi's government addresses the implementation gap for existing laws will define whether her historic appointment translates into substantive progress for women's safety.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Welfare State Saved Capitalism. Now It Can Save European Democracy.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/europe-democracy-welfare-state-spending-authoritarianism-populism/</link>
      <description>A growing skepticism of social spending risks undermining a post-war pillar of Europe’s stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starmer Acknowledges Britain’s China Problem But Overestimates the UK’s Ability to Fix It</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/starmer-acknowledges-britains-china-problem-but-overestimates-the-uks-ability-to-fix-it/</link>
      <description>The real problem is not Britain’s lack of engagement with Beijing, but its shrinking leverage in a China-U.S. power dynamic that London has no power to shape.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Land Degradation and Tajikistan’s Food Security Crisis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/land-degradation-and-tajikistans-food-security-crisis/</link>
      <description>The country's small, fragmented farms and climate pressures threaten food security and economic stability.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USMCA Deal Comes up for Review</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/12/usmca-review-trump-trade-canada-mexico-tariffs/</link>
      <description>Trump has kept Canada and Mexico guessing about whether he will renew the trade agreement.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Really Changed in ‘New Uzbekistan’?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/whats-really-changed-in-new-uzbekistan/</link>
      <description>Since the 2016 death of the country’s first president, Islam Karimov, his successor, Shavkat Mirziyoyev, has strived to present himself as a reformer forging a “New Uzbekistan.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Far Right’s Gender Playbook</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/gender-politics-authoritarians-secret-weapon-by-cynthia-miller-idriss-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around the world, authoritarian leaders are weaponizing gender-based grievances to rally supporters and roll back women’s and LGBTQ+ rights. By casting feminism as a threat to “family stability” and the “moral order,” they seek to shift public sentiment toward a patriarchal, illiberal future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten Years After the Paris Agreement, Let’s Redouble Efforts</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/france-embraced-climate-leadership-since-paris-climate-agreement-by-emmanuel-macron-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is exactly a decade since 195 countries made a historic commitment to work together to keep the long-term rise in global temperatures well below 2°C above pre-industrial levels. Since then, France has fully embraced a leadership role, placing ecology at the heart of its energy, agricultural, and industrial policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An American oil blockade would devastate the Venezuelan regime</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/12/an-american-oil-blockade-would-devastate-the-venezuelan-regime</link>
      <description>The gangsters who prop up Nicolás Maduro rely heavily on money from oil exports</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan’s Uncertain Gamble for Economic Survival</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/afghanistans-uncertain-gamble-for-economic-survival/</link>
      <description>A struggling regime is caught between countervailing forces.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accountability for Nepal’s China-built Pokhara Airport Has Begun</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/accountability-for-nepals-china-built-pokhara-airport-has-begun/</link>
      <description>Nepal's anti-corruption watchdog has filed a corruption case against 55 individuals and a Chinese company in relation to the construction of the $216 million airport.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Europe Lost</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/how-europe-lost-matthijs-tocci</link>
      <description>Can the continent escape its Trump trap?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Multipolar Mirage</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/multipolar-mirage</link>
      <description>Why America and China are the world's only great powers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai Prime Minister Gains Royal Approval For Dissolution of Parliament</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thai-prime-minister-gains-royal-approval-for-dissolution-of-parliament/</link>
      <description>The move, which Anutin Charnvirakul said would &quot;return power to the people,&quot; will pave the way for a snap election in late January or early February.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why North Korea is modernising its conventional arsenal</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/why-north-korea-modernising-its-conventional-arsenal</link>
      <description>Russia's war economy is fuelling Pyongyang's most ambitious military upgrade in decades.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia all at sea on submarine cable risks</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/australia-all-sea-submarine-cable-risks</link>
      <description>Aging fleets and a leadership void threaten the country's subsea cable resilience.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump II Southeast Asia Strategy Tests Agency Beyond the US-China Prism</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/trump-ii-southeast-asia-strategy-tests-agency-beyond-the-us-china-prism/</link>
      <description>From trade deals to the South China Sea, states are navigating risks as they exercise agency amid shifting great power competition.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Allocables’ and other Corruption Keywords in the Philippines</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/allocables-and-other-corruption-keywords-in-the-philippines/</link>
      <description>Our guide to the key concepts and phrases related to the country's ever-widening graft scandal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rights Groups Condemn Myanmar Military Airstrike on Hospital</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/rights-groups-condemn-myanmar-military-airstrike-on-hospital/</link>
      <description>The attack in Rakhine State is part of an offensive that the junta has waged in the run-up to its contentious election on December 28.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenges of Providing Humanitarian Aid</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/gaza-sudan-humanitarian-aid-doha-forum-india-modi-trump-ukraine-europe/</link>
      <description>Organizations working in Gaza and Sudan say their jobs have become harder than ever.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:35:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pacific Islands: “Friends to all” is no longer pragmatic</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/pacific-islands-friends-all-no-longer-pragmatic</link>
      <description>A changing geopolitical climate means the region must work together first before looking outside for help.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why more American seniors are getting high</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/12/11/why-more-american-seniors-are-getting-high</link>
      <description>No age group is taking up cannabis faster</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Ramps Up the Pressure on Maduro</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/us-forces-seize-venezuela-oil-tanker-trump-pressure-campaign-maduro/</link>
      <description>The U.S. seizure of an oil tanker near Venezuela marks a new escalation in the White House’s regime-change ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Accelerates U.S. Pressure Campaign on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/us-forces-seize-venezuela-oil-tanker/</link>
      <description>The U.S. seizure of an oil tanker near Venezuela marks a new escalation in the White House’s regime-change ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin’s Already Won</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/putin-west-russia-ukraine-won/</link>
      <description>He’s exposed fatal divisions in the “West” even as Russians still back his Ukraine invasion.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 22:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s National Security Strategy Is a Blueprint for the Demise of the West</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/trump-national-security-strategy-blueprint-west-demise/</link>
      <description>The White House’s agenda may not be coherent, but it is deeply dangerous.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 21:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Ethnonational Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/trump-s-ethnonational-security-strategy</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States’ new National Security Strategy is a tissue of populist ideology that reflects no understanding of the real challenges facing the country and views the main threat as liberal democracy itself. The result will be bad for most Americans and their European allies, but highly beneficial for financiers, tech billionaires, racists, and authoritarian powers, especially Russia and China.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-s-ethnonational-security-strategy-doc-2025-12</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Cheers for the National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/national-security-strategy-trump-economic-political-democracy/</link>
      <description>Trump’s new document gets much right and a few things wrong.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Geopolitics of Sovereign Wealth Funds</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/qatar-saudi-arabia-sovereign-wealth-funds-united-arab-emirates/</link>
      <description>Countries like Qatar, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates are investing capital right when the world values geopolitical swing states.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Global Economy’s Hidden Rebalancing</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-economy-2026-growth-outlook-unchanged-but-capital-flows-are-shifting-by-marcello-estevao-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the global growth rate in 2026 is projected to be almost the same as it was in 2025, the headline figure belies deeper structural shifts in capital flows and comparative advantage. These shifts are the real story, because they are quietly reshaping how global savings and investment interact over the coming decade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Global AI Governance Could Work</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-ai-governance-should-follow-architectural-model-by-jayant-sinha-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Societies differ in their views on privacy, experimentation, market openness, and safety, so no single regulatory model can ever accommodate everyone’s preferences. But a shared architectural foundation based on certain core principles would give every country the flexibility to strike its own balance between risk and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s Blackout Warfare Needs a U.S. Counter</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/ukraine-blackout-energy-russia-deterrent/</link>
      <description>Deterring Moscow’s assault on Ukraine’s energy will pay off across Europe.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The constitutional dark arts spreading from Russia to the world</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/constitutional-dark-arts-spreading-russia-world</link>
      <description>Concentrating vast power in one office to “save democracy” is the new authoritarian tactic of choice.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Allowing Nvidia to Sell H200 Chips to China Is a Mistake</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/allowing-nvidia-to-sell-h200-chips-to-china-is-a-mistake/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s decision risks undermining the U.S. in its protracted technology competition with China.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Japanese Canary in the Global Debt Coal Mine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-implications-of-japan-raising-interest-rates-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A prospective rise in Japanese interest rates could indicate that not only Japan, but also other heavily indebted economies, including the United States, could face sharply higher yields on government bonds. The only way out for Japan is to boost economic growth; but for the US, it is to raise taxes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Policy Must Learn to Live With Disagreement</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/nuclear-policy-disagreement-climate-ai-public-health/</link>
      <description>From climate to AI, other fields have bridged deep divides.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Is Watching Trump’s Venezuela Campaign Closely</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-china-is-watching-trumps-venezuela-campaign-closely/</link>
      <description>U.S. intervention in Latin America could put China’s growing influence there in jeopardy. That might be the real goal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Treatment for the Most Painful Medical Condition Is Illegal</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/psychedelic-drugs-should-be-legal-for-cluster-headache-by-peter-singer-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sufferers of cluster headaches, also known as &quot;suicide headaches,&quot; will do anything to stop what is possibly the most painful condition known to medicine, including using illegal drugs like psilocybin and LSD. Given strong evidence that psychedelics work, why aren't doctors allowed to prescribe them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why We Still Don’t Know Who the Rich Are in India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-we-still-dont-know-who-the-rich-are-in-india/</link>
      <description>India has detailed systems for measuring poverty. But when it comes to wealth, the data goes dark.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Bets on Unmanned Stealth Bombers</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/china-bets-on-unmanned-stealth-bombers/</link>
      <description>China’s focus on advanced UAVs offers critical insights into the People’s Liberation Army Air Force’s future airpower strategy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weekly cartoon</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/11/the-weekly-cartoon</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/11/business</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/11/politics</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel refuses to withdraw from Syria</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/11/israel-refuses-to-withdraw-from-syria</link>
      <description>That may create more enemies for the Jewish state</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump has not ended conflict between Congo and Rwanda</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/11/donald-trump-has-not-ended-conflict-between-congo-and-rwanda</link>
      <description>But making money may not require making peace</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria’s kidnapping crisis</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/11/nigerias-kidnapping-crisis</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s ire has drawn attention to appalling security failures</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>José Antonio Kast is Chile’s probable next president. How will he govern?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/11/jose-antonio-kast-is-chiles-probable-next-president-how-will-he-govern</link>
      <description>With a hyper-conservative president the country may be a test case for deportations, security crackdowns and spending cuts</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The battle for Warner Bros is a prelude to the real streaming war</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/11/the-battle-for-warner-bros-is-a-prelude-to-the-real-streaming-war</link>
      <description>Professionally made shows face tough competition from independent makers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More reasons for America’s friends to plan for the worst</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/11/more-reasons-for-americas-friends-to-plan-for-the-worst</link>
      <description>A strategy that scorns Europe, bullies Latin America and is vague on Asia</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s hard right is resurgent</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/11/australias-hard-right-is-resurgent</link>
      <description>It includes actual Nazis</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hedging against Trump, Canada reconsiders ties with China</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/11/hedging-against-trump-canada-reconsiders-ties-with-china</link>
      <description>How far it can go will depend on America</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do so many Chinese still smoke?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/11/why-do-so-many-chinese-still-smoke</link>
      <description>One reason: China’s tobacco industry has massive clout</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the fight for MAGA’s foreign policy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/12/11/inside-the-fight-for-magas-foreign-policy</link>
      <description>Donald Trump’s court squabbles over the future of American power</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American doctors are rich and miserable</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/11/american-doctors-are-rich-and-miserable</link>
      <description>A recent study shows they are world leaders in burnout</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much does America know about its boat-strike targets?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/11/how-much-does-america-know-about-its-boat-strike-targets</link>
      <description>Controversies about the lethal strikes touch on intelligence operations</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All hail “The President of Peace”</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/11/all-hail-the-president-of-peace</link>
      <description>But hold the prizes until Donald Trump actually delivers on his new branding</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s trains, the country’s lifeline, have money problems</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/11/ukraines-trains-the-countrys-lifeline-have-money-problems</link>
      <description>Russian drone attacks are only part of the problem</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albania is trying to charm its way into the EU</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/11/albania-is-trying-to-charm-its-way-into-the-eu</link>
      <description>Edi Rama, the prime minister, is held back by his country’s corruption problems</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine struggles to cope with America’s destructive peace plans</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/11/ukraine-struggles-to-cope-with-americas-destructive-peace-plans</link>
      <description>The latest manoeuvres by Donald Trump are familiar</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talks stall between Turkey’s government and the Kurds</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/11/talks-stall-between-turkeys-government-and-the-kurds</link>
      <description>The prize is the ending of four decades of war between the army and the PKK</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A short guide to every business-hotel room</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/11/a-short-guide-to-every-business-hotel-room</link>
      <description>The world’s most commoditised experience</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam’s EV champion is bleeding cash</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/11/vietnams-ev-champion-is-bleeding-cash</link>
      <description>VinFast is seeking salvation in foreign markets</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A window of opportunity for reform in Lebanon is closing</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/11/a-window-of-opportunity-for-reform-in-lebanon-is-closing</link>
      <description>Elections are looming, war drums are beating and the prime minister will soon be a lame duck</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precedent Points to a US War Crime in the Caribbean</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/peleus-case-points-to-us-attacks-on-shipwrecked-survivors-being-a-war-crime-by-allan-j-lichtman-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During World War II, an Allied tribunal convicted German submariners of murdering shipwrecked survivors. In doing so, it set two clear precedents that the Trump administration seems to have overlooked in defending a &quot;second strike&quot; that killed alleged drug smugglers clinging to their capsized boat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German Foreign Minister Wadephul (Finally) Visits China</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/german-foreign-minister-wadephul-finally-visits-china/</link>
      <description>After an earlier trip was postponed, his arrival in Beijing was a positive sign – but ties are not completely mended yet.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Asia, Political Power Is for Sale. Can Global Action Finally Rein It in?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/in-asia-political-power-is-for-sale-can-global-action-finally-rein-it-in/</link>
      <description>Governments must now choose: keep political money largely hidden, or adopt the basic transparency needed to sustain public trust.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle and the hard truths about software</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/11/oracle-and-the-hard-truths-about-software</link>
      <description>Running a giant digital business is not as fun as it used to be</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s Supreme Court should strike down Donald Trump’s tariffs</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/11/americas-supreme-court-should-strike-down-donald-trumps-tariffs</link>
      <description>The judges’ credibility is at stake</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany has a lawyer problem</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/11/germany-has-a-lawyer-problem</link>
      <description>Its endless bureaucratic rules trap would-be reformers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a stiff drink says about China’s economy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/11/what-a-stiff-drink-says-about-chinas-economy</link>
      <description>The baijiu business is the latest to be struck by “involution”</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s bond market is quiet—almost too quiet</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/11/americas-bond-market-is-quiet-almost-too-quiet</link>
      <description>Scott Bessent has a cunning plan</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wall Street is drooling over bank mergers</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/11/wall-street-is-drooling-over-bank-mergers</link>
      <description>The world’s most fragmented financial industry faces dramatic change</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can anyone stop Europe’s populist right?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/11/can-anyone-stop-europes-populist-right</link>
      <description>Apocalyptic warnings by mainstream politicians are doomed to fail</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The populists of Reform UK, already topping the polls, may climb higher</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2025/12/11/the-populists-of-reform-uk-already-topping-the-polls-may-climb-higher</link>
      <description>Claims that its support has peaked are probably wishful thinking</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Once a pariah, the National Rally is now France’s most popular party</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2025/12/11/once-a-pariah-the-national-rally-is-now-frances-most-popular-party</link>
      <description>It could win the presidency in 2027 or parliamentary power even sooner</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Alternative for Germany is the leading party in some German polls</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2025/12/11/the-alternative-for-germany-is-the-leading-party-in-some-german-polls</link>
      <description>Despite retaining its far-right positions</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How did one airline bring Indian aviation to its knees?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/11/how-did-one-airline-bring-indian-aviation-to-its-knees</link>
      <description>The blame is widely shared</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why many Asian megacities are miserable places</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/11/why-many-asian-megacities-are-miserable-places</link>
      <description>And why Shanghai and Tokyo are not</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building an Effective Sovereign Borrowers’ Club</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/borrowers-club-for-global-south-countries-would-improve-debt-sustainability-by-homi-kharas-and-mahmoud-mohieldin-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though creditor coordination has long been institutionalized, borrower countries have often been discouraged from sharing information. Creating a mechanism that enables these countries to discuss technical issues, access capacity-building assistance, and coordinate actions would improve debt sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India Speeds Up Civil Nuclear Sector Privatization</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/india-speeds-up-civil-nuclear-sector-privatization/</link>
      <description>While the government is yet to divulge details, it is considering legislative amendments to relax rules related to the liability of operators and suppliers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did the Pakistan Army Sell Pakistani Neuroscientist Dr. Aafia Siddiqui to the US?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/did-the-pakistan-army-sell-pakistani-neuroscientist-dr-aafia-siddiqui-to-the-us/</link>
      <description>According to a human rights lawyer, the Pakistani army is not interested in securing her release, as that would implicate them in illegal activities they want to keep hidden.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia’s Floods: A Many-headed Serpent of Disaster</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indonesias-floods-a-many-headed-serpent-of-disaster/</link>
      <description>The immediate threat from Sumatra's floods and landslides may be over, but for many survivors the ordeal is only just beginning.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t fear China’s trillion-dollar trade surplus</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/11/dont-fear-chinas-trillion-dollar-trade-surplus</link>
      <description>It is a problem not for the rest of the world, but for itself</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Lessons China Learned from the United States</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/11/lessons-china-learned-superpower/</link>
      <description>America’s greatest export was never democracy or consumer culture. It was the template for global power itself.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Price of American Authoritarianism</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/american-authoritarianism-levitsky-way-ziblatt</link>
      <description>What can reverse democratic decline?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkey’s Second Act</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/turkey/turkeys-second-act</link>
      <description>What a democratic restoration offers the country’s citizens—and the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anwar Speaks to Leaders of Thailand, Cambodia as Border Conflict Rages</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/anwar-speaks-to-leaders-of-thailand-cambodia-as-border-conflict-rages/</link>
      <description>Compared to the fighting in July, there is a greater chance that the current conflict will be more protracted.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support for Bougival Accord waning in New Caledonia</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/support-bougival-accord-waning-new-caledonia</link>
      <description>Noumea’s vote on the next step towards greater autonomy under the Accord reveals that divisions are deepening.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>200,000 Flee Congo After Trump’s ‘Historic’ Peace Deal</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/congo-peace-deal-fighting-rwanda-m23-trump-historic-deal/</link>
      <description>Why the Rwanda-Congo accord misses the point.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia-US Trade Agreement at Risk of Collapse, Report Claims</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indonesia-us-trade-agreement-at-risk-of-collapse-report-claims/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration accuses Jakarta of &quot;backtracking&quot; on agreements to eliminate non-tariff barriers on U.S. goods.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving the puzzle of China's defence spending</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/solving-puzzle-china-s-defence-spending</link>
      <description>Can we accurately calculate China's defence spending now, and even a decade into the future?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 23:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia is not as resilient as it wants you to think</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/10/russia-is-not-as-resilient-as-it-wants-you-to-think</link>
      <description>But Vladimir Putin will keep fighting, and claiming victory prematurely</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consumer goods outlook: Clothing demand under pressure in 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.eiu.com/n/blogs/consumer-goods-2026-outlook/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2026 the global clothing industry will see only moderate&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiu.com/n/blogs/consumer-goods-2026-outlook/&quot;&gt;Consumer goods outlook: Clothing demand under pressure in 2026&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiu.com/n&quot;&gt;Economist Intelligence Unit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From social media to porn, age checks are spreading across the web</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/10/from-social-media-to-porn-age-checks-are-spreading-across-the-web</link>
      <description>Australia is not the only country introducing stricter controls</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Do U.S.-India Ties Stand?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/us-india-relationship-cooperation-diplomacy-trade-deal/</link>
      <description>Officials still seem to be working toward a trade deal, but it won’t be a silver bullet.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Far Will Trump’s Pressure Campaign Against the ICC Go?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/trump-icc-sanctions-hegseth-war-crimes-boat-strike-afghanistan-israel-netanyahu/</link>
      <description>The White House wants the court to alter the Rome Statute so Trump and his officials can’t be prosecuted.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Pressure Campaign Against the ICC Reaches New Heights</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/trump-icc-sanctions-hegseth-war-crimes/</link>
      <description>The White House wants the court to alter the Rome Statute so Trump and his officials can’t be prosecuted.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palau’s Climate Paradox in the Age of Trump 2.0</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/palaus-climate-paradox-in-the-age-of-trump-2-0/</link>
      <description>The same U.S. administration Palau relies on for its security is openly dismissing the climate crisis that threatens Palau’s very existence.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Muslim Brotherhood Still Isn’t a Terrorist Organization</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/trump-muslim-brotherhood-israel-egypt-saudi-arabia-palestine-democracy/</link>
      <description>Naming it one will only bolster repression in the Middle East and the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of China’s record-high trade surplus</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/10/the-meaning-of-chinas-record-high-trade-surplus</link>
      <description>The country is too complacent about its export dependence</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asia’s inexpensive AI stocks should worry American investors</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/10/asias-inexpensive-ai-stocks-should-worry-american-investors</link>
      <description>Tech mania looks very different in Japan, South Korea and Taiwan</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The next version of the web will be built for machines, not humans</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/interactive/science-and-technology/2025/12/10/the-next-version-of-the-web-will-be-built-for-machines-not-humans</link>
      <description>AI will surf, shop and act on your behalf</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.N. Expert Francesca Albanese Says There’s No Cease-Fire in Gaza</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/un-expert-francesca-albanese-cease-fire-genocide-gaza-israel/</link>
      <description>“There is no peace without the end of the occupation,” Albanese said.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Trump Ease Algeria-Morocco Tensions?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/the-us-needs-coherent-strategy-to-resolve-algeria-morocco-western-sahara-conflict-by-dalia-ghanem-and-rachida-chahida-ababsa-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October, Steve Witkoff, the US special envoy to the Middle East, predicted that his team could negotiate a peace deal between Algeria and Morocco in 60 days. But de-escalating this long-standing rivalry requires a coherent US strategy that merges diplomacy, defense, energy, and development policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humans were lighting fires from scratch a lot earlier than previously thought</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/10/humans-were-lighting-fires-from-scratch-a-lot-earlier-than-previously-thought</link>
      <description>A 400,000-year-old tinderbox is found in eastern England</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death Penalty Reinstatement ‘Legally Impossible,’ Kyrgyz Constitutional Court Says</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/death-penalty-reinstatement-legally-impossible-kyrgyz-constitutional-court-says/</link>
      <description>Kyrgyzstan abolished capital punishment in 2007; President Japarov has suggested reinstating it as a way to confront horrific crimes against women and children.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Takaichi Factor: Recalibrating the India-Japan Strategic Equation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-takaichi-factor-recalibrating-the-india-japan-strategic-equation/</link>
      <description>With Japan entering a more security-driven and domestically oriented phase under Takaichi, India must adjust its approach to the relationship accordingly.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Ukraine war works in China’s favour</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/why-ukraine-war-works-china-s-favour</link>
      <description>China has Russia cornered – reliant on Beijing for markets and energy exports and playing the role of junior partner.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trade Wars Destroy the Planet</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-china-trade-war-has-increased-global-carbon-emissions-by-qiyuan-xu-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that China is the world’s largest emitter and has a high carbon intensity, some assume that its trade war with the United States, which has shifted production to third countries, would have environmental benefits. In fact, the conflict has increased carbon dioxide emissions in developing and advanced economies alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan and Afghanistan: Can the ‘Mother of All Relations’ Be Fixed?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/pakistan-and-afghanistan-can-the-mother-of-all-relations-be-fixed/</link>
      <description>The current conflict is the most serious since the Taliban’s return in 2021. Yet it is also a logical extension of the never-ending tensions between the two countries.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who’s Afraid of Stablecoins?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/stablecoins-poorly-suited-to-widespread-use-in-retail-or-wholesale-payments-by-daniel-gros-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From transaction-processing bottlenecks to data-validation delays, a number of factors make stablecoins poorly suited to retail and even wholesale payments. Crucially, the barriers to widespread use of stablecoins are structural: they cannot be overcome without fundamentally transforming how the instrument works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the “Donroe Doctrine” is changing Puerto Rico</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/10/how-the-donroe-doctrine-is-changing-puerto-rico</link>
      <description>The island is central to efforts by the United States to project power throughout its hemisphere</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, Hong Kong’s Governance Is Not Becoming Like China’s. It’s Actually Worse.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/no-hong-kongs-governance-is-not-becoming-like-chinas-its-actually-worse/</link>
      <description>Hong Kong is stuck in a governance vacuum, where neither democratic nor authoritarian accountability functions effectively.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Petition Against Kazakhstan’s Proposed ‘LGBTQ Propaganda’ Law Rejected</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/petition-against-kazakhstans-proposed-lgbtq-propaganda-law-rejected/</link>
      <description>The law is set for consideration in the Senate next week.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Communism Is the Only Option</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/iran-water-crisis-survival-requires-state-control-solidarity-international-cooperation-by-slavoj-zizek-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Iran's flailing response to a nationally destabilizing water crisis should be a warning to everyone. As more societies push up against planetary boundaries, they will confront threats to their very survival, and responses that once seemed drastic or utopian will begin to look like common sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea Kicks off Workers’ Party Plenary Meeting</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/north-korea-kicks-off-workers-party-plenary-meeting/</link>
      <description>North Korea’s state-controlled media reported that Pyongyang began a plenary meeting to prepare for the upcoming Ninth Congress of the ruling WPK.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Behind China’s Trouble on the Afghanistan-Tajikistan Border?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/whats-behind-chinas-trouble-on-the-afghanistan-tajikistan-border/</link>
      <description>An interview with Edward Lemon on the recent attacks targeting Chinese workers near the Afghanistan-Tajikistan border.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Climate Diplomacy Must Account for Domestic Inequalities</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indias-climate-diplomacy-must-account-for-domestic-inequalities/</link>
      <description>Economic liberalization in India has shifted the emissions burden from more equal and developed states to less equal ones. This needs to change.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar Photojournalist Sai Zaw Should Be Able to Report Freely. He Should Not Be In Prison.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/myanmar-photojournalist-sai-zaw-should-be-able-to-report-freely-he-should-not-be-in-prison/</link>
      <description>A colleague describes the reality of being a journalist in a country under military control and shares insights into Sai Zaw’s life in prison.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump to Hold Peace Talks With Cambodian and Thai Leaders</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/trump-to-hold-peace-talks-with-cambodian-and-thai-leaders/</link>
      <description>The death toll is mounting after four days of fierce fighting and Thai aerial bombardments .</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI is transforming forecasting in times of macroeconomic uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://www.eiu.com/n/blogs/eiu-api-forecasting/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI is opening up new fields of economic analysis and&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiu.com/n/blogs/eiu-api-forecasting/&quot;&gt;How AI is transforming forecasting in times of macroeconomic uncertainty&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eiu.com/n&quot;&gt;Economist Intelligence Unit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Multilateralism</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/end-of-multilateralism-as-we-know-it-by-javier-solana-and-angel-saz-carranza-1-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s geopolitical turmoil has undermined the multilateral institutions that have structured international relations since the end of World War II. To avoid a slide into global anarchy, we must begin complementing existing institutions with a patchwork of arrangements that are less formal, less universal, and less binding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promises on Pause in Kashmir</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/10/kashmir-omar-abdullah-jknc-bjp-pdp-india-autonomy-statehood/</link>
      <description>Critics say the region’s leader hasn’t delivered on his defiant campaign rhetoric.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Supreme Court is handing Donald Trump more power</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/10/the-supreme-court-is-handing-donald-trump-more-power</link>
      <description>What overturning Humphrey’s Executor means for the presidency</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sauna Raid Highlights Growing Restrictions on Malaysia’s LGBTQ+ Community</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/sauna-raid-highlights-growing-restrictions-on-malaysias-lgbtq-community/</link>
      <description>Queer community organizations mobilized to help release over 200 men detained following a police raid on a sauna believed to have been used for “immoral activities.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 06:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Comes After the Axis of Resistance?</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/iran/what-comes-after-axis-resistance</link>
      <description>The abiding power of sectarianism in the Middle East.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Time to End the War in Ukraine Is Now</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/ukraine/time-end-war-ukraine-now</link>
      <description>Trump can defy the skeptics and seal the deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s new media platform: Telling stories, shaping narratives</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/china-s-new-media-platform-telling-stories-shaping-narratives</link>
      <description>The Maritime Silk Road Media Cooperation Platform offers opportunities for media outlets from Indonesia – but also poses risks.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postcard from Solomon Islands: The legacy of RAMSI</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/postcard-solomon-islands-legacy-ramsi</link>
      <description>More than two decades on, what are the lasting effects of a mission to save a failing state?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miami elects a new mayor at a pivotal moment</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/10/miami-elects-a-new-mayor-at-a-pivotal-moment</link>
      <description>Her challenge is to make dizzying growth last</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miami elects a rare Democratic mayor at a pivotal moment</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/10/miami-elects-a-rare-democratic-mayor-at-a-pivotal-moment</link>
      <description>Her challenge is to make dizzying growth last</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Farmers Aren’t Out of the Woods Yet</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/trump-farmers-bailout-trade-war-tariff-agriculture-china-soybeans/</link>
      <description>Trump’s bailout offers temporary relief, but trade war pain remains.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 22:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iain Douglas-Hamilton, the scientist who saved the elephants</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/09/iain-douglas-hamilton-the-scientist-who-saved-the-elephants</link>
      <description>The beasts have lost their stoutest defender</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 22:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The IMF's balancing act in Papua New Guinea</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/imf-s-balancing-act-papua-new-guinea</link>
      <description>The IMF reform program is making welcome and unexpected progress, but the hardest work still lies ahead.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 22:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zelensky Defies U.S. Pressure to Cede Territory to Russia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/zelensky-trump-cede-territory-russia-ukraine-donbas/</link>
      <description>The White House has suggested that Moscow will likely win the Russia-Ukraine war.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dirty Air Threatens India’s Global Power</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/india-pollution-environment-air-power-threat/</link>
      <description>How New Delhi’s pollution has become a more fundamental crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s worse for innovation: MAGA or Mao?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/12/09/whats-worse-for-innovation-maga-or-mao</link>
      <description>Donald Trump and Xi Jinping share a dangerous nostalgia</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bad Week for Washington’s China Hawks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/us-china-trump-nvidia-deal-national-security-strategy-hawks/</link>
      <description>Trump’s overtures to Beijing deal a blow to U.S. hard-liners.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Threatens Mexico With Tariffs Over Water</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/trump-mexico-tariffs-water-farmers-ranchers-texas/</link>
      <description>Drought has dried up Mexico’s water supply, much to the chagrin of Texas farmers—and Trump.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Antisemitism Took Hold in China</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-antisemitism-took-hold-in-china/</link>
      <description>Call it “Antisemitism 3.0” – ideological, narrative-driven, geopolitically functional antisemitism has spread throughout China, even without the religious or racial traditions that mark the hateful ideology in the West.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Treason of the Populists</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-national-security-strategy-and-how-pseudo-intellectuals-advance-populism-by-michael-burleigh-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The modern media landscape has given far-right &quot;thinkers&quot; a salience beyond their wildest dreams, reflected in the new US National Security Strategy. But their pseudo-intellectualism will never pass as the real thing, and while they may court the working class, it is financiers and tech billionaires whose interests they serve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India at COP30: A Mismatch Between Grandstanding and Climate Action</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/india-at-cop30-a-mismatch-between-grandstanding-and-climate-action/</link>
      <description>India’s climate policy must demonstrate real achievements vis-à-vis fossil fuels while highlighting modest gains in the realm of green energy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump is tearing up America’s chip-control policy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/09/donald-trump-is-tearing-up-americas-chip-control-policy</link>
      <description>His administration wants China hooked on American technology. China has other ideas</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s flawed plan to get China hooked on Nvidia chips</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/09/donald-trumps-flawed-plan-to-get-china-hooked-on-nvidia-chips</link>
      <description>The president is tearing up America’s export-control policy</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Is the Mosque That Was to Replace the Demolished Babri Masjid?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/where-is-the-mosque-that-was-to-replace-the-demolished-babri-masjid/</link>
      <description>The mosque that was to come up at Dhannipur remains on the drawing board. Meanwhile, a politician has promised to build a “replica” of the demolished mosque in West Bengal.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA’s man in LatAm</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/09/magas-man-in-latam</link>
      <description>Fernando Cerimedo has run right-wing campaigns across Latin America, forging close ties with MAGA and Donald Trump</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Betting Against the Future</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/new-us-national-security-strategy-animated-by-demographic-angst-by-stephen-holmes-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new US National Security Strategy bears the cognitive signature of a movement that experiences demographic and cultural change as existential catastrophe. The goal is not merely to ignore real threats but to redefine the threat itself as the presence of people President Donald Trump calls “garbage.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kambarata-1 to See Joint Financing From Kyrgyzstan, Kazakhstan, and Uzbekistan in 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/kambarata-1-to-see-joint-financing-from-kyrgyzstan-kazakhstan-and-uzbekistan-in-2026/</link>
      <description>2026 looks to be a pivotal year in which the trilateral hydropower project will either make serious steps forward or languish, as previous efforts have, in the void between ambition and reality.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Cash-Strapped Governments Should Be Using this Tool</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/outcomes-based-partnerships-proven-to-deliver-results-for-governments-at-a-lower-cost-by-ronald-cohen-1-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By engaging in outcomes-based partnerships, governments can advance social-policy goals at half the cost, while paying only when targets have been achieved. Better yet, such initiatives can be scaled up massively, because they offer precisely the kind of opportunities that socially minded investors have been seeking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France Didn’t Lose the Sahel—Everyone Did</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/france-mali-europe-eu-africa-union-angola-sahel-al-qaeda/</link>
      <description>Blaming Paris for Mali’s problems won’t solve them. A collective European response is needed.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China raises the cost of Indonesia’s neutrality</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/china-raises-cost-indonesia-s-neutrality</link>
      <description>Far from mere choreography, Beijing is shaping Jakarta’s growth agenda to suit its future core interests.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s Unification Minister Is Not Happy With DMZ Administration</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/south-koreas-unification-minister-is-not-happy-with-dmz-administration/</link>
      <description>While Chung Dong-young’s political agenda is clear, his comments fail to recognize that the DMZ is governed by specific rules and procedures for important reasons.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Roots of Britain’s Economic Malaise</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/five-problems-uk-government-must-address-to-restore-growth-by-jim-o-neill-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are five issues that any UK government must address in order to bring about a robust economic recovery, beginning with launching a process to rejoin the European single market or customs union. But rationalizing spending on the National Health Service, pensions, and welfare benefits will require considerably more courage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India and the Indo-Pacific in Trump’s Second-term Strategy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/india-and-the-indo-pacific-in-trumps-second-term-strategy/</link>
      <description>The new National Security Strategy offers important insights into how a second Trump presidency views the Indo-Pacific and the role India is expected to play within it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem With Taiwan’s $40 Billion Defense Budget</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-problem-with-taiwans-40-billion-defense-budget/</link>
      <description>The defense spending hike is a necessary step, but it avoids harder questions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100 Ships at Sea: Strategic Observations on the Chinese Navy’s 2025 Winter Exercises</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/100-ships-at-sea-strategic-observations-on-the-chinese-navys-2025-winter-exercises/</link>
      <description>The PLAN’s deployments – the biggest to date – stretched from the southern Yellow Sea through the East and South China Seas and deep into the Western Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin’s India Visit Reveals New Delhi’s Complicated Strategy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/putins-india-visit-reveals-new-delhis-complicated-strategy/</link>
      <description>Amid difficult relations with the U.S., India is keen to show that it has other options.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Electric Straitjacket</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-excessive-focus-on-electrification-undermining-innovation-and-resilience-by-ana-palacio-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reaching climate neutrality by 2050 is non-negotiable, but it is impossible to know in 2025 the best way to get there. Rather than attempt to dictate the pathway now, EU policymakers must design a strategy that leaves space for unexpected innovations and adequately accounts for geopolitical risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Diplomatic Machinery Is Wearing Thin</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinas-diplomatic-machinery-is-wearing-thin/</link>
      <description>China’s foreign policy bureaucracy faces a mounting succession crisis that will only multiply in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix and Paramount are battling for more than just Warner Bros</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/09/netflix-and-paramount-are-battling-for-more-than-just-warner-bros</link>
      <description>They present rival visions for the future of entertainment</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paramount fights Netflix for Warner Bros—and the future of Hollywood</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/09/paramount-fights-netflix-for-warner-bros-and-the-future-of-hollywood</link>
      <description>One firm needs scale, the other ideas</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix and Paramount are battling for more than Warner Bros</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/09/netflix-and-paramount-are-battling-for-more-than-warner-bros</link>
      <description>They present rival visions for the future of entertainment</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking the Local Impact of China’s Mega-Projects on Kyrgyzstan’s Regions</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/unpacking-the-local-impact-of-chinas-mega-projects-on-kyrgyzstans-regions/</link>
      <description>Too often opportunities concentrate within capital cities or designated special economic zones, and thereby render the rest of the country peripheral.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postcolonial Chicken</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/2026/01/jollibee-fried-chicken-american-fast-food/684949/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>The U.S. introduced fast food to the Philippines. Now Jollibee is serving it back to America.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Pardon Racket</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/trump-corruption-of-pardon-power-by-stephen-holmes-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pardon power is the only authority the US Constitution places entirely in the president’s hands, immune from legislative override or judicial review. For Alexander Hamilton, who assumed that shame would restrain abuse, Donald Trump is the nightmare scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam Tries to Escape the U.S.-China Trap</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/vietnam-china-us-geopolitics-great-power-competition/</link>
      <description>Hanoi has been quietly expanding partnerships beyond the Indo-Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam’s 2026 Budget, Explained</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/vietnams-2026-budget-explained/</link>
      <description>Strong economic performance sent government revenue soaring in 2025, putting the country in an enviable fiscal position.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nagaland Wants Unrestricted Entry of Foreign Nationals to Boost Tourism</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/nagaland-wants-unrestricted-entry-of-foreign-nationals-to-boost-tourism/</link>
      <description>Unlike Nagaland, Manipur and Mizoram are not opposed to the Protected Area Permit given their concerns over the influx of refugees and rebels from Myanmar.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Richard Nixon Killed National Child Care</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/09/nixon-national-child-care-new-mexico/</link>
      <description>The president’s veto had to do with mounting opposition to his policy of detente.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China Wins the Future</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/how-china-wins-future-elizabeth-economy</link>
      <description>Beijing’s strategy to seize the new frontiers of power.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute Is the New Oil</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/compute-new-oil</link>
      <description>America and the Gulf must work together on artificial intelligence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin and Modi Affirm Russia-India Defense Relations</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/putin-and-moscow-affirm-russia-india-defense-relations/</link>
      <description>Three major areas of strategic concern were discussed in Delhi: defense purchases, nuclear power generation and space technology.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 03:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Court Orders Malaysia Airlines to Pay Compensation Over Missing Flight MH370</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinese-court-orders-malaysia-airlines-to-pay-compensation-over-missing-flight-mh370/</link>
      <description>With the search for MH370 set to resume on December 30, China has approved its first compensation claim involving the doomed aircraft.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 03:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade: then, now and into the future</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/department-foreign-affairs-trade-then-now-future</link>
      <description>DFAT has evolved to be more diverse – but is it equipped to face the challenges of a multipolar world?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 03:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divided India revises voter rolls</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/divided-india-revises-voter-rolls</link>
      <description>Ahead of crucial state elections, old concerns about illegal migration resurface.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar’s National Unity Government in 2025: A Series of Unfortunate Events?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/myanmars-national-unity-government-in-2025-a-series-of-unfortunate-events/</link>
      <description>More than four years after its establishment, the country's opposition government has come under increasing pressure to reform.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress Moves to Restrain Trump in Annual Defense Policy Bill</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/ndaa-congress-defense-bill-trump-aumf-troops-europe-hegseth/</link>
      <description>The National Defense Authorization Act would limit Hegseth’s ability to reduce U.S. troops in Europe and Asia, among other measures.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s chance with Timor-Leste to shift ASEAN’s gaze</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/india-s-chance-timor-leste-shift-asean-s-gaze</link>
      <description>The newest ASEAN member faces the Indian Ocean, not the South China Sea, giving India fresh maritime leverage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Clashes Upend Thailand-Cambodia Cease-Fire</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/thailand-cambodia-airstrikes-border-territory-malaysia-cease-fire/</link>
      <description>Regional leaders warn that the decades-long feud could trigger widespread instability across Southeast Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI is disrupting shopping</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/08/how-ai-is-disrupting-shopping</link>
      <description>Looking for Christmas gifts? Just ask a chatbot</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COP30 and South Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/cop30-and-south-asia/</link>
      <description>Meera Gopal joins host Tushar Shetty to examine the outcomes of COP30 in Belém, Brazil and the implications for South Asia.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Indonesia’s Not Out of the Flood Zone</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/indonesia-floods-aid-government-response/</link>
      <description>The waters may have let up, but an aid crisis continues.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting Trump’s Remarkably Odd US National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/dissecting-trumps-remarkably-odd-us-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <description>Half as long as his previous administration’s NSS, Trump’s newly revealed strategy is perhaps the clearest (though still confusing) outline of the U.S. president’s worldview.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting between Thailand and Cambodia breaks out again</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/08/fighting-between-thailand-and-cambodia-breaks-out-again</link>
      <description>Hundreds of thousands of refugees are back on the move</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia’s PM Calls for Calm After Conflict Reignites Between Thailand and Cambodia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/malaysias-pm-calls-for-calm-after-conflict-reignites-between-thailand-and-cambodia/</link>
      <description>A high-ranking Thai military official has announced that the army plans to &quot;render Cambodia militarily ineffective for a long time.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Strategy That Ignores the Real Threats</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/national-security-strategy-ignores-real-threats-trump/685181/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>The administration’s new policy shows less concern for the American homeland than for building an illiberal world order.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>College campuses have become a front line in America’s sports-betting boom</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/08/college-campuses-have-become-a-front-line-in-americas-sports-betting-boom</link>
      <description>The fun is undeniable but so is the toll it is taking on young men</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>College campuses are at the fore of America’s sports-betting boom</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/08/college-campuses-are-at-the-fore-of-americas-sports-betting-boom</link>
      <description>The fun is undeniable but so is the toll it is taking on young men</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Only War the White House Is Ready for Is Culture War</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/trump-national-security-strategy-culture-war/</link>
      <description>The new U.S. National Security Strategy is a moral and strategic disaster.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China knows how to punish countries that offend it</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/08/china-knows-how-to-punish-countries-that-offend-it</link>
      <description>It is skilful in the dark arts of economic leverage</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe bans Russia’s gas exports, but still buys its gas-based fertiliser</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/08/europe-bans-russias-gas-exports-but-still-buys-its-gas-based-fertiliser</link>
      <description>The EU’s rising tariffs may not solve the problem</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America Will Pay for Pushing India Away</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-visit-to-new-delhi-sends-a-stark-message-to-the-us-by-brahma-chellaney-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin’s visit to New Delhi should be a wake-up call for the United States: attempting to coerce India into actions that compromise its national interest is a recipe for estrangement. Given that India remains crucial to balance China’s aggressive rise, such an outcome would carry high costs for the US.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the 2025 National Security Strategy Means for Asia</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/2025-us-national-security-strategy-trump-asia-china-taiwan/</link>
      <description>The MAGA revolution in U.S. foreign policy brings good news and bad.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Wants to Make Europe White Again</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-national-security-strategy-must-serve-as-wake-up-call-for-europe-by-zaki-laidi-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new US National Security Strategy represents a decisive departure from the universalist values that have guided US foreign policy since 1945. Its nativist, anti-liberal stance should dispel any remaining European illusions about the current state of the transatlantic alliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan, China Trade Accusations Over Radar Lock-on Near Okinawa</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/japan-china-trade-accusations-over-radar-lock-on-near-okinawa/</link>
      <description>The potential is growing for China-Japan tensions to escalate into an actual armed clash.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: A truly radical document</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/08/the-war-room-newsletter-a-truly-radical-document</link>
      <description>Shashank Joshi, our defence editor, reflects on America’s new security strategy</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s New Corollary</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/monroe-doctrine-trump-corollary-national-security-strategy-venezuala/</link>
      <description>The President’s invocation of the Monroe Doctrine is rhetorically satisfying but carries real risks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s New Corollary</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/monroe-doctrine-trump-corollary-national-security-strategy-venezuela/</link>
      <description>The President’s invocation of the Monroe Doctrine is rhetorically satisfying but carries real risks.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Tech Sovereignty Requires Digital Leverage, Not Self-Sufficiency</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/digital-self-sufficiency-alone-will-not-make-europe-a-tech-power-by-anke-hassel-and-frieder-mitsch-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The European Union cannot reduce its digital dependence by investing in infrastructure that leaves underlying power relationships intact. Real power comes from controlling the parts of the value chain that shape decision-making, govern data flows, and set the standards that structure digital markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 in review: Trump, Substack, Europe, and fertility</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/2025-review-trump-substack-europe-fertility</link>
      <description>Lowy Institute staff nominate the most notable books, trends, ideas, and people of 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minxin Pei on China’s Return to Totalitarianism</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/minxin-pei-on-chinas-return-to-totalitarianism/</link>
      <description>“Xi Jinping himself – ideologically and politically – was committed to a form of totalitarian rule. And he was skillful enough, ruthless enough to bring it about.”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Reacts to the New US National Security Strategy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/japan-reacts-to-the-new-us-national-security-strategy/</link>
      <description>The plan codifies demands for Japan to spend more on defense and increase its capabilities – efforts Japanese officials say are already underway.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Climate Activists’ Ambitions Are Crumbling</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/mexican-climate-activists-ambitions-are-crumbling/</link>
      <description>President Claudia Sheinbaum has eroded a key legal tool used to ensure environmental justice.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ford-CATL Deal Should Become the Model for China-US Economic Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-ford-catl-deal-should-become-the-model-for-china-us-economic-cooperation/</link>
      <description>The relevant criterion for evaluating foreign technology partnerships should be ownership and control of domestic assets, not the national origin of licensed expertise.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only Creative Destruction Will Boost European Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/innovation-policy-how-europe-can-return-to-technological-frontier-by-philippe-aghion-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that major geopolitical developments have forced Europeans to rethink how they will ensure their own prosperity, security, and sovereignty, they must not take innovation for granted. This primary engine of economic growth will not run properly unless it is properly tuned and carefully maintained.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the North Korea-Russia Missile Axis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/breaking-the-north-korea-russia-missile-axis/</link>
      <description>The partnership has become a two-way relationship, with missile technology originally transferred to Russia being upgraded and sent back to North Korea.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s Social Media Age Ban Is Days Away. Here Is What It Really Means.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/australias-social-media-age-ban-is-days-away-here-is-what-it-really-means/</link>
      <description>Public debate on the ban has focused on parenting choices. But the real issue is corporate compliance, technical design, and safe spaces for young people.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a China-US Detente Mean for Japanese Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/what-a-china-us-detente-mean-for-japanese-foreign-policy/</link>
      <description>While the United States is refusing to lend Japan a helping hand, the intensity of the China-Japan confrontation is moving in a deeply worrying direction.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mystery of Mohammad Tajik</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/2026/01/mohammad-tajik-iran-cyber-intelligence/684954/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>A man claiming to be an Iranian intelligence officer promised me he’d reveal his country’s secrets. But first he had a game to play.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolia and Cuba’s Diplomatic Relations: Past, Present, and Future</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/mongolia-and-cubas-diplomatic-relations-past-present-and-future/</link>
      <description>Ulaanbaatar’s Cuba diplomacy encapsulates the country’s past as well as its many changes in going from a socialist system to a multi-party democracy today.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hillary Clinton: ‘Congress Has Abdicated Its Responsibility’</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/hillary-clinton-doha-forum/</link>
      <description>The former U.S. secretary of state on Trump’s foreign policy, Americans’ shifting views on Israel, and the fight for women’s rights.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Human Cost of the Largest Electoral Roll Revision Exercise in the World</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-human-cost-of-the-largest-electoral-roll-revision-exercise-in-the-world/</link>
      <description>After reports of suicides and deaths due to overwork, the Diplomat tracked several Booth Level Officers carrying out the Special Intensive Revision to understand the ground reality.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s United States of the Americas</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-national-security-strategy-marks-dangerous-new-era-by-richard-haass-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration's new National Security Strategy envisions a world in which the United States no longer anchors alliances and international institutions, stands up for democracy and human rights, and seeks to uphold the global balance of power. Russia and China will find much opportunity in this new world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Pivot to Pakistan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/08/trump-pakistan-munir-sharif-critical-minerals-cryptocurrency/</link>
      <description>The South Asian nation has deployed a combination of flattery and strategy to get Washington on its side.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>María Corina Machado’s Catholic Revolution</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maria-machado-exponent-of-latin-american-christian-democracy-by-piotr-h-kosicki-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Across the US political spectrum, there is little understanding of how important Catholic politics have been in shaping the Latin American right. But to understand the situation in Venezuela requires recognizing the fundamental role of the tradition of Christian Democracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Afghanistan Taught Us — And Why Libya May Be Lost If the Lesson Is Ignored</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/what-afghanistan-taught-us-and-why-libya-may-be-lost-if-the-lesson-is-ignored/</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Abuse Can America’s Allies Take?</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/how-much-abuse-can-americas-allies-take</link>
      <description>Longtime partners will soon start to drift away.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Power Paradox</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/trumps-power-paradox</link>
      <description>What kind of world order does his national security strategy seek?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is India Recalibrating its Stance Toward Post-Hasina Bangladesh?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/is-india-recalibrating-its-stance-toward-post-hasina-bangladesh/</link>
      <description>Recent statements by Indian Prime Minister Modi and Foreign Minister Jaishankar suggest that change could be in the air.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India-Russia Set Ties on Economic Trajectory During Putin’s Visit</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/india-russia-set-ties-on-economic-trajectory-during-putins-visit/</link>
      <description>They stressed co-production and co-innovation, expansion of the export basket, finalizing an FTA with the Eurasian Economic Union, and revitalizing connectivity projects.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modi-Putin Summit: More Style and Symbolism Than Substance</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/modi-putin-summit-more-style-and-symbolism-than-substance/</link>
      <description>While not altering the global balance of power in any meaningful way, Putin’s visit might actually diminish India’s significance in the eyes of the West.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Marshall Islands’ experiment with a universal basic income</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/marshall-islands-experiment-universal-basic-income</link>
      <description>The scheme tests whether microstates can sustain widespread cash transfers, with the Pacific watching on.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thai and Cambodian Troops Again Clash Along Disputed Border</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thai-and-cambodian-troops-again-clash-along-disputed-border/</link>
      <description>The two governments have accused the other of responsibility for a string of incidents that threaten to ignite another full-scale border conflict.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sumatra floods: Indonesia stuck in a cycle of crisis management</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/sumatra-floods-indonesia-stuck-cycle-crisis-management</link>
      <description>President Prabowo must address years of institutional neglect to tackle the structural failures fuelling disasters.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyclones to coups: Crises drive violence against women</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/cyclones-coups-crises-drive-violence-against-women</link>
      <description>Governments treat gendered violence as an afterthought, leaving millions vulnerable across the Indo-Pacific.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 23:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand’s Aircraft Carrier, the Chakri Naruebet, Charts a New Course</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thailands-aircraft-carrier-the-chakri-naruebet-charts-a-new-course/</link>
      <description>The carrier has mostly been used for HADR missions, and debates about its utility have raged since it entered into service in 1997.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A crisis over using frozen Russian assets to help Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/07/a-crisis-over-using-frozen-russian-assets-to-help-ukraine</link>
      <description>It’s an old-style Euro punch-up in a deadly new context</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 18:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Head in sand, the way of the ASEAN ostrich</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/head-sand-way-asean-ostrich</link>
      <description>Malaysia’s chairmanship sidestepped divisive issues. Manila’s turn will force ASEAN to confront its paralysis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which economy did best in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/07/which-economy-did-best-in-2025</link>
      <description>Our annual ranking returns</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A World of Cons, Crooks, and Culprits</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/07/global-scams-pig-butchering-fat-leonard-crypto-black-widows/</link>
      <description>Where scam industries are thriving around the globe.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A giant iron-ore mine could bring Guinea riches or ruin</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/07/a-giant-iron-ore-mine-could-bring-guinea-riches-or-ruin</link>
      <description>It all depends on how the country’s junta uses the windfall</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Ukraine Fights Corruption, Trump Does the Opposite</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/ukraine-fighting-corruption-trump/685162/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>Ukrainians want honest government, even as American and Russian kleptocrats circle their country.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s Grim Demographic Reality</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/japans-grim-demographic-reality/</link>
      <description>Can an anti-immigration turn really be compatible with a ‘Japan is Back’ narrative?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 23:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checks and Balance newsletter: Don’t count on Congress to restrain Donald Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/06/checks-and-balance-newsletter-dont-count-on-congress-to-restrain-donald-trump</link>
      <description>Charlotte Howard, our New York bureau chief, on the president’s efforts to stretch America’s war powers—and lawmakers’ reluctance to stop him</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Story newsletter: How AI is rewiring childhood</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/06/cover-story-newsletter-how-ai-is-rewiring-childhood</link>
      <description>An exclusive look at how we designed our cover</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin Lives by a Code Trump Doesn’t Understand</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/putin-trump-misunderstanding/685167/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>Where Trump sees a deal, Putin sees submission.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s New National Security Strategy Goes Full ‘America First’</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/trump-national-security-strategy-america-first/</link>
      <description>The long-anticipated plan aims to selectively impose the U.S. president’s worldview around the globe.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 21:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi, Macron Seize Symbolic Victories in Unorthodox Summit</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/xi-jinping-macron-china-chengdu-france-trade-multilateralism-tariffs/</link>
      <description>Both China and France hope to strengthen their images on the world stage amid growing isolationism.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 21:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biden’s Long Shadow Over Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/biden-war-ukraine-russia-putin-zelensky-military-aid/</link>
      <description>His administration failed Ukraine at almost every turn, shaping the war to this day.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the Democratic Recession Comes Home</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/democracy-promotion-united-states-michael-mcfaul-book-review/</link>
      <description>Michael McFaul wants more democracy promotion. Is now the time?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Kaleidoscopic Portrait of Women in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/left-handed-girl-movie-netflix-review/</link>
      <description>“Left-Handed Girl,” Taiwan’s Oscar hopeful, offers a multifaceted view of women learning to live beyond shame.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Jekyll and Hyde for the Manosphere Crowd</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/things-you-kill-movie-film-review-turkey-gender-masculinity-feminism/</link>
      <description>“The Things You Kill” explores the pitfalls of masculinity in modern-day Turkey.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Unsettling Voyages Across the Sea</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/international-fiction-releases-galapagos-fatima-velez-jaguars-roar-micheliny-verunschk/</link>
      <description>Plus, more international fiction releases in December.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What in the World?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/news-quiz-congo-outbreak-trump-pardon-honduras-president-israel-gaza-cease-fire/</link>
      <description>Test yourself on the week of Nov. 29: A disease outbreak ends in Congo, Trump pardons a former Honduran president, and the latest from Israel-Palestine.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Europe Finally Realize It’s Alone?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/national-security-strategy-2025-trump-europe-russia-ukraine-war/</link>
      <description>Washington’s new National Security Strategy ratifies an adversarial relationship.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:36:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain’s Fiscal Watchdog Doesn't See What Matters</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/britain-obr-modeling-ignores-economics-of-productivity-growth-by-paolo-surico-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By ignoring the long-run effects of both government-funded and privately funded innovation, Britain's official budget scorer has been systematically underestimating the economy's potential output and the government's future fiscal headroom. The result is not fiscal discipline, but a costly illusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Critical-Minerals Race Is Putting the Planet at Risk</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/a-fairer-mineral-development-regime-is-still-within-reach-by-johanna-sydow-and-nsama-chikwanka-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As governments weaken environmental protections to promote new mining projects, the global scramble for critical minerals is deepening social divides and harming vital ecosystems. Only reduced consumption and robust, enforceable rules can prevent long-term harm and protect basic human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Transformative Power of Early Childhood Education</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/g20-countries-must-invest-in-early-childhood-education-by-justin-w-van-fleet-and-pia-rebello-britto-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world marked by volatility, no investment yields greater economic returns than supporting children in their first five or six years of life. Yet pre-primary education remains chronically underfunded, blocking the surest route to a more prosperous, peaceful, and stable world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China Now Talks About NATO and Why It Matters for the Asia-Pacific</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-china-now-talks-about-nato-and-why-it-matters-for-the-asia-pacific/</link>
      <description>Until 2021, statements about NATO in Chinese foreign and defense ministry press conferences were few and largely neutral in tone. Then the tone hardened.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybridization of the Terror Threat in India</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/hybridization-of-the-terror-threat-in-india/</link>
      <description>Recent incidents point to the use of advanced operational techniques and technologies, signaling an increasing hybridization of terrorist techniques, tactics, and procedures.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Does China Want? Depends Which China You’re Talking About.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/what-does-china-want-depends-which-china-youre-talking-about/</link>
      <description>China gives conflicting signals because it has three different “personas”: Moral China, Defensive-Assertive China, and Striving China.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India and the Gulf States Could Reshape Global Trade</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-gulf-partnership-offers-alternative-development-model-for-emerging-economies-by-vivek-agarwal-1-and-alexander-george-1-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an increasingly multipolar world, India and the Gulf states are no longer merely trading partners but strategic actors in their own right. Together, they are advancing a model of cooperation that values autonomy, transparency, and mutual gain over coercion and dependence on great powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Has Many Options if the Supreme Court Strikes Down Tariffs</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/trump-tariffs-supreme-court-united-states/</link>
      <description>A weak Congress means a deep toolbox for the president.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Japanese PM Ishiba Shigeru Has Thoughts on His Successor</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/former-japanese-pm-ishiba-shigeru-has-thoughts-on-his-successor/</link>
      <description>Ishiba has critiqued current Prime Minister Takaichi for her Taiwan remarks, nuclear policy, and rice vouchers.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why hangovers get worse as you get older</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/05/why-hangovers-get-worse-as-you-get-older</link>
      <description>But there are things you can do to help</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Forgotten Hostage Crisis: Bangladeshi Citizens in the Arakan Army’s Captivity</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/a-forgotten-hostage-crisis-bangladeshi-citizens-in-the-arakan-armys-captivity/</link>
      <description>Far away from the scrutiny of the international community, the Arakan Army is holding hundreds of Bangladeshi citizens as hostages.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s Tech Firms Need Regulation to Grow</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tech-regulation-and-investment-both-vital-to-european-digital-sovereignty-by-max-von-thun-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The European Commission's rushed plan to water down landmark dig’ital legislation reflects the view that excessive regulation is to blame for the lack of European firms capable of competing with the US tech giants. This logic is fundamentally flawed, and deregulation is destined to backfire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $500 Mistake: Why International Students in Australia Are Selling Their Bank Accounts to Criminals</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-500-mistake-why-international-students-in-australia-are-selling-their-bank-accounts-to-criminals/</link>
      <description>That “easy money” comes with a steep cost: a criminal record, a lifetime ban from Australia, and up to life imprisonment.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong’s Grenfell Tower Moment: When Grief Became Sedition</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/hong-kongs-grenfell-tower-moment-when-grief-became-sedition/</link>
      <description>As families sift through ashes and survivors call for accountability following a catastrophic building fire in Hong Kong, authorities have moved swiftly to silence dissent.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China and India’s National Strategy and Competition in Cislunar Space</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/china-and-indias-national-strategy-and-competition-in-cislunar-space/</link>
      <description>The paths of China and India in space show how Asian space powers are fundamentally transforming the global distribution of capabilities and influence in cislunar space.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASEAN Between China and the US: Navigating a ‘No Single Power’ Global Order</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/asean-between-china-and-the-us-navigating-a-no-single-power-global-order/</link>
      <description>Economic strategy can no longer be separated from geopolitics. How, then, should ASEAN position itself?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want an Explanation for China’s Nuclear Build-up?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/want-an-explanation-for-chinas-nuclear-build-up/</link>
      <description>It’s not in the new white paper.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Theft to Labubu: The Evolution of Intellectual Property Protection in China</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/from-theft-to-labubu-the-evolution-of-intellectual-property-protection-in-china/</link>
      <description>After decades of accusations over counterfeiting foreign brands, Chinese companies are now assuming dual roles: as not only IP violators, but also IP proprietors.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Can’t Make Gwadar Work – Even After Billions Spent</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-china-cant-make-gwadar-work-even-after-billions-spent/</link>
      <description>Gwadar port has often been touted as CPEC’s “crown jewel.” Yet almost two decades after the port began operations, business has been lackluster.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s bleak vision of America’s foreign-policy priorities</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/05/donald-trumps-bleak-vision-of-americas-foreign-policy-priorities</link>
      <description>Allies may panic; despots will cheer</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump’s bleak, incoherent foreign-policy strategy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/05/donald-trumps-bleak-incoherent-foreign-policy-strategy</link>
      <description>Allies may panic; despots will cheer</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Is Threatening His Own World Cup</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/world-cup-draw-trump-immigration-ice-raids/</link>
      <description>Ongoing immigration raids risk the success of the global sporting event.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Authoritarian Innovations</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/how-trump-is-adding-to-the-traditional-authoritarian-playbook-by-ruth-ben-ghiat-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During his second presidency, Donald Trump has joined a long line of autocrats who come to power through elections only to erode democracy, with the ultimate goal of installing an authoritarian regime. But much about his first year back in office more closely resembles the aftermath of coups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand Girds For Early 2026 Polls Amid Economic Stagnation</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thailand-girds-for-early-2026-polls-amid-economic-stagnation/</link>
      <description>Months of political instability expected to ensue</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An AI Bust May Not Be All Bad News</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/05/ai-bust-not-all-bad-news/</link>
      <description>The boom makes it hard for competitors to step away from a treadmill of continuous acceleration.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of the Israel Exception</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/end-israel-exception-andrew-miller</link>
      <description>A new paradigm for American policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Syrians Want</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/syria/what-syrians-want</link>
      <description>A new survey shows the promises and perils facing the country’s new government.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Rohingya Women in Bangladesh, Digital Freedom Is a Distant Ideal</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/for-rohingya-women-in-bangladesh-digital-freedom-is-a-distant-ideal/</link>
      <description>Life in the heaving camps around Cox's Bazar is marked by a daily struggle for even basic connectivity and safety.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia’s Rare Earth Transition</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/malaysias-rare-earth-transition/</link>
      <description>An early adopter hopes to make “super magnets” for electric cars by 2030.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singaporean Court Upholds Opposition Leader’s Conviction for Lying to Parliament</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/singaporean-court-upholds-opposition-leaders-conviction-for-lying-to-parliament/</link>
      <description>Pritam Singh of the Workers' Party told the press that he was &quot;disappointed&quot; with the decision but accepted it &quot;fully and without reservation.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Landlocked Africa is an open opportunity for Australia</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/landlocked-africa-open-opportunity-australia</link>
      <description>Rather than compete on aid volumes, Australia could leverage remote logistics expertise as quality partner for major projects.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting China’s subsidies means copying China’s economic model</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/fighting-china-s-subsidies-means-copying-china-s-economic-model</link>
      <description>Rather than just raising trade barriers, countries should predict where Chinese subsidies will move next to compete there.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indonesia Promises Action on Deforestation as Sumatra Flooding Toll Rises</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indonesia-promises-action-on-deforestation-as-sumatra-flooding-toll-rises/</link>
      <description>Environmentalists say that the flash floods and landslides in Sumatra have been worsened by years of logging linked to mining operations.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump to cast a shadow over coming Greenland talks</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/trump-cast-shadow-over-coming-greenland-talks</link>
      <description>Officials from the US, Denmark and Greenland are expected to hold talks on Monday and Tuesday – the first since the President mused about taking the territory by force.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election Drama Heats Up in Honduras</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/honduras-election-asfura-trump-hernandez-pardon/</link>
      <description>The country is the latest target of Trump’s partisan interventions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pete Hegseth’s Bad Week</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/hegseth-signalgate-venezuela-boat-strikes-congress/</link>
      <description>The defense secretary is under scrutiny for a series of questionable decisions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modi Walks a Tightrope Between Putin and Trump</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/modi-putin-india-russia-us-sanctions-oil-weapons-ukraine/</link>
      <description>This week’s meeting with Putin will test how well India can balance ties with Russia and the United States.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Wants Disaster Bunkers. Norway Wants ‘Preparedness Friends.’</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/norway-silicon-valley-disaster-preppers/</link>
      <description>Norwegians are pioneering better models of catastrophe preparation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Buildings Could Be a Big Part of Its Climate Solution</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indias-buildings-could-be-a-big-part-of-its-climate-solution/</link>
      <description>Integrating solar directly into buildings could turn homes and offices into decentralized power plants and cut emissions right where they begin.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa Was the Biggest Loser of China’s COP30 Triumph</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/africa-china-cop30-emissions/</link>
      <description>Decisions about the continent’s future are being made in foreign capitals.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Peace in Ukraine Remains a Distant Prospect</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-ukraine-russia-peace-remains-a-distant-prospect-by-ian-bremmer-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When two warring parties’ core objectives are fundamentally incompatible, no amount of external pressure or diplomacy can bridge the gap between them. Peace in Ukraine will come eventually, but it almost certainly will not come from US President Donald Trump's current diplomatic push, no matter how many deadlines he sets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurasia’s Great Water Gamble</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/plan-to-redirect-part-siberian-freshwater-to-central-asia-strategic-necessity-by-djoomart-otorbaev-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change is rapidly melting the glaciers that feed Central Asia’s rivers, pushing the region toward an ecological tipping point. Against this backdrop, a new initiative aims to revive a long-abandoned plan to redirect part of Siberia’s freshwater to its southern neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank Violence Threatens Trump’s Gaza Peace Plan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/west-bank-violence-settler-attacks-israel-gaza-trump-peace-plan/</link>
      <description>Rights groups say the Israeli government is complicit.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan Talks Tough</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/sanae-takaichi-right-to-acknowledge-possible-japanese-military-action-in-taiwan-by-ian-buruma-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Japan’s new prime minister, Sanae Takaichi, was not wrong when she recently said that the country must be prepared to defend itself even beyond its borders. But she would be in a stronger position to strengthen Japan’s military muscle if she were willing to reckon with her political forebears’ war crimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Has the Second World War finally ended for Germany and Japan?</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/has-second-world-war-finally-ended-germany-japan</link>
      <description>Doubts about US commitment are pushing Berlin and Tokyo toward military self-reliance they haven’t sought since 1945.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Ukraine Peace Plan Means More War</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/trump-s-ukraine-peace-plan-means-more-war</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After attempting to impose draconian peace terms on Ukraine, the US delegation responsible for negotiating with Russian President Vladimir Putin, who all but dictated those terms, has once again failed to achieve a breakthrough. Even if the Trump administration does manage to get a peace agreement signed, what it contains – and what it omits – is likely to be a formula for renewed conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-s-ukraine-peace-plan-means-more-war-doc-2025-12</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Intensifies ‘Three Warfares’ Targeting Japan Over Takaichi’s Taiwan Remarks</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/china-intensifies-three-warfares-targeting-japan-over-takaichis-taiwan-remarks/</link>
      <description>Beijing is intensifying its use of public opinion warfare, psychological warfare, and legal warfare against Japan.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecuador’s Warning to Trump</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ecuador-referendum-voters-reject-noboa-and-trump-approach-to-security-by-guillaume-long-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By rejecting all four ballot measures in a recent referendum, Ecuadorian voters demonstrated an understanding that neither their right-wing president, Daniel Noboa, nor Donald Trump seems to share. Militarizing poor neighborhoods and inviting US troops is no way to resolve a security crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Can’t Talk to Its Neighbors Anymore</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/04/us-latin-america-trump-summit-americas-dominican-republic/</link>
      <description>What the postponement of the Summit of the Americas reveals about regional relations.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Steps up Defense Cooperation in Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/us-steps-up-defense-cooperation-in-southeast-asia/</link>
      <description>Washington is making progress with a range of states: from staunch ally the Philippines to newer partner Vietnam and even Cambodia, where China's influence dominates.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyz Election Commission Tosses Results From District With Highest Turnout, Citing Violations</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/kyrgyz-election-commission-tosses-results-from-district-with-highest-turnout-citing-violations/</link>
      <description>The commission says all 14 candidates won’t be permitted to run again for the seat, but a court could reverse that decision.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is China’s Real Estate Crisis Driving the Next Stage of Homegrown Innovation?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/is-chinas-real-estate-crisis-driving-the-next-stage-of-homegrown-innovation/</link>
      <description>A closer look at the economic numbers suggests that a bad real estate industry is not all bad news for the Chinese economy.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xi Jinping’s Grip on the Military Is Getting Stronger, Not Weaker</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/xi-jinpings-grip-on-the-military-is-getting-stronger-not-weaker/</link>
      <description>Xi continues to eliminate factional networks that could eventually develop into rivals for PLA loyalty.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Autocrats’ War on Universities</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/autocrats-war-on-universities-no-accident-requires-strategic-resistance-by-jan-werner-mueller-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is no accident that aspiring autocrats try to exert control over higher education, given universities' potential to become sites of resistance and promoters of &quot;democratic competence.&quot; The real question is why university leaders have not done more to anticipate the far right's latest onslaught.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s New ‘Two-Front Strategy’ Against Japan and Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/chinas-new-two-front-strategy-against-japan-and-taiwan/</link>
      <description>The use of both international lawfare and historical narrative warfare signals a major, under-recognized shift in China’s Taiwan strategy and its approach to Japan.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria’s transition has gone better than expected</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/04/syrias-transition-has-gone-better-than-expected</link>
      <description>The president has been a deft diplomat, but must do more reassure Syrians</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyrgyzstan is losing its status as Central Asia’s only democracy</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/04/kyrgyzstan-is-losing-its-status-as-central-asias-only-democracy</link>
      <description>The president is muffling the opposition and consolidating power</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Japan’s efforts to wean itself off Chinese rare earths</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/04/lessons-from-japans-efforts-to-wean-itself-off-chinese-rare-earths</link>
      <description>Numbers one, two and three: it’s a lot harder than it sounds</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South-East Asia and Sri Lanka are reeling from storms and flooding</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/04/south-east-asia-and-sri-lanka-are-reeling-from-storms-and-flooding</link>
      <description>Cyclones close to the equator are rare and dangerous</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After a terrible fire in Hong Kong, public fury smoulders</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/04/after-a-terrible-fire-in-hong-kong-public-fury-smoulders</link>
      <description>The government is determined to suppress protest</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The general who refused to crush Tiananmen’s protesters</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/04/the-general-who-refused-to-crush-tiananmens-protesters</link>
      <description>A leaked video of his court-martial has suddenly appeared</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western armed forces have struggled to fill their ranks to deter Russia</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/12/04/western-armed-forces-have-struggled-to-fill-their-ranks-to-deter-russia</link>
      <description>More sensible recruiting policies could help</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What will your child’s Trump Account be worth?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/04/what-will-your-childs-trump-account-be-worth</link>
      <description>The president has cribbed a signature policy from an unlikely source</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some cocaine-smuggling presidents are more innocent than others</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/04/some-cocaine-smuggling-presidents-are-more-innocent-than-others</link>
      <description>As Donald Trump revives the Monroe Doctrine, he is bewildering America’s neighbours about what it stands for</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A special election puts Democrats on track to flip the House</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/04/a-special-election-puts-democrats-on-track-to-flip-the-house</link>
      <description>Though the predictive power of these contests has shrunk of late</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republicans still don’t know with Obamacare</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/04/republicans-still-dont-know-with-obamacare</link>
      <description>Expiring subsidies are a big political headache</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weekly cartoon</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/04/the-weekly-cartoon</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/04/politics</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-world-this-week/2025/12/04/business</link>
      <description/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why a small corruption scandal is a big problem for the EU</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/04/why-a-small-corruption-scandal-is-a-big-problem-for-the-eu</link>
      <description>Diplomats at the trough in Brussels</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greece is teaching Germany how to get government online</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/04/greece-is-teaching-germany-how-to-get-government-online</link>
      <description>A legendary bureaucracy is making Olympian efforts at digitalisation</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hague is coping with the decline of international courts</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/04/the-hague-is-coping-with-the-decline-of-international-courts</link>
      <description>A loss of prestige for global criminal justice, and for its capital</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy’s populist right stalls a sexual-consent law</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/04/italys-populist-right-stalls-a-sexual-consent-law</link>
      <description>Despite harsher penalties for femicide, Italian machismo is not over</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s peace initiative has stalled in Moscow</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/04/americas-peace-initiative-has-stalled-in-moscow</link>
      <description>Volodymyr Zelensky faces a political crisis over corruption</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will the mega-merger wave destroy value for shareholders?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/04/will-the-mega-merger-wave-destroy-value-for-shareholders</link>
      <description>It’s a coin toss</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How many hours should employees work?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/04/how-many-hours-should-employees-work</link>
      <description>A question that reveals something about every boss</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To halt their decline, VW and others are turning Chinese</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/04/to-halt-their-decline-vw-and-others-are-turning-chinese</link>
      <description>Foreign carmakers are localising their operations in the country</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Even Europe’s penmakers are under threat</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/04/even-europes-penmakers-are-under-threat</link>
      <description>But one quirky Italian brand is thriving</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s unlikely new entertainment capital</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/04/chinas-unlikely-new-entertainment-capital</link>
      <description>Zhengzhou is emerging as the Hollywood of micro-dramas</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Africa needs to generate more electricity</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/04/africa-needs-to-generate-more-electricity</link>
      <description>It also has to create more demand for it</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binyamin Netanyahu has asked for a presidential pardon</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/04/binyamin-netanyahu-has-asked-for-a-presidential-pardon</link>
      <description>Why has he chosen now to do so?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia’s dodgy plan for a pipeline in Congo</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/04/russias-dodgy-plan-for-a-pipeline-in-congo</link>
      <description>If it is built, it will probably benefit Russia rather than ordinary Congolese</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An insurgency may be brewing against Syria’s new leaders</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/04/an-insurgency-may-be-brewing-against-syrias-new-leaders</link>
      <description>Alawites close to the former Assad regime are increasingly unhappy</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Syria uneasily celebrates a year of liberation</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/04/syria-uneasily-celebrates-a-year-of-liberation</link>
      <description>The flaws of Ahmed al-Sharaa’s rule are beginning to show</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China built a swanky cricket pitch to win over tiny Grenada</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/04/china-built-a-swanky-cricket-pitch-to-win-over-tiny-grenada</link>
      <description>The locals love them for it</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republicans still don’t know what to do with Obamacare</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/04/republicans-still-dont-know-what-to-do-with-obamacare</link>
      <description>Expiring subsidies are a big political headache</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Britain’s slot-machine politics</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/04/britains-slot-machine-politics</link>
      <description>Voting is becoming a high-stakes, wildly unpredictable gamble</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong’s Tragic Fire Shows the Consequences of a Hollowed-out Civil Society</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/hong-kongs-tragic-fire-shows-the-consequences-of-a-hollowed-out-civil-society/</link>
      <description>The colossal failure of regulatory oversight across governmental departments is clear – and Hong Kong has quashed the civilian watchdogs that used to close the gaps.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transactional Diplomacy Cannot Bring Peace to Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-peace-process-that-ignores-human-rights-justice-doomed-to-fail-by-oleksandra-matviichuk-and-michael-o-flaherty-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although diplomacy to end Russia's war in Ukraine is intensifying, the goal cannot be limited to a cessation of hostilities. Unless a negotiated settlement is firmly anchored in existing international law and human-rights frameworks, it will not settle anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Asia’s Semiconductor Powerhouse Fits into ASEAN’s Strategic Future</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-asias-semiconductor-powerhouse-fits-into-aseans-strategic-future/</link>
      <description>With tensions between Tokyo and Beijing rising, ASEAN and Taiwan must balance economic integration with the political realities imposed by China’s growing assertiveness.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Timor-Leste’s Digital Statecraft</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/timor-lestes-digital-statecraft/</link>
      <description>How Southeast Asia’s newest ASEAN member built a modern governance model.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patrick Drahi has bested his lenders yet again</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/04/patrick-drahi-has-bested-his-lenders-yet-again</link>
      <description>The world’s messiest debt restructuring just got even uglier</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI is rewiring childhood</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/04/how-ai-is-rewiring-childhood</link>
      <description>The technology presents dazzling opportunities—and ominous risks</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudis Also Fail to Defuse Pakistan-Afghan Taliban Crisis</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/saudis-also-fail-to-defuse-pakistan-afghan-taliban-crisis/</link>
      <description>Although the first round of talks was not successful, the Saudis will persist in their mediatory effort. Their prestige is on the line.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At home and at school, artificial intelligence is transforming childhood</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2025/12/04/at-home-and-at-school-artificial-intelligence-is-transforming-childhood</link>
      <description>It brings many benefits, but also hidden dangers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At home and at school, AI is transforming childhood</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/briefing/2025/12/04/at-home-and-at-school-ai-is-transforming-childhood</link>
      <description>It brings many benefits, but also hidden dangers</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Trump looms over Vladimir Putin’s visit to India</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/04/donald-trump-looms-over-vladimir-putins-visit-to-india</link>
      <description>America’s president is helping to make Indo-Russian relations great again</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI misinformation may have paradoxical consequences</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/04/ai-misinformation-may-have-paradoxical-consequences</link>
      <description>To understand why, consider the side-blotched lizard</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can golden toilets fix China’s economy?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/04/can-golden-toilets-fix-chinas-economy</link>
      <description>Communist Party officials think so</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin has plunged. Strategy Inc is an early victim</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/04/bitcoin-has-plunged-strategy-inc-is-an-early-victim</link>
      <description>It holds 3% of the world’s total supply</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American sanctions are putting Russia under pressure</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/04/american-sanctions-are-putting-russia-under-pressure</link>
      <description>In time, though, its tankers will find new routes</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s Special Intensive Revision of Electoral Rolls Is Claiming Lives</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/indias-special-intensive-revision-of-electoral-rolls-is-claiming-lives/</link>
      <description>The exercise has rapidly deteriorated into a pressure cooker of impossible deadlines, sleepless nights, and unchecked administrative coercion, now actively claiming lives.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Middle East Order</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/middle-east/trumps-middle-east-order</link>
      <description>The president's transactional style is well suited to the region.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America’s Magical Thinking About Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/ukraine/americas-magical-thinking-about-ukraine</link>
      <description>A bad deal is worse than no deal.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam’s Cautious Acceptance of Chinese 5G Technology</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/vietnams-cautious-acceptance-of-chinese-5g-technology/</link>
      <description>Recent agreements with Huawei and ZTE reflect economic pragmatism rather than a shift in strategic trust.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Myanmar Opium Cultivation Jumps to Highest Level Since 2015: UN</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/myanmar-opium-cultivation-jumps-to-highest-level-since-2015-un/</link>
      <description>The country's conflict is also having a countervailing impact on average poppy yields, which “sharply decreased” in 2025.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markets have the money, developing countries need the projects – what’s stopping them?</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/markets-have-money-developing-countries-need-projects-what-s-stopping-them</link>
      <description>Investors assume developing economies are risky, but evidence shows the opposite.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand Seizes $300M in Assets as Scam Crackdown Deepens</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thailand-seizes-300m-in-assets-as-scam-crackdown-deepens/</link>
      <description>Bangkok appears determined to clamp down on Cambodia-based scam syndicates, but allegations of high-level Thai involvement continue to dog Prime Minister Anutin.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happens when Cambodia graduates from aid but isn’t self-sustaining?</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/what-happens-when-cambodia-graduates-aid-isn-t-self-sustaining</link>
      <description>Cambodia’s “missing middle” means economic growth hasn’t yet produced the managers and technicians the country needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hat Yai Flooding Catastrophe a Massive Blow to Thailand’s PM Anutin</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/hat-yai-flooding-catastrophe-a-massive-blow-to-thailands-pm-anutin/</link>
      <description>With a snap general election on the horizon, the Thai leader has been assailed for his government's sluggish response to a disaster that has killed at least 267 people.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Wealth of Nations</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/instrumental-capital-sovereign-wealth-funds-gulf/</link>
      <description>How instrumental capital is reshaping the world.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan’s analog bureaucracy holds back a digital economy</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/japan-s-analog-bureaucracy-holds-back-digital-economy</link>
      <description>Obtaining a criminal-record check should be a simple task, yet in Japan reveals a state capacity problem.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 23:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Suspends All Immigration Requests From 19 ‘High-Risk’ Countries</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/us-immigration-crackdown-19-countries-asylum-green-card-travel-ban/</link>
      <description>Critics say the mandate is evidence of the Trump administration’s xenophobic policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Issues Sweeping Immigration Crackdown on 19 Countries</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/us-immigration-crackdown-19-countries-asylum/</link>
      <description>Critics say the mandate is evidence of the Trump administration’s xenophobic policies.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Chinese firm attempts to bring a rocket stage back to Earth</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/03/a-chinese-firm-attempts-to-bring-a-rocket-stage-back-to-earth</link>
      <description>It fails, but the launch suggests the Americans may soon have real competition</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Chinese firm attempts to bring a booster rocket back to Earth</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/03/a-chinese-firm-attempts-to-bring-a-booster-rocket-back-to-earth</link>
      <description>It fails, but the launch suggests the Americans may soon have real competition</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Chinese rocket industry takes off</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/03/the-chinese-rocket-industry-takes-off</link>
      <description>A reusable booster failed last week, but showed the Americans they may soon have competition</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mali’s Junta Is the Architect of Its Own Disasters</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/mali-junta-france-interventions-un-ecowas/</link>
      <description>Blaming foreign intervention is easy—but mistaken.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 22:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin Heads to New Delhi</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/putin-new-delhi-trip-modi-india-russia-energy/</link>
      <description>The visit comes at a somewhat precarious moment for India-Russia relations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Military Machine Shouldn’t Run on American Chips</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/china-nvidia-chips-ai-trump/</link>
      <description>The GAIN AI Act would have given U.S. buyers priority in the global AI race.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was Guinea-Bissau’s Coup a Sham?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/guinea-bissau-military-coup-election-sham/</link>
      <description>Major African politicians are claiming that Africa’s latest putsch was staged.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the Economic Crisis in Laos Coming to an End?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/is-the-economic-crisis-in-laos-coming-to-an-end/</link>
      <description>The kip has stabilized and inflation is dropping, but the issue of the government's heavy external debt remains unresolved.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stockholm is Europe’s new capital of capital</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/03/stockholm-is-europes-new-capital-of-capital</link>
      <description>And with Sweden embarking on a borrowing spree, it is a bond trader’s paradise</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enough dithering. Europe must pay to save Ukraine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/03/enough-dithering-europe-must-pay-to-save-ukraine</link>
      <description>America will not. Europe’s security depends on agreeing how to</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kazakhstan’s Orda.kz Raided, Editor Placed Under House Arrest</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/kazakhstans-orda-kz-raided-editor-placed-under-house-arrest/</link>
      <description>Pressure has allegedly been mounting for months on the popular outlet.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Kevin Hassett would lead the Federal Reserve?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/03/which-kevin-hassett-would-lead-the-federal-reserve</link>
      <description>He was once a right-of-centre tax expert. He has become a partisan hack</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why autism should not be treated as a single condition</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/03/why-autism-should-not-be-treated-as-a-single-condition</link>
      <description>A better understanding of its biology will lead to better interventions</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surging satellite numbers threaten to dazzle even space telescopes</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2025/12/03/surging-satellite-numbers-threaten-to-dazzle-even-space-telescopes</link>
      <description>Low-flying satellites can ruin astronomical observations</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu Wants a Never-Go-to-Jail Card</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/netanyahu-pardon-request-democracy-threat/685121/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>His bid for a pardon rests on the assumption that he’s irreplaceable.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Uzbekistan’s Peacebuilding Efforts Sustainable in Central Asia?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/are-uzbekistans-peacebuilding-efforts-sustainable-in-central-asia/</link>
      <description>The underlying challenges to lasting peace along Central Asia’s borders lie in the fundamentally top-down structure of regional diplomacy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manias, Panics, and AI</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/three-questions-to-assess-ai-investment-boom-by-simon-johnson-and-piero-novelli-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By any metric, the US – and, by implication, the world – are now in the midst of an intense AI speculative boom. To assess whether all the investment pouring into the industry will build something useful, three questions must be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 17:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will China Forcibly Boost Fertility?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-births-rebound-will-be-temporary-ban-abortion-contraception-unlikely-by-yi-fuxian-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China is widely expected to adopt a range of pronatalist policies in a bid to raise birth rates. But recent efforts to encourage women to have more babies will have short-lived effects, while coercive measures – such as bans on contraception and abortion – would trigger a public backlash and prove futile at best.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A survival guide for advisers to the powerful</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/survival-guide-advisers-powerful</link>
      <description>From Nixon’s downfall to Merkel’s success, history offers hard lessons for those behind the throne.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From micro-dramas to video games, Chinese entertainment is booming</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/03/from-micro-dramas-to-video-games-chinese-entertainment-is-booming</link>
      <description>But how much slack will the Communist Party give creators?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s entertainment industry is booming but needs some slack</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/03/chinas-entertainment-industry-is-booming-but-needs-some-slack</link>
      <description>The Communist Party is in a quandary</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do US Congressional Leaders Keep Beating the Stock Market?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/when-lawmakers-outperform-wall-street-by-shang-jin-wei-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Members of Congress continue to trade individual stocks even as they shape legislative agendas and gain access to non-public information. New research sheds light on how political power affects financial outcomes and underscores the need for reforms that draw a firm line between public office and private profit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine Can Only Rely on Itself</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/ukraine-peace-deal-security-guarantees-military/</link>
      <description>In any peace deal with Russia, security guarantees from outsiders won't guarantee much.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine’s Corruption Scandal Is Bad. But Exposing It Is a Win.</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/ukraines-corruption-democracy-accountability/685120/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>The fight was always for the independence of a country that can hold its powerful to account.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu Is Still Following the Same Failed Gaza Strategy</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/gaza-israel-palestine-ceasefire-trump-netanyahu-hamas/</link>
      <description>Two years of war have brought tactical changes and immense suffering, but the political status quo endures.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why does Donald Trump care about Honduras’s election?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/12/03/why-does-donald-trump-care-about-hondurass-election</link>
      <description>His interventions have complicated matters</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Outlook for China-US Strategic Competition in 2026</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-outlook-for-china-us-strategic-competition-in-2026/</link>
      <description>Insights from Sarah M. Beran.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India’s defence-tech startups are thriving</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/asia/2025/12/03/indias-defence-tech-startups-are-thriving</link>
      <description>The recent war with Pakistan has infused new energy into the sector</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lee Jae-myung’s Latest Policy Signals to North Korea</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/lee-jae-myungs-latest-policy-signals-to-north-korea/</link>
      <description>Lee has downgraded “denuclearization” as a goal. Will it be enough to attract interest from Pyongyang?</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Massive Costs of Anti-Immigration Policies</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/anti-immigration-sentiments-undermine-growth-and-innovation-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even as aging populations leave the workforce and critical sectors scramble for talent, an anti-immigrant backlash is gathering force across much of the developed world. The result is a widening gap between economic fundamentals and policy choices that threatens long-term growth and prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokundi Bombing: A Threat to Pakistan’s Economic and Strategic Future</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/nokundi-bombing-a-threat-to-pakistans-economic-and-strategic-future/</link>
      <description>The attack targeted foreign nationals working on mining projects in Balochistan’s mineral-rich Chagai district.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As Cyclone Ditwah Recedes, Sri Lanka Confronts the Failures That Made a Disaster Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/as-cyclone-ditwah-recedes-sri-lanka-confronts-the-failures-that-made-a-disaster-inevitable/</link>
      <description>The total economic losses incurred are estimated to be around $6-$7 billion. This is more than the country’s foreign reserves.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Return to Nuclear Testing Looks Inevitable. Here’s How to Manage It.</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/a-return-to-nuclear-testing-looks-inevitable-heres-how-to-manage-it/</link>
      <description>A limited test ban would set important guardrails to manage escalation among nuclear weapons states, particularly the U.S., Russia, and China.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Totalitarianism in China: Resurrected and Rejuvenated by Reform</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/totalitarianism-in-china-resurrected-and-rejuvenated-by-reform/</link>
      <description>Amid the political and economic changes of the early 2000s, it seemed unthinkable that China would revert back to Mao-era repression. But's that's exactly what happened.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year After Martial Law Debacle, South Korea’s New President Vows to Complete ‘Light Revolution’</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/one-year-after-martial-law-debacle-south-koreas-new-president-vows-to-complete-light-revolution/</link>
      <description>In a special address, Lee Jae-myung expressed gratitude toward the citizens for their defense of Korean democracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Security Screening: What the National Guard Shooting Reveals About Afghan Resettlement</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/beyond-security-screening-what-the-national-guard-shooting-reveals-about-afghan-resettlement/</link>
      <description>This incident is a reminder that individual acts of violence cannot be understood, or prevented, through security measures alone.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Global Africa</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-africa-continent-and-diaspora-should-pursue-deeper-economic-integration-by-temwa-gondwe-1-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If the global community of people of African descent was fashioned into an integrated economy, it would present an unparalleled opportunity for deepening trade, mobilizing investment, and creating shared prosperity. All that has been lacking is a vision, and the political will to pursue it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:42:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Cheers for the London Consensus</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/london-consensus-principles-for-21st-century-by-anne-marie-slaughter-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the old Washington Consensus forced developing countries into an austerity straitjacket that inflicted enormous pain on ordinary people, a new set of principles from a multinational roster of economists organized by the London School of Economics offers a long-needed alternative. This time, politics isn't assumed away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is the Filibuster Good For?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/03/filibuster-congress-history-good-for/</link>
      <description>A term originally used to describe pirates is now synonymous with U.S. congressional dysfunction.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Aid With Chinese Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/china/foreign-aid-chinese-characteristics</link>
      <description>Where Beijing is—and isn’t—seeking influence.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The India Trump Made</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/india/india-trump-made</link>
      <description>Where American bullying is leading New Delhi.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Congress rein in Pete Hegseth and his boat-bombing campaign?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/03/will-congress-rein-in-pete-hegseth-and-his-boat-bombing-campaign</link>
      <description>A deadly strike raises stark questions about America’s anti-drug war</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawmakers demand answers about Pete Hegseth’s boat-bombing campaign</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/03/lawmakers-demand-answers-about-pete-hegseths-boat-bombing-campaign</link>
      <description>A deadly strike raises stark questions about America’s anti-drug war</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the Indo-Pacific as a single ocean system</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/rethinking-indo-pacific-single-ocean-system</link>
      <description>The waters that connect the region matter more than the distances between its shores, and 2026 will test that principle.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japan lost its climate leadership – and now Australia can help</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/japan-lost-its-climate-leadership-now-australia-can-help</link>
      <description>Japan’s largest supplier of coal and LNG has just pledged to transition from fossil fuels – creating both tension and opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corruption Allegations and Family Drama Hound Philippine President Marcos</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/corruption-allegations-and-family-drama-hound-philippine-president-marcos/</link>
      <description>Despite the corruption allegations against him, Marcos has so far survived the crisis, but his presidency has been weakened.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 23:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republicans Criticize Hegseth for Deadly Caribbean Double Strike</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/republicans-criticize-hegseth-caribbean-strike/</link>
      <description>Bipartisan lawmakers are demanding congressional probes into the defense secretary’s handling of a deadly boat strike.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu Just Admitted He’s Unfit to Lead Israel</title>
      <link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/2025/12/netanyahu-pardon-request-israel/685116/?utm_source=feed</link>
      <description>In attempting to call off his corruption trial, Netanyahu didn’t incriminate himself, but he did something just as damning.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia bets on old laws to manage new AI risks</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/australia-bets-old-laws-manage-new-ai-risks</link>
      <description>Relying on legacy laws may seem pragmatic, but other countries are racing ahead with purpose-built AI regulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Fire Highlights Hong Kong’s Predicament</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/hong-kong-apartment-fire-china-political-freedoms/</link>
      <description>The tragedy confirmed to many locals that the city’s freedoms have vanished.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Favorite Role? Foreign-Policy Czar.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/trumps-favorite-role-foreign-policy-czar/</link>
      <description>In diplomacy, the U.S. president always seems to follow his own transactional view of human affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Favorite Role? Foreign-Policy Czar.</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/trump-foreign-policy-us-ukraine-peace-plan/</link>
      <description>In diplomacy, the U.S. president always seems to follow his own transactional view of human affairs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin’s Threats Against Europe Undermine Russia-Ukraine Peace Talks</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/putin-witkoff-kushner-russia-ukraine-peace-talks-moscow/</link>
      <description>Moscow remains opposed to surrendering its territorial ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin Meets With Witkoff, Kushner to Discuss Ukraine Peace Plan</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/putin-witkoff-kushner-russia-ukraine-peace-talks/</link>
      <description>Moscow remains opposed to surrendering its territorial ambitions.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 22:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpworld thinks Europe has betrayed the West</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/international/2025/12/02/trumpworld-thinks-europe-has-betrayed-the-west</link>
      <description>Centrist governments across the continent rightly sense a trap</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tajikistan Launches National Messenger ORIZ Amid Surveillance Concerns</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/tajikistan-launches-national-messenger-oriz-amid-surveillance-concerns/</link>
      <description>The government's push for &quot;digital sovereignty&quot; follows similar efforts in Russia and Kazakhstan, raising fears about expanded state monitoring in a country with a dismal human rights record.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Minerals That Drive Trump’s Global Agenda</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/the-minerals-that-drive-trumps-global-agenda/</link>
      <description>From Canada to Pakistan, an interest in critical minerals is a through line in the White House’s foreign policy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AIs could turn opinion polls into gibberish</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/02/ais-could-turn-opinion-polls-into-gibberish</link>
      <description>Large language models can answer surveys and pass the tests to check that a respondent is human</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Venezuela Fixation Is Not About the Oil</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/trump-venezuela-fixation-oil-regime-change-maduro/</link>
      <description>There are lots of reasons why the Trump administration is angling for regime change in Caracas, but heavy oil isn’t one of them.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Korea’s Fractured Democracy: One Year After Martial Law</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/south-koreas-fractured-democracy-one-year-after-martial-law/</link>
      <description>The country’s political polarization has metastasized. What can be done?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renminbi Internationalization Is Closing the Climate Finance Gap</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-panda-dim-sum-ftz-bonds-closing-gap-left-by-dollar-by-ma-jun-and-sean-kidney-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Through a trifecta of fast-growing markets for renminbi-denominated bonds, China is showing that it can support domestic sustainability projects across the Global South. With the United States and other traditional creditors stepping back, Chinese finance is filling the vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chris Waller, not Kevin Hassett, should lead the Federal Reserve</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/12/02/chris-waller-not-kevin-hassett-should-lead-the-federal-reserve</link>
      <description>President Trump is about to make the wrong appointment</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahead of peace talks, Russia’s battlefield advances remain slow</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/12/02/ahead-of-peace-talks-russias-battlefield-advances-remain-slow</link>
      <description>Even at an accelerated recent pace, seizing Ukraine’s eastern regions would take more than two years</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As America pushes peace, Russia’s battlefield advances remain slow</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/12/02/as-america-pushes-peace-russias-battlefield-advances-remain-slow</link>
      <description>Even at an accelerated recent pace, seizing Ukraine’s eastern regions would take more than two years</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADB’s Emphasis on Critical Minerals Sparks Fear in Philippines</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/adbs-emphasis-on-critical-minerals-sparks-fear-in-philippines/</link>
      <description>The ADB’s new program fits right into the Philippine government’s plans for transition mining – to the detriment of Indigenous communities.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Pakistan Adapt to Climate Disaster?</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/pakistan-climate-finance-gap-funding-cop30-adaptation/</link>
      <description>Three years ago, the country became a poster child for climate justice. Now, it faces a steep learning curve to secure the funding it needs.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Chinese Workers Killed in 2 Attacks in Tajikistan Along Afghan Border</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/5-chinese-workers-killed-in-2-attacks-in-tajikistan-along-afghan-border/</link>
      <description>In one of the attacks, a drone was reportedly used to drop grenades on Chinese workers.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Just Transition for Land</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/unccd-mobilize-financing-for-just-land-transition-by-andrea-meza-murillo-and-bradley-hiller-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Annual economic losses linked to desertification, land degradation, and drought amount to $878 billion – far more than the investments needed to mitigate their impact. Only by using innovative financing mechanisms and collaborating more effectively can a just transition to a sustainable and resilient land economy be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High stakes in India’s refusal to send former Bangladesh PM to trial</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/high-stakes-india-s-refusal-send-former-bangladesh-pm-trial</link>
      <description>A carefully worded extradition treaty means New Delhi can hedge its bets, but it should be prepared for blowback.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative Destruction Should Not Spare Commercial Banks</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/cbdcs-great-potential-but-opposed-by-traditional-banks-by-katharina-pistor-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New technologies offer new opportunities to revamp payment and credit systems, making them not only more efficient but also safer. It would be a shame if these were foregone because banks believe that they have a right to a business model that they inherited from political compromises struck centuries ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia’s National AI Plan Has Just Been Released. Who Exactly Will Benefit?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/australias-national-ai-plan-has-just-been-released-who-exactly-will-benefit/</link>
      <description>The plan’s primary goal seems to be attracting international data center investment – even at the cost of abandoning regulation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>India-China Engage in War of Words Over Arunachal Pradesh</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/india-china-engage-in-war-of-words-over-arunachal-pradesh/</link>
      <description>Chinese officials detained an Indian national for 18 hours at Shanghai airport, claiming that her Indian passport was not valid as she is from Arunachal Pradesh.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a 42-year-old Massacre Is Returning to Roil Assam’s Politics</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-a-42-year-old-massacre-is-returning-to-roil-assams-politics/</link>
      <description>The long-suppressed Tiwari Commission report on the 1983 Nellie massacre has finally been released, but early responses suggest it may ignite debate on demographic change rather than accountability for one of India’s deadliest episodes of mass violence.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Latest Earthquake Was a Warning Sign: Bangladesh Isn’t Ready</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/the-latest-earthquake-was-a-warning-sign-bangladesh-isnt-ready/</link>
      <description>The recent M5.5 earthquake occurred outside the better known seismic hazard zones and is a wake-up call to boost preparedness.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can America Win the New Race for Scientific Leadership?</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-race-for-scientific-leadership-talent-china-more-proactive-than-us-by-nancy-qian-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even as China and the United States compete for scientific leadership, the Trump administration has slashed investment in research and tightened immigration rules. If the US has truly entered a second Cold War, it should repeat the strategy that helped it win the first one: expanding the scientific frontier at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toy Seller’s Legal Battle Shines Spotlight on China’s Ultra Strict Gun Rules</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/toy-sellers-legal-battle-shines-spotlight-on-chinas-ultra-strict-gun-rules/</link>
      <description>A merchant selling “gel blasters” is the latest person to face serious criminal charges for possession of seemingly harmless guns.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is the PPP Still Defending Yoon Suk-yeol?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-is-the-ppp-still-defending-yoon-suk-yeol/</link>
      <description>A year after the illegitimate declaration of martial law, the conservative People Power Party is still justifying Yoon’s decision.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkic or Central Asian? Azerbaijan’s Entry Tests the Region’s Identity</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/turkic-or-central-asian-azerbaijans-entry-tests-the-regions-identity/</link>
      <description>What, exactly, is “Central Asia” today?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Taiwan Views the China-Japan Spat</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/how-taiwan-views-the-china-japan-spat/</link>
      <description>A war of perceptions over framings of Japanese Prime Minister Takaichi is taking shape in Taiwan.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America is foolishly waving goodbye to thousands of Chinese boffins</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/china/2025/12/02/america-is-foolishly-waving-goodbye-to-thousands-of-chinese-boffins</link>
      <description>Hostile policies and attacks on science are driving them back into China’s arms</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deeper into the Public Procurement Goldmine</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/public-procurement-most-underused-driver-of-economic-growth-by-ricardo-hausmann-and-yariv-gabay-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Public procurement is one of the world’s most powerful yet underused industrial-policy tools. Rather than treating procurement as a routine administrative task, policymakers must harness it to guide innovators toward developing and scaling solutions to complex societal challenges, from infrastructure to climate resilience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why China Did Not Do a ‘Kissinger’ to Split Europe From America</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/china-europe-russia-ukraine-war-peace-trump-us-geopolitics/</link>
      <description>Europe would have given almost anything for peace, but Beijing had a different calculus.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The G20 Must Follow Through on Debt Relief</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/g20-must-improve-common-framework-for-debt-treatment-restructuring-by-olusegun-obasanjo-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Governments across Africa, Asia, and Latin America have been forced to cut spending on education, health care, and infrastructure to keep funds flowing to foreign creditors, undermining global stability and prosperity. To break this vicious cycle, G20 leaders must urgently revamp the Common Framework for Debt Treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia’s Borneo Election Spells Trouble for Anwarjos</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/02/sabah-election-results-borneo-east-malaysia/</link>
      <description>“Sabah for Sabahans” undermines the country’s precarious ethno-political balance.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Pakistan Army Can’t Afford to Eliminate Imran Khan</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/why-the-pakistan-army-cant-afford-to-eliminate-imran-khan/</link>
      <description>Eliminating the immensely popular leader would not end the crisis; it would unleash one that the Pakistani state may not survive.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to fix Defence? Start by cutting bureaucratic bloat</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/want-fix-defence-start-cutting-bureaucratic-bloat</link>
      <description>Same people, same jobs, new structure – but somehow performance will improve. This story has been told before.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Promise—and Limits—of a Free Press</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/promise-and-limits-free-press</link>
      <description>Journalists alone cannot stave off autocracy.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The West’s Last Chance</title>
      <link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/wests-last-chance</link>
      <description>How to build a new global order before it’s too late.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami’s 5-hour Work Plan for Women: A Patriarchal Ploy?</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/bangladesh-jamaat-e-islamis-5-hour-work-plan-for-women-a-patriarchal-ploy/</link>
      <description>Many Bangladeshis believe that this is a strategy of the Jamaat to send working women back home.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thailand Extradites Prominent Montagnard Rights Activist to Vietnam</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/thailand-extradites-prominent-montagnard-rights-activist-to-vietnam/</link>
      <description>The extradition of Y Quynh Bdap, 33, is a sign of a growing crackdown on Vietnamese refugees and asylum seekers in Thailand, rights groups say.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to Brunei’s Land Ownership Laws Stoke Concerns, Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/changes-to-bruneis-land-ownership-laws-stoke-concerns-uncertainty/</link>
      <description>Non-citizens, including established ethnic Chinese families, face the downgrade of freehold titles – some inherited over generations – into 30-to-60-year leases.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 01:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian universities: A waning soft power</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/australian-universities-waning-soft-power</link>
      <description>Driven by political mood rather than long-term strategy, higher education has become fast, fragile and transactional.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 01:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death Toll From Southeast Asia Storms Nears 800 as Recovery Efforts Continue</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/death-toll-from-southeast-asia-storms-nears-800-as-recovery-efforts-continue/</link>
      <description>At least 176 people have been killed in Thailand and three in Malaysia, while the death toll in Indonesia has climbed above 600.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 23:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One size does not fit all for social media bans</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/one-size-does-not-fit-all-social-media-bans</link>
      <description>With half its population under 18, Nigeria shows why Australia-style digital bans could stifle democratic activism.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 23:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Intensifies Pressure Campaign on Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/01/trump-us-military-boat-strikes-venezuela-caribbean-hegseth-war-crimes/</link>
      <description>But as the legality of U.S. boat strikes comes into question, the White House’s regime-change ambitions may be curbed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Considers Expanding Military Operations to Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/01/trump-us-military-boat-strikes-venezuela-caribbean-hegseth/</link>
      <description>But as the legality of U.S. boat strikes comes into question, the White House’s regime-change ambitions may be curbed.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to spot a bubble bursting</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/finance-and-economics/2025/12/01/how-to-spot-a-bubble-bursting</link>
      <description>Forget valuations. Look out for search-engine hits and fund managers getting fired</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech’s Tarnished Halo</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/01/tech-ai-silicon-valley-america-prestige-soft-power/</link>
      <description>How Silicon Valley’s declining image is dimming America’s light.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaf blowers are the latest thing dividing Americans</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/united-states/2025/12/01/leaf-blowers-are-the-latest-thing-dividing-americans</link>
      <description>An argument that pitches neighbour against neighbour</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American-Led Regime Change Is Usually Disastrous</title>
      <link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/12/01/venezuela-iraq-regime-change-trump/</link>
      <description>The arrogance that led to Iraq now threatens catastrophe in Venezuela.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the frontiers of AI adoption</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/business/2025/12/01/lessons-from-the-frontiers-of-ai-adoption</link>
      <description>Why coders and call-centre agents are especially vulnerable to the technology</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War Room newsletter: Sleepwalking into Africa’s next war</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/01/the-war-room-newsletter-sleepwalking-into-africas-next-war</link>
      <description>Tom Gardner, our Africa correspondent, explores lessons from 20th-century Europe for the Horn of Africa</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Hindu Nationalists Really Believe</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/what-hindu-nationalists-really-believe/</link>
      <description>Hindu nationalism has become the dominant political ideology in India today. What does it actually mean?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe is going on a huge military spending spree</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/12/01/europe-is-going-on-a-huge-military-spending-spree</link>
      <description>But with America now an unreliable ally, will it be enough to counter Russia?</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mormonism’s surprising boom in Africa</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2025/12/01/mormonisms-surprising-boom-in-africa</link>
      <description>The American sect has come a long way from being “the white people’s church”</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigeria Needs Safe Schools</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/nigeria-school-kidnappings-recurrent-problem-requires-safety-measures-by-gordon-brown-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Terrorists are once again targeting Nigeria’s schools, kidnapping more than 300 children in recent weeks. The international community must provide the Nigerian government with immediate surveillance support to secure the release of the abducted students, as well as long-term resources to help make the country’s schools safer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump’s Tariffs Are Hitting India Hard</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-must-seek-tariff-carve-outs-while-pursuing-trade-diversification-and-economic-upgrading-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump’s punishing tariffs have laid bare the fragility of India’s export model, which depends on a handful of markets and a narrow band of relatively low-value-added products. Only by embracing a new model – which emphasizes diversification, regional cooperation, and value addition – can India build long-term resilience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of China’s “Electro-State”</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/china-must-overcome-challenges-to-complete-its-economic-transformation-by-ludovic-subran-1-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China has built the machinery of an innovative, low-carbon industrial economy capable of leading the global net-zero transition and the unfolding AI revolution. But whether this model will be sustainable depends on China's ability to overcome several major challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European pensions are in dire need of reform</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/nuunc/https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2025/12/01/european-pensions-are-in-dire-need-of-reform</link>
      <description>Some countries are much better prepared for ageing than others</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Mongolia’s Athletic Prowess Makes a Splash on Netflix</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/team-mongolias-athletic-prowess-makes-a-splash-on-netflix/</link>
      <description>Mongolia’s performance in the show “Physical: Asia” introduced the country – and its sporting prowess – to a new global audience.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA’s Death Wish</title>
      <link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/maga-destructiveness-motivated-by-frustrated-nostalgia-by-stephen-holmes-2025-12</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The future Donald Trump's supporters want – a pre-feminist white Christian America – cannot be attained, which means his MAGA movement has no constructive program. It can only destroy, because nothing it can build would satisfy it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why xenophobia won't solve South Korea's China problem</title>
      <link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/why-xenophobia-won-t-solve-south-korea-s-china-problem</link>
      <description>A rise in anti-Chinese sentiment damages Seoul’s image and fails to address the real issues of defence and security.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dysfunctional Checks and Balances Are to Blame for Hong Kong’s Devastating Fire – Not Bamboo Scaffolding</title>
      <link>https://thediplomat.com/2025/12/dysfunctional-checks-and-balances-are-to-blame-for-hong-kongs-devastating-fire-not-bamboo-scaffolding/</link>
      <description>Residents had been complaining about fire safety for over a year. That their concerns were neglected raises serious questions about oversight in Hong Kong.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
